<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-212-191668-3060608">
<headline>
The joy of $8 gas
</headline>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-16T07:16:00" id="p1">
<a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/opinion/commentary/la-oe-stein11-2008jul11,0,6314598.column">The joy of $8 gas - Los Angeles Times</a>

<quote>
The joy of $8 gas
Why life would be better if the cost of fuel here were as high here as in Europe. Joel Stein
July 11, 2008

I love $4 gas. It makes me appreciate freedom. I watch as the dollars spin and think, "You, Triceratops, did not get squished by an asteroid in vain. You got squished for a $60 drive to Vegas."

So I didn't go to Wednesday's MoveOn.org protests against high gas prices, which included one at the most expensive gas station in the city, the 76 in Beverly Hills. MoveOn's news release explained: "We want to make sure the world knows that Beverly Hills residents are fed up with gas prices and want a president in the White House who will bring the cost of gas down." MoveOn always understands the problems plaguing Americans, such as the cost of gas in Beverly Hills. If the group succeeds on this issue, I hope it'll next tackle the onerous two-year contract on the new iPhone and how late heirloom tomatoes arrived this year.

If MoveOn and Barack Obama really were going to bravely confront America with hard, necessary truths, they'd tell us how great $4 gas has been for us. With public transit use nationally at a 50-year high, traffic dropped 2.1% in the first four months of this year across the country. That mileage reduction -- along with people driving smaller cars, and more slowly, to save gas -- could mean that 12,000 fewer people will die in traffic accidents this year, according to a study by professors Michael Morrisey at the University of Alabama at Birmingham and David C. Grabowski at Harvard Medical School. Air pollution has been reduced enough, according to UC Davis economics professor J. Paul Leigh, to prevent 2,200 respiratory-related deaths over the last year. Less eating out and more walking and biking could mean a 10% reduction in obesity, according to Charles Courtemanche, an assistant economics professor at the University of North Carolina at Greensboro. And, apparently, higher gas prices also keep econ professors employed.

Yes, it's easy for me to revel in $4 gas because I'm rich. And because my wife and I own a Mini Cooper and a Prius. And because I work at home. And because some of the mutual funds I own contain a fair amount of Exxon Mobil stock. And because I'm brave enough to ignore the manufacturer's suggestion to use high-octane gas.

Cheap gas is unfair. Driving creates huge social costs in the form of traffic, health-damaging pollution and global warming that aren't suffered solely by the person buying the gasoline. Governments usually set up idiotic systems to offset such social costs (emissions trading, ethanol subsidies, taco truck regulations) instead of forcing individuals to pay for their own mess by adding a tax to remedy the imbalance. That kind of tax -- the most fair kind, really -- is called a Pigovian tax, and its use is why gas costs $8 to $10 a gallon in Europe, where they have fewer road deaths even though they drive like complete idiots.

If the U.S. were to slowly jack up gas taxes until we're in the $8 range, life would be better. We'd not only be safer and have reduced greenhouse-gas emissions, we'd probably be happier too. Studies show that the only thing that consistently increases personal happiness is social interaction; high gas prices have led to real estate prices falling faster in suburbs and exurbs than in cities, so we may soon have more content downtown-dwellers. Those same studies show that the thing that makes people least happy is commuting, and telecommuting is way up this year. We could use the tax revenue to fund public transportation. And we'd go back to the days when driving a car was a way to show people what a rich jerk you were. In other words, we would no longer need SUVs for that.

Sure, $8 gas is unfair to poor people, but so is all of capitalism. Rich people get more of the globe's resources. No one has a right to cheap gas any more than he has a right to other things needed for a full and productive life, like an iPhone or a weekly newspaper column where you can tick people off.

We spent 50 years using government money to build the freeways that led to the driving-centric, mall-rat lifestyle I grew up with, so it will surely take decades more to restructure our society into something better. And as bummed as I am to pay a lot for gas, it's a fair price for improving society. I also think government should look into some kind of heavy taxation on Facebook usage.
</quote>
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-16T07:21:00" id="p2">
I'm all for $8 a gallon of gasoline, but not by artificially inflating it with taxes. Expensive gas gets those air hauling status symbols off the streets. I've already noticed light traffic and fewer SUVs.

I'm not rich. I just know that there's a cost to driving, like everything else in life. I drive what I need to and no more.
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-16T07:26:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
I'm all for $8 a gallon of gasoline, but not by artificially inflating it with taxes. Expensive gas gets those air hauling status symbols off the streets. I've already noticed light traffic and fewer SUVs.

I'm not rich. I just know that there's a cost to driving, like everything else in life. I drive what I need to and no more.

</quote>

I think there is a part missing to this article. I have read something like that in the other post. There it was combined with reduction in payroll taxes.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-16T07:28:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
I think there is a part missing to this article. I have read something like that in the other post. There it was combined with reduction in payroll taxes.

</quote>

Soooo....it's a regressive taxation scheme? Who thought of this stuff? Not the democrats I hope.

I'm all for regressive taxation. There should be an incentive to be rich, not a punishment.
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-16T08:59:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
Soooo....it's a regressive taxation scheme? Who thought of this stuff? Not the democrats I hope.

I'm all for regressive taxation. There should be an incentive to be rich, not a punishment.

</quote>

Remember, however, that income beyond ~$90K doesn't have a payroll tax, so it would be regressive vis a vis the middle class vs. the lower class. The evil rich don't benefit here.
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-16T09:02:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
I'm all for $8 a gallon of gasoline, but not by artificially inflating it with taxes. Expensive gas gets those air hauling status symbols off the streets. I've already noticed light traffic and fewer SUVs.

I'm not rich. I just know that there's a cost to driving, like everything else in life. I drive what I need to and no more.

</quote>

Timing the tax is what's critical here. Increasing it by $4 at once would be a killer. Adding $0.10 every quarter would take 10 years to implement the full tax. People can adjust their consumption habits over this time frame, i.e., buy the Prius instead of the Expedition at their next car purchase, etc.
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2008-07-16T13:58:00" id="p7">
<quote>
I also think government should look into some kind of heavy taxation on Facebook usage.
</quote>

Hold on there, killer! That's crazy talk! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/>

...'course, 'twould certainly be an effective way of paying the national debt. And it would cut down on my timewasting significantly. Hm...
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-16T14:35:00" id="p8">
Very funny and shallow text...If things could only be that simple.
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-16T14:39:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
Timing the tax is what's critical here. Increasing it by $4 at once would be a killer. Adding $0.10 every quarter would take 10 years to implement the full tax. People can adjust their consumption habits over this time frame, i.e., buy the Prius instead of the Expedition at their next car purchase, etc.

</quote>

Unfortunately Shek, you don't have the 10 years. You had 5 years back in 2003 but now, the time has ran out.
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2008-07-16T14:43:00" id="p10">
I just noticed your posting times....goodness gracious....do you stay up after the All Star game?!?!?!

And I just traded in my 2001 Durango for a 2008 Toyota RAV 4...4 cylinder. Cost me $41 to fill instead of $78 and I got 125 more miles. I am letting someone else pull the Scout trailer for now on!
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-16T15:15:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="Albany Rifles">
I just noticed your posting times....goodness gracious....do you stay up after the All Star game?!?!?!

And I just traded in my 2001 Durango for a 2008 Toyota RAV 4...4 cylinder. Cost me $41 to fill instead of $78 and I got 125 more miles. I am letting someone else pull the Scout trailer for now on!

</quote>

I'm drinking hefeweissen while looking at the Zugspitze <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) TDY can be rough!
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-16T15:15:00" id="p12">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
Unfortunately Shek, you don't have the 10 years. You had 5 years back in 2003 but now, the time has ran out.

</quote>

How has it run out?
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2008-07-16T15:17:00" id="p13">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
I'm drinking hefeweissen while looking at the Zugspitze <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) TDY can be rough!

</quote>

I hate you.....have one for me!
</post>
<post author="HistoricalDavid" datetime="2008-07-16T15:21:00" id="p14">
Flying over Dallas, I could only think: Christ, the $10 gallon is gonna KILL that urban sprawl stone dead. That was nothing compared to trips through New Mexico, though.

(My flight also took me over Detroit. I don't mean to judge a city from 35,000 feet, but I think I've seen enough...)
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-16T15:27:00" id="p15">
<quote orig_author="Albany Rifles">
I hate you.....have one for me!

</quote>

Mission complete! I've already had a few (over the course of the week) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/> I've even got the wife drinking beer. Well, at least Radler...
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2008-07-16T17:13:00" id="p16">
<quote orig_author="HistoricalDavid">
(My flight also took me over Detroit. I don't mean to judge a city from 35,000 feet, but I think I've seen enough...)

</quote>

<img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-16T17:20:00" id="p17">
<quote orig_author="HistoricalDavid">
Flying over Dallas, I could only think: Christ, the $10 gallon is gonna KILL that urban sprawl stone dead. That was nothing compared to trips through New Mexico, though.

(My flight also took me over Detroit. I don't mean to judge a city from 35,000 feet, but I think I've seen enough...)

</quote>

I have some chaps working for me out there in Irving, near Dallas and they tell me that unlike the Seattle area, where I live, there is very little mass transit over there. I keep wondering how I would survive over there.

I HATE driving to work (unless its, like, next door <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/> ), I would lose out on the beauty sleep <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/tongue.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-16T18:09:00" id="p18">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
Remember, however, that income beyond ~$90K doesn't have a payroll tax, so it would be regressive vis a vis the middle class vs. the lower class. The evil rich don't benefit here.

</quote>

That's correct. But isn't that tied to the Social Security and the benefit amount tops out at a certain income level. Obama argued to increase payroll tax on the rich based on the argument that it's regressive. However the system as designed by FDR put that limit in place because of the benefit limit.

<quote orig_author="Shek">
Timing the tax is what's critical here. Increasing it by $4 at once would be a killer. Adding $0.10 every quarter would take 10 years to implement the full tax. People can adjust their consumption habits over this time frame, i.e., buy the Prius instead of the Expedition at their next car purchase, etc.

</quote>

We pay enough taxes on gasoline already. Various direct federal, state, and local taxes amount to almost 25% of the cost. And that's after the massive royalties and corporate taxes the government collect on the oil companies before we see a drop of fuel.
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-16T18:18:00" id="p19">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
We pay enough taxes on gasoline already. Various direct federal, state, and local taxes amount to almost 25% of the cost. And that's after the massive royalties and corporate taxes the government collect on the oil companies before we see a drop of fuel.

</quote>

It would give us a chance to wean us off our gas addiction. We have started seeing some of the benefits already. The money can be fuelled back to us either through social benefits funded by these taxes (leftist model) or through payroll deductions (conservative model)

Else we will be paying the rick sheikhs the same amount in a few years.
</post>
<post author="mweber24" datetime="2008-07-16T20:46:00" id="p20">
Independant transportation and free choice are GOOD things, not bad. Our quality of life and productivity improve with cheap gas. Why do people live away from cities and drive their own big cars? Because home farther from the city center can be affordably big, more space, and give a better quality of life. They also give better access to the countryside. Your own car increases productivity because you waste less time trying to coordinate mass transit. Your time is your own, to do with as you please. Big cars can haul more stuff, and are arguably safer than tiny cars. At the very least they give their drivers increased pleasure, because it is what they want, again a higher quality of life. The goal should be cheap energy for transportation. We are NOT addicted to oil or gas or energy, we simply desire a higher quality of life. Oil is a means to an end. If you want to substitute oil of a more efficient (ie cheaper) alternative, that is certainly logical, but I see no reason why should be made to feel guilty over wanting a better life! Maybe we should all work for half pay if we feel our lives are so excessive! But then, what would the government tax? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Herodotus" datetime="2008-07-16T21:04:00" id="p21">
I was surprised that MoveOn actually organized a protest against high gas prices...at a gas station, no less. Do they not know what causes prices to go up or down? Maybe someone needs to teach them economics. I can live with 8 dollar gas, I can live with 15 dollar gas too; I'm getting in great shape riding my bike. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-16T21:39:00" id="p22">
<quote orig_author="mweber24">
Independant transportation and free choice are GOOD things, not bad. Our quality of life and productivity improve with cheap gas. Why do people live away from cities and drive their own big cars? Because home farther from the city center can be affordably big, more space, and give a better quality of life. They also give better access to the countryside. Your own car increases productivity because you waste less time trying to coordinate mass transit. Your time is your own, to do with as you please. Big cars can haul more stuff, and are arguably safer than tiny cars. At the very least they give their drivers increased pleasure, because it is what they want, again a higher quality of life. The goal should be cheap energy for transportation. We are NOT addicted to oil or gas or energy, we simply desire a higher quality of life. Oil is a means to an end. If you want to substitute oil of a more efficient (ie cheaper) alternative, that is certainly logical, but I see no reason why should be made to feel guilty over wanting a better life! Maybe we should all work for half pay if we feel our lives are so excessive! But then, what would the government tax? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>

</quote>

I have no problem with improving quality of life and I certinly dont want anyone to feel guilty for that. I would actually like to have a Hummer, that I would use to drive from my Mcmansion in the suburbs to the big city during the weekends.

Hell, I would like to travel around in my private chopper every evening.

You can still do all of what you said, its a free country after all.

You just have to have the moolah to pay for it all.

<quote orig_author="Herodotus">
I was surprised that MoveOn actually organized a protest against high gas prices...at a gas station, no less. Do they not know what causes prices to go up or down? Maybe someone needs to teach them economics. I can live with 8 dollar gas, I can live with 15 dollar gas too; I'm getting in great shape riding my bike. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>

</quote>

Same here, I love sleeping in the bus to/ from work <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="Herodotus" datetime="2008-07-16T22:22:00" id="p23">
<quote>
Same here, I love sleeping in the bus to/ from work
</quote>

It's stress-free, let someone else worry about the traffic. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-16T23:10:00" id="p24">
<quote orig_author="Herodotus">
It's stress-free, let someone else worry about the traffic. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )

</quote>

Absolutely <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>

the only bummer is sometimes I fail to wake up at my stop and then have to walk all the way back <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/tongue.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-17T11:33:00" id="p25">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
How has it run out?

</quote>

Ahh, how has it run out...it has run out in an ironic way.

I was going to save this writings for the other thread about oil but this one seems to be appropriate just as Bluesman's thread. I don't hate America or Americans but some things that happen now and things that will continue to happen in the future are solely your mess that you cooked and served.

I will start with the text that this jolly gentleman wrote for the L.A. Times. The jolly gentleman loves $4 per gallon. The $4 per gallon will reduce pollution, it will improve the health by reducing hazard emissions and make people walk more which will make them thinner and more fit, also it will make public transit popular and people can socialize there and be truly happy…Oh,Yay!!! How splendid vision that is. And bad cheap gas made all this mess, separating the people, by sending them into the suburbs and making them to commute for hours. Cheap gasoline is a baddy. More expensive gasoline is a goody. And the more expensive gasoline is the more joy it will bring. On the down side, the poor people are going to suffer the most but what the heck, it is the capitalism way, so that is ok. But jolly gentleman is proud to state that he can afford the $4 per gallon, that he lives in suburbia and that he has Exxon mobile stocks. Jolly gentleman works from home too. It doesn’t matter because he is rich, he has his heart at the right place. He cares for the benefit of all. So he is a philanthropist. That is so nifty.

I wonder what the jolly gentleman would have to say if he wasn’t the rich guy. What do you think? Would he be so blabby about good things that high fuel prices bring? I don’t think so. And the title of his text the joy of $4 bucks per gallon is deeply offensive. It is offensive because his $4 bucks per gallon will kill next year a couple of million people.
So from his text, I think that the jolly gentleman is happy person cause his Exxon mobile stocks are going up and he is getting richer. But enough about him and his jolly views….

The offshore drilling and Alaska drilling won’t help. I was watching that video with the priest whom is talking about AWR. He mentioned about how oil company pumps gas back to the earth, aka back to the oil well and he refers that as a waste. Pumping gas back to the oil well means only one thing, and that is that the oil reserve is so deep that you need to pump gas to force the oil out. The thing that people don’t know about oil and the peak of production is that oil comes out from the ground under pressure and when you extract oil and gas that pressure drops and than you need to put more gas, water or whatever in to force the oil out. The problem is, that you can do that only to a certain level, later on it doesn’t matter how much effort you put in the oil well the price of extraction of oil will go higher making the overall price of oil higher. Technically we will never run out of oil physically, we will run out of oil because the price of its extraction will be higher than the oil itself. There is simply no way that you can extract all oil out of the ground and have the same price. And if the story about US peak in the 70’es is true, that means that USA has oil but the price of its extraction is so high that it won’t make any difference at the market. The drop by 9$ is just a temporary and it will go up again this year. There is no quick and easy way out of this by any means.

The problem with the US and oil is deep and very complex. The problem is systemic and very hard to solve without huge cuts and some radical changes.
The oil story and the oil crisis in the US go like this.
1. Oil is discovered.
2. Cars are build
3. Cities are dirty from industry and over populated
4. Suburbia is created as a model of life
5. Cars are build even more to transport people from suburbia to the city to work
6. Roads are build to meet the increasing demand for transport
7. Suburbia is spreading, roads are getting wider and longer
8. City is decaying
9. Mass transport is destroyed to boost production of cars
10. Roads maintenance is rising rapidly
11. Prices of oil are getting higher
12. Suburbia needs to lower the prices or loosen the credit policies to continue to grow and make profits.
13. People are getting poorer
14. The value of the house is getting lower than the credit issued for it
15. Housing bubble bursts
16. Mortgage banking goes down with it.
17. Oil prices go higher
18. Car production is getting slower, profits are getting smaller as the costs are getting higher
19. Car industry goes down
20. Without oil and cars, suburbia goes down as a model of life.

People are getting back to the cities only to find out that the cities are full of desperate poor people and what follows is:
1. Rate of crime goes up
2. Law enforcement is growing and becomes brutal.
3. Riots accrue.

Since mostly non whites are poor and hopeless the tensions get racial context and larger violence breaks out..
1. More violent measures are applied
2. Democracy disappears.

The problem with the free market is, although it has huge benefits, that it is very very very short sighted. If you apply the free market on,for an example the military research and development do you think that the F22 would fly today? No it wouldn't.
Since you didn't do reforms in the 80 es and 90 es you are totally unprepared for the oil peak and decline of production. I mean you can't send marines to every place where oil is discovered just to keep suburbia alive.
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-17T12:16:00" id="p26">
Versus,

The problem with your story is that it's wrong. Crime hasn't been on a continuous upward spiral and has fallen over the past decade plus on average. The mortgage industry isn't dying. Wealth is still increasing (across the entire spectrum). The US is still the land of opportunity as evidenced by the number of immigrants (legal and illegal) that flow across the borders everyday.
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-17T17:07:00" id="p27">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
Ahh, how has it run out...it has run out in an ironic way.

I was going to save this writings for the other thread about oil but this one seems to be appropriate just as Bluesman's thread. I don't hate America or Americans but some things that happen now and things that will continue to happen in the future are solely your mess that you cooked and served.

I will start with the text that this jolly gentleman wrote for the L.A. Times. The jolly gentleman loves $4 per gallon. The $4 per gallon will reduce pollution, it will improve the health by reducing hazard emissions and make people walk more which will make them thinner and more fit, also it will make public transit popular and people can socialize there and be truly happyOh,Yay!!! How splendid vision that is. And bad cheap gas made all this mess, separating the people, by sending them into the suburbs and making them to commute for hours. Cheap gasoline is a baddy. More expensive gasoline is a goody. And the more expensive gasoline is the more joy it will bring. On the down side, the poor people are going to suffer the most but what the heck, it is the capitalism way, so that is ok. But jolly gentleman is proud to state that he can afford the $4 per gallon, that he lives in suburbia and that he has Exxon mobile stocks. Jolly gentleman works from home too. It doesnt matter because he is rich, he has his heart at the right place. He cares for the benefit of all. So he is a philanthropist. That is so nifty.

I wonder what the jolly gentleman would have to say if he wasnt the rich guy. What do you think? Would he be so blabby about good things that high fuel prices bring? I dont think so. And the title of his text the joy of $4 bucks per gallon is deeply offensive. It is offensive because his $4 bucks per gallon will kill next year a couple of million people.
So from his text, I think that the jolly gentleman is happy person cause his Exxon mobile stocks are going up and he is getting richer. But enough about him and his jolly views.

The offshore drilling and Alaska drilling wont help. I was watching that video with the priest whom is talking about AWR. He mentioned about how oil company pumps gas back to the earth, aka back to the oil well and he refers that as a waste. Pumping gas back to the oil well means only one thing, and that is that the oil reserve is so deep that you need to pump gas to force the oil out. The thing that people dont know about oil and the peak of production is that oil comes out from the ground under pressure and when you extract oil and gas that pressure drops and than you need to put more gas, water or whatever in to force the oil out. The problem is, that you can do that only to a certain level, later on it doesnt matter how much effort you put in the oil well the price of extraction of oil will go higher making the overall price of oil higher. Technically we will never run out of oil physically, we will run out of oil because the price of its extraction will be higher than the oil itself. There is simply no way that you can extract all oil out of the ground and have the same price. And if the story about US peak in the 70es is true, that means that USA has oil but the price of its extraction is so high that it wont make any difference at the market. The drop by 9$ is just a temporary and it will go up again this year. There is no quick and easy way out of this by any means.

The problem with the US and oil is deep and very complex. The problem is systemic and very hard to solve without huge cuts and some radical changes.
The oil story and the oil crisis in the US go like this.
1. Oil is discovered.
2. Cars are build
3. Cities are dirty from industry and over populated
4. Suburbia is created as a model of life
5. Cars are build even more to transport people from suburbia to the city to work
6. Roads are build to meet the increasing demand for transport
7. Suburbia is spreading, roads are getting wider and longer
8. City is decaying
9. Mass transport is destroyed to boost production of cars
10. Roads maintenance is rising rapidly
11. Prices of oil are getting higher
12. Suburbia needs to lower the prices or loosen the credit policies to continue to grow and make profits.
13. People are getting poorer
14. The value of the house is getting lower than the credit issued for it
15. Housing bubble bursts
16. Mortgage banking goes down with it.
17. Oil prices go higher
18. Car production is getting slower, profits are getting smaller as the costs are getting higher
19. Car industry goes down
20. Without oil and cars, suburbia goes down as a model of life.

People are getting back to the cities only to find out that the cities are full of desperate poor people and what follows is:
1. Rate of crime goes up
2. Law enforcement is growing and becomes brutal.
3. Riots accrue.

Since mostly non whites are poor and hopeless the tensions get racial context and larger violence breaks out..
1. More violent measures are applied
2. Democracy disappears.

The problem with the free market is, although it has huge benefits, that it is very very very short sighted. If you apply the free market on,for an example the military research and development do you think that the F22 would fly today? No it wouldn't.
Since you didn't do reforms in the 80 es and 90 es you are totally unprepared for the oil peak and decline of production. I mean you can't send marines to every place where oil is discovered just to keep suburbia alive.

</quote>

Lovely analysis, simple and easy to understand. The fact that it is flawed, of course, is besides the point, but you do know how to get your message across.
Good.

As for your conclusion, well, people adjust. Europe and the rest of the world has adjusted, so will America. the wuality of life in Europe is not far behind the US. In fact, having lived in both places, I would day that the areas where America trumps Europe has nothing to do with oil/ cars/ travelling, but with innovation in products. Europe, of course, trumps the US in mass transit but that be developed.

You have seen the changes in transportation already happening. I myself can testify to the fact that mass transit is being used more and more. Across the US the federal and state governments will take those steps because the people will clamour for them. The great thing about capitalism is that the financila impetus makes people respond faster than a centrally planned model would.
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-17T18:13:00" id="p28">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
Lovely analysis, simple and easy to understand. The fact that it is flawed, of course, is besides the point, but you do know how to get your message across.
Good.

As for your conclusion, well, people adjust. Europe and the rest of the world has adjusted, so will America. the wuality of life in Europe is not far behind the US. In fact, having lived in both places, I would day that the areas where America trumps Europe has nothing to do with oil/ cars/ travelling, but with innovation in products. Europe, of course, trumps the US in mass transit but that be developed.

You have seen the changes in transportation already happening. I myself can testify to the fact that mass transit is being used more and more. Across the US the federal and state governments will take those steps because the people will clamour for them. The great thing about capitalism is that the financila impetus makes people respond faster than a centrally planned model would.

</quote>

Heh, thank you for the kind words. Yes, it is too simplified and some connections are not given the depth they deserve but you got the point.
Well, I sincerely hope so that people will be able to make that turn as fast as they could, the more they delay the more the problem will grow and make things harder. I would really really like to see some changes in urban planning and recent announcement by Volkswagen to build factory in the US is a sign of progress. Let's just hope that the urban re development will be quick as it is needed.
</post>
<post author="Southie" datetime="2008-07-17T18:22:00" id="p29">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
I HATE driving to work (unless its, like, next door <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/> ), I would lose out on the beauty sleep <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/tongue.gif"/>

</quote>

Luckily my job is pretty much next door! It's about 2 miles from where I live. I can fill my Hyundai Accent up at around $32.00 and get two weeks on it! I love it! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/tongue.gif"/> And that's still with driving around town, when my daughter get's the urge to "go somewhere"!
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-17T20:10:00" id="p30">
<quote orig_author="Southie">
Luckily my job is pretty much next door! It's about 2 miles from where I live. I can fill my Hyundai Accent up at around $32.00 and get two weeks on it! I love it! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/tongue.gif"/> And that's still with driving around town, when my daughter get's the urge to "go somewhere"!

</quote>

Met a guy biking his way to work, at the bus stop this morning. I think he was a Brit, going by his accent.

He started by saying that gas prics are making us all fitter and that he didn't care it the prices hit the roof, "bring it on".

He went on to say that America, instead of wasting $700 bn on the Iraq war, should have given the money to "General Motors or something" for researching better engines <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>

Not sure what he meant by giving the car companies more money, but I couldn't help thinking that in the Seattle area, people are adjusting pretty well to high gas prices <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/cool.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Tarek Morgen" datetime="2008-07-17T20:28:00" id="p31">
just wondering, does the us have now a working public transport system? Or just in some areas?
</post>
<post author="omon" datetime="2008-07-17T20:45:00" id="p32">
<quote orig_author="Tarek Morgen">
just wondering, does the us have now a working public transport system? Or just in some areas?

</quote>

big citys have mass transit,
in nyc we have 24 subway lines, about 360+ stations, about 100 different bus routes, including express, there is a ferry service from manhatten to st. island. long island rail road, and other trains going to new jersy, connecticut.

but in long island, about 45 min drive from the city, there are few bus routes, but you'll be wating a while for them.
</post>
<post author="Tarek Morgen" datetime="2008-07-17T21:20:00" id="p33">
and how do you get from state to state? how good/useful is your nationwide railsystem for personal transfer?
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2008-07-17T21:36:00" id="p34">
<quote orig_author="Tarek Morgen">
and how do you get from state to state? how good/useful is your nationwide railsystem for personal transfer?

</quote>

A close approximation to utterly useless.
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-17T21:49:00" id="p35">
<quote orig_author="Tarek Morgen">
and how do you get from state to state? how good/useful is your nationwide railsystem for personal transfer?

</quote>

American railroads are reduced to junk due to development of trucking system.
</post>
<post author="snc128" datetime="2008-07-17T21:55:00" id="p36">
I think you guys should be happy for this low price of gasoline. It is 3 times expensive in Turkey. Shocked?
on the other hand, I have to admit that when compared to the era it was sold in cents, it is really expensive now.

btw Tarek,
I was in New York city two days ago.
as far as I observed the public transportation system sucks in small cities, but in big and crowded cities like NY City, public transportation is good in terms of transpostation. But the subways are way dirty and cannot be compared to the ones in Europe. But yeah, they are huge and working properly. it is almost impossible to get lost in New York.
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2008-07-17T22:02:00" id="p37">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
American railroads are reduced to junk due to development of trucking system.

</quote>

Not exactly. Rail travel has all but disappeared in the US because of a number of factors -the interstate highway system and cheap gas looming large among them. Rail transport, OTOH, is still quite important. Not as important as it used to be, of course -like you said, the trucking system has taken away business, although that is in part due to adoption of Japanese 'just in time' ordering and inventory practices by US companies. But for bulk transport, and heavy stuff, rail still reigns supreme, especially for long hauls. There's a railway that goes right through the town I'm living in, there's probably at least one train every hour or so.
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2008-07-17T23:45:00" id="p38">
<quote orig_author="Tarek Morgen">
and how do you get from state to state? how good/useful is your nationwide railsystem for personal transfer?

</quote>

We drive or fly.

When I lived in Michigan I was within an 11hr drive to my family in the New England area (Massachusetts, Connecticut). So it was easy to just hop in the car in the morning and head out for the day. Now that I'm in Minnesota I'm 2 days away by car so I have to fly and consequently visit less. I did do a two-day drive in the spring to retrieve some of my father's things but that was a special trip since one of those things was a car. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>

I think most Americans without small children are like me - within a day's drive, we drive without thinking too much about it.

-dale
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-17T23:46:00" id="p39">
Coming from a country said to have the 4th largest railway network in the world, and having travelled many thousands of miles on trains, I really miss rail travel in the US. I had tried to find out about rail travel, for the "experience", but gave up when I saw the costs.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-18T00:14:00" id="p40">
<quote orig_author="Tarek Morgen">
and how do you get from state to state? how good/useful is your nationwide railsystem for personal transfer?

</quote>

What's a rail system? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/confused.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="omon" datetime="2008-07-18T00:33:00" id="p41">
there are trains, between states, but as it was mentioned above, but the cost is as much as plane tickets, but much slower.

there are trains coming to grand central station, from nj and ct, the riders are ppl that live in those states, and work in nyc.
my cooworker lives in ct, he takes metro north to GC st, than lokal train to actual work, it takes him 3 hours each way everyday, there are planty ppl like him.

but other than than i doubt interstate trains are popular.

i personaly travel inside usa and canada by car, i go where i want, at the time i want, it has its minuses, but more pluses, imo
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2008-07-18T00:38:00" id="p42">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
Coming from a country said to have the 4th largest railway network in the world, and having travelled many thousands of miles on trains, I really miss rail travel in the US. I had tried to find out about rail travel, for the "experience", but gave up when I saw the costs.

</quote>

Way back when I was in grad school, I inherited a car from one of my sisters. I grabbed a train from Connecticut and zipped down to Delaware to pick it up. On that train I met a Brit who was on the last leg of a month-long Amtrak tour of America with his family. We chatted about the different trips and I remember him being kindof surprised that I could simply plan to hop in a car and zip to a destination 4 hrs away without any advance planning. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>

-dale
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-18T01:05:00" id="p43">
There was plenty of planning that goes into our car trips. We have to bring enough coke and cheetos and MP3s.

My nephew IMed me a few months ago complaining that his gaming computer died. I told him it's probably a dead power supply after he told me the symptoms. I offered to ship a new power supply over and walk him through the procedure to replace it. He refused.

A few days later he asked me if I would be home the next day. I said yes. He said he would stop by so I can change the power supply for him. He packed his computer into his car and left Phoenix, AZ at 6am. He showed up at my house at noon time in California. He had plenty of coke and cheetos in his car. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2008-07-18T02:51:00" id="p44">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
There was plenty of planning that goes into our car trips. We have to bring enough coke and cheetos and MP3s.

My nephew IMed me a few months ago complaining that his gaming computer died. I told him it's probably a dead power supply after he told me the symptoms. I offered to ship a new power supply over and walk him through the procedure to replace it. He refused.

A few days later he asked me if I would be home the next day. I said yes. He said he would stop by so I can change the power supply for him. He packed his computer into his car and left Phoenix, AZ at 6am. He showed up at my house at noon time in California. He had plenty of coke and cheetos in his car. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )

</quote>

Yeah, I may be completely out of my mind but based on the admittedly-limited feedback I've gotten from Euros and Brits our understanding of distance is completely different. In one of his books Keegan draws a line between Americans and Euros by pointing out that Euros measure distances in miles and Americans in hours.

Like the Brit on that train years ago: "How far is it between your sister's house and your place?" "Oh, probably about 4 or 5 hours." "No, I mean how far - how many miles?" "I have no idea."

-dale
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-18T03:42:00" id="p45">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
Way back when I was in grad school, I inherited a car from one of my sisters. I grabbed a train from Connecticut and zipped down to Delaware to pick it up. On that train I met a Brit who was on the last leg of a month-long Amtrak tour of America with his family. We chatted about the different trips and I remember him being kindof surprised that I could simply plan to hop in a car and zip to a destination 4 hrs away without any advance planning. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>

-dale

</quote>

Hmm, but Europe also has a pretty good road system, does it not? I have traveled on the British motorways and did not find a great deal of difference between those and the American freeways.

I personally don't like those 4-5 hour drives, seems like too much work to me. Thats when I miss those trains

As for the joys of train travel, difficult to explain...

Standing in the open doorways enjoying the stiff breeze, the countryside rushing by, sleeping on the bunk beds, and oh - the food from the hawkers esp. at the stations

Ahhhh <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="bolo121" datetime="2008-07-18T06:17:00" id="p46">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
As for the joys of train travel, difficult to explain...

Standing in the open doorways enjoying the stiff breeze, the countryside rushing by, sleeping on the bunk beds, and oh - the food from the hawkers esp. at the stations

Ahhhh <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>

</quote>

Ok as someone who actually travels by train almost every week, I've got to burst this bubble. Add to your memory, the hijras demanding cash, people stealing your seat in the coach, the stench of the toilet after a couple of hours, the guy opposite you spitting paan into the airstream as you take evasive action....i could go on and on.
My main memory of the trains is always the unmistakeable smell, a blend of sweaty bodies and jasmine flowers.
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2008-07-18T06:22:00" id="p47">
<quote orig_author="bolo121">
jasmine flowers.

</quote>

Jasmine Flowers? Didn't President Clinton stick a flashlight in her hoo-haw that one time?

-dale
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-18T06:24:00" id="p48">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
Yeah, I may be completely out of my mind but based on the admittedly-limited feedback I've gotten from Euros and Brits our understanding of distance is completely different. In one of his books Keegan draws a line between Americans and Euros by pointing out that Euros measure distances in miles and Americans in hours.

Like the Brit on that train years ago: "How far is it between your sister's house and your place?" "Oh, probably about 4 or 5 hours." "No, I mean how far - how many miles?" "I have no idea."

-dale

</quote>

That is so true! Even in short distances like work, we use minutes rather than miles. It's about a 15 min drive for me to go to work. That's roughly 10 miles because I live far from freeway and lots of red lights in between. I know it's 10 miles because I tracked it with my car's odometer.

It's about 4.5 hours for me to hit Vegas, 280 miles away. When I say 4.5 hours, Americans say "oh ok." When I say 280 miles, they say "duh...how long does it take you to drive there?" <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="bolo121" datetime="2008-07-18T06:39:00" id="p49">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
Jasmine Flowers? Didn't President Clinton stick a flashlight in her hoo-haw that one time?

-dale

</quote>

You see, in south India most women wear jasmine flowers in their hair..but after a while they tend to lose their deodorant effect. Absolutely nothing to do with
Hil though... <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-18T06:49:00" id="p50">
<quote orig_author="bolo121">
Ok as someone who actually travels by train almost every week, I've got to burst this bubble. Add to your memory, the hijras demanding cash, people stealing your seat in the coach, the stench of the toilet after a couple of hours, the guy opposite you spitting paan into the airstream as you take evasive action....i could go on and on.
My main memory of the trains is always the unmistakeable smell, a blend of sweaty bodies and jasmine flowers.

</quote>

The last time I travelled on long distance train was in Dec 2004, and that was in AC 2 tier. the last time I travelled in Sleeper 3 tier was probably 2001. i have travelled on local trains, of course, but the last time I did that was in early 2006. It was part of the commuting traffic, and the journey was to my sasural (you know what that means <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/> )

So yes, I do remember those inconveniences that yu mentioned but as time went past the good memories are the only ones that have reamined. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Asim Aquil" datetime="2008-07-18T07:00:00" id="p51">
Just want to mention we pay $1.6/gallon.

The government's spending big on getting better public transport options in place to avoid similar situations here in the future when the oil supply runs low.

However unlike Europe and America, we aren't blessed with great cool weather. Last week the temperature hit a high of 60C in some places of Dubai.

Imagine walking to the bus stop, the metro station in that heat?

However Sheikh Mo came up with an ingenius solution. He says we'll replace all the pavements with air conditioned corridors.

Ultimately public transport is the answer to all of the high gas price problems. European countries have great public transport and thats why they're so car independent.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-18T07:58:00" id="p52">
<quote orig_author="Asim Aquil">
Just want to mention we pay $1.6/gallon.

The government's spending big on getting better public transport options in place to avoid similar situations here in the future when the oil supply runs low.

However unlike Europe and America, we aren't blessed with great cool weather. Last week the temperature hit a high of 60C in some places of Dubai.

</quote>

No way! That's close to 150F! Is that some kind of record? I think that beats Death Valley.

<quote orig_author="Asim Aquil">
Ultimately public transport is the answer to all of the high gas price problems. European countries have great public transport and thats why they're so car independent.

</quote>

It's great if you pack people into small metro areas like Hong Kong or Manhattan. It doesn't work here in California where we have a 50 mile radius of single story houses. Public transportation is great if population density is high. We don't like that. See how rude New Yorkers are? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-18T08:18:00" id="p53">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
No way! That's close to 150F! Is that some kind of record? I think that beats Death Valley.

It's great if you pack people into small metro areas like Hong Kong or Manhattan. It doesn't work here in California where we have a 50 mile radius of single story houses. Public transportation is great if population density is high. We don't like that. See how rude New Yorkers are? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>

</quote>

Gunnut,

Public transportation may be difficult in a suburban sprawl, but car pooling isn't. The suburbes of America present a great opportunity for entrepreneurs to start carpooling services/ shuttles. You get the same benefits (well nearly). It has started working in the suburbs of the Seattle area (Redmond, to be specific)

Actually, I don't know if I agree with the theory that it does not work in a sprawl. I can think of effective use of Park &amp; Rides, combined with a bus transit system that can make it work.

By thway, Londoners, as far as I have seen, are not rude <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-18T08:49:00" id="p54">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
Gunnut,

Public transportation may be difficult in a suburban sprawl, but car pooling isn't. The suburbes of America present a great opportunity for entrepreneurs to start carpooling services/ shuttles. You get the same benefits (well nearly). It has started working in the suburbs of the Seattle area (Redmond, to be specific)

Actually, I don't know if I agree with the theory that it does not work in a sprawl. I can think of effective use of Park &amp; Rides, combined with a bus transit system that can make it work.

By thway, Londoners, as far as I have seen, are not rude <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>

</quote>

Slugging in DC is an amazing grassroots solution that developed, less in response to gas prices and more in response to home prices which forced people to move farther and farther out of the city (making a vehicle commute both time consuming and expensive because of the mileage put on vehicles). This, combined with the HOV lanes that hum along while the regular lanes crawled, provided the incentive to develop carpools that didn't have to rely on dedicated groups, but informal groups with a unique culture.

<a href="http://www.slug-lines.com/">Slug-Lines.com - Slugging and Slug Lines Information For Washington DC</a>

Me, I bought a house 15 minutes from the metro so I wouldn't need to drive my car unless I felt like being lazy.
</post>
<post author="Asim Aquil" datetime="2008-07-18T08:54:00" id="p55">
yeah, thats one thing I noticed about America. Every thing is far far away.

We're used to walking to the grocery store here.

But then you also have more space to make the infrastructure for the public transport.

I think 60C was a Dubai record. Its mostly to do with all the contruction going on and the dust particles forming a greenhouse effect. The official temperature report was a high of 51C, but the greenhouse effect took it higher.

150F is common! Weird thing is, these Europeans come to Dubai and they're like "wow what a lovely sunshine" and we're like WTF is wrong with you? I deduced that we each hate our own weather.

<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HS5tbTn7_C4">YouTube - Emirates - Keep Discovering: Snow</a>
</post>
<post author="bolo121" datetime="2008-07-18T09:00:00" id="p56">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
The last time I travelled on long distance train was in Dec 2004, and that was in AC 2 tier. the last time I travelled in Sleeper 3 tier was probably 2001. i have travelled on local trains, of course, but the last time I did that was in early 2006. It was part of the commuting traffic, and the journey was to my sasural (you know what that means <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/> )

So yes, I do remember those inconveniences that yu mentioned but as time went past the good memories are the only ones that have reamined. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>

</quote>

Ah yes nostalgia....i can relate, the only thing I remember about visiting france nowadays is how very nifty i found the Paris Metro. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="glyn" datetime="2008-07-18T09:01:00" id="p57">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
Coming from a country said to have the 4th largest railway network in the world, and having travelled many thousands of miles on trains, I really miss rail travel in the US. I had tried to find out about rail travel, for the "experience", but gave up when I saw the costs.

</quote>

The British built over 40,000 miles of railway tracks during their occupation of the sub-continent. I don't know how these were arranged since the split between India and Pakistan, and then Bangladesh - or how many miles have been added since.
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-18T09:01:00" id="p58">
<quote orig_author="bolo121">
Ah yes nostalgia....i can relate, the only thing I remember about visiting france nowadays is how very nifty i found the Paris Metro. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )

</quote>

The Paris Metro smelled like urine everywhere I went. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-18T09:12:00" id="p59">
<quote orig_author="glyn">
The British built over 40,000 miles of railway tracks during their occupation of the sub-continent. I don't know how these were arranged since the split between India and Pakistan, and then Bangladesh - or how many miles have been added since.

</quote>

That would have been for thew whole subcontinent. Not sure how muh was left for India after the Partition

Here is the wiki page on the Indian Railways - it talks about 65,000 miles coverage
</post>
<post author="von Spreuth" datetime="2008-07-18T09:32:00" id="p60">
<quote orig_author="Southie">
Luckily my job is pretty much next door! It's about 2 miles from where I live.

</quote>

2 MILES and you go by CAR? We use a FANTASTIC new invention that may not have been heard of there yet called FEET. You user them for WALKING.
</post>
<post author="von Spreuth" datetime="2008-07-18T09:41:00" id="p61">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
Euros measure distances in miles

</quote>

Ah. NO!

Europeans measure the distance in KILOMETERS.

What the "Brits" do is up to them. They never wanted to be part of Europe any way, so stuff them.
</post>
<post author="bolo121" datetime="2008-07-18T09:59:00" id="p62">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
The Paris Metro smelled like urine everywhere I went. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/>

</quote>

Thats what i meant by nostalgia, you dont remember the crowding and smell only the sheer convenience of the thing. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="bolo121" datetime="2008-07-18T10:01:00" id="p63">
<quote orig_author="glyn">
The British built over 40,000 miles of railway tracks during their occupation of the sub-continent. I don't know how these were arranged since the split between India and Pakistan, and then Bangladesh - or how many miles have been added since.

</quote>

For all your Indian Railway Needs... enjoy

<a href="http://www.irfca.org/">IRFCA - The Indian Railways Fan Club</a>
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-18T10:03:00" id="p64">
<quote orig_author="bolo121">
Thats what i meant by nostalgia, you dont remember the crowding and smell only the sheer convenience of the thing. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>

</quote>

Of all the metropolitan transportation systems I've seen (subway, commuter rail, bus), Munich is hands down the best. I haven't visited any Asian cities, so maybe some of them are better, but across the US and Europe, Munich's my #1 vote.
</post>
<post author="Ironduke" datetime="2008-07-18T10:13:00" id="p65">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
Coming from a country said to have the 4th largest railway network in the world, and having travelled many thousands of miles on trains, I really miss rail travel in the US. I had tried to find out about rail travel, for the "experience", but gave up when I saw the costs.

</quote>

Rail travel seems reasonably priced. I looked up a ticket on Amtrak departing today and returning on the 23rd from Minneapolis to Chicago, $119. Expedia's least expensive flight for the same was $425. I'd take the train.
</post>
<post author="von Spreuth" datetime="2008-07-18T10:28:00" id="p66">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
Of all the metropolitan transportation systems I've seen (subway, commuter rail, bus), Munich is hands down the best.

</quote>

Berlin is MUCH better.

No one NEEDS a car in Berlin. NO where in the city is EVER more than 45 minutes away by public transport, 24 hours per day 7 days per week, 365.25 days per year.

<a href="http://www.bvg.de/index.php/en/Bvg/Index/folder/475/name/Home+page">BVG.de - Es lebe Berlin. - Home page</a>
</post>
<post author="Tarek Morgen" datetime="2008-07-18T11:04:00" id="p67">
I have been to both cities, and within in the city-limits and even the sourrunding area (to a degree) one can live perfectly without a car. Though i dont dare to judge which one might be better.
</post>
<post author="glyn" datetime="2008-07-18T11:24:00" id="p68">
<quote orig_author="von Spreuth">
Ah. NO!

Europeans measure the distance in KILOMETERS.

What the "Brits" do is up to them. They never wanted to be part of Europe any way, so stuff them.

</quote>

Another foolish remark from you. I suggest it's you who needs stuffing, preferably with the blunt end of a ragmans trumpet!
</post>
<post author="Southie" datetime="2008-07-18T12:58:00" id="p69">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
Slugging in DC is an amazing grassroots solution that developed, less in response to gas prices and more in response to home prices which forced people to move farther and farther out of the city (making a vehicle commute both time consuming and expensive because of the mileage put on vehicles). This, combined with the HOV lanes that hum along while the regular lanes crawled, provided the incentive to develop carpools that didn't have to rely on dedicated groups, but informal groups with a unique culture.

<a href="http://www.slug-lines.com/">Slug-Lines.com - Slugging and Slug Lines Information For Washington DC</a>

Me, I bought a house 15 minutes from the metro so I wouldn't need to drive my car unless I felt like being lazy.

</quote>

Having lived in VA and worked at the Pentagon, we used the HOV all the time. The regular traffic did crawl along, and as long as there weren't any accidents, the HOV moved pretty fast.

As for the slug lines, when my husband, and our two friends moved to different jobs or retired, I hooked up with other friends to ensure us of the HOV. There were times when we had to go to the slug line and pick up someone. When it was just myself and my co-worker (female) it was kind of scary not knowing who you were going to pick up! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Southie" datetime="2008-07-18T13:02:00" id="p70">
<quote orig_author="bolo121">
Ok as someone who actually travels by train almost every week, I've got to burst this bubble. Add to your memory, the hijras demanding cash, people stealing your seat in the coach, the stench of the toilet after a couple of hours, the guy opposite you spitting paan into the airstream as you take evasive action....i could go on and on.
My main memory of the trains is always the unmistakeable smell, a blend of sweaty bodies and jasmine flowers.

</quote>

I've traveled on the Metro in DC, the "T" in Boston, but my most memorable time was in S. Korea. A friend and I decided to go to Seoul to shop, and we took the subway once we got there. We boarded during rush hour and were literally sandwiched in. I told Pete to hang on to my backpack so when the crowd got off at their stop, I wouldn't be pushed along with them. It was so packed you didn't need to hold on to rails, because you weren't moving! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) Oh, and the smell of kimchi... <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2008-07-18T13:51:00" id="p71">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
Hmm, but Europe also has a pretty good road system, does it not? I have traveled on the British motorways and did not find a great deal of difference between those and the American freeways.

I personally don't like those 4-5 hour drives, seems like too much work to me. Thats when I miss those trains

As for the joys of train travel, difficult to explain...

Standing in the open doorways enjoying the stiff breeze, the countryside rushing by, sleeping on the bunk beds, and oh - the food from the hawkers esp. at the stations

Ahhhh <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>

</quote>

Europe does have a fairly integrated road system...but it is overtaxed in some places. Try driving through south and central Germany. The roads are absolutely clogged. The British motorway system is not a part of that system for one very obvious reason..And it works fine...so long as you are far away from London.

Here in the US we have an excellent highway system (correctly named the Dwight D. Eisenhowere National Defense Interstate Highway system). I go from Southern Virginia to New England several times a year...about a 10 hour drive. To do that I have to find a way to get through Washington, DC, and New York City. Imagine the traffic of London and Paris within 200 miles of each other and you MAY get half of the ide of what it is like. But I regularly cover 600 + miles (950 kms) in abotu 10 hours. Why? Because I have abotu 4 options to get there, almost all on interstates. I can take straight I-95. I can go east of DC along US 301 and out US 50 through Annaplis and the Eastern Shore, pick up the New Jersey Turnpike, go Garden State Pkwy and over the Tappan Zee Bridge and go to pick up I-95 again. Or go the Merrit Pkwy to I-91 to I-84. Or I could go out to I-81 through Winchester to I-78 in HArrisburg to I -287 in New York to I-84 and then east to CT.

In other words, lots of options to drive. Rail works great...if you are a 40 foot ISO container.

What a lot of Europeans do not really understand is just how big the continental US is.

Go to the map of the US in Google Maps. Look at the second I in Virginia. That is where I live. The trip above end at where the line from Massachusetts touches the map. Compare that distance to the rest of size of the country.
</post>
<post author="Southie" datetime="2008-07-18T13:58:00" id="p72">
<quote orig_author="von Spreuth">
2 MILES and you go by CAR? We use a FANTASTIC new invention that may not have been heard of there yet called FEET. You user them for WALKING.

</quote>

And living in Florida, with the hot and humid weather, I would be drenched by the time I got to work! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/> Other than the couple of months a year where the weather is decent, the rest of the months are hot and sticky. Considering I don't have a shower in my office, that's not an option!

And of course there is the rainy season! Plus, I need my car to take school records downtown which is more than 2 miles away!!
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-18T14:16:00" id="p73">
<quote orig_author="Albany Rifles">
Europe does have a fairly integrated road system...but it is overtaxed in some places. Try driving through south and central Germany. The roads are absolutely clogged. The British motorway system is not a part of that system for one very obvious reason..And it works fine...so long as you are far away from London.

Here in the US we have an excellent highway system (correctly named the Dwight D. Eisenhowere National Defense Interstate Highway system). I go from Southern Virginia to New England several times a year...about a 10 hour drive. To do that I have to find a way to get through Washington, DC, and New York City. Imagine the traffic of London and Paris within 200 miles of each other and you MAY get half of the ide of what it is like. But I regularly cover 600 + miles (950 kms) in abotu 10 hours. Why? Because I have abotu 4 options to get there, almost all on interstates. I can take straight I-95. I can go east of DC along US 301 and out US 50 through Annaplis and the Eastern Shore, pick up the New Jersey Turnpike, go Garden State Pkwy and over the Tappan Zee Bridge and go to pick up I-95 again. Or go the Merrit Pkwy to I-91 to I-84. Or I could go out to I-81 through Winchester to I-78 in HArrisburg to I -287 in New York to I-84 and then east to CT.

In other words, lots of options to drive. Rail works great...if you are a 40 foot ISO container.

What a lot of Europeans do not really understand is just how big the continental US is.

Go to the map of the US in Google Maps. Look at the second I in Virginia. That is where I live. The trip above end at where the line from Massachusetts touches the map. Compare that distance to the rest of size of the country.

</quote>

EZ Pass rules!
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2008-07-18T14:25:00" id="p74">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
EZ Pass rules!

</quote>

VA to Maine without stopping!!!!

(Well, except for the bladder breaks!)
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2008-07-18T14:28:00" id="p75">
<quote orig_author="Southie">
And living in Florida, with the hot and humid weather, I would be drenched by the time I got to work! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/> Other than the couple of months a year where the weather is decent, the rest of the months are hot and sticky. Considering I don't have a shower in my office, that's not an option!

And of course there is the rainy season! Plus, I need my car to take school records downtown which is more than 2 miles away!!

</quote>

Also, if it is like some areas, there are a) no sidewalks b) big drainage ditches so you can't walk on the verge, c) walking on the road itself will get you a mirror to the head.

I tried taking a bicycle to work a few years ago. I gave up the experiment because of the logging trucks, school buses and tractor trailers on my rural road system.
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2008-07-18T14:29:00" id="p76">
Oh, I just went over 1,000 posts. Where are the baloons?
</post>
<post author="Knaur Amarsh" datetime="2008-07-18T14:30:00" id="p77">
<quote orig_author="bolo121">
Ok as someone who actually travels by train almost every week, I've got to burst this bubble. Add to your memory, the hijras demanding cash, people stealing your seat in the coach, the stench of the toilet after a couple of hours, the guy opposite you spitting paan into the airstream as you take evasive action....i could go on and on.
My main memory of the trains is always the unmistakeable smell, a blend of sweaty bodies and jasmine flowers.

</quote>

My main memory is standing at the open door and smoking while looking over my shoulder to spot any railway cops looking for some quick bucks, or smoking in the washroom..was in there smoking with a friend once, the guy waiting outside was pretty shocked to see 2 guys steppin' out <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Knaur Amarsh" datetime="2008-07-18T14:32:00" id="p78">
<quote orig_author="Southie">
I've traveled on the Metro in DC, the "T" in Boston, but my most memorable time was in S. Korea. A friend and I decided to go to Seoul to shop, and we took the subway once we got there. We boarded during rush hour and were literally sandwiched in. I told Pete to hang on to my backpack so when the crowd got off at their stop, I wouldn't be pushed along with them. It was so packed you didn't need to hold on to rails, because you weren't moving! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) Oh, and the smell of kimchi... <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>

</quote>

Multiply the crowd by ten times and you have an average day in the life of a Mumbai local trains commuter <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="Knaur Amarsh" datetime="2008-07-18T14:41:00" id="p79">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
the food from the hawkers esp. at the stations

Ahhhh <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>

</quote>

was crap <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/> at least the one I ate

Frankly, I ate it only because there was nothing else to eat

To each his own I suppose!

As for anyone who complains about airplane food, let the try the Indian Railways fare once <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> Airline food will seem like manna from heaven

I remember when there was the whole pesticides in cola controversy, they tested all the mineral water bottles too, "Rail Neer" the Indian railway mineral water was at the very bottom, just a tad below municipal tap water:PIIRC

Only good thing about the fare in long route trains is the well stocked bar <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/> Bribe the pantry guy and you can get anything, the first time I did that, I asked the dude if I could possibly get some alcohol or rettes, "Sure", he said :D "Which brands?"
</post>
<post author="von Spreuth" datetime="2008-07-18T15:34:00" id="p80">
<quote orig_author="glyn">
Another foolish remark from you. I suggest it's you who needs stuffing, preferably with the blunt end of a ragmans trumpet!

</quote>

So. We measure in miles and the Brits love Europe.

Is THAT what you are attempting to infer?

Because if not. I see nothing wrong withj my post.

Any one else care to comment?
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-18T15:53:00" id="p81">
<quote orig_author="ArmchairGeneral">
Not exactly. Rail travel has all but disappeared in the US because of a number of factors -the interstate highway system and cheap gas looming large among them. Rail transport, OTOH, is still quite important. Not as important as it used to be, of course -like you said, the trucking system has taken away business, although that is in part due to adoption of Japanese 'just in time' ordering and inventory practices by US companies. But for bulk transport, and heavy stuff, rail still reigns supreme, especially for long hauls. There's a railway that goes right through the town I'm living in, there's probably at least one train every hour or so.

</quote>

What???? How could the US adopt the Japan's just in time ordering and inventory practice, considering the size of Japan compared to the size of US?
Jesus Christ... <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> Well you might as well adopt the paper houses from them as well...
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2008-07-18T15:57:00" id="p82">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
What???? How could the US adopt the Japan's just in time ordering and inventory practice, considering the size of Japan compared to the size of US?
Jesus Christ... <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> Well you might as well adopt the paper houses from them as well...

</quote>

Ever hear of:

FedEx...or UPS...or DHL?

Truck lines running 24 hours a day like the old Pony Express?

Container trains running across country in under 30 hours?

That is how.

Works just fine.
</post>
<post author="bolo121" datetime="2008-07-18T16:49:00" id="p83">
<quote orig_author="Southie">
And living in Florida, with the hot and humid weather, I would be drenched by the time I got to work! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/> Other than the couple of months a year where the weather is decent, the rest of the months are hot and sticky. Considering I don't have a shower in my office, that's not an option!

And of course there is the rainy season! Plus, I need my car to take school records downtown which is more than 2 miles away!!

</quote>

How hot is it usually where you live? Here in Chennai India, in mid summer its around 43 tp 47 degrees Centigrade. Now with Summer over we have average 35 degree days. I need to walk for 15 mins to get to bus stop, and another 15 to get to my office.
</post>
<post author="bolo121" datetime="2008-07-18T16:52:00" id="p84">
<quote orig_author="Knaur Amarsh">
My main memory is standing at the open door and smoking while looking over my shoulder to spot any railway cops looking for some quick bucks, or smoking in the washroom..was in there smoking with a friend once, the guy waiting outside was pretty shocked to see 2 guys steppin' out <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>

</quote>

Ah hah! so it was you! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>
No wonder i start coughing when i open the toilet door. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Southie" datetime="2008-07-18T16:56:00" id="p85">
<quote orig_author="bolo121">
How hot is it usually where you live? Here in Chennai India, in mid summer its around 43 tp 47 degrees Centigrade. Now with Summer over we have average 35 degree days. I need to walk for 15 mins to get to bus stop, and another 15 to get to my office.

</quote>

OK, I'm setting myself up for I'm sure lots of remarks...It can be in the high 90's with humidity sometimes around 90%. Of course today it is currently 88 degrees (F) and the humidity is 75%. But this is not the norm!!! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>

I just can't stand the heat. I'd much rather be living in a cooler climate! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Knaur Amarsh" datetime="2008-07-18T17:03:00" id="p86">
<quote orig_author="bolo121">
How hot is it usually where you live? Here in Chennai India, in mid summer its around 43 tp 47 degrees Centigrade. Now with Summer over we have average 35 degree days. I need to walk for 15 mins to get to bus stop, and another 15 to get to my office.

</quote>

Scrooge,

<a href="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/world-affairs-board-pub/45550-motorbikes-you-owned-do-2.html#post515912">motorbikes you owned or do.</a>

What do you keep that for? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="omon" datetime="2008-07-18T17:03:00" id="p87">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
The Paris Metro smelled like urine everywhere I went. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/>

</quote>

lol, nyc mta is the same, lots of stations stink,
there is a train station right by my house, i take a train to work from there half the times(whenever i miss my last bus), i,ve seen crap(i kid you not) right in the middle or the platform, few times, good thing it is outside-elevated platform, otherways stink would be awefull, yet it continues to happen and nobody does anything about it, keep in mind transit police pct. is right under that station.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-18T18:24:00" id="p88">
<quote orig_author="Asim Aquil">
yeah, thats one thing I noticed about America. Every thing is far far away.

</quote>

We like it that way. The annoying neighbor is just a bit farther away. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>

<quote orig_author="Asim Aquil">
We're used to walking to the grocery store here.

</quote>

Takes me 30 min to walk to the closest supermarket. Driving is about 3 min. I figure $0.5 worth of gasoline is a good trade off for 1 hour of my time.

<quote orig_author="Asim Aquil">
I think 60C was a Dubai record. Its mostly to do with all the contruction going on and the dust particles forming a greenhouse effect. The official temperature report was a high of 51C, but the greenhouse effect took it higher.

150F is common! Weird thing is, these Europeans come to Dubai and they're like "wow what a lovely sunshine" and we're like WTF is wrong with you? I deduced that we each hate our own weather.

<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HS5tbTn7_C4">YouTube - Emirates - Keep Discovering: Snow</a>

</quote>

I think the Germans are the ones who love the extreme heat. We have quite a few tourists visiting the Death Valley every summer. A few years ago several German tourists went off on a hike in the Death Valley, in the summer. They had no water. Just beer. Their rental van was found. They weren't there. I don't know what happened to this story.

I go to Las Vegas every summer just to enjoy the heat. It's not that extreme, but going from constant 75F to 115F is quite a jump for me.
</post>
<post author="von Spreuth" datetime="2008-07-18T18:50:00" id="p89">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
I think the Germans are the ones who love the extreme heat.

</quote>

Na. A gang of Afrika Korps vets?

And don't forget, the Scandinavians invented the sauna. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>

I reckon it is "tanking up". A bit like a squirral collecting nuts for winter.

All that heat comes out like a stone radiator and keeps you going till the next summer/sauna.

Thats my theory any way, and I am sticking to it. Mad ot not. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="Lathyrus" datetime="2008-07-18T18:51:00" id="p90">
<quote orig_author="von Spreuth">
So. We measure in miles and the Brits love Europe.

Is THAT what you are attempting to infer?

Because if not. I see nothing wrong withj my post.

Any one else care to comment?

</quote>

Seems like we have no choice, whether or not we agree

<a href="http://www.dailyexpress.co.uk/posts/view/52947">Daily Express: The World's Greatest Newspaper :: UK News :: Sold out to Europe: Brown makes Queen sign away our sovereignty</a> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-18T19:04:00" id="p91">
<quote orig_author="Albany Rifles">
Ever hear of:

FedEx...or UPS...or DHL?

Truck lines running 24 hours a day like the old Pony Express?

Container trains running across country in under 30 hours?

That is how.

Works just fine.

</quote>

So you think that nothing should be changed in the US? The way how you live, work, travel, do economy? No changes are needed, right?
</post>
<post author="omon" datetime="2008-07-18T19:07:00" id="p92">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
So you think that nothing should be changed in the US? The way how you live, work, travel, do economy? No changes are needed, right?

</quote>

what makes you think we need any changes???
economy could use some boosting, but the rest pretty good the way it is.

have you ever been to us?
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2008-07-18T19:11:00" id="p93">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
The Paris Metro smelled like urine everywhere I went. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/>

</quote>

Wear rubber pants next time.

HAH! I made fun of SHEK. NO one does that. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>

Seriously though, you kinda lofted that one over the plate.

-dale
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2008-07-18T19:14:00" id="p94">
<quote orig_author="Albany Rifles">
Ever hear of:

FedEx...or UPS...or DHL?

Truck lines running 24 hours a day like the old Pony Express?

Container trains running across country in under 30 hours?

That is how.

Works just fine.

</quote>

Exactly. Although I should modify what I said: American companies have adopted Japanese style business practices. That is to say, they still often keep larger inventories than Japanese businesses do. So it's been modified, probably in part due to, as Versus mentioned, distance issues.
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2008-07-18T19:17:00" id="p95">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
Wear rubber pants next time.

HAH! I made fun of SHEK. NO one does that. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>

-dale

</quote>

You're DOOMED, man, DOOMED. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2008-07-18T19:19:00" id="p96">
<quote orig_author="von Spreuth">
So. We measure in miles and the Brits love Europe.

Is THAT what you are attempting to infer?

Because if not. I see nothing wrong withj my post.

Any one else care to comment?

</quote>

Oh relax, he was making a joke. What are you, German or something?

-dale
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2008-07-18T19:21:00" id="p97">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
So you think that nothing should be changed in the US? The way how you live, work, travel, do economy? No changes are needed, right?

</quote>

Yep. Pretty much perfect.

-dale
</post>
<post author="von Spreuth" datetime="2008-07-18T19:51:00" id="p98">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
Oh relax, he was making a joke.

</quote>

It was in reply to Glen (?) who was not.

<quote orig_author="dalem">
What are you, German or something?

</quote>

Yes. Why?

<quote orig_author="Lathyrus">
Seems like we have no choice, whether or not we agree

</quote>

As you know, I was quite a fan of Europe, but only as it was in 1972.

I will also suport it when wrong is done to it (Meaning when things are blamed on it, that are not the E.U's fault). But I am getting slightly....jaded, shall we say. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>

Nice to hear from you. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2008-07-18T19:53:00" id="p99">
<quote orig_author="omon">
have you ever been to us?

</quote>

He lived in California for a while, I believe.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-18T20:02:00" id="p100">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
So you think that nothing should be changed in the US? The way how you live, work, travel, do economy? No changes are needed, right?

</quote>

There shouldn't be changes for changes sake. Change should come about when people switch their habits based on a cost-benefit analysis. The cost shouldn't be distorted using government cohercion. The market will direct people to the most efficient way to utilize our resources.
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-18T20:11:00" id="p101">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
There shouldn't be changes for changes sake. Change should come about when people switch their habits based on a cost-benefit analysis. The cost shouldn't be distorted using government cohercion. The market will direct people to the most efficient way to utilize our resources.

</quote>

Gunnut,

It is probably a foregone conclusion that gas prices will continue to drive northwards.
The Pigovian type tax example that the article talks about would help us to gear up for that kind of change and the payroll tax feedback would bring down the hardship level.

If we do not do gear ourselves now, we will anyway be hit later and we will not be able o do a thing
</post>
<post author="omon" datetime="2008-07-18T20:25:00" id="p102">
<quote orig_author="ArmchairGeneral">
He lived in California for a while, I believe.

</quote>

in that case i,d love to hear, what he thinks is wrong with how we live, work, travel, do economy.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-18T20:27:00" id="p103">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
Gunnut,

It is probably a foregone conclusion that gas prices will continue to drive northwards.
The Pigovian type tax example that the article talks about would help us to gear up for that kind of change and the payroll tax feedback would bring down the hardship level.

If we do not do gear ourselves now, we will anyway be hit later and we will not be able o do a thing

</quote>

We should not use taxes as a social engineering device. Let's say we put a $4 tax on gasoline and it's now $8.50 a gallon. What happens if gasoline price goes up? Do you decrease the taxes and hold the consumer price at $8.50 a gallon? Or will the price goes up to $8.90 a gallon? If so, what's the point?

Artificially high prices is detrimental to efficiency. Let's say you put the $4 gas tax on and make gasoline $8.50 a gallon. That makes ethanol a bargain at $7 a gallon. You switch from $8.50 gasoline to $7 ethanol. Did you save money? Gasoline really is $4.50 a gallon. You paid more. Where does that money go? To ethanol makers. What makes ethanol? Corn. Corn price will go up. It is caused by an artificial demand created by social engineering project. How is that different than giving massive farm subsidies to corn growers to make ethanol cheap?
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2008-07-18T20:36:00" id="p104">
<quote orig_author="omon">
in that case i,d love to hear, what he thinks is wrong with how we live, work, travel, do economy.

</quote>

He's said a lot before in other threads. Here's a couple.

<a href="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/political-discussions/44009-universal-care-cheaper-better-than-private-insurance.html">http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/pol...insurance.html</a>

<a href="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/political-discussions/44693-whats-so-wrong-socialism.html">http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/pol...socialism.html</a>
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-18T21:06:00" id="p105">
<quote orig_author="omon">
what makes you think we need any changes???
economy could use some boosting, but the rest pretty good the way it is.

have you ever been to us?

</quote>

Yep, I lived in Minnesota and California, from 2002 till 2004. All my American friends, all with the background in military and politics agreed with me that US needed reforms so that is why I popped the question.
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-18T21:13:00" id="p106">
<quote orig_author="ArmchairGeneral">
He's said a lot before in other threads. Here's a couple.

<a href="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/political-discussions/44009-universal-care-cheaper-better-than-private-insurance.html">http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/pol...insurance.html</a>

<a href="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/political-discussions/44693-whats-so-wrong-socialism.html">http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/pol...socialism.html</a>

</quote>

You forgot to add the Bluesman's thread about oil. Actually I was most active in the aviation threads, since that is my primary interest and I had couple of posts in Iraq and Iran threads as well as couple of posts on Kosovo issue.
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2008-07-18T21:17:00" id="p107">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
You forgot to add the Bluesman's thread about oil. Actually I was most active in the aviation threads, since that is my primary interest and I had couple of posts in Iraq and Iran threads as well as couple of posts on Kosovo issue.

</quote>

Yeah, I'm lazy. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) Just searched for some of the discussions I remembered participating in with you. I'd forgotten about that one.
</post>
<post author="omon" datetime="2008-07-18T21:18:00" id="p108">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
Yep, I lived in Minnesota and California, from 2002 till 2004. All my American friends, all with the background in military and politics agreed with me that US needed reforms so that is why I popped the question.

</quote>

every country needs reforms, in some ways, but, reforms that seem right and helpfull, usually end up falling under unintended cosiquenses rule, cuz there is no way you can see every side effect, in advance,

i personaly like the way we work, whoever doesn,t most likely has a wrong job.
the way we travel, i love it, and if someone doesn,t like it, than they do their traveling wrong.

and the way we live, what is not to like.

all of the above depends on the person, cuz everyone can b,,ch and moan, but it won,t get anyone far, it is individual's job to adjust his living to situation at hand. and use situation at hand to his advantage. and if one can,t do it, no reforms will help him.
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-18T21:18:00" id="p109">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
There shouldn't be changes for changes sake. Change should come about when people switch their habits based on a cost-benefit analysis. The cost shouldn't be distorted using government cohercion. The market will direct people to the most efficient way to utilize our resources.

</quote>

So I shouldn't worry about looming catastrophe? Ok, no biggy, maybe it is all in my head after all.
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-18T21:28:00" id="p110">
<quote orig_author="omon">
every country needs reforms, in some ways, but, reforms that seem right and helpfull, usually end up falling under unintended cosiquenses rule, cuz there is no way you can see every side effect, in advance,

i personaly like the way we work, whoever doesn,t most likely has a wrong job.
the way we travel, i love it, and if someone doesn,t like it, than they do their traveling wrong.

and the way we live, what is not to like.

all of the above depends on the person, cuz everyone can b,,ch and moan, but it won,t get anyone far, it is individual's job to adjust his living to situation at hand. and use situation at hand to his advantage. and if one can,t do it, no reforms will help him.

</quote>

I just think that you can do much better and efficient than this. I see a great danger coming to the US and I am worried about it since it will reflect all around the world including this small place where I live now. But again, if you don't feel threaten than maybe my views are not right. Problem is, I rarely make mistakes when geopolitics comes in question. Too much time spent in that field.
</post>
<post author="Big K" datetime="2008-07-18T21:30:00" id="p111">
here we are buying 1 liter of super-unleaded gas for approx. 2,5 Dollars.
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-18T21:33:00" id="p112">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
We should not use taxes as a social engineering device. Let's say we put a $4 tax on gasoline and it's now $8.50 a gallon. What happens if gasoline price goes up? Do you decrease the taxes and hold the consumer price at $8.50 a gallon? Or will the price goes up to $8.90 a gallon? If so, what's the point?

Artificially high prices is detrimental to efficiency. Let's say you put the $4 gas tax on and make gasoline $8.50 a gallon. That makes ethanol a bargain at $7 a gallon. You switch from $8.50 gasoline to $7 ethanol. Did you save money? Gasoline really is $4.50 a gallon. You paid more. Where does that money go? To ethanol makers. What makes ethanol? Corn. Corn price will go up. It is caused by an artificial demand created by social engineering project. How is that different than giving massive farm subsidies to corn growers to make ethanol cheap?

</quote>

First of all, the tax should not be imposed at one go, other wise the shock effect will be ruinuos. Secondly, where the gas prices will go will depend on the inelasticity of demand for gas, as Shek pointed out in his Economic Riddles thread - <a href="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/world-affairs-board-pub/41799-economic-riddles-8.html">Economic Riddles</a>

You can also have a graded tax system, where congested areas like urban metros pay more while fur flung, hard to reach areas pay less.
Also, what about the after effects of high gas prices (for the consumer)? Already we have seen high mass transit ridership and use of carpooling etc. In the USA, I have heard that revenues from gas tax is used to build mass transit, so more people riding the trains to work depresses demand even further.

All of this is an academic exercise.

Raising the taxes would be a "courageous" measure given the current political climate, and it looks like politicians are actually walking the other way.
<a href="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/24120727/">McCain calls for 'gas-tax holiday' - John McCain News - MSNBC.com</a>
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-18T21:44:00" id="p113">
<quote orig_author="omon">
i personaly like the way we work, whoever doesn,t most likely has a wrong job.
the way we travel, i love it, and if someone doesn,t like it, than they do their traveling wrong.

</quote>

Yeah, I love travelling on the bus, and I tell the guy companing about high gas prices at the coffee machine to get his b*tt onto a bus or suck it up and pay the price a the pump for the pleasure of being able to drive to work thorugh all that traffic

So, yeah, I agree with you. Whoever complains may go ahead and change the way they do things.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-18T22:10:00" id="p114">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
So I shouldn't worry about looming catastrophe? Ok, no biggy, maybe it is all in my head after all.

</quote>

What looming catastrophe? Global warming? Peak oil? Stock market bubble?

How about terrorist attack? Paying more than 30% gross income to tax and rising? Zombie attacks?
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-18T22:17:00" id="p115">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
First of all, the tax should not be imposed at one go, other wise the shock effect will be ruinuos. Secondly, where the gas prices will go will depend on the inelasticity of demand for gas, as Shek pointed out in his Economic Riddles thread - <a href="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/world-affairs-board-pub/41799-economic-riddles-8.html">Economic Riddles</a>

</quote>

I never said to add the taxes in one go, or many goes, or any go. The end result is the same, a distorted market that benefits inefficient use of our resources.

<quote orig_author="antimony">
You can also have a graded tax system, where congested areas like urban metros pay more while fur flung, hard to reach areas pay less.
Also, what about the after effects of high gas prices (for the consumer)? Already we have seen high mass transit ridership and use of carpooling etc. In the USA, I have heard that revenues from gas tax is used to build mass transit, so more people riding the trains to work depresses demand even further.

</quote>

Too many things wrong with that proposal. We already have higher taxes in congested urban areas on gasoline. Look at San Francisco and NYC. They have mass transits too. People still drive.

If the taxes collected on gasoline goes to where they're supposed to, that's one thing. But as of now, our politicians have a tendency to "borrow" money to fund their pet projects. That's another reason we shouldn't give them any more money.

People don't like mass transit. We like our personal space. Look up studies on personal spaces. American personal space is about 3 to 4 feet. We get uncomfortable when people we don't know get within this distance. This figure is much smaller in Europe and Asia. We like our open spaces.

<quote orig_author="antimony">
All of this is an academic exercise.

Raising the taxes would be a "courageous" measure given the current political climate, and it looks like politicians are actually walking the other way.
<a href="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/24120727/">McCain calls for 'gas-tax holiday' - John McCain News - MSNBC.com</a>

</quote>

Reducing taxes is the courageous thing to do. You tell people to rely on themselves rather than the government.
</post>
<post author="omon" datetime="2008-07-18T22:36:00" id="p116">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
I just think that you can do much better and efficient than this. I see a great danger coming to the US and I am worried about it since it will reflect all around the world including this small place where I live now. But again, if you don't feel threaten than maybe my views are not right. Problem is, I rarely make mistakes when geopolitics comes in question. Too much time spent in that field.

</quote>

i assume that danger isn,t the way we live, work or travel.
as for geopolitics, ppl that make thing happen on world scale, care about their own agendas, not little ppl.
</post>
<post author="BenRoethig" datetime="2008-07-18T23:28:00" id="p117">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
Hmm, but Europe also has a pretty good road system, does it not? I have traveled on the British motorways and did not find a great deal of difference between those and the American freeways.

I personally don't like those 4-5 hour drives, seems like too much work to me. Thats when I miss those trains

As for the joys of train travel, difficult to explain...

Standing in the open doorways enjoying the stiff breeze, the countryside rushing by, sleeping on the bunk beds, and oh - the food from the hawkers esp. at the stations

Ahhhh <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>

</quote>

Europe also has 75% of its population is large metropolitan areas. What would $8 gas do? Make life very difficult away from the coasts leading to a major increase in families needing govt. welfare, cause food prices to skyrocket because agriculture would be near unaffordable, real estate would also skyrocket with more families moving to large cities, and finish off the airlines leading to basically an airline version of AMTRAK. Life might be better for those sipping martinis in the hollywood hills, but it would cause a major recession elsewhere.
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2008-07-18T23:36:00" id="p118">
<quote orig_author="BenRoethig">
Europe also has 75% of its population is large metropolitan areas. What would $8 gas do? Make life very difficult away from the coasts leading to a major increase in families needing govt. welfare, cause food prices to skyrocket because agriculture would be near unaffordable, real estate would also skyrocket with more families moving to large cities, and finish off the airlines leading to basically an airline version of AMTRAK. Life might be better for those sipping martinis in the hollywood hills, but it would cause a major recession elsewhere.

</quote>

Only if it went up in one fell swoop. A gradual increase would not hurt us very much at all. We use huge amounts of gas in large part because it is cheap, not because it's vital to sustaining our way of life.
</post>
<post author="bolo121" datetime="2008-07-19T05:12:00" id="p119">
<quote orig_author="Knaur Amarsh">
Scrooge,

<a href="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/world-affairs-board-pub/45550-motorbikes-you-owned-do-2.html#post515912">motorbikes you owned or do.</a>

What do you keep that for? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>

</quote>

Hehe <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> If only. Its sitting in Bangalore where my cousin is using it to go to College. I just dont want to go to the hassle of transporting it to Chennai and then getting the migration papers done for the RTO and then submitting them at Chennai and so on. Not worth the trouble.
I went through the whole procedure with my old suzuki when i was in Kerala for a year and it was a major headache. You end up being a sort of free money dispenser for all the local cops. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Knaur Amarsh" datetime="2008-07-19T10:00:00" id="p120">
<quote orig_author="bolo121">
Not worth the trouble.
I went through the whole procedure with my old suzuki when i was in Kerala for a year and it was a major headache. You end up being a sort of free money dispenser for all the local cops. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/>

</quote>

True <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> In my personal experience, RTO and the land registry thing are two places where anything rarely gets done without greasing a few palms, or else it takes months
</post>
<post author="von Spreuth" datetime="2008-07-19T10:06:00" id="p121">
I had to abandon three Triumph Tigers in the U.K for similar reasons. The customs and tax paper work, and the amount I would have to have paid, for tax, registration, transport etc was four to five times more than the bloody motorbikes were worth if they were in good condition.
</post>
<post author="Knaur Amarsh" datetime="2008-07-19T10:11:00" id="p122">
<quote orig_author="von Spreuth">
I had to abandon three Triumph Tigers in the U.K for similar reasons. The customs and tax paper work, and the amount I would have to have paid, for tax, registration, transport etc was four to five times more than the bloody motorbikes were worth if they were in good condition.

</quote>

Abandon, sir? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )Didn't you realise you could sell them?
</post>
<post author="bugs" datetime="2008-07-19T11:13:00" id="p123">
<quote orig_author="HistoricalDavid">
(My flight also took me over Detroit. I don't mean to judge a city from 35,000 feet, but I think I've seen enough...)

</quote>

<img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="von Spreuth" datetime="2008-07-19T11:20:00" id="p124">
<quote orig_author="HistoricalDavid">
I don't mean to judge a city from 35,000 feet, but I think I've seen enough...)

</quote>

Why not? Your Grandfathers did with Dresden.

<quote orig_author="Knaur Amarsh">
Abandon, sir? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )Didn't you realise you could sell them?

</quote>

No time. It can take a month to get an advert in the magazines that would appreciate them, such as "Classic Bike". I had two days.
</post>
<post author="HistoricalDavid" datetime="2008-07-19T12:02:00" id="p125">
<quote orig_author="von Spreuth">
Why not? Your Grandfathers did with Dresden

</quote>

ROFFLES.

Leaving aside the technicality that none of my family is actually British, and leaving aside another technicality that the Lancaster had an effective ceiling well below 35,000 feet (Glyn, your knowledge required here), what has the non-moralistic bombing campaign by the RAF, aiming at crippling German morale and economics, got to do with my oh-so-witty little comment about the hellhole that Detroit looks like?

So long as we are talking about the sins of the father...

<a href="http://isurvived.org/Pictures_Isurvived/children_Polish.gif">http://isurvived.org/Pictures_Isurvi...ren_Polish.gif</a>

Pic 1. You know as well as I there are plenty more.

The merits of the bombing campaign are open to debate - but in the appropriate context and thread. I'm not gonna tolerate someone from Germany criticising me on nothing other than my nationality.
</post>
<post author="glyn" datetime="2008-07-19T12:08:00" id="p126">
[QUOTE=von Spreuth;518514]Why not? Your Grandfathers did with Dresden.

What is your problem, exactly? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/confused.gif"/> You seem to like aggressive speech and throw away sneers. Do you think it makes you appear to be a big man? Let me assure you that it does not. Not to put too fine a point on it you appear to be a prat! By the way, my father was in Bomber Command during WW2, piloting Wellingtons and Halifaxes but I don't recall seeing Dresden in his logbook.
</post>
<post author="pate" datetime="2008-07-19T12:12:00" id="p127">
von Spreuth, you lost your signature. For King and Country is how I read it. If I am not mistaken, Germans can still track royalty. I think that's cool. Yes, the fire bombings were awful. What we do in war is often awful. I wonder what the projects in Insledom (Usedom? That wierd Island you split with Poland) would have produced if left unchecked on Britian... Any way you look at it, Usedom (Insledom?) was some good vacation land. As I recall, two years ago, petrol was about $8 a gallon back then... I am of course wrong... I still love your country, friend...
</post>
<post author="von Spreuth" datetime="2008-07-19T12:30:00" id="p128">
<quote orig_author="glyn">
What is your problem, exactly? You seem to like aggressive speech and throw away sneers.

</quote>

Aye, well, it's not me that jumps into the middle of other peoples coversations with personal attacks is it Granpa?

<quote orig_author="pate">
von Spreuth, you lost your signature. For King and Country is how I read it.

</quote>

Yup.

It keeps coming and going. Don't know why.

<quote>
If I am not mistaken, Germans can still track royalty.
</quote>

Aye. The Hohenzollerns are in fine fettle.

Georg Friedrich von Hohenzollern, Prinz von Preußen is the present head, and would be Kaiser had it not been for a slight hickup in 1918.

Met him at Fehrbellin three weeks ago. He is quite often at the re-enactments. Same as the currant von bismarck.

<quote>
Insledom (Usedom?
</quote>

Usedom is the place.

Still not a bad place to go, but still recovering from 40 odd years of bloody pinkoe rule.
</post>
<post author="HistoricalDavid" datetime="2008-07-19T12:59:00" id="p129">
<quote orig_author="von Spreuth">
Aye, well, it's not me that jumps into the middle of other peoples coversations with personal attacks is it Granpa?

</quote>

I retroactively give him full permission to jump into this conversation.

PS

<a href="http://patratosu.files.wordpress.com/2008/03/einsatzgruppen-the-last-jew-in-vinnitsa.jpg">http://patratosu.files.wordpress.com...n-vinnitsa.jpg</a>
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2008-07-19T15:58:00" id="p130">
<quote orig_author="von Spreuth">
Why not? Your Grandfathers did with Dresden.

</quote>

Hey, what's another Nazi or two, eh?

Let me give you a hint, von. Start taking everything personally and engaging in trolling and you will last about 5 minutes on this board before one of the mods gives you the boot.

-dale
</post>
<post author="omon" datetime="2008-07-19T16:09:00" id="p131">
actually, my grandfather bombed germany, he flew a20 with red stars on wings and tail. and the rest of my family did the same on the ground and seas, i,m proud of them.
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2008-07-19T16:15:00" id="p132">
<quote orig_author="von Spreuth">
Yup.

It keeps coming and going. Don't know why.

</quote>

It only shows on your first post on a page.
</post>
<post author="von Spreuth" datetime="2008-07-19T16:17:00" id="p133">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
Let me give you a hint, von. Start taking everything personally and engaging in trolling and you will last about 5 minutes on this board before one of the mods gives you the boot.

</quote>

And let me give YOU a hint, when you donated your sense of humour for sceintific research, they forgot to tell you you only had one.

Thanks Armchair General.
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2008-07-19T17:48:00" id="p134">
I'm getting lectured on humor by a German?

That takes stones, laddie. Big clapping brass ones. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>

-dale
</post>
<post author="HistoricalDavid" datetime="2008-07-19T22:04:00" id="p135">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
I'm getting lectured on humor by a German?

That takes stones, laddie. Big clapping brass ones. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>

-dale

</quote>

Yeah, what next, Saudi Arabia, Cuba, China etc sitting on human rights panels? Oh, wait... <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="omon" datetime="2008-07-19T22:56:00" id="p136">
lol.
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rD4roXEY8hk">YouTube - German Coast Guard - Lost in Translation</a>
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-19T23:26:00" id="p137">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
Too many things wrong with that proposal. We already have higher taxes in congested urban areas on gasoline. Look at San Francisco and NYC. They have mass transits too. People still drive.

</quote>

I will need to look up what sort of tax is there. As far as I am aware, there isn't any congestion tax like in London. As to why people drive, don't know, but they do pay the price for doing so.

<quote orig_author="gunnut">
If the taxes collected on gasoline goes to where they're supposed to, that's one thing. But as of now, our politicians have a tendency to "borrow" money to fund their pet projects. That's another reason we shouldn't give them any more money.

</quote>

So come down hard on pork barrel spending.

<quote orig_author="gunnut">
People don't like mass transit. We like our personal space. Look up studies on personal spaces. American personal space is about 3 to 4 feet. We get uncomfortable when people we don't know get within this distance. This figure is much smaller in Europe and Asia. We like our open spaces.

</quote>

You don't like mass transit, but you cannot generalise and say thats a choice across the board. I like mass transit. I would hate driving around in the city during rush hour, worrying about where I should be parking. I have too many things to think about to/ from work, without all that crowding my mind. However, people are different, and you may have an entirely different set of priorities.

<quote orig_author="gunnut">
Reducing taxes is the courageous thing to do. You tell people to rely on themselves rather than the government.

</quote>

At this point in time, it is rank opportunism with an eye on the November elections.

By the way, it seems that folks have diverted a wee bit from the topic...
</post>
<post author="von Spreuth" datetime="2008-07-20T14:50:00" id="p138">
<quote orig_author="HistoricalDavid">
Yeah, what next, Saudi Arabia, Cuba, China etc sitting on human rights panels? Oh, wait... <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>

</quote>

Aye. And not the SLIGHTEST hint of a tongue in the cheek when they claim their place. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Tarek Morgen" datetime="2008-07-20T16:42:00" id="p139">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
I'm getting lectured on humor by a German?

That takes stones, laddie. Big clapping brass ones. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>

-dale

</quote>

Germans do have humor, most people just don't understand it. For example the munich treaty..we did not expect anyone to take it seriously...and also invading France is somewhat of a running gag here.

(no this post is not suppossed to be serious)
</post>
<post author="glyn" datetime="2008-07-20T18:19:00" id="p140">
<quote orig_author="Tarek Morgen">
Germans do have humor, most people just don't understand it. For example the munich treaty..we did not expect anyone to take it seriously...and also invading France is somewhat of a running gag here.

(no this post is not suppossed to be serious)

</quote>

I don't entirely blame the Germans, Tarek, as it seems to be in their genes. Two schnapps and the urge to invade Poland becomes overwhelming! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="mudwhistle" datetime="2008-07-20T18:31:00" id="p141">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
Soooo....it's a regressive taxation scheme? Who thought of this stuff? Not the democrats I hope.

I'm all for regressive taxation. There should be an incentive to be rich, not a punishment.

</quote>

Sorry, the Dems have no incentives, just punishments for pursuing the American Dream.
</post>
<post author="Knaur Amarsh" datetime="2008-07-20T18:36:00" id="p142">
<quote orig_author="Tarek Morgen">
Germans do have humor, most people just don't understand it. For example the munich treaty..we did not expect anyone to take it seriously...and also invading France is somewhat of a running gag here.

(no this post is not suppossed to be serious)

</quote>

<img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )

<quote orig_author="glyn">
I don't entirely blame the Germans, Tarek, as it seems to be in their genes. Two schnapps and the urge to invade Poland becomes overwhelming! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )

</quote>

<img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="Tarek Morgen" datetime="2008-07-20T18:50:00" id="p143">
<quote orig_author="glyn">
I don't entirely blame the Germans, Tarek, as it seems to be in their genes. Two schnapps and the urge to invade Poland becomes overwhelming! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )

</quote>

everyone invades Poland now and then. Even the Swedens.

I think there was once a joke on the daily show that went something like this:

"Why do the Germans don't want to invade Iraq? Simply, it like with a former alcoholic. They are afraid that while everything starts with a few harmless bombs on Baghdad they wake up the next morning with a huge hangover and annexed Czech during their blackout."
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2008-07-20T19:01:00" id="p144">
<quote orig_author="Tarek Morgen">
everyone invades Poland now and then. Even the Swedens.

I think there was once a joke on the daily show that went something like this:

"Why do the Germans don't want to invade Iraq? Simply, it like with a former alcoholic. They are afraid that while everything starts with a few harmless bombs on Baghdad they wake up the next morning with a huge hangover and annexed Czech during their blackout."

</quote>

<img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="BD1" datetime="2008-07-20T19:54:00" id="p145">
<quote orig_author="Tarek Morgen">
everyone invades Poland now and then. Even the Swedens.

I think there was once a joke on the daily show that went something like this:

"Why do the Germans don't want to invade Iraq? Simply, it like with a former alcoholic. They are afraid that while everything starts with a few harmless bombs on Baghdad they wake up the next morning with a huge hangover and annexed Czech during their blackout."

</quote>

And after that it´s downhill - the best chassis for German Panzerkorps will be T-72 as Pz-38 was at one time and German officers killing themselves on highways in Skoda Fabias which would be much less glorious, but since Tatra is out of business.... <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>

Actually - how much this comedy show comment mirrors public opinion ?
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-21T09:06:00" id="p146">
<quote orig_author="BenRoethig">
Europe also has 75% of its population is large metropolitan areas. What would $8 gas do? Make life very difficult away from the coasts leading to a major increase in families needing govt. welfare, cause food prices to skyrocket because agriculture would be near unaffordable, real estate would also skyrocket with more families moving to large cities, and finish off the airlines leading to basically an airline version of AMTRAK. Life might be better for those sipping martinis in the hollywood hills, but it would cause a major recession elsewhere.

</quote>

Ben,

Your scenario depends upon the pace of changes. If you up gas overnight to $8, sure there'll be a recession. If you give consumers (and producers) time to react, then you won't see the same impact. Precisely because people can forecast when changes go into effect, they can smoothly change their behavior. As far as farming at $8/gallon of gas, it will not be unaffordable. Farmers will make more money for their food to cover the cost. They will change their behavior to farm at the most efficient level given that gas would be $8. Maybe smaller, inefficient farms will go out of business, but if the land is efficient, then some agrobusiness or adjacent farmer will buy them out and put the land to efficient use.
</post>
<post author="BenRoethig" datetime="2008-07-21T14:59:00" id="p147">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
Ben,

Your scenario depends upon the pace of changes. If you up gas overnight to $8, sure there'll be a recession. If you give consumers (and producers) time to react, then you won't see the same impact. Precisely because people can forecast when changes go into effect, they can smoothly change their behavior. As far as farming at $8/gallon of gas, it will not be unaffordable. Farmers will make more money for their food to cover the cost. They will change their behavior to farm at the most efficient level given that gas would be $8. Maybe smaller, inefficient farms will go out of business, but if the land is efficient, then some agrobusiness or adjacent farmer will buy them out and put the land to efficient use.

</quote>

And many families who have been on THEIR land for well over 100 years will find themselves doing something else why another conglomerate takes over. What's the point if all we have to all we have to look forward to are taxes, crowded buses, and a tiny apartment. All we'd be as cramped and unhappy as the Europe our families left.
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-21T22:10:00" id="p148">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
Ben,

Your scenario depends upon the pace of changes. If you up gas overnight to $8, sure there'll be a recession. If you give consumers (and producers) time to react, then you won't see the same impact. Precisely because people can forecast when changes go into effect, they can smoothly change their behavior. As far as farming at $8/gallon of gas, it will not be unaffordable. Farmers will make more money for their food to cover the cost. They will change their behavior to farm at the most efficient level given that gas would be $8. Maybe smaller, inefficient farms will go out of business, but if the land is efficient, then some agrobusiness or adjacent farmer will buy them out and put the land to efficient use.

</quote>

And how exactly do you think to give them more time to adjust? There are more people on the planet consuming more resources which leads in shortages of supply.Shortages of supply lead to higher prices and higher prices lead to recession and depression later on. The second out of five great mistakes that US did was moving production to China. Funny thing was, that no one thought that giving a billion and some people ability to buy cars won't have any effects on global economy.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-22T00:35:00" id="p149">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
I will need to look up what sort of tax is there. As far as I am aware, there isn't any congestion tax like in London. As to why people drive, don't know, but they do pay the price for doing so.

</quote>

Ever noticed how gasoline is cheaper in the suburbs and conservative areas?

I think New York does have a tax like the one in London. Not exactly the same, but similar.

<quote orig_author="antimony">
So come down hard on pork barrel spending.

</quote>

Starve the pig to reduce waste.

<quote orig_author="antimony">
You don't like mass transit, but you cannot generalise and say thats a choice across the board. I like mass transit. I would hate driving around in the city during rush hour, worrying about where I should be parking. I have too many things to think about to/ from work, without all that crowding my mind. However, people are different, and you may have an entirely different set of priorities.

</quote>

Fine. Get together with your fellow mass transit...ites and build your own system based on the capitalist model of making it worthwhile. Don't tell me to pay for your convenience. You don't see me asking the liberals to give me a subsidy on my car.

<quote orig_author="antimony">
At this point in time, it is rank opportunism with an eye on the November elections.

By the way, it seems that folks have diverted a wee bit from the topic...

</quote>

Not at all. I still think expensive gasoline is a good thing as long as it's due to market forces rather than heavy taxation.
</post>
<post author="Skywatcher" datetime="2008-07-22T05:36:00" id="p150">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
Ever noticed how gasoline is cheaper in the suburbs and conservative areas?

I think New York does have a tax like the one in London. Not exactly the same, but similar.

Starve the pig to reduce waste.

Fine. Get together with your fellow mass transit...ites and build your own system based on the capitalist model of making it worthwhile. Don't tell me to pay for your convenience. You don't see me asking the liberals to give me a subsidy on my car.

Not at all. I still think expensive gasoline is a good thing as long as it's due to market forces rather than heavy taxation.

</quote>

I don't see how mass transit would be anything more than an extension of the Pacific Railways and the Interstate Highway systems. It would be more sensible though to simply have government provide incentives that favor mass transit (like the Homestead Act), simply because there are a whole lot more potatoes to fry at the moment.
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-22T07:17:00" id="p151">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
And how exactly do you think to give them more time to adjust? There are more people on the planet consuming more resources which leads in shortages of supply.Shortages of supply lead to higher prices and higher prices lead to recession and depression later on. The second out of five great mistakes that US did was moving production to China. Funny thing was, that no one thought that giving a billion and some people ability to buy cars won't have any effects on global economy.

</quote>

Versus,

Trade has improved the prosperity of America by leaps and bounds. It's also cushioned the impact of the slow down. (And the United States has increased its absolute production levels precisely because it's engaged in more trade for manufactured goods) The average Chinese consumer is not what's driving demand for oil - it's the boom in construction not only in China, but in India and elsewhere. It also doesn't follow that shortages lead to recession and depression. If so, I'd ask where the depression was during the previous oil and other natural resource shocks?

Lastly, to address your question about how you give folks time to adjust, as a thought experiment, let's say that the US government announces that on 1 January 2013, a $2 increase in federal taxes on gas will be imposed and then on 1 January 2018, another $2 increase will be levied. The first date is over four years from now, and the second date is nearly ten years from now. When it comes time to buy your next car, how will your choice be different? When it comes time to purchase your next living quarters, how will your choice be different? When it comes time to purchase your next appliances, how will your choice be different? Based on the expected shift in demand, how will producers change?

Put another way, let's put ourselves a century ago and ask how the invention of the gasoline powered automobile changed things. If you were a horse carriage manufacturer, how would you change your R&amp;D? Would you research better horse carriages? Would you create an engine division and figure out how to modify your carriages to fit the engine and compete in this new sector? Is this good or bad for consumers? Is the death of some horse carriage companies bad for consumers? Why or why not?
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-22T07:19:00" id="p152">
<quote orig_author="BenRoethig">
And many families who have been on THEIR land for well over 100 years will find themselves doing something else why another conglomerate takes over. What's the point if all we have to all we have to look forward to are taxes, crowded buses, and a tiny apartment. All we'd be as cramped and unhappy as the Europe our families left.

</quote>

Ben,

47 out 100 Americans has stopped farming over the past century (leaving only 3 out of 100 still tilling the land) and moved into greater prosperity elsewhere. If you doubt this, then an excellent thought experiment is to compare the standard of living in 2008 to 1908. Which would you choose?
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-22T07:21:00" id="p153">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
I will need to look up what sort of tax is there. As far as I am aware, there isn't any congestion tax like in London. As to why people drive, don't know, but they do pay the price for doing so.

</quote>

SF has a pilot program that prices parking based on peak demand periods - I don't believe that it has congestion tolls like London or Singapore. NYC had their proposal shot down by the NY State Legislature, who had to approve funding in order to get the necessary matching funding from the Feds to move forward on the project.
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2008-07-22T07:58:00" id="p154">
<quote orig_author="Skywatcher">
I don't see how mass transit would be anything more than an extension of the Pacific Railways and the Interstate Highway systems. It would be more sensible though to simply have government provide incentives that favor mass transit (like the Homestead Act), simply because there are a whole lot more potatoes to fry at the moment.

</quote>

Hey, no one said it was supposed to be easy. Me, I'm wedded to my car or motorcycle. I like the range, the freedom, and the control.

Give me access to a mass transit system that reasonably sways my opinion enough and I'll use it. Like most people who go to Euroland, I also really enjoyed my experiences on the trains there, short-haul and long-haul.

Hell, ask Billy Gates or Georgie Soros to build the damned thing - they can afford to eat diesel fumes for a half a decade while the thing sells itself.

-dale
</post>
<post author="HistoricalDavid" datetime="2008-07-22T20:27:00" id="p155">
How feasible would it be to identify the busiest few medium and short-haul US domestic air routes and replace them with 300mph Maglev lines? I imagine that would slash world oil usage by quite a few tenths of a percent.
</post>
<post author="BenRoethig" datetime="2008-07-22T20:49:00" id="p156">
It would be enormously expensive to build, but we'll get a better idea if the Baltimore-Washington and Vegas to Anaheim/L.A. ever get built. Maglevs are cheap to maintain and operate but the cost as much per mile as an 8-lane freeway.
</post>
<post author="Versus" datetime="2008-07-22T21:47:00" id="p157">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
Versus,

Trade has improved the prosperity of America by leaps and bounds. It's also cushioned the impact of the slow down. (And the United States has increased its absolute production levels precisely because it's engaged in more trade for manufactured goods) The average Chinese consumer is not what's driving demand for oil - it's the boom in construction not only in China, but in India and elsewhere. It also doesn't follow that shortages lead to recession and depression. If so, I'd ask where the depression was during the previous oil and other natural resource shocks?

Lastly, to address your question about how you give folks time to adjust, as a thought experiment, let's say that the US government announces that on 1 January 2013, a $2 increase in federal taxes on gas will be imposed and then on 1 January 2018, another $2 increase will be levied. The first date is over four years from now, and the second date is nearly ten years from now. When it comes time to buy your next car, how will your choice be different? When it comes time to purchase your next living quarters, how will your choice be different? When it comes time to purchase your next appliances, how will your choice be different? Based on the expected shift in demand, how will producers change?

Put another way, let's put ourselves a century ago and ask how the invention of the gasoline powered automobile changed things. If you were a horse carriage manufacturer, how would you change your R&amp;D? Would you research better horse carriages? Would you create an engine division and figure out how to modify your carriages to fit the engine and compete in this new sector? Is this good or bad for consumers? Is the death of some horse carriage companies bad for consumers? Why or why not?

</quote>

Before I answer I need to ask couple of questions first.
Why did the US and than the rest of the world moved its production to China and India or any other undeveloped country?
Why the outsourced jobs in the domestic counters have not be replaced with the new ones?
How much the outsourcing of jobs, when seen as a whole, impacts the diversity on the job market?
And one question more. Which company or branch of industry has first moved its jobs outside the US?
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-22T22:10:00" id="p158">
The "why" is easy. Cheap Chinese labor. Why should I pay $5.15/hr when I can pay $1/hr? My job as a businessman is to make money, for me and for my shareholders. Besides have you seen manufacturing jobs? They suck! They are unpleasant. They are monotonous. They are not challenging. I don't understand how democrats want to keep manufacturing jobs here. We have better uses for our time.
</post>
<post author="HistoricalDavid" datetime="2008-07-22T23:03:00" id="p159">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
Why the outsourced jobs in the domestic counters have not be replaced with the new ones?

</quote>

They have been, obviously.

Manufacturing leaves, more and more specialised service sector jobs become available. If what you said was true, then the US would have massive double-digit unemployment rates.
</post>
<post author="Herodotus" datetime="2008-07-23T04:22:00" id="p160">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
SF has a pilot program that prices parking based on peak demand periods - I don't believe that it has congestion tolls like London or Singapore. NYC had their proposal shot down by the NY State Legislature, who had to approve funding in order to get the necessary matching funding from the Feds to move forward on the project.

</quote>

Shek,

Quick economics questions, this came up on another thread, but maybe you can answer it here. What effect does the weak dollar have on oil prices? And in general what effect or effects does a weak dollar have on the US economy, if any?

Thanks
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-23T09:58:00" id="p161">
<quote orig_author="Versus">
Before I answer I need to ask couple of questions first.
Why did the US and than the rest of the world moved its production to China and India or any other undeveloped country?

</quote>

Because for jobs where labor is used more intensively than capital, it is smarter to find labor that can produce more efficiently in terms of cost per output.

<quote orig_author="Versus">
Why the outsourced jobs in the domestic counters have not be replaced with the new ones?

</quote>

The US actually insources more value than it outsources. If "outsourcing" were banned and foreign countries retaliated with the same, the US would be a net loser.

To answer your question direct, the jobs have been replaced by jobs in other sectors. The thought process is the exact same that you make everyday when you don't attempt to grow all of your own food, cook all of your own food, create all your cloth and then sew all of your clothes, etc. You "outsource" these activities outside of your family precisely because you realize that you'll achieve a higher standard of living if you concentrate on that which you do best and then trade that with others to purchase those things which you "outsourced". Instead of bartering direct for everything, the use of currency allows a medium of exchange that allows for even more efficiency and trade.

Likewise, the same analogy applies to countries. Outsource to more efficient producers so you can concentrate on those things that you do best. Just because a line was drawn on a map, the concept doesn't suddenly become invalid.

<quote orig_author="Versus">
How much the outsourcing of jobs, when seen as a whole, impacts the diversity on the job market?

</quote>

Diversity increases. Because of having the ability to apply resources away from less efficient industries/sectors, the US has been able to concentrate more on its forte, which is the leading edge of technology and innovation. Precisely because more resources can be used for innovation, the ability to increase diversity exists since you are creating new industries.

<quote orig_author="Versus">
And one question more. Which company or branch of industry has first moved its jobs outside the US?

</quote>

I'd probably venture a guess that it was agriculture. As crops were found to not grow well in the US versus other geograhpical locations, US farmers concentrated on certain crops (e.g., tobacco, cotton, corn) and then moved jobs offshore to other countries where other crops were more efficiently grown.

However, economic history isn't my forte, so I could easily be wrong.
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-23T11:54:00" id="p162">
<quote orig_author="Herodotus">
Shek,

Quick economics questions, this came up on another thread, but maybe you can answer it here. What effect does the weak dollar have on oil prices? And in general what effect or effects does a weak dollar have on the US economy, if any?

Thanks

</quote>

Time is running short today - I will try to answer tomorrow <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/redface.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-23T17:58:00" id="p163">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
SF has a pilot program that prices parking based on peak demand periods - I don't believe that it has congestion tolls like London or Singapore. NYC had their proposal shot down by the NY State Legislature, who had to approve funding in order to get the necessary matching funding from the Feds to move forward on the project.

</quote>

Yes, thats what I thought too, that the NYC plan did not take off. I believe that the city lost out though
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-23T18:05:00" id="p164">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
Yes, thats what I thought too, that the NYC plan did not take off. I believe that the city lost out though

</quote>

You just like social engineering projects.
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-23T18:08:00" id="p165">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
Ever noticed how gasoline is cheaper in the suburbs and conservative areas?

</quote>

Sure, and they also tend to have lower quality amenities. By the way, I went to Dallas yesterday. The condition of the roads to and from the DFW airport was absolutely pathetic. And I thought it would be otherwise given that Texas is a republican state

<quote orig_author="gunnut">
Starve the pig to reduce waste.

</quote>

Well, none of the major parties are introduced in reducing pork, if the recent Farm Bill is to serve as an indication <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/>

<quote orig_author="gunnut">
Fine. Get together with your fellow mass transit...ites and build your own system based on the capitalist model of making it worthwhile. Don't tell me to pay for your convenience. You don't see me asking the liberals to give me a subsidy on my car.

</quote>

Mass transitities - that was a good one <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>

As for funding it ourselves, money raised through any tax may be used either to build roads or to build mass transit systems (roads/ trains/ bus systems). It is upto the voters finally to decide. And they would be basing their decision based on prevalent condiitions. I will tell you this, gas prices will not go back to cents, whether you like it or not. you can either start preparing right now or pay through your nose in the future. The Pigovian tax model is just another model to prepare us for that future.
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2008-07-23T18:16:00" id="p166">
<a href="http://www.dixiechopper.com/home.php#start">Dixie Chopper</a>

Not all production has moved overseas.

We still make the worlds fastest lawnmowers!!!

And a lot of the growth in the developing world? Its being done with machines made in Peoria, Wichita, Fargo, etc. and have names on them like Case, John Deere and Caterpillar
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-23T18:21:00" id="p167">
<quote orig_author="antimony">
Sure, and they also tend to have lower quality amenities. By the way, I went to Dallas yesterday. The condition of the roads to and from the DFW airport was absolutely pathetic. And I thought it would be otherwise given that Texas is a republican state

</quote>

Have you driven in Los Angeles before? It's a thoroughly liberal democrat city and I can guarantee you the roads are not better than Dallas. And I have never even been to Dallas.

<quote orig_author="antimony">
Well, none of the major parties are introduced in reducing pork, if the recent Farm Bill is to serve as an indication <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/>

</quote>

Now you know why conservatives are not too happy with Bush. Bush spends money like Ted Kennedy. The only one worse is a drunken Ted Kennedy. At least McCain is trying to cut down pork. The candidate of "change," Obama, tries to continue the old way of pork spending. How ironic is that?

<quote orig_author="antimony">
Mass transitities - that was a good one <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>

As for funding it ourselves, money raised through any tax may be used either to build roads or to build mass transit systems (roads/ trains/ bus systems). It is upto the voters finally to decide. And they would be basing their decision based on prevalent condiitions. I will tell you this, gas prices will not go back to cents, whether you like it or not. you can either start preparing right now or pay through your nose in the future. The Pigovian tax model is just another model to prepare us for that future.

Not at all. I still think expensive gasoline is a good thing as long as it's due to market forces rather than heavy taxation.

</quote>

Americans have voted. We want cars and roads. Not mass transit. There's a road in front of my house. My car can get on this road and drive all the way to Stephen King's house in Maine. There is no bus stop or train station in front of my house, nor do I want one. Air port is a form of mass transit. No one wants one of those in their neighborhood.
</post>
<post author="glyn" datetime="2008-07-23T20:19:00" id="p168">
[QUOTE=gunnut;520253]Have you driven in Los Angeles before? It's a thoroughly liberal democrat city and I can guarantee you the roads are not better than Dallas. And I have never even been to Dallas.

I would like to mention that I found driving about Los Angeles to be a terrifying experience. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/redface.gif"/> I have never seen such a concentration of cars to match it anywhere else.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-23T22:05:00" id="p169">
<quote orig_author="glyn">
I would like to mention that I found driving about Los Angeles to be a terrifying experience. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/redface.gif"/> I have never seen such a concentration of cars to match it anywhere else.

</quote>

I think 3 of the 10 most congested freeway interchanges are in LA: 101/405, 10/405 (Santa Monica), 5/10 (downtown). Hell, 5 is crowded 24/7 throughout LA and Orange counties.

However, I must admit Beijing is not far behind, if not worse already. There may not be as many cars, but the traffic patterns are poorly planned.
</post>
<post author="zraver" datetime="2008-07-24T02:05:00" id="p170">
<quote>
Americans have voted. We want cars and roads. Not mass transit. There's a road in front of my house. My car can get on this road and drive all the way to Stephen King's house in Maine. There is no bus stop or train station in front of my house, nor do I want one. Air port is a form of mass transit. No one wants one of those in their neighborhood.
</quote>

I didn't know we voted. After WW2, Europe built more rail, we built highways. Both peoples learned to thrive with what they had. Now with gas skyrocketing perhaps mass transit for urban populations makes sense. Although the higher prices affect rural populations more.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-24T04:10:00" id="p171">
<quote orig_author="zraver">
I didn't know we voted. After WW2, Europe built more rail, we built highways. Both peoples learned to thrive with what they had. Now with gas skyrocketing perhaps mass transit for urban populations makes sense. Although the higher prices affect rural populations more.

</quote>

We have voted with our pocket books. We like our cars. They grant us much more independence and freedom. Without cars, the sprawling suburbs would not be possible. Imagine cramming people into urban areas filled with highrises and tiny apartments. I like having a front yard and a back yard. I enjoy going to my friend's place and hop into the pool in the back yard.

I've lived in the city. I don't like it. I've visited cities with great mass transit systems. Good places to visit, but I wouldn't want to live there.
</post>
<post author="s_qwert63" datetime="2008-07-24T05:16:00" id="p172">
Wait so how much do you pay for a litre (1/4 gallon), or per gallon in America now?
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-24T07:35:00" id="p173">
<quote orig_author="zraver">
I didn't know we voted. After WW2, Europe built more rail, we built highways. Both peoples learned to thrive with what they had. Now with gas skyrocketing perhaps mass transit for urban populations makes sense. Although the higher prices affect rural populations more.

</quote>

Zraver,

From my sample of where I've lived in the past decade, light rail initiatives have been rejected by referendums in Washington state and elections over the past decade in Virginia have been won and lost through promises to build more roads. People may change their minds based on price doing its thing, but in the past, Americans have voted for roads.
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-24T07:36:00" id="p174">
<quote orig_author="s_qwert63">
Wait so how much do you pay for a litre (1/4 gallon), or per gallon in America now?

</quote>

Around a dollar, give or take 10 or so cents in either direction depending on where you live.
</post>
<post author="bolo121" datetime="2008-07-24T07:54:00" id="p175">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
Around a dollar, give or take 10 or so cents in either direction depending on where you live.

</quote>

Incredible! Thats cheaper than our massively subsidised petrol here!
one dollar = Rupees 42.017
One Litre = Rupees 55.00
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-24T08:06:00" id="p176">
<quote orig_author="bolo121">
Incredible! Thats cheaper than our massively subsidised petrol here!
one dollar = Rupees 42.017
One Litre = Rupees 55.00

</quote>

My guess is that economies of scale helps make refining costs cheaper here in the States per litre than elsewhere. Also, because it is done almost exclusively in the States, there won't be any premium attached (maybe a totally wrong assumption, but I'm guessing that India imports some of its refined products?).
</post>
<post author="bolo121" datetime="2008-07-24T08:32:00" id="p177">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
My guess is that economies of scale helps make refining costs cheaper here in the States per litre than elsewhere. Also, because it is done almost exclusively in the States, there won't be any premium attached (maybe a totally wrong assumption, but I'm guessing that India imports some of its refined products?).

</quote>

Well AFAIK we have plenty of refining capacity, mostly though our private owned refineries tend to export their production because of subsidies that state owned companies enjoy.
As to import of refined petroleum products here's what i could find.

<quote>
India imported 91.224 million tons of crude oil for US$48.027 billion in April-December 2007, as against import of 82.774 million tons for US$37.095 billion in the corresponding period of last fiscal, according to latest data from the Petroleum Ministry.

Import of 15.576 million tons of petroleum products cost the nation US$173 billion in first nine months of current fiscal while export of 29.614 million tons of products earned the country US$395 billion.

net oil import bill (crude oil import plus petroleum product import minus exports) in April-December was US$805 billion, as against US$359 billion in the same period a year ago.
</quote>

<a href="http://www.valuenotes.com/valuenotes/research/industryhome.asp?cn=155">Petroleum, Oil &amp; Gas news opinions research and statistics</a>
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2008-07-24T08:46:00" id="p178">
The corner gas stations near my house have come down in price over the last 2 weeks. It's now $4.259 per gallon of gasoline, down $0.30 over the last 2 weeks. If we apply the global warming model, price of gas should be down to $1.259 per gallon in 10 weeks. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="s_qwert63" datetime="2008-07-24T09:11:00" id="p179">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
Around a dollar, give or take 10 or so cents in either direction depending on where you live.

</quote>

Why you guys complaining?!

I come from an oil producing country, Chevron and Exxonmobil own half of our largest oilfield. And they pay about the same price over there.

I lived in Australia and they pay $1.50 oz dollars, theyre about the same level with US$ now.

I lived in Holland for 8 years and last I been there they pay 1.35 Euro, that is about US$ 2.10.

You guys should be happy that you getting it so cheap!
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-24T09:24:00" id="p180">
<quote orig_author="Herodotus">
Shek,

Quick economics questions, this came up on another thread, but maybe you can answer it here. What effect does the weak dollar have on oil prices? And in general what effect or effects does a weak dollar have on the US economy, if any?

Thanks

</quote>

Herodotus,

The linkage between a weak dollar and oil prices exist, but the relationship is weak. The following picture from the following link is a great illustration of this. It takes a look at a period from last fall where we saw movement in both the exchange rates and the price of oil. If it were a 1:1 relationship in terms of the movement of the $ exchange rate and the price of oil, then we'd expect that only the price of oil in dollars would change - the price would remain constant for the other currencies. As you can see, prices increase for everyone, but not at the same rate, indicating an impact, but a weak one.

<a href="http://www.econbrowser.com/archives/2007/11/oil_and_the_dol.html">Econbrowser: Oil and the dollar</a>

<img src="http://www.econbrowser.com/archives/2007/11/p_oil_currencies_nov_07.png"/>

Fundamentals are what's driving the rise in oil prices. I think this graph illustrates the concept in pretty simple but convincing terms:

<img src="http://www.theoildrum.com/files/CFTC_Fig_1.png"/>

Lastly, the impact of a changing dollar strength is mostly sectoral. If you are an export sector, you're happy. I suspect that businesses such as Catepillar are thrilled right now since it's making their stuff look cheap abroad and creating more quantities demanded. For the import businesses, things are rougher since it's costing more to get what used to be relatively cheaper. I suspect that when I go to Disney World this coming summer that I'll hear a lot of foreign languages. Likewise, I know that the weak dollar is hurting the ferienwohnung that I'm staying at here in Germany. They are used to keeping their place full with lots of American during the summer months (with Germans filling the place during the winter months since the ski slopes are a 10 minute walk). However, the weak dollar is making Euro vacations much more expensive (and a shock since we left Europe in mid-2000 nearly at the most recent height of the dollar - where it was twice as strong and we could get bottles of very good wine for $3).

However, in the big scheme, a weak dollar won't slow down the economy in the long-run, but it can cause a slow down as the sectoral shift occurs and people try to figure out whether the change is the exchange is temporary or longer lasting. By almost all accounts, people expect that the dollar will strengthen back to around $1.20/euro (it's in the $1.55 range right now).
</post>
<post author="Shek" datetime="2008-07-24T09:26:00" id="p181">
<quote orig_author="s_qwert63">
Why you guys complaining?!

I come from an oil producing country, Chevron and Exxonmobil own half of our largest oilfield. And they pay about the same price over there.

I lived in Australia and they pay $1.50 oz dollars, theyre about the same level with US$ now.

I lived in Holland for 8 years and last I been there they pay 1.35 Euro, that is about US$ 2.10.

You guys should be happy that you getting it so cheap!

</quote>

I'm not complaining! It is what it is.
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2008-07-24T14:28:00" id="p182">
I would like to mention that I found driving about Los Angeles to be a terrifying experience. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/redface.gif"/> I have never seen such a concentration of cars to match it anywhere else. [/QUOTE]

I will admit that the LA has tremendous congestion...but if you want to get REALLY scared, try driving in rush hour in Boston! People drive in the breakdown lanes, turning up a one way street the wrong way is normal, a turn signal is either a) an out of towner or b) a deception plan, everyone is on cell phones...and all of this at 65 mph.

DC is pretty bad, too.

Here in rural VA this AM unleaded regular is $3.87 this AM, down 4 cents from a high last week of 3.91.
</post>
<post author="Southie" datetime="2008-07-24T15:04:00" id="p183">
<quote orig_author="Albany Rifles">
I would like to mention that I found driving about Los Angeles to be a terrifying experience. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/redface.gif"/> I have never seen such a concentration of cars to match it anywhere else.

</quote>

I will admit that the LA has tremendous congestion... but if you want to get REALLY scared, try driving in rush hour in Boston! People drive in the breakdown lanes, turning up a one way street the wrong way is normal, a turn signal is either a) an out of towner or b) a deception plan, everyone is on cell phones...and all of this at 65 mph.
DC is pretty bad, too.

Here in rural VA this AM unleaded regular is $3.87 this AM, down 4 cents from a high last week of 3.91.[/QUOTE]

Never drove in Boston, and don't want to. Especially when the BIG DIG was going on!! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> It was every person for themselves. I take the "T" everywhere I go! Much safer!
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2008-07-24T15:05:00" id="p184">
No Guts, No Glory, Southie!!!
</post>
<post author="Southie" datetime="2008-07-24T15:14:00" id="p185">
<quote orig_author="Albany Rifles">
No Guts, No Glory, Southie!!!

</quote>

Ah yes, and the fear of getting killed when driving in Boston! Although I was able to handle the DC traffic fairly well!
</post>
<post author="Herodotus" datetime="2008-07-24T16:37:00" id="p186">
Thanks Shek,

That was informative. I need to brush up on my economics more <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/redface.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="pravin" datetime="2008-07-24T18:03:00" id="p187">
why all this you must really come to mumbai.You will know what real congestion is
</post>
<post author="antimony" datetime="2008-07-24T18:42:00" id="p188">
<quote orig_author="Shek">
Zraver,

From my sample of where I've lived in the past decade, light rail initiatives have been rejected by referendums in Washington state and elections over the past decade in Virginia have been won and lost through promises to build more roads. People may change their minds based on price doing its thing, but in the past, Americans have voted for roads.

</quote>

The light rail initiative in Washington was bundled into an immensely complicated proposal called Propostition 1 which rejected as it was all bundled into an incredibly complex road + Rail + everything else proposal.

<a href="http://seattletimes.nwsource.com/ABPub/2007/10/20/2003965191.pdf">http://seattletimes.nwsource.com/ABP...2003965191.pdf</a>

The transit authorities are working on new proposals which include enhancing the bus system in the Puget Sound area.

Interestingly, there is another one coming up called Initiative 985, which will focus on developing road infrastructure instead of mass transit. This includes opening HOV lanes during non peak hours. Lets see how that goes. the link below gives the details of this new proposals, which says that implementation will reduce congestion.

<a href="http://www.secstate.wa.gov/elections/initiatives/text/i984.pdf">http://www.secstate.wa.gov/elections.../text/i984.pdf</a>
</post>
<post author="astralis" datetime="2008-07-24T18:50:00" id="p189">
southie,

<quote>
Although I was able to handle the DC traffic fairly well!
</quote>

try driving in georgetown at rush-hour. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>

or hell, in taiwan, where traffic lights and stop signals are...suggestions, and gentle ones at that.
</post>
</doc>
