<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-199-192769-6677679">
<headline>
Who plays on E-bay, and does this look funny?
</headline>
<post author="Rockhead" datetime="2009-01-07T11:50:00" id="p1">
I am selling a car on E-bay for the first time, and got a response that seems not quite right...

Dear seller,

Thank you for the quick email. You have offered a very good price and i agreed with it. PLEASE BEFORE WE GO AHEAD I CAN ONLY DO BUSINESS WITHIN THE UNITED STATES, NO INTERNATIONAL PURCHASE.

I must let you know that i am kind of Handicapped because i sustained Leg Injury and minor auditory problem in a road side bombing during the period of serving my fatherland in Iraq war. But be it as it may, i will be using the most secured and easy way to process the payment and also will be using the service of a shipping company that will handle the pick up once you have cleared the payment.

My mode of payment will be ELECTRONIC BANK CHECK because this is the fastest and most acceptable form of check payment in the United States Bank. The ELECTRONIC BANK CHECK will be prepared online [ <a href="http://www.iversacheck.com]">www.iversacheck.com]</a> and you will only need to print the check out and deposit into your account for clearing withing 24-48hrs.

Once the check clears, i can then do the pick up. You will be printing out ELECTRONIC BANK CHECK [ ECHECK] through Bank Compliant Blank Security Check Paper and Magnetic Versa Ink with Colored Printer. After printing the checks, you will then go ahead and deposit at your bank for clearing.

You can now go ahead and buy the following :

BLANK SECURITY CHECK PAPER WITH VALIDATION CODE

MAGNETIC VERSA INK

You can buy from any of the following stores :

OFFICEMAX

OFFICE DEPOT

STAPLES

FRY'S ELECTRONICS

STATIONERY STORE

Please note that i will refund the cost of purchasing the materials. The Bank check takes only 24-48hrs to clear because it is drawn on United States Bank. I will be looking forward to hear back from you. If you don't mind, please lets chat on Yahoo messenger. My id is xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx.

Best Regards,
Axxx xxxxxx

((Ping.))
</post>
<post author="squinney" datetime="2009-01-07T11:55:00" id="p2">
Dear xxxx xxxxxxx,

Uh, yeah, right.

I'll be headin' down to Staples right away. Do me a favor and hold your breath until I get back.

Sincerely,

OOOO OOOOOO

(actually, don't reply at all)
</post>
<post author="Green Witch" datetime="2009-01-07T12:05:00" id="p3">
We got an almost identical letter when selling an expensive piece of farm equipment. We didn't respond, but we did notify Ebay fraud.
</post>
<post author="Rockhead" datetime="2009-01-07T12:18:00" id="p4">
This is the most clever of the non serious responses I have received, a couple others just wanted to see if they could get me to pull the ad.

(what a nice planet of folks we have turned into...)
</post>
<post author="Ragman" datetime="2009-01-07T13:13:00" id="p5">
@Rockhead,

the phrase "serving my fatherland " made me chuckle a bit!
</post>
<post author="shewolfnm" datetime="2009-01-07T13:36:00" id="p6">
but i suffer head injury

i not scammer
</post>
<post author="edgarblythe" datetime="2009-01-07T13:55:00" id="p7">
A friend received a nearly identical response when he tried to sell a motorcycle online.
</post>
</doc>
