<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-212-191666-3033403">
<headline>
Well-informed, patriotic, registered Democrat.
</headline>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-19T21:26:00" id="p1">
Pick any two.
</post>
<post author="Shamus" datetime="2007-11-19T21:46:00" id="p2">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
Pick any two.

</quote>

Uhhhhh.......how long do I have? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/confused.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-19T21:47:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="Shamus">
Uhhhhh.......how long do I have? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/confused.gif"/>

</quote>

HAH! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Gun Grape" datetime="2007-11-19T21:56:00" id="p4">
Since he call's hisself an Independant Democrat since the last election, does Joe Lieberman count?

If so theres 1. Damned if I can think of another
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-11-19T22:00:00" id="p5">
*raises hand*

oh oh oh.... me me me

I'm registered as a democrat, fairly patriotic, and somewhat informed.

Do I count?
</post>
<post author="Gun Grape" datetime="2007-11-19T22:09:00" id="p6">
I got it.

Thomas Jefferson and James Madison.

What? you mean present day ones.

"Never mind"
</post>
<post author="FibrillatorD" datetime="2007-11-19T22:22:00" id="p7">
Fritz Mondale
</post>
<post author="Dwarven Pirate" datetime="2007-11-20T00:42:00" id="p8">
Senator Patrick Leahy, Vermont.
Senator Chris Dodd, Connecticut.
My grandmother.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-20T00:49:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
*raises hand*

oh oh oh.... me me me

I'm registered as a democrat, fairly patriotic, and somewhat informed.

Do I count?

</quote>

You DEFINITELY count. I'm absolutely flummoxed as to WHY, though.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-20T00:50:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="Gun Grape">
Since he call's hisself an Independant Democrat since the last election, does Joe Lieberman count?

If so theres 1. Damned if I can think of another

</quote>

I concede that one. But...yeah...trying to come up with another...hmm...
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-20T00:51:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="Dwarven Pirate">
Senator Patrick Leahy, Vermont.
Senator Chris Dodd, Connecticut.
My grandmother.

</quote>

Don't know your granny, but I'll spot you THAT one. The other two...nah.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-11-20T01:04:00" id="p12">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
You DEFINITELY count. I'm absolutely flummoxed as to WHY, though.

</quote>

I registered as a democrat when I was young, dumb, and full of...well, let's just say I was dumb. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>

Since then I have been too lazy to switch. Besides, it's fun to tell all the dem pollsters something they don't hear often. And there's the added benefit of getting a "voter's guide" during election from the DNC. I use that as a guide on what NOT to vote for.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-20T03:44:00" id="p13">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
I registered as a democrat when I was young, dumb, and full of...well, let's just say I was dumb. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>

Since then I have been too lazy to switch. Besides, it's fun to tell all the dem pollsters something they don't hear often. And there's the added benefit of getting a "voter's guide" during election from the DNC. I use that as a guide on what NOT to vote for.

</quote>

Laffin' here...

Okay, that's all to your cedit. After all, if you play life as the straight man all the way through, where's the fun?

Introduce some comedy into the role; this is a good example. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="astralis" datetime="2007-11-20T14:59:00" id="p14">
bluesman,

biden ain't half bad either, although he is a gas-bag.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-20T16:41:00" id="p15">
<quote orig_author="astralis">
bluesman,

biden ain't half bad either, although he is a gas-bag.

</quote>

Can't stand him.
</post>
<post author="Dwarven Pirate" datetime="2007-11-20T18:28:00" id="p16">
So we have a gunnut - Lieberman ticket with Grammy Pirate as chief of staff? It's a good start. Plenty of fudge and banana bread in the White House.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-20T22:11:00" id="p17">
It just occurred to me that my OP was mis-interpreted. Instead of asking y'all to pick any two Democrats that are all three characteristics, I was saying that you could have any two of the charcteristics in a single person, but not all three.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-11-20T23:04:00" id="p18">
<img src="http://i91.photobucket.com/albums/k281/blurr91/political/lieberman.jpg"/>

Have you noticed we have never seen them together before? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Feanor" datetime="2007-11-21T00:01:00" id="p19">
<quote orig_author="Dwarven Pirate">
So we have a gunnut - Lieberman ticket with Grammy Pirate as chief of staff? It's a good start. Plenty of fudge and banana bread in the White House.

</quote>

The first American candidate I would vote for <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Shamus" datetime="2007-11-21T00:02:00" id="p20">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
It just occurred to me that my OP was mis-interpreted. Instead of asking y'all to pick any two Democrats that are all three characteristics, I was saying that you could have any two of the charcteristics in a single person, but not all three.

</quote>

Uhhh.....again...how much time do I have??? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/confused.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="JohnFlint1985" datetime="2007-11-21T02:35:00" id="p21">
Joseph Biden and Hillary Clinton
</post>
<post author="Julie" datetime="2007-11-21T03:08:00" id="p22">
<quote orig_author="JohnFlint1985">
Joseph Biden and Hillary Clinton

</quote>

I second that.
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2007-11-21T04:32:00" id="p23">
Neither Biden nor Hillary Clinton demonstrate the characteristic of being well-informed. They may indeed be so, but Biden sounds like an idiot and Hillary sounds like a clown.

-dale
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2007-11-21T04:50:00" id="p24">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
Neither Biden nor Hillary Clinton demonstrate the characteristic of being well-informed. They may indeed be so, but Biden sounds like an idiot and Hillary sounds like a clown.

-dale

</quote>

Hillary as a clown? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> Good grief, do you want THL 's phobia to turn into outright paranoia?
</post>
<post author="JohnFlint1985" datetime="2007-11-21T13:24:00" id="p25">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
Neither Biden nor Hillary Clinton demonstrate the characteristic of being well-informed. They may indeed be so, but Biden sounds like an idiot and Hillary sounds like a clown.

-dale

</quote>

Don't forget it is an election year - so everything sounds artificial and goofy. But you should look deeper then that. I think that both are quite knowledgeable and both are relatively center oriented. I don't see them as particularly left wing. But is is a matter of an opinion of course.
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2007-11-21T14:28:00" id="p26">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
It just occurred to me that my OP was mis-interpreted. Instead of asking y'all to pick any two Democrats that are all three characteristics, I was saying that you could have any two of the charcteristics in a single person, but not all three.

</quote>

Well this is where we can agree to disagree.

I consider myself all of them.

I read from many sources and base my decisions on my life expereinces, what I have learned and the strong moral compass which was given to me by my parents and my faith...though those are private matters.

A good friend of mine described me as a Sam Nunn Democrat...of course in the smae beath he said I was a Nelson Rockefeller Republican.

As for someone right now who is serving who fits these....I would say Jim Webb, Jay Rockefeller and Jon Tester to name a few.

The point to remember....and it has been forgotten by BOTH sides if the aisle, is we have different views but we ar ento enemies.
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2007-11-21T18:19:00" id="p27">
<quote orig_author="JohnFlint1985">
Don't forget it is an election year - so everything sounds artificial and goofy. But you should look deeper then that. I think that both are quite knowledgeable and both are relatively center oriented. I don't see them as particularly left wing. But is is a matter of an opinion of course.

</quote>

Don't assume I'm a dumbass please, I've been listening to Joe Biden for years. He's a dolt. If he's NOT a dolt he sure sounds like one. Same with Hillary - she's clearly not stupid, and doesn't sound stupid, but trying to get a coherent, logical, and consistant string of sentences out of her is a losing proposition.

And if you can honestly sit there and claim that Hillary is "center-oriented" then I wonder how far Left you must really be.

She wants socialized medicine, massive wealth redistribution via high taxes, and severe gun control laws, to pick three of her issues. How is this NOT a wildly left of center position?

-dale
</post>
<post author="JohnFlint1985" datetime="2007-11-21T22:38:00" id="p28">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
Don't assume I'm a dumbass please, I've been listening to Joe Biden for years. He's a dolt. If he's NOT a dolt he sure sounds like one. Same with Hillary - she's clearly not stupid, and doesn't sound stupid, but trying to get a coherent, logical, and consistant string of sentences out of her is a losing proposition.

And if you can honestly sit there and claim that Hillary is "center-oriented" then I wonder how far Left you must really be.

She wants socialized medicine, massive wealth redistribution via high taxes, and severe gun control laws, to pick three of her issues. How is this NOT a wildly left of center position?

-dale

</quote>

I don't consider anybody a dumb ass. All I am saying - politicians have their own language. This is why their true intentions are hard to understand. I don't listen to interviews a lot - I am concerned with their actions. This is all I want to say about it.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-21T23:29:00" id="p29">
<quote orig_author="Albany Rifles">
Well this is where we can agree to disagree.

I consider myself all of them.

I read from many sources and base my decisions on my life expereinces, what I have learned and the strong moral compass which was given to me by my parents and my faith...though those are private matters.

A good friend of mine described me as a Sam Nunn Democrat...of course in the smae beath he said I was a Nelson Rockefeller Republican.

As for someone right now who is serving who fits these....I would say Jim Webb, Jay Rockefeller and Jon Tester to name a few.

The point to remember....and it has been forgotten by BOTH sides if the aisle, is we have different views but we ar ento enemies.

</quote>

If a Democrat is well-informed, then he/she can see what's become of that moral sewer of a party. If that person can then still BE a Democrat, then, yeah, they're my enemy.

If a person is patriotic and loves the United States, but is ignorant of the fact that they can lend their support to a party that isn't, then, yeah, they're my enemy.

Here's my position: you simply canNOT support what they do when you know the details, and still say your objective is the best outcome for the country. Either you're deluded about what the party now advocates and stands for and what they are trying to do, OR you're of the mind that America is what's wrong with the world, and that you believe we're the horrible place that the Left says we are and always have been. You fear American power and primacy in the world, and believe that we're not the benign force for good that we are, and that we're no different from any other dominant hegemon throughout mankind's history.

Did anybody see the Colbert Report last night? I NEVER watch that drivel, but on the way past, I paused long enough to hear that tomorrow, we'll be celebrating genocide and racism and conquest. This is the view of the Left, and the Democrats are the Party of the Left. You see what they think of their country, their military, their government, their heritage, their history and their fellow citizens everytime they open their mouths, or put pen to paper. They despise this country, its history, people, culture...EVERYthing about it.

Am I the only one that sees this? Do you not notice that a Democrat seeks to emulate an effete, effeminate, emasculated, ennervated Europe, that he/she wishes that we would comply with World Courts and United Nations and the lowest common denominator of 'world opinion' in matters that are properly within our national sovreignty? Does a Democrat believe in American exceptionalism, or does he believe in American culpability in every manner of crime, both at home and abroad?

When you see the term 'Amerika', or 'Amerikkka', or the 'United States' with the esses made into lightning bolt runes, it'll be a Democratic party supporter that wrote it. When you see the country disparaged as evil, a Democrat said it. When I pointed out the absurdity of a John Kerry political career in the GOP after his testimony before Congress in '73, nobody seemed to really understand what I meant. But the point is, to do as he and his ilk do and be anything BUT a Democrat is laughable. And to FAIL to do that as a Democrat is laughable, as well; it's the must-have blocks you have to check on your resume' to be accepted.

Who will it be that will go overseas, sometimes into an adversary country, and get themselves plastered all over their state-run propaganda organs with admissions of American perfidy, wrongdoing and failure? It will ALWAYS be a Democrat.

If the military is maligned and accused of exactly the same things our enemies - OUR ENEMIES! - accuse them of, which party does the speaker/writer identify with?

I could go on, and I'm so dam' bitter about having lived through the horror show that the Democrats made out of the 'Seventies, and to which they look back with fond nostalgia on the time when they were ascendant and did such immense damage to the country, and to which they fervently seek to return, but I'll let you answer if you're of a mind to.

Pick any two, but friend, if you're asking me to believe that you're all three, NO SALE. Democrats are either anti-American on purpose (in which case they're not patriotic), or by accident (because they're not up-to-speed on what the party does, and how, and why). But Democrats simply cannot do what they do and say that they're about doing the best they can in good faith for the country.

Last point: if you'd like for me to return to posting the Daily Democratic War-Losing Measure again, I certainly could, because there's no shortage of material to work with. Each and every day, a Democrat can be counted on to do something against the interests of the country, and NO, I'm not perpared to believe that it's merely a difference of opinion, that somehow, if I looked at it in a different perspective, I'd see that, by golly, they WERE trying to do a Good Thing for the good ole US of A, and I'm just too right-wing-reactionary to understand it. So what do you say: would you care for me to tell you what the Democrats did today to screw the country over? Tomorrow? The day after, and on and on and on? Because this is as certain as my loathing for them: they won't let me down. There will be SOMEthing to point out, and after awhile, don't you, as an American, think that MAYBE you've pledged your support to people that simply don't want America to succeed?

So, do you consider yourself to be patriotic, well-informed, or supportive of Democratic Party objectives and points-of-view? If you pick either or both of the first two, you can't choose the third, because they're just not compatible.
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2007-11-22T01:17:00" id="p30">
Bluesman-

I see your point, and in large part agree with it, but I do think that it's a little unfair to expect every Democrat to drop their party affiliation quite so fast.

For instance, let's look at everyone's favorite Democrat, President Bill Clinton.

Is he well-informed? Yes. I don't think anyone ever questioned his intellectual ability or scope.

Is he a registered Democrat? I assume yes.

Is he patriotic? Here's the stickler. Now, I am not one who thinks of patriotism is some sort of magic antimatter thingie that can't be touched. The morons dancing their commie-monkey useful idiot protest dance in Olympia, WA right now are NOT patriots. Michael Moore is NOT a patriot. Sean Penn is NOT a patriot. They and their ilk actively and deliberately act against America's interests.

There are other examples.

But for all his personal and political failings, for all the domestic and international damage he may or may not have caused or enabled, I think President Clinton is a patriot. I think it's a bit of a disservice to imply he's not. I think that his vision of America that he believes in and defends is close enough to what it's supposed to be (Land of the Free, Home of the Brave) that it qualifies as a touch of "America, right or wrong", and I think the same can be said of a lot of the polarizing figures we yak about a lot.

I mean, simplify the imagery. If the barbarians were swarming over the walls and you were in the midst of an argument with one of the Olympia trash or Michael Moore, etc., do you think they'd grab a spear and face off against the barbarians with you? Or would they run away? Or turn on you?

I think they'd be more likely to do the latter.

But plenty of smart, well-informed registered Dems would do the former; defend the camp and the flag against the barbarians WITH you. Sure they might continue the annoying and silly argument while you're skewering barbarians (think of what a fun buddy movie that would make!), but they'd be there poking alongside you: Clinton, Lieberman and some of my Dem friends would be there with us, and my best friend's mom would be slitting their throats as they dropped (she's tiny but tough).

To me that's patriotism.

In my opinion, to suggest anything less is bordering on the reflexive intolerance of "different is evil!" that the far Left has so effectively embraced. That intolerance IS percolating up into the mainstream Democratic Party, and it makes them ugly.

Let's not be ugly like them.

-dale
</post>
<post author="ArmchairGeneral" datetime="2007-11-22T02:22:00" id="p31">
Great post, Dale.
</post>
<post author="Julie" datetime="2007-11-22T02:37:00" id="p32">
<quote orig_author="ArmchairGeneral">
Great post, Dale.

</quote>

Ditto that. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-22T04:22:00" id="p33">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
Bluesman-

I see your point, and in large part agree with it, but I do think that it's a little unfair to expect every Democrat to drop their party affiliation quite so fast.

For instance, let's look at everyone's favorite Democrat, President Bill Clinton.

Is he well-informed? Yes. I don't think anyone ever questioned his intellectual ability or scope.

Is he a registered Democrat? I assume yes.

Is he patriotic? Here's the stickler. Now, I am not one who thinks of patriotism is some sort of magic antimatter thingie that can't be touched. The morons dancing their commie-monkey useful idiot protest dance in Olympia, WA right now are NOT patriots. Michael Moore is NOT a patriot. Sean Penn is NOT a patriot. They and their ilk actively and deliberately act against America's interests.

There are other examples.

But for all his personal and political failings, for all the domestic and international damage he may or may not have caused or enabled, I think President Clinton is a patriot. I think it's a bit of a disservice to imply he's not. I think that his vision of America that he believes in and defends is close enough to what it's supposed to be (Land of the Free, Home of the Brave) that it qualifies as a touch of "America, right or wrong", and I think the same can be said of a lot of the polarizing figures we yak about a lot.

I mean, simplify the imagery. If the barbarians were swarming over the walls and you were in the midst of an argument with one of the Olympia trash or Michael Moore, etc., do you think they'd grab a spear and face off against the barbarians with you? Or would they run away? Or turn on you?

I think they'd be more likely to do the latter.

But plenty of smart, well-informed registered Dems would do the former; defend the camp and the flag against the barbarians WITH you. Sure they might continue the annoying and silly argument while you're skewering barbarians (think of what a fun buddy movie that would make!), but they'd be there poking alongside you: Clinton, Lieberman and some of my Dem friends would be there with us, and my best friend's mom would be slitting their throats as they dropped (she's tiny but tough).

To me that's patriotism.

In my opinion, to suggest anything less is bordering on the reflexive intolerance of "different is evil!" that the far Left has so effectively embraced. That intolerance IS percolating up into the mainstream Democratic Party, and it makes them ugly.

Let's not be ugly like them.

-dale

</quote>

Alright, suppose I grant you the point.

Then, Bill Clinton endorses Ron Dellums for Chairman of the Armed Services Committee. And the supply of spear-points and the doctrine of using them on babrbarians are beaten into ploughshares, and we're all killed.

Some patriot; some love of country.

I'm saying that if you THINK this country is worthwhile, you've simply got to work for the immediate political obliteration of the Democratic Party. Bill Clinton didn't, and he still treats Jimmy Carter as a great statesman.

Democrats are dangerous, maybe not as individuals, but certainly as a party. And that's what I'm trying to get across: knowing what is absolutely clear about the modern Democratic Party, lending your support to it is quite literally one step - a SMALL step - short of treason.

And I will not relent in defending the point, either, whether somebody thinks that's too extreme or not, because if one seeks to delude one's self about what has been done and continues to be done against this country's welfare and security, there's nothing more to be said.

I'll welcome any help with the spearing when the barbarians come over the wall. But the issue I've been flogging is simply that we'd be on THEIR wall, and not playing out the 'Last Stand' scene if half the country believed in the worthiness of American triumphalism.
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2007-11-22T04:36:00" id="p34">
B-man-

I still see your point, and I still agree with the need to fix the Democratic party, and one way to do that is to get folks to abandon it.

There is no doubt in my mind that the core principles of the Democratic party - high taxes, weak America, decrease in self-reliance and personal responsibility, institutionalization of magic - are bad and in some cases dangerous.

But I don't want to call 'em all jerks.

-dale
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-22T04:50:00" id="p35">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
B-man-

I still see your point, and I still agree with the need to fix the Democratic party, and one way to do that is to get folks to abandon it.

There is no doubt in my mind that the core principles of the Democratic party - high taxes, weak America, decrease in self-reliance and personal responsibility, institutionalization of magic - are bad and in some cases dangerous.

But I don't want to call 'em all jerks.

-dale

</quote>

As usual, I'm right there witcha.

And if they don't want to be part of what's going on, they can dam' well do something about it.

And if they don't, they deserve every bit of the disdain that they've earned from me.

Democrats, get control of that gang of Fifth Columinists, or leave 'em for a PRO-American political afilliation.

That's what I've been saying: be patriotic, be aware, and be something besides a Democrat, because all three together simply is indefensible.
</post>
<post author="Julie" datetime="2007-11-22T12:50:00" id="p36">
In retrospect to all of that, I would just like to say that having BOTH parties have seemed to work well thus far to the Advancement of America. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-22T14:24:00" id="p37">
<quote orig_author="Julie">
In retrospect to all of that, I would just like to say that having BOTH parties have seemed to work well thus far to the Advancement of America. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>

</quote>

That's because up until 1968, both were more or less PRO-American. Well, that proposition has been dead-'n'-buried for almost 40 years now. Up until then, Democrats were merely feckless, and devoted to a stupid political philosophy that sought in its fuzzy-headed, illogical and well-meant way to try to do right by the country with a concept and worldview that was ditzy and airheaded and belied by history's lessons, but wasn't explicitly designed to actually do damage on purpose.

They were doing plenty of damage anyway, but it wasn't malicious.

But this is an entirely NEW Democratic Party. Sam Nunn, whom you've mentioned before in this thread, would be cudgeled every bit as viciously as Lieberman has been, and there is simply no person in the party I can point to that's worthy of his American birthright.

I wish they'd all emigrate, I really, truly do.
</post>
<post author="Feanor" datetime="2007-11-22T16:53:00" id="p38">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
That's because up until 1968, both were more or less PRO-American. Well, that proposition has been dead-'n'-buried for almost 40 years now. Up until then, Democrats were merely feckless, and devoted to a stupid political philosophy that sought in its fuzzy-headed, illogical and well-meant way to try to do right by the country with a concept and worldview that was ditzy and airheaded and belied by history's lessons, but wasn't explicitly designed to actually do damage on purpose.

They were doing plenty of damage anyway, but it wasn't malicious.

But this is an entirely NEW Democratic Party. Sam Nunn, whom you've mentioned before in this thread, would be cudgeled every bit as viciously as Lieberman has been, and there is simply no person in the party I can point to that's worthy of his American birthright.

I wish they'd all emigrate, I really, truly do.

</quote>

Yesss. Yess. Make America a one party state please. It would make my day, I honestly would celebrate. If there's a surer way to bring down empire America, I don't know what it is.
</post>
<post author="Shipwreck" datetime="2007-11-22T16:57:00" id="p39">
Capt. Larry Seaquist, US Navy (Ret.)
</post>
<post author="Parihaka" datetime="2007-11-22T20:22:00" id="p40">
With all the money that currently gets spent on campaigns, why doesn't someone like Lieberman instead raise money to start a new party? Is it impossible for the US to have three parties?
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-22T21:41:00" id="p41">
<quote orig_author="Parihaka">
With all the money that currently gets spent on campaigns, why doesn't someone like Lieberman instead raise money to start a new party? Is it impossible for the US to have three parties?

</quote>

The deck is stacked. Like all corrupted people in power always will, both parties made dam' sure that any political threat is so marginalized as to be no threat to their continued co-dominance.

By the way, note that I acknowledge BOTH sides' culpability here.
</post>
<post author="Feanor" datetime="2007-11-22T22:19:00" id="p42">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
The deck is stacked. Like all corrupted people in power always will, both parties made dam' sure that any political threat is so marginalized as to be no threat to their continued co-dominance.

By the way, note that I acknowledge BOTH sides' culpability here.

</quote>

It's not the fault of the sides. It's the fault of the system.
</post>
<post author="Dwarven Pirate" datetime="2007-11-22T22:27:00" id="p43">
<quote orig_author="Feanor">
It's not the fault of the sides. It's the fault of the system.

</quote>

Yes, sort of. All 'sides' wish to preserve the status quo; the 'system' provides the means to easily accomplish that.

If a third party were to rise, it would collude in order to prevent a fourth, and any system can be manipulated to bestow or deny favor, IMO. Its natural for what resists change to stagnate and degenerate. Inevitable even.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-22T22:41:00" id="p44">
<quote orig_author="Dwarven Pirate">
Yes, sort of. All 'sides' wish to preserve the status quo; the 'system' provides the means to easily accomplish that.

If a third party were to rise, it would collude in order to prevent a fourth, and any system can be manipulated to bestow or deny favor, IMO. Its natural for what resists change to stagnate and degenerate. Inevitable even.

</quote>

Maybe your only post I entirely agree with.

Are you feeling alright?
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-11-22T22:51:00" id="p45">
<quote orig_author="Parihaka">
With all the money that currently gets spent on campaigns, why doesn't someone like Lieberman instead raise money to start a new party? Is it impossible for the US to have three parties?

</quote>

Yes, it's nearly impossible due to our winner-take-all presidential elections and vote-for-your-representative local election to the federal government.

Winner takes all means you have the top 2 guys hogging up nearly all the electoral votes. A 3rd party candidate might get a few here and there, but not likely. This further discourages the people from voting the "certain loser."

We vote for the person as our representative to the Congress in our local elections. We don't vote for the party and then the seats get assigned. So again it comes down to the top 2 guys hogging up most of the "winner take all" seat.

We usually vote for the lesser of the 2 evils because if we vote our conscience, the evil might get elected.

Clinton got only 45% of the popular vote in 1992. Bush got something like 40%. Perot got 15% I believe. The conservatives were unhappy with Bush so they voted for Perot. The center right voted for Bush. All the left side voted for Clinton. Bush could have won if Perot didn't siphon off the conservative base.

Does that make any sense?
</post>
<post author="Parihaka" datetime="2007-11-22T23:57:00" id="p46">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
Does that make any sense?

</quote>

Yeah sort of. Because of our MMP system we of course have a lot more parties who can all have an influence on the Government, we haven't had a majority Government since MMP began. From how I see it you'd have to change your entire system of elections to have anything other than the two existing parties?
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2007-11-23T06:02:00" id="p47">
<quote orig_author="Parihaka">
Yeah sort of. Because of our MMP system we of course have a lot more parties who can all have an influence on the Government, we haven't had a majority Government since MMP began. From how I see it you'd have to change your entire system of elections to have anything other than the two existing parties?

</quote>

We really would. It would have to be closer to a power sharing model, and we don't do that. Like gunnut pointed out, it's winner take all. Personally I prefer it.

-dale
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-11-23T10:56:00" id="p48">
<quote orig_author="dalem">
We really would. It would have to be closer to a power sharing model, and we don't do that. Like gunnut pointed out, it's winner take all. Personally I prefer it.

-dale

</quote>

I prefer it as well.

Both systems have faults. Nothing is perfect.

With our system, we have basically 2 choices: one that's closer to your ideals and the other that's farther. Kinda limited. But at the same time we won't need a coalition government or power sharing deal between multiple parties. Our government will always be there with a majority. We don't need to call for an election if the parties don't agree and things just grind to a halt.
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2007-11-23T15:06:00" id="p49">
I can easily identify as a Democrat and still believe in all things.

And at its core, the values of the Democratic party are about taking care of our fellow man, that government can and does help people but does not have to be huge and bloated, that we need to protect our country and all its citzens.

Now, do the elected representatives in our Congress reflect all of those values? Nope, I acknowledge that. Is the best way to fix something always to tear it apart or abandon it? Nope; in fact, if that were the case, then the US Army would be in worse shape than it is. And before you throw up the 1970s as some great, dark time visited on this country by the Democratic Party, the Republican Party held the White Hosue that entire decade until Jan 1977. And Reagan's great expansion of the military happened with weapon systems designed and funded during a Democratic administration and funded by a Democratic Congress.

Trust me, over the years, I have looked across the aisle to the Republican Party but I always find it wanting in too many ways.

I agree there has to be a fix to the immigration problem but I don't think we need to hunt down people and throw them in jail. And did you know that Latin immigrants, tend to end up being more conservative than native born Americans once they become citizens.

I don't complain about taxes...in fact I don't mind paying taxes. Taxes are the price we pay for a civilized society. Taxes have paid my salary, directly or indirectly, most of my adult life. Bu ttaxes are how we pay for roads and schools, police and fire. No do I think we could have a better tax code? Sure.

Does the government always provide the best answer to a problem? Nope but when there is no one else trying to answer the problem then someone has to step in...again, it is the sign of a civilized society. An example here is Welfare. I think the Welfare Reformn of the 1990s was a good idea btu I don't think we have gone far enough. Okay we say someone has to work...no problem. But what if that someone has 3 kids and no child care? Do we punich them forever for mistakes when they were younger? How about we subsidize soem child care so that person can go to work? And that person then can pay...some tax!

As for Steven Colbert and his ilk, I listed for a laugh not for my information on the world. I read, I listen to the news, I discuss. I force myself to be an informed citizen.

Look, Bluesman, I know we can disagree but I can not actually believe that you think I do not love my country. You do not know me well enough to know how I developed into the person I am and why I have the beliefs I hold.

We can agree to disagree but that does not mean we have to be enemies.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-23T18:33:00" id="p50">
A good post. I appreciate it, especially when I'm baiting y'all as hard as I can. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )

More later...
</post>
<post author="Julie" datetime="2007-11-23T20:08:00" id="p51">
We all wantthe same things in life. We want freedom; we want the chance for prosperity; we want to be the best we can be; we want as few people suffering as possible, economically; we want healthy children; we want to have crime-free streets; all these things, theyre pretty common The argument is how to achieve them. ~Rush Limbaugh, July 9, 2004
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-24T04:39:00" id="p52">
This is my problem with mainstream American voting for ANY Democrat: it leads to their control eventually, and then they buy their positions for life with our money, while simultaneously screwing up the country.

Do you know how close we are to losing this war? I sincerely thought we HAD lost the war the day after the elections last year, and with ANYbody else in the White House, we would have. And we are now 14 months away from a new crisis, and another Last Chance to hang on for just awhile longer.

YOU contribute to that state of affairs. Do you not KNOW that? Are you not AWARE that the Chairman of both Armed Services Committees are trying with all that's in 'em to destroy what they're in charge of? And YOU helped that happen.

You love your country, and you're offended that I say you're either ignorant or treacherous. Well, explain to me why you're not either, when you're contributing your support to this:
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-24T04:39:00" id="p53">
Tell me WHY you're aiding and abetting this.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-24T04:44:00" id="p54">
<quote orig_author="Julie">
We all wantthe same things in life. We want freedom; we want the chance for prosperity; we want to be the best we can be; we want as few people suffering as possible, economically; we want healthy children; we want to have crime-free streets; all these things, theyre pretty common The argument is how to achieve them. ~Rush Limbaugh, July 9, 2004

</quote>

Apparently, by losing a winnable war, your side aims to improve the country, like ALL of want to. Explain that, and try to make sense.
</post>
<post author="Albany Rifles" datetime="2007-11-25T00:47:00" id="p55">
Tell me why your side of the aisle will excoriate homosexuals then there are stories of "wide stances"?

Tell me why you party speaks of honor and service and then trashes a disabled veteran like Max Clelland.

Tell me why when a Democratic Congress wants to vote for more funds for VA benefits for vedterans you party supports upholding a presidential veto?

Okay, so you have pictures of Howard Dean and Speaker Pelosi.....and I say they represent me how?

You need to show me pictures of Jim Webb, Tim Kaine, John Warner and Bobby Scott to show me the people I have voted for recently. And I can listen to folks like Lindsay Graham and John McCain as well as Chris Shays and agree with a lot of what they have to say.

I often hear about a supposed "East Coast" bias and a dismissal of folks from the Northeast as being academic snobs. Well, I am none of those...and neither are my friends nor members of my family. I find it amusing and irritating that folks who are from a state which has Nancy Pelosi as a member of its' states Congressional delegation calls into question the patriotism and political views of someone from the East Coast. Don't like your local politics...then move.

So if you disagree with my views....that is fine, (a long paragraph has been redacted so I won't be accused of a Strateypage-like flaming!)
</post>
<post author="Julie" datetime="2007-11-25T00:53:00" id="p56">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
Apparently, by losing a winnable war, your side aims to improve the country, like ALL of want to. Explain that, and try to make sense.

</quote>

Because Bush succeeded in deflecting America's anger from Osama Bin Laden to Saddam Hussein, and in doing that, was one of the greatest public relations conjuring tricks in history.

You do remember Osama Bin Laden, don't you?
</post>
<post author="troung" datetime="2007-11-25T01:30:00" id="p57">
<quote>
Apparently, by losing a winnable war, your side aims to improve the country, like ALL of want to. Explain that, and try to make sense.
</quote>

There is the war in Afghanistan (not going terribly well - despite the fact they hit us on 9-11), the situation in Pakistan (ditto) and a feeling the Iraqis have shown through their elected officials and their readiness to kill each other that they aren't worth wasting the money and lives. From vacations during the summer to the Sunni groups in Anbar who are still opposed to the central government (and vise-versa).

It seems a lot of people don't plan to marry themselves to Iraq for the next decade.

<quote>
This is my problem with mainstream American voting for ANY Democrat: it leads to their control eventually, and then they buy their positions for life with our money, while simultaneously screwing up the country.
</quote>

Republicans do the same, both parties once in power too long become corrupt and get shown the door.
</post>
<post author="Feanor" datetime="2007-11-25T04:03:00" id="p58">
The problem isn't the parties. It's the system. Both parties place their interests of gaining power before the good of the nation.
</post>
<post author="FibrillatorD" datetime="2007-11-25T04:10:00" id="p59">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
I could go on, and I'm so dam' bitter about having lived through the horror show that the Democrats made out of the 'Seventies, and to which they look back with fond nostalgia on the time when they were ascendant and did such immense damage to the country, and to which they fervently seek to return, but I'll let you answer if you're of a mind to.

</quote>

<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
That's because up until 1968, both were more or less PRO-American. Well, that proposition has been dead-'n'-buried for almost 40 years now. Up until then, Democrats were merely feckless, and devoted to a stupid political philosophy that sought in its fuzzy-headed, illogical and well-meant way to try to do right by the country with a concept and worldview that was ditzy and airheaded and belied by history's lessons, but wasn't explicitly designed to actually do damage on purpose.

</quote>

<quote>
December 2007 Atlantic Monthly

Is Iraq Vietnam? Who really won in 2000? Which side are you on in the culture wars? These questions have divided the Baby Boomers and distorted our politics. One candidate could transcend them.

by Andrew Sullivan
Goodbye to All That

The logic behind the candidacy of Barack Obama is not, in the end, about Barack Obama. It has little to do with his policy proposals, which are very close to his Democratic rivals' and which, with a few exceptions, exist firmly within the conventions of our politics. It has little to do with Obama's considerable skills as a conciliator, legislator, or even thinker. It has even less to do with his ideological pedigree or legal background or rhetorical skills. Yes, as the many profiles prove, he has considerable intelligence and not a little guile. But so do others, not least his formidably polished and practiced opponent Senator Hillary Clinton.

Obama, moreover, is no saint. He has flaws and tics: Often tired, sometimes crabby, intermittently solipsistic, he's a surprisingly uneven campaigner.

A soaring rhetorical flourish one day is undercut by a lackluster debate performance the next. He is certainly not without self-regard. He has more experience in public life than his opponents want to acknowledge, but he has not spent much time in Washington and has never run a business. His lean physique, close-cropped hair, and stick-out ears can give the impression of a slightly pushy undergraduate. You can see why many of his friends and admirers have urged him to wait his turn. He could be president in five or nine years' timewhy the rush?

But he knows, and privately acknowledges, that the fundamental point of his candidacy is that it is happening now. In politics, timing matters. And the most persuasive case for Obama has less to do with him than with the moment he is meeting. The moment has been a long time coming, and it is the result of a confluence of events, from one traumatizing war in Southeast Asia to another in the most fractious country in the Middle East. The legacy is a cultural climate that stultifies our politics and corrupts our discourse.

Obama's candidacy in this sense is a potentially transformational one. Unlike any of the other candidates, he could take Americafinallypast the debilitating, self-perpetuating family quarrel of the Baby Boom generation that has long engulfed all of us. So much has happened in America in the past seven years, let alone the past 40, that we can be forgiven for focusing on the present and the immediate future. But it is only when you take several large steps back into the long past that the full logic of an Obama presidency stares directlyand uncomfortablyat you.

At its best, the Obama candidacy is about ending a warnot so much the war in Iraq, which now has a mo*mentum that will propel the occupation into the next decadebut the war within America that has prevailed since Vietnam and that shows dangerous signs of intensifying, a nonviolent civil war that has crippled America at the very time the world needs it most. It is a war about warand about culture and about religion and about race. And in that war, Obamaand Obama aloneoffers the possibility of a truce.

The traces of our long journey to this juncture can be found all around us. Its most obvious manifestation is political rhetoric. The high temperatureBill O'Reilly's nightly screeds against anti-Americans on one channel, Keith Olbermann's "Worst Person in the World" on the other; MoveOn.org's "General Betray Us" on the one side, Ann Coulter's Treason on the other; Michael Moore's accusation of treason at the core of the Iraq War, Sean Hannity's assertion of treason in the opposition to itis particularly striking when you examine the generally minor policy choices on the table. Something deeper and more powerful than the actual decisions we face is driving the tone of the debate.

Take the biggest foreign-policy questionthe war in Iraq. The rhetoric ranges from John McCain's "No Surrender" banner to the "End the War Now" absolutism of much of the Democratic base. Yet the substantive issue is almost comically removed from this hyperventilation. Every potential president, Republican or Democrat, would likely inherit more than 100,000 occupying troops in January 2009; every one would be attempting to redeploy them as prudently as possible and to build stronger alliances both in the region and in the world. Every major candidate, moreover, will pledge to use targeted military force against al-Qaeda if necessary; every one is committed to ensuring that Iran will not have a nuclear bomb; every one is committed to an open-ended deployment in Afghanistan and an unbending alliance with Israel.We are fighting over something, to be sure. But it is more a fight over how we define ourselves and over long-term goals than over what is practically to be done on the ground.

On domestic policy, the primary issue is health care. Again, the ferocious rhetoric belies the mundane reality. Between the boogeyman of "Big Government" and the alleged threat of the drug companies, the practical differences are more matters of nuance than ideology. Yes, there are policy disagreements, but in the wake of the Bush administration, they are underwhelming. Most Republicans support continuing the Medicare drug benefit for seniors, the largest expansion of the entitlement state since Lyndon Johnson, while Democrats are merely favoring more cost controls on drug and insurance companies. Between Mitt Romney's Massachusetts planindividual mandates, private-sector leadershipand Senator Clinton's triangulated update of her 1994 debacle, the difference is more technical than fundamental. The country has moved ever so slightly leftward. But this again is less a function of ideological transformation than of the current system's failure to provide affordable health care for the insured or any care at all for growing numbers of the working poor.

If the Supreme Court overturns Roe v. Wade, it will set off tectonic shifts in the American political landscape not seen since the civil-rights movementor perhaps even the Civil War. By Jeffrey Rosen

Even on issues that are seen as integral to the polarization, the practical stakes in this election are minor. A large consensus in America favors legal abortions during the first trimester and varying restrictions thereafter. Even in solidly red states, such as South Dakota, the support for total criminalization is weak. If Roe were to fall, the primary impact would be the end of a system more liberal than any in Europe in favor of one more in sync with the varied views that exist across this country. On marriage, the battles in the states are subsiding, as a bevy of blue states adopt either civil marriage or civil unions for gay couples, and the rest stand pat. Most states that want no recognition for same-sex couples have already made that decision, usually through state constitutional amendments that allow change only with extreme difficulty. And the one state where marriage equality exists, Massachusetts, has decided to maintain the reform indefinitely.

Given this quiet, evolving consensus on policy, how do we account for the bitter, brutal tone of American politics? The answer lies mainly with the biggest and most influential generation in America: the Baby Boomers. The divide is stillamazinglybetween those who fought in Vietnam and those who didn't, and between those who fought and dissented and those who fought but never dissented at all. By defining the contours of the Boomer generation, it lasted decades. And with time came a strange intensity.

The professionalization of the battle, and the emergence of an array of well-funded interest groups dedicated to continuing it, can be traced most proximately to the bitter confirmation fights over Robert Bork and Clarence Thomas, in 1987 and 1991 respectively. The presidency of Bill Clinton, who was elected with only 43 percent of the vote in 1992, crystallized the new reality. As soon as the Baby Boomers hit the commanding heights, the Vietnam power struggle rebooted. The facts mattered little in the face of such a divide. While Clinton was substantively a moderate conservative in policy, his countercultural origins led to the drama, ultimately, of religious warfare and even impeachment. Clinton clearly tried to bridge the Boomer split. But he was trapped on one side of itand his personal foibles only reignited his generation's agonies over sex and love and marriage. Even the failed impeachment didn't bring the two sides to their senses, and the election of 2000 only made matters worse: Gore and Bush were almost designed to reflect the Boomers' and the country's divide, which deepened further.

The trauma of 9/11 has tended to obscure the memory of that unprecedentedly bitter election, and its nail- biting aftermath, which verged on a constitutional crisis. But its legacy is very much still with us, made far worse by President Bush's approach to dealing with it. Despite losing the popular vote, Bush governed as if he had won Reagan's 49 states. Instead of cementing a coalition of the center-right, Bush and Rove set out to ensure that the new evangelical base of the Republicans would turn out more reliably in 2004. Instead of seeing the post-'60s divide as a wound to be healed, they poured acid on it.

With 9/11, Bush had a reset momenta chance to reunite the country in a way that would marginalize the extreme haters on both sides and forge a national consensus. He chose not to do so. It wasn't entirely his fault. On the left, the truest believers were unprepared to give the president the benefit of any doubt in the wake of the 2000 election, and they even judged the 9/11 attacks to be a legitimate response to decades of U.S. foreign policy. Some could not support the war in Afghanistan, let alone the adventure in Iraq. As the Iraq War faltered, the polarization intensified. In 2004, the Vietnam argument returned with a new energy, with the Swift Boat attacks on John Kerry's Vietnam War record and CBS's misbegotten report on Bush's record in the Texas Air National Guard. These were the stories that touched the collective nerve of the political classesbecause they parsed once again along the fault lines of the Boomer divide that had come to define all of us.

The result was an even deeper schism. Kerry was arguably the worst candidate on earth to put to rest the post-1960s culture warand his decision to embrace his Vietnam identity at the convention made things worse. Bush, for his part, was unable to do nuance. And so the campaign became a matter of symbolismpitting those who took the terror threat "seriously" against those who didn't. Supporters of the Iraq War became more invested in asserting the morality of their cause than in examining the effectiveness of their tactics. Opponents of the war found themselves dispirited. Some were left to hope privately for American failure; others lashed out, as distrust turned to paranoia. It was and is a toxic cycle, in which the interests of the United States are supplanted by domestic agendas born of pride and ruthlessness on the one hand and bitterness and alienation on the other.

This is the critical context for the election of 2008. It is an election that holds the potential not merely to intensify this cycle of division but to bequeath it to a new generation, one marked by a new war that need not bethat should not beseen as another Vietnam. A Giuliani-Clinton matchup, favored by the media elite, is a classic intragenerational strugglewith two deeply divisive and ruthless personalities ready to go to the brink. Giuliani represents that Nixonian disgust with anyone asking questions about, let alone actively protesting, a war. Clinton will always be, in the minds of so many, the young woman who gave the commencement address at Wellesley, who sat in on the Nixon implosion and who once disdained baking cookies. For some, her husband will always be the draft dodger who smoked pot and wouldn't admit it. And however hard she tries, there is nothing Hillary Clinton can do about it. She and Giuliani are conscripts in their generation's war. To their respective sides, they are war heroes.

In normal times, such division is not fatal, and can even be healthy. It's great copy for journalists. But we are not talking about routine rancor. And we are not talking about normal times. We are talking about a world in which Islamist terror, combined with increasingly available destructive technology, has already murdered thousands of Americans, and tens of thousands of Muslims, and could pose an existential danger to the West. The terrible failures of the Iraq occupation, the resurgence of al-Qaeda in Pakistan, the progress of Iran toward nuclear capability, and the collapse of America's prestige and moral reputation, especially among those millions of Muslims too young to have known any American president but Bush, heighten the stakes dramatically.

Perhaps the underlying risk is best illustrated by our asking what the popular response would be to another 9/11style attack. It is hard to imagine a reprise of the sudden unity and solidarity in the days after 9/11, or an outpouring of support from allies and neighbors. It is far easier to imagine an even more bitter fight over who was responsible (apart from the perpetrators) and a profound suspicion of a government forced to impose more restrictions on travel, communications, and civil liberties. The current president would be unable to command the trust, let alone the support, of half the country in such a time. He could even be blamed for provoking any attack that came.

Of the viable national candidates, only Obama and possibly McCain have the potential to bridge this widening partisan gulf. Polling reveals Obama to be the favored Democrat among Republicans. McCain's bipartisan appeal has receded in recent years, especially with his enthusiastic embrace of the latest phase of the Iraq War. And his personal history can only reinforce the Vietnam divide. But Obama's reach outside his own ranks remains striking. Why? It's a good question: How has a black, urban liberal gained far stronger support among Republicans than the made-over moderate Clinton or the southern charmer Edwards? Perhaps because the Republicans and independents who are open to an Obama candidacy see his primary advantage in prosecuting the war on Islamist terrorism. It isn't about his policies as such; it is about his person. They are prepared to set their own ideological preferences to one side in favor of what Obama offers America in a critical moment in our dealings with the rest of the world. The war today matters enormously. The war of the last generation? Not so much. If you are an American who yearns to finally get beyond the symbolic battles of the Boomer generation and face today's actual problems, Obama may be your man.

What does he offer? First and foremost: his face. Think of it as the most effective potential re-branding of the United States since Reagan. Such a re-branding is not trivialit's central to an effective war strategy. The war on Islamist terror, after all, is two-pronged: a function of both hard power and soft power. We have seen the potential of hard power in removing the Taliban and Saddam Hussein. We have also seen its inherent weaknesses in Iraq, and its profound limitations in winning a long war against radical Islam. The next president has to create a sophisticated and supple blend of soft and hard power to isolate the enemy, to fight where necessary, but also to create an ideological template that works to the West's advantage over the long haul. There is simply no other candidate with the potential of Obama to do this. Which is where his face comes in.

Consider this hypothetical. It's November 2008. A young Pakistani Muslim is watching television and sees that this manBarack Hussein Obamais the new face of America. In one simple image, America's soft power has been ratcheted up not a notch, but a logarithm. A brown-skinned man whose father was an African, who grew up in Indonesia and Hawaii, who attended a majority-Muslim school as a boy, is now the alleged enemy. If you wanted the crudest but most effective weapon against the demonization of America that fuels Islamist ideology, Obama's face gets close. It proves them wrong about what America is in ways no words can.

The other obvious advantage that Obama has in facing the world and our enemies is his record on the Iraq War. He is the only major candidate to have clearly opposed it from the start. Whoever is in office in January 2009 will be tasked with redeploying forces in and out of Iraq, negotiating with neighboring states, engaging America's estranged allies, tamping down regional violence. Obama's interlocutors in Iraq and the Middle East would know that he never had suspicious motives toward Iraq, has no interest in occupying it indefinitely, and foresaw more clearly than most Americans the baleful consequences of long-term occupation.

This latter point is the most salient. The act of picking the next president will be in some ways a statement of America's view of Iraq. Clinton is running as a centrist Democratvoting for war, accepting the need for an occupation at least through her first term, while attempting to do triage as practically as possible. Obama is running as the clearer antiwar candidate. At the same time, Obama's candidacy cannot fairly be cast as a McGovernite revival in tone or substance. He is not opposed to war as such. He is not opposed to the use of unilateral force, eitheras demonstrated by his willingness to target al-Qaeda in Pakistan over the objections of the Pakistani government. He does not oppose the idea of democratization in the Muslim world as a general principle or the concept of nation building as such. He is not an isolationist, as his support for the campaign in Afghanistan proves. It is worth recalling the key passages of the speech Obama gave in Chicago on October 2, 2002, five months before the war:

I don't oppose all wars. And I know that in this crowd today, there is no shortage of patriots, or of patriotism. What I am opposed to is a dumb war. What I am opposed to is a rash war  I know that even a successful war against Iraq will require a U.S. occupation of undetermined length, at undetermined cost, with undetermined consequences. I know that an invasion of Iraq without a clear rationale and without strong international support will only fan the flames of the Middle East, and encourage the worst, rather than best, impulses of the Arab world, and strengthen the recruitment arm of al-Qaeda. I am not opposed to all wars. I'm opposed to dumb wars.

The man who opposed the war for the right reasons is for that reason the potential president with the most flexibility in dealing with it. Clinton is hemmed in by her past and her generation. If she pulls out too quickly, she will fall prey to the usual browbeating from the rightthe same theme that has played relentlessly since 1968. If she stays in too long, the antiwar base of her own party, already suspicious of her, will pounce. The Boomer legacy imprisons herand so it may continue to imprison us. The debate about the war in the next four years needs to be about the practical and difficult choices ahead of usnot about the symbolism or whether it's a second Vietnam.

A generational divide also separates Clinton and Obama with respect to domestic politics. Clinton grew up saturated in the conflict that still defines American politics. As a liberal, she has spent years in a defensive crouch against triumphant post-Reagan conservatism. The mau-mauing that greeted her health-care plan and the endless nightmares of her husband's scandals drove her deeper into her political bunker. Her liberalism is warped by what you might call a Political Post-Traumatic Stress Syndrome. Reagan spooked people on the left, especially those, like Clinton, who were interested primarily in winning power. She has internalized what most Democrats of her generation have internalized: They suspect that the majority is not with them, and so some quotient of discretion, fear, or plain deception is required if they are to advance their objectives. And so the less-adept ones seem deceptive, and the more-practiced ones, like Clinton, exhibit the plastic-ness and inauthenticity that still plague her candidacy. She's hiding her true feelings. We know it, she knows we know it, and there is no way out of it.

Obama, simply by virtue of when he was born, is free of this defensiveness. Strictly speaking, he is at the tail end of the Boomer generation. But he is not of it.

"Partly because my mother, you know, was smack-dab in the middle of the Baby Boom generation," he told me. "She was only 18 when she had me. So when I think of Baby Boomers, I think of my mother's generation. And you know, I was too young for the formative period of the '60scivil rights, sexual revolution, Vietnam War. Those all sort of passed me by. "

Obama's mother was, in fact, born only five years earlier than Hillary Clinton. He did not politically come of age during the Vietnam era, and he is simply less afraid of the right wing than Clinton is, because he has emerged on the national stage during a period of conservative decadence and decline. And so, for example, he felt much freer than Clinton to say he was prepared to meet and hold talks with hostile world leaders in his first year in office. He has proposed sweeping middle-class tax cuts and opposed drastic reforms of Social Security, without being tarred as a fiscally reckless liberal. (Of course, such accusations are hard to make after the fiscal performance of today's "conservatives.") Even his more conservative positionslike his openness to bombing Pakistan, or his support for merit pay for public-school teachersdo not appear to emerge from a desire or need to credentialize himself with the right. He is among the first Democrats in a generation not to be afraid or ashamed of what they actually believe, which also gives them more freedom to move pragmatically to the right, if necessary. He does not smell, as Clinton does, of political fear.

There are few areas where this Democratic fear is more intense than religion. The crude exploitation of sectarian loyalty and religious zeal by Bush and Rove succeeded in deepening the culture war, to Republican advantage. Again, this played into the divide of the Boomer yearsbetween God-fearing Americans and the peacenik atheist hippies of lore. The Democrats have responded by pretending to a public religiosity that still seems strained. Listening to Hillary Clinton detail her prayer life in public, as she did last spring to a packed house at George Washington University, was at once poignant and repellent. Poignant because her faith may well be genuine; repellent because its Methodist genuineness demands that she not profess it so tackily. But she did. The polls told her to.

Obama, in contrast, opened his soul up in public long before any focus group demanded it. His first book, Dreams From My Father, is a candid, haunting, and supple piece of writing. It was not concocted to solve a political problem (his second, hackneyed book, The Audacity of Hope, filled that niche). It was a genuine display of internal doubt and conflict and sadness. And it reveals Obama as someone whose "complex fate," to use Ralph Ellison's term, is to be both believer and doubter, in a world where such complexity is as beleaguered as it is necessary.

This struggle to embrace modernity without abandoning faith falls on one of the fault lines in the modern world. It is arguably the critical fault line, the tectonic rift that is advancing the bloody borders of Islam and the increasingly sectarian boundaries of American politics. As humankind abandons the secular totalitarianisms of the last century and grapples with breakneck technological and scientific discoveries, the appeal of absolutist faith is powerful in both developing and developed countries. It is the latest in a long line of rebukes to liberal modernitybut this rebuke has the deepest roots, the widest appeal, and the attraction that all total solutions to the human predicament proffer. From the doctrinal absolutism of Pope Benedict's Vatican to the revival of fundamentalist Protestantism in the U.S. and Asia to the attraction for many Muslims of the most extreme and antimodern forms of Islam, the same phenomenon has spread to every culture and place.

You cannot confront the complex challenges of domestic or foreign policy today unless you understand this gulf and its seriousness. You cannot lead the United States without having a foot in both the religious and secular camps. This, surely, is where Bush has failed most profoundly. By aligning himself with the most extreme and basic of religious orientations, he has lost many moderate believers and alienated the secular and agnostic in the West. If you cannot bring the agnostics along in a campaign against religious terrorism, you have a problem.

Here again, Obama, by virtue of generation and accident, bridges this deepening divide. He was brought up in a nonreligious home and converted to Christianity as an adult. Butcriticallyhe is not born-again. His faithat once real and measured, hot and coollives at the center of the American religious experience. It is a modern, intellectual Christianity. "I didn't have an epiphany," he explained to me. "What I really did was to take a set of values and ideals that were first instilled in me from my mother, who was, as I have called her in my book, the last of the secular humanistsyou know, belief in kindness and empathy and discipline, responsibilitythose kinds of values. And I found in the Church a vessel or a repository for those values and a way to connect those values to a larger community and a belief in God and a belief in redemption and mercy and justice  I guess the point is, it continues to be both a spiritual, but also intellectual, journey for me, this issue of faith."

The best speech Obama has ever given was not his famous 2004 convention address, but a June 2007 speech in Connecticut. In it, he described his religious conversion:

One Sunday, I put on one of the few clean jackets I had, and went over to Trinity United Church of Christ on 95th Street on the South Side of Chicago. And I heard Reverend Jeremiah A. Wright deliver a sermon called "The Audacity of Hope." And during the course of that sermon, he introduced me to someone named Jesus Christ. I learned that my sins could be redeemed. I learned that those things I was too weak to accomplish myself, he would accomplish with me if I placed my trust in him. And in time, I came to see faith as more than just a comfort to the weary or a hedge against death, but rather as an active, palpable agent in the world and in my own life.

It was because of these newfound understandings that I was finally able to walk down the aisle of Trinity one day and affirm my Christian faith. It came about as a choice and not an epiphany. I didn't fall out in church, as folks sometimes do. The questions I had didn't magically disappear. The skeptical bent of my mind didn't suddenly vanish. But kneeling beneath that cross on the South Side, I felt I heard God's spirit beckoning me. I submitted myself to his will, and dedicated myself to discovering his truth and carrying out his works.

To be able to express this kind of religious conviction without disturbing or alienating the growing phalanx of secular voters, especially on the left, is quite an achievement. As he said in 2006, "Faith doesn't mean that you don't have doubts." To deploy the rhetoric of Evangelicalism while eschewing its occasional anti-intellectualism and hubristic certainty is as rare as it is exhilarating. It is both an intellectual achievement, because Obama has clearly attempted to wrestle a modern Christianity from the encumbrances and anachronisms of its past, and an American achievement, because it was forged in the only American institution where conservative theology and the Democratic Party still communicate: the black church.

And this, of course, is the other element that makes Obama a potentially transformative candidate: race. Here, Obama again finds himself in the center of a complex fate, unwilling to pick sides in a divide that reaches back centuries and appears at times unbridgeable. His appeal to whites is palpable. I have felt it myself. Earlier this fall, I attended an Obama speech in Washington on tax policy that underwhelmed on delivery; his address was wooden, stilted, even tedious. It was only after I left the hotel that it occurred to me that I'd just been bored on tax policy by a national black leader. That I should have been struck by this was born in my own racial stereotypes, of course. But it won me over.

Obama is deeply aware of how he comes across to whites. In a revealing passage in his first book, he recounts how, in adolescence, he defused his white mother's fears that he was drifting into delinquency. She had marched into his room and demanded to know what was going on. He flashed her "a reassuring smile and patted her hand and told her not to worry." This, he tells us, was "usually an effective tactic," because people

were satisfied as long as you were courteous and smiled and made no sudden moves. They were more than satisfied; they were relievedsuch a pleasant surprise to find a well-mannered young black man who didn't seem angry all the time.

And so you have Obama's campaign for white America: courteous and smiling and with no sudden moves. This may, of course, be one reason for his still-lukewarm support among many African Americans, a large number of whom back a white woman for the presidency. It may also be because African Americans (more than many whites) simply don't believe that a black man can win the presidency, and so are leery of wasting their vote. And the persistence of race as a divisive, even explosive factor in American life was unmissable the week of Obama's tax speech. While he was detailing middle-class tax breaks, thousands of activists were preparing to march in Jena, Louisiana, after a series of crude racial incidents had blown up into a polarizing conflict.

Jesse Jackson voiced puzzlement that Obama was not at the forefront of the march. "If I were a candidate, I'd be all over Jena," he remarked. The South Carolina newspaper The State reported that Jackson said Obama was "acting like he's white." Obama didn't jump into the fray (no sudden moves), but instead issued measured statements on Jena, waiting till a late-September address at Howard University to find his voice. It was simultaneously an endorsement of black identity politics and a distancing from it:

When I'm president, we will no longer accept the false choice between being tough on crime and vigilant in our pursuit of justice. Dr. King said: "It's not either/or, it's both/and." We can have a crime policy that's both tough and smart. If you're convicted of a crime involving drugs, of course you should be punished. But let's not make the punishment for crack cocaine that much more severe than the punishment for powder cocaine when the real difference between the two is the skin color of the people using them. Judges think that's wrong. Republicans think that's wrong, Democrats think that's wrong, and yet it's been approved by Republican and Democratic presidents because no one has been willing to brave the politics and make it right. That will end when I am president.

Obama's racial journey makes this kind of both/and politics something more than a matter of political compromise. The paradox of his candidacy is that, as potentially the first African American president in a country founded on slavery, he has taken pains to downplay the racial catharsis his candidacy implies. He knows race is important, and yet he knows that it turns destructive if it becomes the only important thing. In this he again subverts a Boomer paradigm, of black victimology or black conservatism. He is neither Al Sharpton nor Clarence Thomas; neither Julian Bond nor Colin Powell. Nor is he a post-racial figure like Tiger Woods, insofar as he has spent his life trying to reconnect with a black identity his childhood never gave him. Equally, he cannot be a Jesse Jackson. His white mother brought him up to be someone else.

In Dreams From My Father, Obama tells the story of a man with an almost eerily nonracial childhood, who has to learn what racism is, what his own racial identity is, and even what being black in America is. And so Obama's relationship to the black American experience is as much learned as intuitive. He broke up with a serious early girlfriend in part because she was white. He decided to abandon a post-racial career among the upper-middle classes of the East Coast in order to reengage with the black experience of Chicago's South Side. It was an act of integrationpersonal as well as communalthat called him to the work of community organizing.

This restlessness with where he was, this attempt at personal integration, represents both an affirmation of identity politics and a commitment to carving a unique personal identity out of the race, geography, and class he inherited. It yields an identity born of displacement, not rootedness. And there are times, I confess, when Obama's account of understanding his own racial experience seemed more like that of a gay teen discovering that he lives in two worlds simultaneously than that of a young African American confronting racism for the first time.

And there are also times when Obama's experience feels more like an immigrant story than a black memoir. His autobiography navigates a new and strange world of an American racial legacy that never quite defined him at his core. He therefore speaks to a complicated and mixed identitynot a simple and alienated one. This may hurt him among some African Americans, who may fail to identify with this fellow with an odd name. Black conservatives, like Shelby Steele, fear he is too deferential to the black establishment. Black leftists worry that he is not beholden at all. But there is no reason why African Americans cannot see the logic of Americanism that Obama also represents, a legacy that is ultimately theirs as well. To be black and white, to have belonged to a nonreligious home and a Christian church, to have attended a majority-Muslim school in Indonesia and a black church in urban Chicago, to be more than one thing and sometimes not fully anythingthis is an increasingly common experience for Americans, including many racial minorities. Obama expresses such a conflicted but resilient identity before he even utters a word. And this complexity, with its internal tensions, contradictions, and moods, may increasingly be the main thing all Americans have in common.

None of this, of course, means that Obama will be the president some are dreaming of. His record in high office is sparse; his performances on the campaign trail have been patchy; his chief rival for the nomination, Senator Clinton, has bested him often with her relentless pursuit of the middle ground, her dogged attention to her own failings, and her much-improved speaking skills. At times, she has even managed to appear more inherently likable than the skinny, crabby, and sometimes morose newcomer from Chicago. Clinton's most surprising asset has been the sense of security she instills. Her husbandand the good feelings that nostalgics retain for his presidencyhave buttressed her case. In dangerous times, popular majorities often seek the conservative option, broadly understood.

The paradox is that Hillary makes far more sense if you believe that times are actually pretty good. If you believe that America's current crisis is not a deep one, if you think that pragmatism alone will be enough to navigate a world on the verge of even more religious warfare, if you believe that today's ideological polarization is not dangerous, and that what appears dark today is an illusion fostered by the lingering trauma of the Bush presidency, then the argument for Obama is not that strong. Clinton will do. And a Clinton-Giuliani race could be as invigorating as it is utterly predictable.

But if you sense, as I do, that greater danger lies ahead, and that our divisions and recent history have combined to make the American polity and constitutional order increasingly vulnerable, then the calculus of risk changes. Sometimes, when the world is changing rapidly, the greater risk is caution. Close-up in this election campaign, Obama is unlikely. From a distance, he is necessary. At a time when America's estrangement from the world risks tipping into dangerous imbalance, when a country at war with lethal enemies is also increasingly at war with itself, when humankind's spiritual yearnings veer between an excess of certainty and an inability to believe anything at all, and when sectarian and racial divides seem as intractable as ever, a man who is a bridge between these worlds may be indispensable.

We may in fact have finally found that bridge to the 21st century that Bill Clinton told us about. Its name is Obama.
</quote>

.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-25T05:44:00" id="p60">
<quote orig_author="Albany Rifles">
Tell me why your side of the aisle will excoriate homosexuals then there are stories of "wide stances"?

</quote>

No, I won't, and as easy as it would be to sling this right back at you because it's wrong from the very start about every single word including 'the', the point was, you can't defend what you aid and abet even when you attempt to attack with this weak crap.

Tell me why you're supporting Democrats when Democrats are attempting to lose the war that has enormous consequences for the entire country. Don't ask me irrelevent questions that start from false premises.

<quote>
Tell me why you party speaks of honor and service and then trashes a disabled veteran like Max Clelland.
</quote>

See above, ALL of the above.

<quote>
Tell me why when a Democratic Congress wants to vote for more funds for VA benefits for vedterans you party supports upholding a presidential veto?
</quote>

How long you want to keep this up?

<quote>
Okay, so you have pictures of Howard Dean and Speaker Pelosi.....and I say they represent me how?
</quote>

Democrat majorities in both national legislative bodies happened because you aided it. Ms. Pelosi, as far left as you can dam' well GET, is now SPEAKER OF THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, if you can friggin' believe it, and YOU get partial credit. They head those committees and set agendas and do a hundred other crucial things that should be done by somebody that doesn't have national suicide as a burning deeply-cherished goal.

But you pick and choose the 'good' Democrats that have no issue caucusing with people that are ideological twins and helpmates of those disgusting creatures.

So, where's the line? Do Democrats get a pass from you as long as they've got a DD214, whether they sell us out themselves, or accept money from other people that sell us out, or vote the same way as people that sell us out, or just provide political help and friendly words to people that sell us out? What line do YOUR Democrats draw - you know, the GOOD ones, all them true-blue loyal Americans - that is beyond what YOU find acceptable?

<quote>
You need to show me pictures of Jim Webb, Tim Kaine, John Warner and Bobby Scott to show me the people I have voted for recently.
</quote>

No, I dam' well do NOT. If you think about what a political party is, you'll find that it's a collection of people that believe more-or-less the same things, have a common political philosophy. What I'm trying to get across is that the Democrats are DANGEROUS, and they are in the majority (due in part to YOU), made up with people like the ones you voted for, and are attempting in concert to execute their party's platform.

<quote>
And I can listen to folks like Lindsay Graham and John McCain as well as Chris Shays and agree with a lot of what they have to say.
</quote>

Me, too. And the minute one goes so far wrong as to put his own political fortunes ahead of what's best for the country, I'll get rid of him like a live grenade.

<quote>
I often hear about a supposed "East Coast" bias and a dismissal of folks from the Northeast as being academic snobs. Well, I am none of those...and neither are my friends nor members of my family. I find it amusing and irritating that folks who are from a state which has Nancy Pelosi as a member of its' states Congressional delegation calls into question the patriotism and political views of someone from the East Coast. Don't like your local politics...then move.
</quote>

What the HELL are you talking about? Don't worry, I have never given into the bias that Northeasterners are in any way superior to anybody else. Don't think I will anytime soon, either.

<quote>
So if you disagree with my views....that is fine, (a long paragraph has been redacted so I won't be accused of a Strateypage-like flaming!)
</quote>

Mate, I really do like you. I'm not being snarky, either; I mean it.

But I'm absolutely at a loss to see how the Democrats get any votes from anybody that knows what their party is about, and that love their country. I'm serious; I just can't fathom the mindset that isn't absolutely outraged by a real, serious effort to lose a war. (I've seen it before, and from some of the same people, DEFINITELY the same party.) That this is what's going on is simply undeniable at this point, and that we have lost so many fine Americans needlessly, how much extra money it's cost, and we're not done by now, and it's all at the feet of a party that you lend your support to.

I just don't get that. Why aren't you as furious and scandalized as I am? Why isn't EVERY American? Well, because some are ignorant, and some others despise America. Frequently, it's for BOTH reasons. But it's never because it's neither.

My wife, my only son are both serving military members, and will be going to Iraq in '08, my son in about 70 days. Democrats are quite literally aiding and abetting the people that are trying to kill them, and you're aiding and abetting THEM. Your vote empowers them, and if we lose this war, YOU will have helped. If either my wife or son is killed or injured, YOU will have helped. I may tend to resent that just a bit.

And I'm ANGRY, because this is a perfect example of history repeating itself. Not ancient history, either, but within a single generation, we're going to let the very worst among us cripple our country AGAIN, and YOU, my friend, YOU are able to see it, YOU can comprehend it, YOU can countenance it, and YOU are helping it happen.

And I simply don't understand that.
</post>
<post author="Parihaka" datetime="2007-11-25T05:44:00" id="p61">
Nice find FibrillatorD, a great definition of the political divide in the states whatever anyone may think of Obama.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-25T06:01:00" id="p62">
<quote orig_author="troung">
Republicans do the same, both parties once in power too long become corrupt and get shown the door.

</quote>

I don't like 'em either. But when they stop seeking victory, however prone to mistakes they may be, they lose my support until they earn my respect by being for America's interests again. Democrats, in distinct counterpoise, are actively trying to LOSE THE WAR.

What you don't get and probably never will is that Democrats are actually ANTI-AMERICAN, and have been for at least 40 years. Read what they write; listen to what they say. No enemy can slur the country as viciously as a Democrat in full flight about what's wrong with us, our heritage and history, our culture, people. You don't need examples, either: look in any direction at anytime, and you'll find a Democrat hatin' on America.

By the way, you're as wrong as you can dam' well be re: Afghanistan. The fact is that some metrics SEEM to indicate things are getting worse, such as IED attacks on the rise. But, in a way that proves my point for me, the media (by-and-large liberal and Democratic-leaning) utterly ignores the mass of trends that indicate much progress. By using only carefully selected metrics in a way that only a statistician can to prove a point, it seems like Afghanistan is getting away from us. It's not. In my own area of expertise, man-hunting the HVIs, I can tell you that the job with the worst job security is 'Taleban commander'. They can't so much as do a day trip to Afghanistan anymore without getting Hellfire'd by a Predator or a pack of A-10s.

Villages are giving the Taleban the right-about-turn; women and children are participating in government and schools again; and properity is going up by every measure that independent research evaluates.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-25T06:08:00" id="p63">
<quote orig_author="Julie">
Because Bush succeeded in deflecting America's anger from Osama Bin Laden to Saddam Hussein, and in doing that, was one of the greatest public relations conjuring tricks in history.

You do remember Osama Bin Laden, don't you?

</quote>

Don't take that tone with ME. I'm trying to help kill him; you're trying to help him WIN, but you don't even realize that.

You, of all people, have got a LOT o' dam' gall to try that crap with ME, of all people. You don't have the right to even try that, and I sure as hell don't deserve to have that tried on me.

I cannot even believe you're a mod here.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-11-25T07:30:00" id="p64">
<quote orig_author="Julie">
Because Bush succeeded in deflecting America's anger from Osama Bin Laden to Saddam Hussein, and in doing that, was one of the greatest public relations conjuring tricks in history.

You do remember Osama Bin Laden, don't you?

</quote>

And how often do we hear about either of them today?

Osama has thrown some video tapes and lately audio tapes at us since 9-11.

I am willing to bet that he still wants to hurt us, but for some odd reason he has not been able to in the last 6 years. I wonder where the credit is due?
</post>
<post author="JAD_333" datetime="2007-11-25T07:35:00" id="p65">
<quote orig_author="FibrillatorD">
.

</quote>

<quote>
December 2007 Atlantic Monthly

Is Iraq Vietnam? Who really won in 2000? Which side are you on in the culture wars? These questions have divided the Baby Boomers and distorted our politics. One candidate could transcend them.
</quote>

[/quote]\

Obama as savior? It's tempting to get behind a candidate who is ostensibly about healing. But healing what? Has there ever been a time in this nation's history when a dynamic of opposing political forces hasn't existed? Do we need above all things to let the steam out? That seems to be the author's theme. And of course, if that is the case, he has just the right candidate for the job. I like Obama, but I disagree with him on several key international and domestic issues. Iraq for one. Social Security for another.

The author weaves a complicated, psychological picture of the current American political psyche drawing on abstractions like baby boomers and the Vietnam syndrome. No doubt the human mind is always bombarded by outside influences, and any attempt to grasp how the collective mind affects present events is going to be complicated. But is it really so complicated to see threats to our national security and what we must do to counter them? Isit so complicated to see that the Social Security trust fund is on a course to be drained in 20 or 50 years and to act accordingly? The same goes for all the pressing problems the country has. What we need is a president and a Congress that will get busy doing what has to be done, not a leader whose sole value is to deflate the nation's political tension, which tension has existed since George Washington's time and has driven the country to its greatest achievements. Don't be lulled.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-11-25T07:43:00" id="p66">
<quote orig_author="JAD_333">
Obama as savior? It's tempting to get behind a candidate who is ostensibly about healing. But healing what? Has there ever been a time in this nation's history when a dynamic of opposing political forces hasn't existed? Do we need above all things to let the steam out? That seems to be the author's theme. And of course, if that is the case, he has just the right candidate for the job. I like Obama, but I disagree with him on several key international and domestic issues. Iraq for one. Social Security for another.

The author weaves a complicated, psychological picture of the current American political psyche drawing on abstractions like baby boomers and the Vietnam syndrome. No doubt the human mind is always bombarded by outside influences, and any attempt to grasp how the collective mind affects present events is going to be complicated. But is it really so complicated to see threats to our national security and what we must do to counter them? Isit so complicated to see that the Social Security trust fund is on a course to be drained in 20 or 50 years and to act accordingly? The same goes for all the pressing problems the country has. What we need is a president and a Congress that will get busy doing what has to be done, not a leader whose sole value is to deflate the nation's political tension, which tension has existed since George Washington's time and has driven the country to its greatest achievements. Don't be lulled.

</quote>

Yes, sir, it is.

Liberals truly believe George Bush is a bigger threat to the world than Osama bin Laden and the US is a terrorist state.

Liberals also believe the rich pays no tax and the best way to fix Social Security is to make the rich pay more taxes.

rich = anyone over poverty line
</post>
<post author="JAD_333" datetime="2007-11-25T07:44:00" id="p67">
<quote orig_author="Julie">
Because Bush succeeded in deflecting America's anger from Osama Bin Laden to Saddam Hussein, and in doing that, was one of the greatest public relations conjuring tricks in history.

You do remember Osama Bin Laden, don't you?

</quote>

If this is what you think, I'd expect you to say so, but if it's a fact, I would like to see your proof.

So, you were content with Saddam and angry at OBL until Bush distracted you, and now you're content with OBL and angry at Saddam. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/confused.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="JAD_333" datetime="2007-11-25T07:54:00" id="p68">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
Yes, sir, it is.

</quote>

I hope you realize those were rhetorical questions. I believe when things are broke, we ought to fix 'em.

<quote>
rich = anyone over poverty line
</quote>

So, I've noticed. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-25T07:55:00" id="p69">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
And how often do we hear about either of them today?

Osama has thrown some video tapes and lately audio tapes at us since 9-11.

I am willing to bet that he still wants to hurt us, but for some odd reason he has not been able to in the last 6 years. I wonder where the credit is due?

</quote>

A very well-made point. I want to kill him more than I want to take my next breath. But frustrating him and securing the country from his sickos is purty good, too.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-11-25T07:57:00" id="p70">
<quote orig_author="JAD_333">
I hope you realize those were rhetorical questions.

</quote>

I take rhetorical questions very seriously and answer them to the best of my abilities. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="troung" datetime="2007-11-25T08:41:00" id="p71">
<quote>
Villages are giving the Taleban the right-about-turn; women and children are participating in government and schools again; and properity is going up by every measure that independent research evaluates.
</quote>

Villages didn't like them before hand, they were never terribly popular. But by most accounts they have recovered lost ground and increased their presence across the south.

<quote>
By the way, you're as wrong as you can dam' well be re: Afghanistan. The fact is that some metrics SEEM to indicate things are getting worse, such as IED attacks on the rise. But, in a way that proves my point for me, the media (by-and-large liberal and Democratic-leaning) utterly ignores the mass of trends that indicate much progress. By using only carefully selected metrics in a way that only a statistician can to prove a point, it seems like Afghanistan is getting away from us. It's not. In my own area of expertise, man-hunting the HVIs, I can tell you that the job with the worst job security is 'Taleban commander'. They can't so much as do a day trip to Afghanistan anymore without getting Hellfire'd by a Predator or a pack of A-10s.
</quote>

Afghanistan is barely touched on, and if the media were simply a DNC mouth piece we would hear about 2 badly executed wars.

I'm very happy they have a lot of upward mobility for the lower ranking members, with little job security <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>

But by most accounts they have been pushing up the level of violence, we have the ISAF issues (people in the south are getting stretched, people in the north ain't coming south), and most of our resources were taken off the ball and placed into a different theater. And the Taliban are increasing their presence into other provinces.

Six years into the game they are rebounding and still have the same safe areas from Pakistan.

========
Cool if I PM you in the next day or so?
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-25T09:01:00" id="p72">
ANYtime, amigo.

Come Monday, I'm off the bench and back in the game. But my day will start stoopid early and end really late, because I've got about the worst commute that doesn't involve an altimeter, so my replies may be delayed and brief.

I can't wait; I last worked on 29 June, and I feel like Martin Sheen's character in 'Apocolypse Now', when he was in the hotel in Saigon, waiting for his mission orders:

<quote>
Saigon... sh!t; I'm still only in Saigon... Every time I think I'm gonna wake up back in the jungle. When I was home after my first tour, it was worse. I'd wake up and there'd be nothing. I hardly said a word to my wife, until I said "yes" to a divorce. When I was here, I wanted to be there; when I was there, all I could think of was getting back into the jungle. I'm here a week now... waiting for a mission... getting softer; every minute I stay in this room, I get weaker, and every minute Charlie squats in the bush, he gets stronger. Each time I looked around, the walls moved in a little tighter.
</quote>

<img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/cool.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2007-11-25T12:32:00" id="p73">
I can't believe someone posted an article by Andrew Sullivan. When was the last time that guy was relevant?

-dale
</post>
<post author="FibrillatorD" datetime="2007-11-25T16:04:00" id="p74">
<quote orig_author="JAD_333">
Obama as savior? It's tempting to get behind a candidate who is ostensibly about healing. But healing what? Has there ever been a time in this nation's history when a dynamic of opposing political forces hasn't existed? Do we need above all things to let the steam out? That seems to be the author's theme. And of course, if that is the case, he has just the right candidate for the job. I like Obama, but I disagree with him on several key international and domestic issues. Iraq for one. Social Security for another.

The author weaves a complicated, psychological picture of the current American political psyche drawing on abstractions like baby boomers and the Vietnam syndrome. No doubt the human mind is always bombarded by outside influences, and any attempt to grasp how the collective mind affects present events is going to be complicated. But is it really so complicated to see threats to our national security and what we must do to counter them? Isit so complicated to see that the Social Security trust fund is on a course to be drained in 20 or 50 years and to act accordingly? The same goes for all the pressing problems the country has. What we need is a president and a Congress that will get busy doing what has to be done, not a leader whose sole value is to deflate the nation's political tension, which tension has existed since George Washington's time and has driven the country to its greatest achievements. Don't be lulled.

</quote>

I would love to see our country engage in a real debate about how to solve Iraq and social security and every other problem we have. As it is, every argument dissolves into one that harkens back to the anger of the 70s: Are you pro-America, or are you Communist?

Sullivan can be long-winded and soft on substance, but does anyone doubt that the following is now true of America?

<quote>
It is hard to imagine a reprise of the sudden unity and solidarity in the days after 9/11, or an outpouring of support from allies and neighbors. It is far easier to imagine an even more bitter fight over who was responsible (apart from the perpetrators) and a profound suspicion of a government forced to impose more restrictions on travel, communications, and civil liberties. The current president would be unable to command the trust, let alone the support, of half the country in such a time. He could even be blamed for provoking any attack that came.
</quote>

Does anyone really doubt that we're stuck in the rubric of the 70s? Vietnam and baby boomers aren't hazy abstractions at all. They hold America in a headlock and it makes me sick that 2 generations don't care enough about their country and their kids to NOT pass these feuds on. The sorriest thing of all is that the same people who fought about Vietnam and in the culture wars of the seventies are currently running the country, and want history to view Iraq in the same terms Vietnam was seen. Its so easy and natural for them.

Sorry, I wasn't around during Vietnam. Communism was dead when I became politically-aware, and Obama is one of very few candidates that so far has been immune from the usual election-year scathing. With Obama, for whatever reason, arguments seem to keep a healthy distance from personal attacks. You said yourself you don't like Obama's policies. Fine. You didn't call him a pinko commie traitor scumbag.

So, Bluesman, straight up: Is Barack Obama a pinko commie traitor scumbag?

If you say he is, I won't vote for him.
</post>
<post author="dalem" datetime="2007-11-25T16:23:00" id="p75">
Sullivan is cherry-picking. He and his ilk keep trying to paint this picture of overwhelming support for America, both from within and without, but it's bullsh!t. I remember because it made me furious - less than 24 hours after the murdering pig-b@stards did their work, and already people all over the world, including right here in Apple Pie Land, were mewling about how we deserved it, caused it, invited it, needed to question our motives, and not react.

We shouldn't attack Afghanistan, we will fail if we try, we will perish in the harsh conditions, we have no right to attack the Taliban, blah blah blah.

We had help, support, and allies for sure during and after that day, but it wasn't everyone by a long shot, and there were plenty of other voices too.

The fantasy world that Sullivan is trying to rewrite into history simply didn't exist, so f*ck him for his delusions and f*ck anybody else who believes them.

And Obama? I don't care if he sleeps with a copy of Adam Smith under his pillow every night - he's a political lightweight and a defeatist. He should be tarred and feathered, not voted for.

-dale
</post>
<post author="Julie" datetime="2007-11-25T18:19:00" id="p76">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
Don't take that tone with ME.

</quote>

LOL...what "tone" did I use? If you don't like my answers, do not ask me questions.

<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
I'm trying to help kill him

</quote>

Oh really? You've been patrolling the tribal borders of Pakistan and Afghanistan lately? I didn't realize that. My bad.

<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
I cannot even believe you're a mod here.

</quote>

I've got squatters rights over you....I was here long before you got here. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> If you have a problem with that, take it up with an Admin, not on open forum, since there is a rule to that effect you know. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="JohnFlint1985" datetime="2007-11-25T18:54:00" id="p77">
This thread is a loose cannon. Because patriotism is not measured by party affiliation and the question itself is biased.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-25T19:37:00" id="p78">
<quote orig_author="Julie">
LOL...what "tone" did I use? If you don't like my answers, do not ask me questions.

</quote>

The tone that insinuated that YOU knew all about ObL, but that I did NOT. Do you know what I do, what my professional life is all about?

<quote>
Oh really? You've been patrolling the tribal borders of Pakistan and Afghanistan lately? I didn't realize that. My bad.
</quote>

Your bad; cute. You're disgusting.

Don't you dare attempt to de-value the work I do. YES, as a matter of fact, I actually AM trying to kill him, and YOU, and people that 'think' like you, are attempting to hobble me, to impede me, to frustrate me.

I don't walk through the foothills of Afghanistan; that's the role of others, and I work with 'em every day I go to work. They can't go ANYwhere without the support I provide, from Special Operations Command and Central Command Headquarters in Tampa, from NSA Headquarters in Ft Meade, from a ground station downlinked to the Predators that one will kill him one day from Beale AFB.

That is MY role. I hope very much I will play a part in ObL's death. You have no shot at that, so maybe you'll acknowledge that I can actually claim to be striving to kill him, and you have the sheer gall to say that I don't. You're a real piece of work.

<quote>
I've got squatters rights over you....I was here long before you got here. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> If you have a problem with that, take it up with an Admin, not on open forum, since there is a rule to that effect you know. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>
</quote>

I violated no rule; I was making an observation.

On occasion, you yourself are pretty free with the rules regarding me, too.
</post>
<post author="Julie" datetime="2007-11-26T00:47:00" id="p79">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
The tone that insinuated that YOU knew all about ObL, but that I did NOT.

</quote>

That is being presumptuous, and paranoid, on your part.

<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
Do you know what I do, what my professional life is all about?

</quote>

No, and I don't really care.

<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
You're disgusting.

</quote>

There you go again.

<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
Don't you dare attempt to de-value the work I do. YES, as a matter of fact, I actually AM trying to kill him, and YOU, and people that 'think' like you, are attempting to hobble me, to impede me, to frustrate me.

</quote>

I did no such of a thing, you asked the question, and you lead yourself there. If you have a guilty conscience about something, take responsibility for it, instead of blaming everyone else.

<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
I don't walk through the foothills of Afghanistan; that's the role of others, and I work with 'em every day I go to work. They can't go ANYwhere without the support I provide, from Special Operations Command and Central Command Headquarters in Tampa, from NSA Headquarters in Ft Meade, from a ground station downlinked to the Predators that one will kill him one day from Beale AFB.

That is MY role. I hope very much I will play a part in ObL's death..

</quote>

Meaning, YOU are the reason he hasn't been found and killed yet?

<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
You have no shot at that, so maybe you'll acknowledge that I can actually claim to be striving to kill him, and you have the sheer gall to say that I don't. You're a real piece of work.

</quote>

That's what my taxpayer dollars are paying you to do supposedly. Maybe we should "outsource" that as well, and see if it works a little better.

<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
I violated no rule; I was making an observation.

</quote>

You violate a rule everytime you criticize a Mod, in any way, in open forum, which are occurring more frequently lately, and I am getting very tired of being called an idiot, and disgusting, by you, in open forum.

<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
On occasion, you yourself are pretty free with the rules regarding me, too.

</quote>

I think I've been very patient, but patience do turn thin after awhile.

Not that you've ever paid heed to anything I've ever said, but I strongly advise you to govern yourself accordingly, since I'm really NOT in the "patient" mood today, with all that has been going on today on this board.

I approve this message. Julie
</post>
<post author="FarSide" datetime="2007-11-26T01:07:00" id="p80">
While I am not a Democrat, nor can I even register as one now, I would suppose I would call myself Democrat if I was forced to choose. But I would do so with great reluctance.

Bluesman, while I respect the work you do and one day hope do be doing the same, I must express my wholehearted disagreement with most of your politics. I realize I'm extremely new here but I have been lurking for awhile and it was quite hard not to stumble on your many rather, outspoken, posts.

The first thing I would take issue with is your extreme hatred and bitterness towards any and all democrats with whom you are not acquainted. I am a patriot, I love my country more than anything, but I would identify with Democrats more than Republicans. But you seem to draw the conclusion that all Democrats support the likes of Pelosi and Code Pink. Personally I think that they're both disgusting and I dislike them. I am and was for the war in Afghanistan, that was a war worth fighting. However, the war in Iraq was idiotic, mis-guided and unjustifiable. Saddam was of no threat to us anymore and while he was a horrible ruler he was stable and kept Iran in check. Now that Iraq has been rendered a non-entity in the political stage of the Middle East, Iran has taken the chance to seize power and make a move. We all know how thats playing out.

I guess my point is that I qualify for your patriotic Democrat.

What you have to realize, Bluesman, is that the actual number of hardliners is very small, they just happen to be more outspoken.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T02:11:00" id="p81">
<quote orig_author="FarSide">
While I am not a Democrat, nor can I even register as one now, I would suppose I would call myself Democrat if I was forced to choose. But I would do so with great reluctance.

Bluesman, while I respect the work you do and one day hope do be doing the same, I must express my wholehearted disagreement with most of your politics. I realize I'm extremely new here but I have been lurking for awhile and it was quite hard not to stumble on your many rather, outspoken, posts.

The first thing I would take issue with is your extreme hatred and bitterness towards any and all democrats with whom you are not acquainted.

</quote>

What I hate and am bitter about is the disregard for what they do as a party. You're a Democrat? WHY? <a href="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/war-iraq/39708-democrats-what-most-politically-advantageous-number-dead-us-troops-60.html#post430927">Explain your acceptance of this.</a>

<quote>
I am a patriot, I love my country more than anything, but I would identify with Democrats more than Republicans.
</quote>

Well, you remember how much you love your country when you meet down at the rally with people that run the gamut from you right down the scale to the scum that carry signs at the anti-war rally: 'We support our troops when they kill their officers.'

<quote>
But you seem to draw the conclusion that all Democrats support the likes of Pelosi and Code Pink. Personally I think that they're both disgusting and I dislike them. I am and was for the war in Afghanistan, that was a war worth fighting. However, the war in Iraq was idiotic, mis-guided and unjustifiable. Saddam was of no threat to us anymore and while he was a horrible ruler he was stable and kept Iran in check. Now that Iraq has been rendered a non-entity in the political stage of the Middle East, Iran has taken the chance to seize power and make a move. We all know how thats playing out.
</quote>

Do you know how the system even works? Are you aware that when you help elect a Democrat to Congress, you ensure that Pelosi, whom neither of us like apparently, will become Speaker of the House of Representatives of the United States of America, instead of being just another harridan from the deepest-blue nest of anti-American vipers from a place that doesn't end in 'stan'.

YOU make that happen; YOU need to accept the responsibility for prolonging the war and ensuring that it cost more than it should in money, time, and blood.

<quote>
I guess my point is that I qualify for your patriotic Democrat.
</quote>

Choose one of those two words; you can't be both.

<quote>
What you have to realize, Bluesman, is that the actual number of hardliners is very small, they just happen to be more outspoken.
</quote>

And what YOU have to realize is that by voting Democrat, you made Pelosi and Reid into something a REAL loyal American is horrified at, and that a Democrat will be in charge of every single committee in Congress, because YOU HELPED 'EM DO IT.

How can you be proud of THAT?
</post>
<post author="FarSide" datetime="2007-11-26T02:36:00" id="p82">
<quote>
What I hate and am bitter about is the disregard for what they do as a party. You're a Democrat? WHY? Explain your acceptance of this.
</quote>

I do not accept it. I think that people who use the deaths of troops as political fodder are the worst kind of scum. Just because I most identify with Democrats does not mean I universally support them. In fact, my identifying with Democrats is more of a lesser of two evils thing than actually supporting them of choice. I've said it before and I'll say it again, I'm not a Republican or Democrat, but I am an American.

<quote>
Well, you remember how much you love your country when you meet down at the rally with people that run the gamut from you right down the scale to the scum that carry signs at the anti-war rally: 'We support our troops when they kill their officers.'
</quote>

I don't rally and I certainly don't support those who support troops fragging their officers. After all, I hope to be an officer one day so it'd be rather foolish and stupid do support such a thing.

<quote>
Do you know how the system even works? Are you aware that when you help elect a Democrat to Congress, you ensure that Pelosi, whom neither of us like apparently, will become Speaker of the House of Representatives of the United States of America, instead of being just another harridan from the deepest-blue nest of anti-American vipers from a place that doesn't end in 'stan'.

YOU make that happen; YOU need to accept the responsibility for prolonging the war and ensuring that it cost more than it should in money, time, and blood.
</quote>

Well, this is kind of a moot point since I cannot vote anyway (16) but as I said before; its not that I support the Democrats its more that I view them as the lesser of two evils. Pelosi, however is indefensible, I cannot stand her.

<quote>
Choose one of those two words; you can't be both.
</quote>

I did not realize that was impossible. However, as stated before I am not a Democrat but I would identify with them more. For the purposes of this discussion I will refer to myself as a Democrat. Does some arbitrary definition make anyone less of a patriot? Registration does not make someone Anti-American or a traitor, actions and politics make them so. A Democrat is no more automatically a traitor than a Republican is. To say as such is a dangerous and downright foolish thing to do.

<quote>
And what YOU have to realize is that by voting Democrat, you made Pelosi and Reid into something a REAL loyal American is horrified at, and that a Democrat will be in charge of every single committee in Congress, because YOU HELPED 'EM DO IT.

How can you be proud of THAT?
</quote>

I'm not proud of calling myself a Democrat, both parties make me sick and are equally unqualified to run the country. Its a sad state of affairs that one has to choose between the lesser of two evils when electing people to very important positions in the most powerful nation in the world, but thats how it is. Although, this point is, again moot because I'm too young to vote.

Politics is as dirty as business as being muscle for the mob, but less respectable.
</post>
<post author="Shuttlecat" datetime="2007-11-26T03:03:00" id="p83">
I think I'll pick all three, because Democrats aren't the spawn of Satan the last time I checked.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T03:07:00" id="p84">
<quote orig_author="FarSide">
Pelosi, however is indefensible, I cannot stand her.

</quote>

But when you CAN vote in two years, a vote for a Democrat is a vote for Pelosi and Reid as majority Leaders. That's a Bad Thing to anybody that wants America to win her wars.

<quote>
I did not realize that was impossible. However, as stated before I am not a Democrat but I would identify with them more. For the purposes of this discussion I will refer to myself as a Democrat. Does some arbitrary definition make anyone less of a patriot? Registration does not make someone Anti-American or a traitor, actions and politics make them so. A Democrat is no more automatically a traitor than a Republican is. To say as such is a dangerous and downright foolish thing to do.
</quote>

Ordinarily, I'd agree with you. I'm not investing the GOP with any special virtue, and I'm not saying you'll go to hell if you don't vote this or that way. But will say that a vote for a Democrat is a vote for defeat. I'll not get into why I'm against everything else they believe, because intelligent people of good will may disagree about policy matters. You be a Democrat in outlook on every other matter, and I'll respect it if you've taken an objective look at the alternative points-of-view.

<quote>
I'm not proud of calling myself a Democrat, both parties make me sick and are equally unqualified to run the country. Its a sad state of affairs that one has to choose between the lesser of two evils when electing people to very important positions in the most powerful nation in the world, but thats how it is. Although, this point is, again moot because I'm too young to vote.
</quote>

Two years pass in the blink of your parents' eye, young friend. And there are ample reasons to be cynical, sure. But as long as we've got TWO pro-American parties (we only have one at the moment), we've got the best system for providing security and prosperity to the most people. Stay with it, and do the best you can to support it. With all our faults, she's worth our support and love.

<quote>
Politics is as dirty as business as being muscle for the mob, but less respectable.
</quote>

It CAN be, certainly. But sometimes, every once in awhile, a true public servant comes along, dedicated to his duty. The trick is recognizing the REAL one, and the one that just wants to fool you into thinking he's the one.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T03:08:00" id="p85">
<quote orig_author="Shuttlecat">
I think I'll pick all three, because Democrats aren't the spawn of Satan the last time I checked.

</quote>

They're expressly dedicated to defeat, the last time I checked.

TWO.
</post>
<post author="Shuttlecat" datetime="2007-11-26T03:10:00" id="p86">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
They're expressly dedicated to defeat, the last time I checked.

TWO.

</quote>

And the last time I checked, you're still paranoid about a Democratic government.

And by the way, are you a mod?
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T03:12:00" id="p87">
<quote orig_author="Shuttlecat">
And the last time I checked, you're still paranoid about a Democratic government.

And by the way, are you a mod?

</quote>

I'm neither paranoid, nor a mod.
</post>
<post author="Shuttlecat" datetime="2007-11-26T03:13:00" id="p88">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
...nor a mod.

</quote>

Then stop threatening me.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T03:19:00" id="p89">
<quote orig_author="Shuttlecat">
Then stop threatening me.

</quote>

You haven't been threatened, pwecious. How did you come to THAT?
</post>
<post author="brokensickle" datetime="2007-11-26T03:21:00" id="p90">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
If a Democrat is well-informed, then he/she can see what's become of that moral sewer of a party. If that person can then still BE a Democrat, then, yeah, they're my enemy.

If a person is patriotic and loves the United States, but is ignorant of the fact that they can lend their support to a party that isn't, then, yeah, they're my enemy.

Here's my position: you simply canNOT support what they do when you know the details, and still say your objective is the best outcome for the country. Either you're deluded about what the party now advocates and stands for and what they are trying to do, OR you're of the mind that America is what's wrong with the world, and that you believe we're the horrible place that the Left says we are and always have been. You fear American power and primacy in the world, and believe that we're not the benign force for good that we are, and that we're no different from any other dominant hegemon throughout mankind's history.

Did anybody see the Colbert Report last night? I NEVER watch that drivel, but on the way past, I paused long enough to hear that tomorrow, we'll be celebrating genocide and racism and conquest. This is the view of the Left, and the Democrats are the Party of the Left. You see what they think of their country, their military, their government, their heritage, their history and their fellow citizens everytime they open their mouths, or put pen to paper. They despise this country, its history, people, culture...EVERYthing about it.

Am I the only one that sees this? Do you not notice that a Democrat seeks to emulate an effete, effeminate, emasculated, ennervated Europe, that he/she wishes that we would comply with World Courts and United Nations and the lowest common denominator of 'world opinion' in matters that are properly within our national sovreignty? Does a Democrat believe in American exceptionalism, or does he believe in American culpability in every manner of crime, both at home and abroad?

When you see the term 'Amerika', or 'Amerikkka', or the 'United States' with the esses made into lightning bolt runes, it'll be a Democratic party supporter that wrote it. When you see the country disparaged as evil, a Democrat said it. When I pointed out the absurdity of a John Kerry political career in the GOP after his testimony before Congress in '73, nobody seemed to really understand what I meant. But the point is, to do as he and his ilk do and be anything BUT a Democrat is laughable. And to FAIL to do that as a Democrat is laughable, as well; it's the must-have blocks you have to check on your resume' to be accepted.

Who will it be that will go overseas, sometimes into an adversary country, and get themselves plastered all over their state-run propaganda organs with admissions of American perfidy, wrongdoing and failure? It will ALWAYS be a Democrat.

If the military is maligned and accused of exactly the same things our enemies - OUR ENEMIES! - accuse them of, which party does the speaker/writer identify with?

I could go on, and I'm so dam' bitter about having lived through the horror show that the Democrats made out of the 'Seventies, and to which they look back with fond nostalgia on the time when they were ascendant and did such immense damage to the country, and to which they fervently seek to return, but I'll let you answer if you're of a mind to.

Pick any two, but friend, if you're asking me to believe that you're all three, NO SALE. Democrats are either anti-American on purpose (in which case they're not patriotic), or by accident (because they're not up-to-speed on what the party does, and how, and why). But Democrats simply cannot do what they do and say that they're about doing the best they can in good faith for the country.

Last point: if you'd like for me to return to posting the Daily Democratic War-Losing Measure again, I certainly could, because there's no shortage of material to work with. Each and every day, a Democrat can be counted on to do something against the interests of the country, and NO, I'm not perpared to believe that it's merely a difference of opinion, that somehow, if I looked at it in a different perspective, I'd see that, by golly, they WERE trying to do a Good Thing for the good ole US of A, and I'm just too right-wing-reactionary to understand it. So what do you say: would you care for me to tell you what the Democrats did today to screw the country over? Tomorrow? The day after, and on and on and on? Because this is as certain as my loathing for them: they won't let me down. There will be SOMEthing to point out, and after awhile, don't you, as an American, think that MAYBE you've pledged your support to people that simply don't want America to succeed?

So, do you consider yourself to be patriotic, well-informed, or supportive of Democratic Party objectives and points-of-view? If you pick either or both of the first two, you can't choose the third, because they're just not compatible.

</quote>

Blue's I'm in agreement. If I were to pick a couple of reasoned democrats I would pick a Zell Miller, Joseph Liberman ticket. But they are too right-wing, patriotic and hawkish for the Dem's.

It seems the democrat voting blocks don't trust their own personal observations and just believe lock-step whatever the radical left spews out.
The democrat voting blocks like lemmings by virtue of remaining uninformed and will run over the cliff of that the left is preparing for this country. And why is the left destroying our image, sovereignty and constitution? Answer, you have to break it before recreating it into a dismal leftist community.

They will understand the problem when, and only when there freedoms have been usurped by the left. Enter the world of Hugo Chavez where opposing views are not tolerated.

"Evil opposes freedom and uses those who pervert it as pawns to destroy it."

~~~IVAN~~~~&gt;&lt;//&gt;~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
</post>
<post author="Shuttlecat" datetime="2007-11-26T03:30:00" id="p91">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
You haven't been threatened, pwecious. How did you come to THAT?

</quote>

"TWO" as in strike two before you bring in the supposed dragons. And, of course,

<quote>
If this sort of thang gets going, we'll have problems up in here.
</quote>

from
<a href="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/current-affairs/41378-detroit-most-dangerous-us-city-4.html#post430975">http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/cur...tml#post430975</a>

Don't even try to tell me those aren't threats to bring down some superior force.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T03:33:00" id="p92">
Look, I'm not against an opposing view, even an opposing policy, as long as it's not actually opposing the country. There are LOTS of things that I believe would be bad for America, should the Democrats get their way on this or that issue. But NOTHING is as crucial as matters of victory or defeat in war.

It's as if Democrats believe that the battlefield is an extension of the domestic political sphere. Well, it should not be, and politics should stop at the waters' edge. If there is an objection to strategy or leadership or ANY other question about the conduct of war operations, it is perfectly legitimate to question it, even to change it through the political process over the objection of the Commander-in-Chief. But what's absolutely out-of-bounds is any discussion of whether we should seek defeat, so that the opposition party can capitalize on the nation's defeat politically.

You want to discuss the Administration's screw-ups (and there's plenty to fight about in this arena), or whether we need more this-or-that, or whether our tactics and strategy is sound is absolutely within the purview of the Democrats.

Deciding we should be defeated by terrorists so that they can hang a defeat around Bush's neck and they can benefit is NOT legitimate.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T03:35:00" id="p93">
<quote orig_author="Shuttlecat">
"TWO" as in strike two before you bring in the supposed dragons. And, of course,

from
<a href="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/current-affairs/41378-detroit-most-dangerous-us-city-4.html#post430975">http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/cur...tml#post430975</a>

Don't even try to tell me those aren't threats to bring down some superior force.

</quote>

Well, I WILL tell you that, because you mis-read what I wrote. try to follow this:

You said you were going to pick all three traits. I said 'TWO', as in that's all that I have been insisting that's possible in any one package.

Not two strikes.. You're wrong; you haven't been threatened, Gidget.
</post>
<post author="Shuttlecat" datetime="2007-11-26T03:36:00" id="p94">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
Look, I'm not against an opposing view

</quote>

I advise you to read some of your own anti-Democrat posts.

And one last question. When Hilary or Obama gets elected, are you planning on leaving the country (if you haven't already)?
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T03:38:00" id="p95">
And also notice that I was about as gentle as I'm ever inclined to be when you mis-quoted me in the other thread.

And in the spirit of reconciliation, we can start over if you'd like. Deal?

Oh, and what I meant with 'we'll have problems' is that the WAB will have problems with mis-understandings, not that WE - me and you - were about to throw down, or something. You got me now?
</post>
<post author="FarSide" datetime="2007-11-26T03:39:00" id="p96">
<quote>
But when you CAN vote in two years, a vote for a Democrat is a vote for Pelosi and Reid as majority Leaders. That's a Bad Thing to anybody that wants America to win her wars.
</quote>

I realize that if I were to vote Democrat I would be indirectly lending support to Pelosi but that doesn't mean I'd never vote for a Democrat, despite the obvious down side. Th way I see it, you'll almost never find a true candidate who you'll agree with on every issue but you vote for them because you most agree with him, even though you know that you're also supporting a stance you don't agree with. When I vote, I might vote Democrat because I agree with them despite the obvious downside of Pelosi. (Although, I'm holding out hope for her to go away somehow before that becomes a present decision.) I'd never vote a party line, doing as such undermines America in the worst way. I'd vote for Castor and I'd vote for Young, regardless of party.

<quote>
Ordinarily, I'd agree with you. I'm not investing the GOP with any special virtue, and I'm not saying you'll go to hell if you don't vote this or that way. But will say that a vote for a Democrat is a vote for defeat. I'll not get into why I'm against everything else they believe, because intelligent people of good will may disagree about policy matters. You be a Democrat in outlook on every other matter, and I'll respect it if you've taken an objective look at the alternative points-of-view.
</quote>

But how can you say that? There are Democrats who support the war and there are Republicans who don't. I happen to not believe in the war in Iraq and I would like for us not to be there but an immediate pull out is out of the question and I am hopeful that Petraeus will help calm the situation down and bring order to Iraq. That doesn't mean I wouldn't vote for a Democrat.

The trouble with this is that I'm not a Democrat on most issues. I'm anti-abortion, very pro-gun, anti-war in Iraq, pro-Afghanistan, anti-Illegal Immigration and pro legal immigration. That does not fit any cookie cutter political stance which is why I'm so against parties in general.

<quote>
Two years pass in the blink of your parents' eye, young friend. And there are ample reasons to be cynical, sure. But as long as we've got TWO pro-American parties (we only have one at the moment), we've got the best system for providing security and prosperity to the most people. Stay with it, and do the best you can to support it. With all our faults, she's worth our support and love.
</quote>

Of course, our government has the best design in the world but its in the application wherein she's lacking. Although she is still the best, despite her faults. And of course I'll support her and stay with it, the only way a system like ours works is with the free exchange of ideas, which is why I plan to be here for a long time.

<quote>
It CAN be, certainly. But sometimes, every once in awhile, a true public servant comes along, dedicated to his duty. The trick is recognizing the REAL one, and the one that just wants to fool you into thinking he's the one.
</quote>

Yes, of course. Not all politicians are the scum some are but there are a great many out there, unfortunately. On the subject, I believe John McCain to be probably the only respectable candidate for President, I often don't agree with him but I do like him.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T03:39:00" id="p97">
<quote orig_author="Shuttlecat">
I advise you to read some of your own anti-Democrat posts.

And one last question. When Hilary or Obama gets elected, are you planning on leaving the country (if you haven't already)?

</quote>

Certainly not; the opposition will need every voice we can get, if we plan to save the country. Are you planning on surrendering to terrorists immediately?
</post>
<post author="Shuttlecat" datetime="2007-11-26T03:40:00" id="p98">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
Well, I WILL tell you that, because you mis-read what I wrote. try to follow this:

You said you were going to pick all three traits. I said 'TWO', as in that's all that I have been insisting that's possible in any one package.

Not two strikes.. You're wrong; you haven't been threatened, Gidget.

</quote>

Then the other thread still stands. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Shuttlecat" datetime="2007-11-26T03:44:00" id="p99">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
Certainly not; the opposition will need every voice we can get, if we plan to save the country. Are you planning on surrendering to terrorists immediately?

</quote>

No, but I do plan on voting for a Democrat.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T03:46:00" id="p100">
<quote orig_author="FarSide">
I realize that if I were to vote Democrat I would be indirectly lending support to Pelosi but that doesn't mean I'd never vote for a Democrat, despite the obvious down side. Th way I see it, you'll almost never find a true candidate who you'll agree with on every issue but you vote for them because you most agree with him, even though you know that you're also supporting a stance you don't agree with. When I vote, I might vote Democrat because I agree with them despite the obvious downside of Pelosi. (Although, I'm holding out hope for her to go away somehow before that becomes a present decision.) I'd never vote a party line, doing as such undermines America in the worst way. I'd vote for Castor and I'd vote for Young, regardless of party.

But how can you say that? There are Democrats who support the war and there are Republicans who don't. I happen to not believe in the war in Iraq and I would like for us not to be there but an immediate pull out is out of the question and I am hopeful that Petraeus will help calm the situation down and bring order to Iraq. That doesn't mean I wouldn't vote for a Democrat.

The trouble with this is that I'm not a Democrat on most issues. I'm anti-abortion, very pro-gun, anti-war in Iraq, pro-Afghanistan, anti-Illegal Immigration and pro legal immigration. That does not fit any cookie cutter political stance which is why I'm so against parties in general.

Of course, our government has the best design in the world but its in the application wherein she's lacking. Although she is still the best, despite her faults. And of course I'll support her and stay with it, the only way a system like ours works is with the free exchange of ideas, which is why I plan to be here for a long time.

Yes, of course. Not all politicians are the scum some are but there are a great many out there, unfortunately. On the subject, I believe John McCain to be probably the only respectable candidate for President, I often don't agree with him but I do like him.

</quote>

REALLY good stuff, there. I've got to rack out, and I've wasted almost the entire day on here, so I won't go any farther.

But I enjoyed your posts.

Now, then...I'm goin' back to my li'l piece of the War tomorrow, for the first time since I left off on 29 June. Can't wait to get off the bench and back in the game...

But I'll look for your posts. You're pretty interesting, dude.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T03:46:00" id="p101">
<quote orig_author="Shuttlecat">
No, but I do plan on voting for a Democrat.

</quote>

Purty close to the same thang.
</post>
<post author="Shuttlecat" datetime="2007-11-26T03:49:00" id="p102">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
And also notice that I was about as gentle as I'm ever inclined to be when you mis-quoted me in the other thread.

</quote>

You never did explain to me what those "dragons" were.
</post>
<post author="FarSide" datetime="2007-11-26T04:01:00" id="p103">
<quote>
REALLY good stuff, there. I've got to rack out, and I've wasted almost the entire day on here, so I won't go any farther.

But I enjoyed your posts.

Now, then...I'm goin' back to my li'l piece of the War tomorrow, for the first time since I left off on 29 June. Can't wait to get off the bench and back in the game...

But I'll look for your posts. You're pretty interesting, dude.
</quote>

Thank you, I've also enjoyed debating with you. This is what the free exchange is ideas is about, we both displayed our stances in a well-reasoned way without name calling or petty quibbling.

Were you on leave? Well, if you're going back good luck and God Bless.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T04:04:00" id="p104">
<quote orig_author="Shuttlecat">
You never did explain to me what those "dragons" were.

</quote>

I just meant that we don't want to go there, kinda like old maps that didn't portray what was waaaay over there by the edge were marked 'Here there be Dragons', in a warning to the mariners that hadn't sailed off their maps before.

See? I just write in a way that only dalem and TopHatter and Confed understand. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T04:04:00" id="p105">
<quote orig_author="FarSide">
Thank you, I've also enjoyed debating with you. This is what the free exchange is ideas is about, we both displayed our stances in a well-reasoned way without name calling or petty quibbling.

Were you on leave? Well, if you're going back good luck and God Bless.

</quote>

Yeah, well, you're just an idiot.
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2007-11-26T04:06:00" id="p106">
KIDDING! Just kiddin'.

ANYhoo, I had to leave my job at CENTCOM when my wife (an Air Force nurse) got orders to Travis AFB. So, I got hired on as an intelligence analyst again, but this time, as an Air Force civvie.
</post>
<post author="Shuttlecat" datetime="2007-11-26T04:13:00" id="p107">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
Purty close to the same thang.

</quote>

Really? How so? In what way do they resemble terrorists? Do they really gave the same goals to destroy America? I bet those scumbags have secret meetings in which they discuss how best to undermine the American government and people.
</post>
<post author="brokensickle" datetime="2007-11-26T04:13:00" id="p108">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
KIDDING! Just kiddin'.

ANYhoo, I had to leave my job at CENTCOM when my wife (an Air Force nurse) got orders to Travis AFB. So, I got hired on as an intelligence analyst again, but this time, as an Air Force civvie.

</quote>

zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz
zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz
zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz
zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz
zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz
zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz

These zee's 4U

Yawwwwwn.

ivan
</post>
<post author="Feanor" datetime="2007-11-26T05:03:00" id="p109">
<quote orig_author="Shuttlecat">
I bet those scumbags have secret meetings in which they discuss how best to undermine the American government and people.

</quote>

Really? Are there any democrats on these forums? I would like to sit in on one of your meetings. I know I can't vote to help <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/frown.gif"/>...... but maybe I can at least show some support? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/eek.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> ) <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="TopHatter" datetime="2007-11-26T18:29:00" id="p110">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
Yeah, well, you're just an idiot.

</quote>

<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
KIDDING! Just kiddin'.

</quote>

I know, you're kidding. But we gotta stop with the name calling. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>

For one thing I know that you are capable of some astonishingly eloquent discourses on a regular basis. Why resort to name-calling? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/confused.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="JAD_333" datetime="2007-11-26T21:02:00" id="p111">
<quote orig_author="FibrillatorD">
I would love to see our country engage in a real debate about how to solve Iraq and social security and every other problem we have. As it is, every argument dissolves into one that harkens back to the anger of the 70s: Are you pro-America, or are you Communist?

</quote>

We've been debating both topics a long time. But what is the point of debate when the goal of one party isn't to find the right solution, but to make political hay at the polls by carping on the negatives?

<quote>
Sullivan can be long-winded and soft on substance, but does anyone doubt that the following is now true of America?

<quote>
It is hard to imagine a reprise of the sudden unity and solidarity in the days after 9/11, or an outpouring of support from allies and neighbors. It is far easier to imagine an even more bitter fight over who was responsible (apart from the perpetrators) and a profound suspicion of a government forced to impose more restrictions on travel, communications, and civil liberties. The current president would be unable to command the trust, let alone the support, of half the country in such a time. He could even be blamed for provoking any attack that came.
</quote>

</quote>

That template in one or more of its aspects would fit neatly over any number of periods in which we have been engaged in war. It doesn't even come close in one period of war: the Civil War. Restictions on civil liberties are sometimes necessary. We don't want to provide our enemies with shields to undermine us. Still, I take your point, if you mean restrictions must be adopted legally and done away with when the danger has passed.

<quote>
Does anyone really doubt that we're stuck in the rubric of the 70s?
</quote>

No, I don't. I saw the antiwar demonstrations firsthand: 400,000 parading in DC, the Weather Underground and SDS trying to goad them into a riot. The people gathered twice in DC on the mall. I saw the buses surrounding the White House as a barrier in case of riot. I remember Kent State. I was in Chicago during the 1968 riots at the dem convention, smelled the tear gas, helped injured demonstrators...what I see today, is a congenital opposition going through the motions and a dem party turning a generally restrained military operation into a political bonanza.

<quote>
Vietnam and baby boomers aren't hazy abstractions at all.
</quote>

They are just groups defined by accident of birth whose "members" are all over the spectrum in points of view. Those who really remember Vietnam don't want to go down that path again and many of them don't want to quit another war.

<quote>
They hold America in a headlock and it makes me sick that 2 generations don't care enough about their country and their kids to NOT pass these feuds on.
</quote>

I don't get your meaning. Maybe the new generations have their own feuds now.

<quote>
The sorriest thing of all is that the same people who fought about Vietnam and in the culture wars of the seventies are currently running the country, and want history to view Iraq in the same terms Vietnam was seen. Its so easy and natural for them.
</quote>

Well, that's good. They have the benefit of experience. Maybe they learned something from it.

<quote>
Sorry, I wasn't around during Vietnam.
</quote>

We were lied to, but worse of all, we fought trying to win the next hamlet, but not the war. What a sickening waste...more than 50K troops died there. Is it any wonder that we who saw that, don't want a repeat?

<quote>
Communism was dead when I became politically-aware.
</quote>

You are condemned to learn from books. It will take you longer to grasp what it was than it did those who lived through it. But you seem to be off to a good start.

<quote>
...Obama is one of very few candidates that so far has been immune from the usual election-year scathing. With Obama, for whatever reason, arguments seem to keep a healthy distance from personal attacks. You said yourself you don't like Obama's policies. Fine. You didn't call him a pinko commie traitor scumbag.
</quote>

He's not a commie. He's an honest intellectual with a talent for a well-rounded phrase and a nice speaking voice. But if you think he's a world leader, think twice. I am not saying he can't be; I just saying there's no don't see any solid evidence of it yet. A good speech does not signify a good leader.

<quote>
So, Bluesman, straight up: Is Barack Obama a pinko commie traitor scumbag?

If you say he is, I won't vote for him
</quote>

.

Blues must be honored to control your vote. You are generous. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="Shamus" datetime="2007-11-26T21:40:00" id="p112">
<quote orig_author="Bluesman">
I just write in a way that only dalem and TopHatter and Confed understand. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )

</quote>

I occasionally have epiphanies reading your posts when the haze that permeates what's left of my grey matter clears for a few precious moments allowing me some cognitive reasoning ability <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>.
</post>
<post author="ExNavyAmerican" datetime="2008-01-05T05:20:00" id="p113">
1. Joe Lieberman

2. John Murhtha <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )
</post>
<post author="Bluesman" datetime="2008-01-06T23:12:00" id="p114">
<quote orig_author="ExNavyAmerican">
1. Joe Lieberman

2. John Murhtha <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/> )

</quote>

No, you didn't understand me. I didn't mean for you to pick two examples of those three characteristics. (And I see you, like me, couldn't do it, because NObody could).

No, I meant to pick two out of the three characteristics, because you can't have all three at once.
</post>
<post author="Ironduke" datetime="2008-02-11T07:54:00" id="p115">
Astralis and Lieberman? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/wink.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Parihaka" datetime="2008-02-11T09:33:00" id="p116">
<quote orig_author="Shamus">
I occasionally have epiphanies reading your posts.

</quote>

You can get pills for that.
</post>
<post author="astralis" datetime="2008-02-12T03:18:00" id="p117">
ironduke,

sorry, i'm not a registered dem <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>

gunnut would be a better choice. <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/> <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
</doc>
