<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-170-181118-15958450">
<headline>
U.S. Soldier Accused of Afghan Massacre Begins Building Defense
</headline>
<post author="eots" datetime="2012-03-20T16:44:00" id="p1">
this poor bastards is a victim..4 deployments...twice wounded..head injury..put on ant-psychotic drugs,known to cause such reactions as psychosis and violent behavior...he should be allowed to return to his wife and children and given help to heal...he is not the one that should hang for this..god bless him and his family

<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Fo95pfscdQ">U.S. Soldier Accused of Afghan Massacre Begins Building Defense - YouTube</a>
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Fo95pfscdQ"> U.S. Soldier Accused of Afghan Massacre Begins Building Defense - YouTube</a>
</post>
<post author="eots" datetime="2012-03-20T17:00:00" id="p2">
Tuesday, February 15, 2011
For some military troops, psychiatric drug cocktails have deadly effects

From The NY Times:

In his last months alive, Senior Airman Anthony Mena (pictured) rarely left home without a backpack filled with medications.

He returned from his second deployment to Iraq complaining of back pain, insomnia, anxiety and nightmares. Doctors diagnosed post-traumatic stress disorder and prescribed powerful cocktails of psychiatric drugs and narcotics.

Yet his pain only deepened, as did his depression. “I have almost given up hope,” he told a doctor in 2008, medical records show. “I should have died in Iraq.”

<a href="http://media-dis-n-dat.blogspot.ca/2011/02/fro-some-military-troops-psychiatric.html">Media dis&amp;dat: For some military troops, psychiatric drug cocktails have deadly effects</a>
</post>
<post author="RetiredGySgt" datetime="2012-03-20T17:02:00" id="p3">
80 percent of people that have depression are treatable with medication. You are a lying hack.
</post>
<post author="eots" datetime="2012-03-20T17:02:00" id="p4">
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pCNGVftY5A8">Prozac: The Military's Secret Weapon - YouTube</a>
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pCNGVftY5A8"> Prozac: The Military's Secret Weapon - YouTube</a>
</post>
<post author="eots" datetime="2012-03-20T17:12:00" id="p5">
<quote orig_author="RetiredGySgt">
80 percent of people that have depression are treatable with medication. You are a lying hack.

</quote>

where do you get your information ?..EI Lilly flyers ?...The fact is a placebo is all but equally effective...why cant you grasp that fact ??..look at the studies done by the drug companies themselves and you can see for yourself even according to their studies anti-depressants are only slightly more effective than a placebo it is true 80% will report improvement on medication but it is equally true that a placebo will also get all most the same result from a placebo...its a simple fact..as is the the fact these drugs can cause violent behaviors and suicides
</post>
<post author="earlycuyler" datetime="2012-03-20T17:22:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="RetiredGySgt">
80 percent of people that have depression are treatable with medication. You are a lying hack.

</quote>

This is true, but that leaves the other 20% to deal with. Thees men were part of that 20%. Our soldiers are being pushed to hard for political reasons and being sent back to combat to avoid higher unemployment numbers for the great Obama.
</post>
<post author="The Gadfly" datetime="2012-03-20T18:26:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="eots">
this poor bastards is a victim..4 deployments...twice wounded..head injury..put on ant-psychotic drugs,known to cause such reactions as psychosis and violent behavior...he should be allowed to return to his wife and children and given help to heal...he is not the one that should hang for this..god bless him and his family

<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Fo95pfscdQ">U.S. Soldier Accused of Afghan Massacre Begins Building Defense - YouTube</a>

</quote>

Do you happen to have a link that indicates just what drugs this man was on, and when? If he was still on any true anti-psychotic drug, he should NEVER have been medically cleared for deployment.

As for your other link the content is beyond disturbing; if that's how the services are treating PTSD we have a serious problem.

You will, I hope forgive me for being a bit leery of material you post, based on your track record of postings on various conspiracy theories; this one, however appears legitimate.
</post>
<post author="The Gadfly" datetime="2012-03-20T18:43:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="RetiredGySgt">
80 percent of people that have depression are treatable with medication. You are a lying hack.

</quote>

Gunny, with all due respect, your stats are a little off. About 80% of patients with clinical depression can be effectively treated with some combination of cognitive/behavioral therapies and medication where indicated Some patients do not require medication; others find it helpful in varying degrees. That still leaves 20% whose illness appears less than adequately responsive to either psychotherapy, or medication. It's good that you are one of the 80% and I am glad you are, but medical science still does not have as much to offer some patients as would be desirable, despite recent advances. There are more and better treatment options available these days, but there's still no help for some; we can only hope....

Meanwhile, you keep hanging in there, brother. Depression, like PTSD, is a hard fight, but one you CAN win; I know. Don't give up; don't EVER give up!
</post>
<post author="RetiredGySgt" datetime="2012-03-20T18:52:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="eots">
<quote orig_author="RetiredGySgt">
80 percent of people that have depression are treatable with medication. You are a lying hack.

</quote>

where do you get your information ?..EI Lilly flyers ?...The fact is a placebo is all but equally effective...why cant you grasp that fact ??..look at the studies done by the drug companies themselves and you can see for yourself even according to their studies anti-depressants are only slightly more effective than a placebo it is true 80% will report improvement on medication but it is equally true that a placebo will also get all most the same result from a placebo...its a simple fact..as is the the fact these drugs can cause violent behaviors and suicides

</quote>

You are a LIAR. But thanks for proving it.
</post>
<post author="eots" datetime="2012-03-20T19:27:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="retiredgysgt">
<quote orig_author="eots">
<quote orig_author="retiredgysgt">
80 percent of people that have depression are treatable with medication. You are a lying hack.

</quote>

where do you get your information ?..ei lilly flyers ?...the fact is a placebo is all but equally effective...why cant you grasp that fact ??..look at the studies done by the drug companies themselves and you can see for yourself even according to their studies anti-depressants are only slightly more effective than a placebo it is true 80% will report improvement on medication but it is equally true that a placebo will also get all most the same result from a placebo...its a simple fact..as is the the fact these drugs can cause violent behaviors and suicides

</quote>

you are a liar. But thanks for proving it.

</quote>

no they are absolute facts..and all you can counter them with
is..liar
</post>
<post author="eots" datetime="2012-03-20T19:42:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="the gadfly">
<quote orig_author="eots">
this poor bastards is a victim..4 deployments...twice wounded..head injury..put on ant-psychotic drugs,known to cause such reactions as psychosis and violent behavior...he should be allowed to return to his wife and children and given help to heal...he is not the one that should hang for this..god bless him and his family

<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7fo95pfscdq">u.s. Soldier accused of afghan massacre begins building defense - youtube</a>

</quote>

do you happen to have a link that indicates just what drugs this man was on, and when? If he was still on any true anti-psychotic drug, he should never have been medically cleared for deployment.

As for your other link the content is beyond disturbing; if that's how the services are treating ptsd we have a serious problem.

You will, i hope forgive me for being a bit leery of material you post, based on your track record of postings on various conspiracy theories; this one, however appears legitimate.

</quote>

it reported he was prescribed anti-depressants and was twice wounded and had received a head injury from a concision for which he was medicated it was on a radio show with doctor david berrgin who has been instumental in many important court cases involving peopel who committed crimes due to medication induced psychosis...i will try and find a link in print
</post>
<post author="eots" datetime="2012-03-20T19:49:00" id="p12">
The U.S. staff sergeant who allegedly killed 16 Afghan civilians on Sunday served three tours in Iraq and was diagnosed with traumatic brain injury in 2010 in a vehicle rollover incident. According to the Washington Post, the 38-year-old soldier, who the military refuses to identify until they are able to formally charge him, joined the Army 11 years ago as a sniper, is a married father of two and was deployed to Afghanistan for the first time in December. After sustaining the brain injury, he was declared fit for duty. “We’re going to do a thorough investigation," commander of U.S. and NATO forces in Afghanistan, Marine Gen. John Allen told CNN. "We’re going to hold this individual accountable.”

<a href="http://gothamist.com/2012/03/14/sergeant_implicated_in_killing_of_1.php">Soldier Suspected In Killing Of 16 Afghan Civilians Suffered Brain Injury In 2010: Gothamist</a>
</post>
<post author="eots" datetime="2012-03-20T20:04:00" id="p13">
Over 1 million survivors of traumatic brain injury receive maintenance pharmacotherapy, of which a substantial number receive antipsychotic agents for the treatment of psychoses, agitation and aggres sion, and other maladaptive behaviours. In spite of the common clinical uses of antipsychotics, the cognitive risks versus benefits are unclear. The purpose of this study was to assess differences in cognitive functioning before, during, and after discontinuation of antipsychotic agents in inpatients undergoing rehabilitation for traumatic brain injury. Neuropsychiatric tests Reys Auditory-Verbal Learning, Trail Making A B, Digit Span Forwards and Backwards evaluating cognitive skills of verbal ability, visuomotor speed, memory, learning, attention, and spatial ability were administered to each subject at baseline immediately prior to tapering or discontinuing antipsychotic, when taper reached 50 of baseline dose, 1 week after antipsychotic discontinuation, and 3 weeks after discontinuation. These data suggest that select areas of cognition improve after antipsychotic discontinuation in subjects with traumatic brain injury. The magnitude of improvement appeared to be greater after discontinua tion with thioridazine, a low potency agent, compared to haloperidol, a high potency agent. Results, although very preliminary, support the hypothesis of cholinergic involvement in regulating cognitive processes, and this underscores the need for more systematic research in this area

Read More: <a href="http://informahealthcare.com/doi/abs/10.1080/026990597123494">Cognitive effects of antipsychotic agents in persons with traumatic brain injury, Brain Injury, Informa Healthcare</a>
</post>
<post author="eots" datetime="2012-03-20T20:22:00" id="p14">
it would appear the doctors information was most likely correct
</post>
<post author="waltky" datetime="2012-04-02T15:55:00" id="p15">
Genetic link to PTSD?...
<img src="http://www.usmessageboard.com/images/smilies/confused.gif"/>
Gene clue to post-traumatic stress disorder risk
2 April 2012 : Susceptibility to post-traumatic stress disorder could be partially determined by gene variants, says a study.

<quote>
A US team looked at the DNA from 200 members of 12 families who survived the 1988 Armenian earthquake. It found those who carried two gene variants which affect the production of serotonin - which affects mood and behaviour - were more likely to display symptoms of PTSD. The research is published in Journal of Affective Disorders.

PTSD can arise after any kind of experience that causes trauma, whether that be in war, after a natural disaster or because of child abuse or sexual assault. Symptoms can include flashbacks, feeling emotionally numb or hyper-alert to danger, and avoiding situations that act as reminders of the original trauma. It is estimated that up to 3% of the general population is likely to be affected by PTSD at some point.

Screening hope

The Armenian earthquake, which had a magnitude of 7.1, occurred on 7 December 1988. It hit the northern part of Armenia, which was then part of the Soviet Union. It killed at least 25,000 people. All those who took part in the study had experienced the earthquake, 90% saw dead bodies and 92% saw people who had been seriously injured. They also undertook a recognised assessment to evaluate what, if any, PTSD symptoms they had experienced. When the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) researchers analysed the Armenian families' DNA, they saw that those who had experienced more PTSD symptoms were more likely to have two specific gene variants - TPH1 and TPH2.

Dr Armen Goenjian, a research professor of psychiatry who led the work, said: "We suspect that the gene variants produce less serotonin, predisposing these family members to PTSD after exposure to violence or disaster. "Our next step will be to try and replicate the findings in a larger, more heterogeneous population." But he said that, if larger studies did confirm the finding, they could eventually lead to new ways to screen people at risk of PTSD, and target specific medicines for preventing and treating the disorder. Dr Goenjian added: "A diagnostic tool based upon TPH1 and TPH2 could enable military leaders to identify soldiers who are at higher risk of developing PTSD, and reassign their combat duties accordingly. "Our findings may also help scientists uncover alternative treatments for the disorder, such as gene therapy or new drugs that regulate the chemicals responsible for PTSD symptoms."

<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/health-17560680">Depression link</a>

</quote>
</post>
</doc>
