<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-203-185940-347385">
<headline>
NMR: Man stealing Rolex from airport security in Florida
</headline>
<post author="ch ch ch c..." datetime="2012-02-17T13:03:00" id="p1">
Did you all see this story?
<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/02/14/man-steals-rolex-watch-airport-security_n_1276344.html">http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/02/14/man-steals-rolex-watch-airport-security_n_1276344.html</a>
I was surprised the other night when they showed the video clip on the ABC nightly news. I mean, is this *really* national news?
The guy is obviously a total jerk with low moral standards, but can he really be arrested for picking up something that someone left behind? If you found a Rolex laying on the sidewalk, picked it up, and kept it - could you be arrested for that?
</post>
<post author="+v+" datetime="2012-02-17T13:13:00" id="p2">
I think it is interesting because the guy is obviously shady asfuck.
Florida statute on this:

705.101 (2)  “Lost property” means all tangible personal property which does not have an identifiable owner and which has been mislaid on public property, upon a public conveyance, on premises used at the time for business purposes, or in parks, places of amusement, public recreation areas, or other places open to the public in a substantially operable, functioning condition or which has an apparent intrinsic value to the rightful owner.

705.102  Reporting lost or abandoned property. — (1)  Whenever any person finds any lost or abandoned property, such person shall report the description and location of the property to a law enforcement officer.
(2)  The law enforcement officer taking the report shall ascertain whether the person reporting the property wishes to make a claim to it if the rightful owner cannot be identified or located. If the person does wish to make such claim, he or she shall deposit with the law enforcement agency a reasonable sum sufficient to cover the agency’s cost for transportation, storage, and publication of notice. This sum shall be reimbursed to the finder by the rightful owner should he or she identify and reclaim the property.
(3)  It is unlawful for any person who finds any lost or abandoned property to appropriate the same to his or her own use or to refuse to deliver the same when required.
(4)  Any person who unlawfully appropriates such lost or abandoned property to his or her own use or refuses to deliver such property when required commits theft as defined in s. <a href="http://www.flsenate.gov/Laws/Statutes/2011/812.014">812.014</a>, punishable as provided in s. <a href="http://www.flsenate.gov/Laws/Statutes/2011/775.082">775.082</a>, s. <a href="http://www.flsenate.gov/Laws/Statutes/2011/775.083">775.083</a>, or s. <a href="http://www.flsenate.gov/Laws/Statutes/2011/775.084">775.084</a>.

So yes, it looks like you could be arrested for keeping the Rolex you find on a sidewalk.

(This is not legal advice)
</post>
<post author="liveinthev..." datetime="2012-02-17T13:20:00" id="p3">
I don't think the scenarios are comparable.
She didn't drop it. She was forced to take it off and someone took it while it was in the security bin.
</post>
<post author="ch ch ch c..." datetime="2012-02-17T13:20:00" id="p4">
Interesting....
Still seems weird that this made the national nightly news.
</post>
<post author="His#1Girl" datetime="2012-02-17T13:26:00" id="p5">
I saw the video and IMO, he's stealing. If he was just walking down the street and found it on the ground, then I think it would be different. (Even though +v+'s post gives insight on that particular situation). In the sidewalk situation, clearly the watch would have been a lost item because no one puts a watch on a sidewalk for safekeeping.
In this case, the watch was placed in a bin, provided by the TSA as safekeeping for her property until she passed through security and he removed it from the bin knowing that someone put it there at the request of the TSA and accidentally left it behind. He took the watch instead of turning it in to TSA Agents.
There might even be argument that the article did have an identifiable owner, namely, the traveller who preceeded him in the security checkpoint.
</post>
<post author="starlily31..." datetime="2012-02-17T13:29:00" id="p6">
One of my friends successfully prosecuted a "theft of lost property" case. The defendant was such a jerk during his testimony that the judge sentenced him to 30 days.
</post>
<post author="Flamingo S..." datetime="2012-02-17T14:25:00" id="p7">
How stupid is this guy? You are being recorded and you take something like that? Geesh!
</post>
<post author="MrsBPO" datetime="2012-02-19T10:27:00" id="p8">
Yeah, he's shady as phuque. He palmed the watch so he knew exactly what he was doing.
DH and I flew into Ft. Lauderdale for a job interview/visit with friend in Coral Gables a few years ago. We were in line for the rental car and talking with the folks in line with us when she looked up and went "Hey, that's my cart!" Someone was trying to walk off with her entire cart of luggage. It kind of put a damper on our first visit to the Miami area and dinged our opinion on the job just a smidge, honestly. (That and the commute time to get into CG from anywhere more than 3 miles away.) But yeah, quite the intro. I don't know why this doesn't surprise me that it happened at FTL but it could have happened anywhere.
I agree on the "this is national news?" aspect. Maybe they were doing it as a human-interest, "watch out for this while you're traveling" angle rather than a lead story?
</post>
</doc>
