<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-200-192453-5803774">
<headline>
What do you think of my view on rape?
</headline>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-03T02:23:00" id="p1">
i think rape is just as bad a murder (if not worse) because it is someone using another human being as a means to satisfy a disgusting desire of pleasure or power from someone being degraded, exploited etc.. (not in all cases ofcourse).
I would like opinions on my views:
1.People who commite rape (particularly more vile rapes) should be put to death.
2.People who rape should be castrated and imprisoned.

Now obviously theres the arguement that you can't prove it, but lets say all rapes were true.
Do you agree with my views?

EDIT: I didnt specify what situations:

I don't think someone who is drunk and gets taken advantage off is as bad a crime as if a girl is kidnapped and subject to sexual abuses/rape. It's rather the latter example where my view applies, the former is still disgusting to me and he should be punished so severly but its not as bad.

<a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/crime/9039015/Rapist-who-struck-to-teach-women-a-lesson.html">http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/ukne...-a-lesson.html</a> &lt; where my view applies.

I've Noticed There are about the same likes-dislikes.
Clearly there are a reasonable amount of people who agree with me and disagree.
I think in conclusion its agreed there should be much tougher sentances for rape but not the death penalty?
</post>
<post author="worker13" datetime="2012-02-03T02:33:00" id="p2">
I believe in forgiveness, understanding and rehabilitation although I wouldn't blame a rape victim at all if she did kill her attacker in an act of revenge.
</post>
<post author="Goody2Shoes-x" datetime="2012-02-03T02:35:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
i think rape is just as bad a murder (if not worse) because it is someone using another human being as a means to satisfy a disgusting desire of pleasure or power from someone being degraded, exploited etc.. (not in all cases ofcourse).
I would like opinions on my views:
1.People who commite rape (particularly more vile rapes) should be put to death.
2.People who rape should be castrated and imprisoned.

Now obviously theres the arguement that you can't prove it, but lets say all rapes were true.
Do you agree with my views?

</quote>

Although I too agree rape can be just as bad murder in some cases, you fail to classify when.

What about statutory rape, involving a boy over 16, and a 15 year old girl?

A person can be coerced into having sex, does that mean they were raped? Taken advantage of?

What if someone wakes up after a night out and doesn't remember having sex? Should the person they had sex with be killed as a rapist?

Rape is a tricky area - and even in cases where it is black and white, and a guilty verdict can easily be found, I wouldn't agree with the death penalty.

People who rape have often experiences traumatic childhoods, or abusive relationships themselves. I don't think this in any way can excuse or condone this behaviour, but if they are psychoanalyzed, it can help us understand what types of behaviours and patterns can lead to someone committing this kind of act, and can perhaps help us figure out better methods to prevent rape.

And even if there is no history of trauma, if somebody is just the stereotypical bad rapist, I wouldn't agree with the death penalty. Make them of some use to society, supervized community work in the day, locked in their cell at night, perhaps.
</post>
<post author="pineapple86" datetime="2012-02-03T02:36:00" id="p4">
They deserve to be strung up.
</post>
<post author="ChunkyFudgeLover101" datetime="2012-02-03T02:36:00" id="p5">
I'm not really for the death penalty, here or anywhere...
In this case the person is found guilty of rape.
-What happens if we execute them? What good comes out of it? The criminal doesn't have to actually live with what they've done.
They get a quick root out. i'd rather they stayed incarcerated for the rest of their lives or for a very long time.
I don't think solving violence with violence helps. What lesson is learned?
What about when the innocent is found guilty? It's to risky.
And Castrated- again, with the whole innocent thing... risky
</post>
<post author="Aequat omnes cinis" datetime="2012-02-03T02:37:00" id="p6">
No. You cannot even justify the argument with the 'eye for an eye' argument since your proposed punishments outweigh the crimes committed. Castration is inhumane in any case (good luck getting that one past the European Court of Human Rights). Murder cannot be justified by the eye for the eye principle, and it should not be a punishment for rape.

I have some support for the death penalty but you can't justify it for rape.
</post>
<post author="ckingalt" datetime="2012-02-03T02:42:00" id="p7">
I am temped to agree but that is an emotional response to a repulsive act. I reject the death penalty as a matter of principle. My principles are based on logic and logic&gt;emotion.
</post>
<post author="ScheduleII" datetime="2012-02-03T02:49:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="ckingalt">
I am temped to agree but that is an emotional response to a repulsive act. I reject the death penalty as a matter of principle. My principles are based on logic and logic&gt;emotion.

</quote>

I tend to agree viscerally on major nonces like the plymouth pervert in 1998 but logically and from a properly considered viewpoint, I can't support capital punishment for a crime other than murder.
</post>
<post author="OMG TOOTHBRUSH" datetime="2012-02-03T02:54:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="ChunkyFudgeLover101">
I'm not really for the death penalty, here or anywhere...
In this case the person is found guilty of rape.
- What happens if we execute them? What good comes out of it? The criminal doesn't have to actually live with what they've done.
They get a quick root out. i'd rather they stayed incarcerated for the rest of their lives or for a very long time.
I don't think solving violence with violence helps. What lesson is learned?
What about when the innocent is found guilty? It's to risky.
And Castrated- again, with the whole innocent thing... risky

</quote>

They would have a 0 chance of raping anyone else.
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-03T03:03:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="OMG TOOTHBRUSH">
I don't think it's as bad as murder, at least a rape victim has the chance to recover from the crime. Some people have never recovered from it and have committed suicide because of it though so I'd say it's almost as bad a crime.

In hypothetical situations where guilt is certain I would agree with your opinions on the punishment. I'm torn between life imprisonment and putting them to death though.

</quote>

True atleast they have a life to live, but then they could be mentally scarred for life, as their life has been ruined per say anyway. Atleast with murder (not the kind commited by a sick sick individual) for example a gangster shooting someone the killing most likely wasn't meant to cause humiliation,degregation etc for the guys own pleasure whereas rape could.
</post>
<post author="Tommyjw" datetime="2012-02-03T03:05:00" id="p11">
The average rape is never as bad as the average murder, how ****ing ridiculous.
</post>
<post author="Addzter" datetime="2012-02-03T03:05:00" id="p12">
Putting a rapist to death is just the avenging someone's giving in to one carnal urge (rape) by means of another (murder).
</post>
<post author="ScheduleII" datetime="2012-02-03T03:23:00" id="p13">
<quote orig_author="Tommyjw">
The average rape is never as bad as the average murder, how ****ing ridiculous.

</quote>

Correct. There have been a few rapists given longer sentences than a murderer. The number is very small though and so it should be.
</post>
<post author="prog2djent" datetime="2012-02-03T03:28:00" id="p14">
A murderer is ending someone's existance completely, I think, well, I would rather live with a traumatic expirience then not exist anymore. I can understand someone not wanting to live if they are in physical pain, or physchological torment that it makes their brain justs shut down, but as an athiest, to end your life, to never be aware of reality again, to not even know anything is far worse imho. Murder&gt;Rape
</post>
<post author="Rascacielos" datetime="2012-02-03T03:33:00" id="p15">
Much as I'm inclined to agree with the death penalty for certain murders, I don't support it for rape. It's too hard to prove and the Law is too sketchy.
</post>
<post author="Wave" datetime="2012-02-03T03:35:00" id="p16">
I dont condone rape but I do believe the "it's on the level of murder" type of revulsion against rape is just a human cultural thing. If I attacked a woman and forced my finger up her nose should I be put to death as a rapist? I could of got tons of sexual satisfaction out of it, the woman could of been intensly traumatised by it. But if I were to shove a different body part up her nose then suddenly it's on par with murder? Even forcing your finger up someone's anus is entrely subjective to the culture as to whether that is actually a sexual attack (the anus is as much of a sexual organ as the nostril is). Again of course rape is abominable but it is in no way worse than murder. Your family never see you again. You never get to live again, god knows what happens to you when you die it could be horrifically awful.

Furthermore I assume the evilness of rape originates from how traumatising it is for the victim. So should we have the death penalty for any sort of equally traumatising attack against a human? I have a phobia of snakes and I would hands down 10000000000000000% rather be violently gang raped by the entire England rugby team than if someone were to throw a boa constrictor into my bed. I would certainly not enjoy it but my point is that there are somethings that people may find to be even more traumatising than being raped.
</post>
<post author="angrydanmarin" datetime="2012-02-03T04:35:00" id="p17">
Death penalty for rapists?
Sometimes i wonder where some people's morals come from *facepalm*
</post>
<post author="kat91s" datetime="2012-02-03T04:42:00" id="p18">
I read the article, and I know a guy of the exact same name... except he's younger so at least I can be glad it's not him.

Rape does not call for the death sentence, in fact there is a reason why the death sentence has been abolished even for murder. It's a tricky subject, because it can't always be proven, but at the same time, rapists should be rightly punished.
</post>
<post author="takethyfacehence" datetime="2012-02-03T05:20:00" id="p19">
<quote orig_author="Wave">
I dont condone rape but I do believe the "it's on the level of murder" type of revulsion against rape is just a human cultural thing. If I attacked a woman and forced my finger up her nose should I be put to death as a rapist? I could of got tons of sexual satisfaction out of it, the woman could of been intensly traumatised by it. But if I were to shove a different body part up her nose then suddenly it's on par with murder? Even forcing your finger up someone's anus is entrely subjective to the culture as to whether that is actually a sexual attack (the anus is as much of a sexual organ as the nostril is). Again of course rape is abominable but it is in no way worse than murder. Your family never see you again. You never get to live again, god knows what happens to you when you die it could be horrifically awful.

Furthermore I assume the evilness of rape originates from how traumatising it is for the victim. So should we have the death penalty for any sort of equally traumatising attack against a human? I have a phobia of snakes and I would hands down 10000000000000000% rather be violently gang raped by the entire England rugby team than if someone were to throw a boa constrictor into my bed. I would certainly not enjoy it but my point is that there are somethings that people may find to be even more traumatising than being raped.

</quote>

Your first paragraph is just... especially wrong. Imho. The fact that it's a 'human cultural thing'.. how does that detract from the point at all? Doesn't that really support the point of how disgusting an act it is - our reaction to it? Sex and everything about it is incredibly important to human culture, yes, and we do recognise sexual abuse as a category of its own as opposed to just plain physical abuse.

In general, I personally wouldn't mind if racists were put to death. It's just the inherent complications of making it systematic. But if I knew I could get away with it (and had the balls for it) I would have no moral qualms about killing a rapist. A rapist most probably has a ****ed up upbringing and possibly has been a victim themselves, but my gut feeling is that they've committed an act that shows they are too far gone with perversity and dare I say it, evil, their life is worthless.

On that cheery note...!

With the whole rape and murder kind of comparison, the thing is that murder is a lot easier to understand, as a blanket term. I mean, cold-blooded murder on an innocent person is damned hard to understand just like rape is, but rape is just another level of... sickness.
</post>
<post author="Wave" datetime="2012-02-03T05:28:00" id="p20">
<quote orig_author="takethyfacehence">
Your first paragraph is just... especially wrong. Imho. The fact that it's a 'human cultural thing'.. how does that detract from the point at all? Doesn't that really support the point of how disgusting an act it is - our reaction to it? Sex and everything about it is incredibly important to human culture, yes, and we do recognise sexual abuse as a category of its own as opposed to just plain physical abuse.

In general, I personally wouldn't mind if racists were put to death. It's just the inherent complications of making it systematic. But if I knew I could get away with it (and had the balls for it) I would have no moral qualms about killing a rapist. A rapist most probably has a ****ed up upbringing and possibly has been a victim themselves, but my gut feeling is that they've committed an act that shows they are too far gone with perversity and dare I say it, evil, their life is worthless.

On that cheery note...!

With the whole rape and murder kind of comparison, the thing is that murder is a lot easier to understand, as a blanket term. I mean, cold-blooded murder on an innocent person is damned hard to understand just like rape is, but rape is just another level of... sickness.

</quote>

Yeah but in my post I said what really cosnstitutes sexual abuse?

And as for killing people for their beliefs (racists) that is an abhorrent idea. If a guy is going around saying how much he hates black people and whatever that's his personal beliefs and he should not be so much as arrested for it. Educated yes but certainly not punished. It should only become criminal if he abuses or harms someone else because of his beliefs.
</post>
<post author="DontWantYourBloodMoney" datetime="2012-02-03T05:35:00" id="p21">
I whole heartedly agree with castration and imprisonment, in most cases, as is always there are many different situations in which this would not be applied (most of which have been described before such as a 16 year old and 15 year old who consent, or some drunken mistake etc).
</post>
<post author="SilverArch" datetime="2012-02-03T12:07:00" id="p22">
I hate rape but I hate the death penalty even more. Castration no because people's bodies are also their own, and the government can't choose to chop off your limbs any more than they can choose to kill you or enslave you

However, life imprisonment with no parole..hell yes!! No way should serial rapists ever be back in society. And I want longer sentences for rape across the board
</post>
<post author="riotgrrl" datetime="2012-02-03T12:14:00" id="p23">
I disagree. As awful and horrific as rape is, I don't want to hand over any more power to the state than we have to.
</post>
<post author="Architecture-er" datetime="2012-02-03T12:17:00" id="p24">
Has anyone watched "The Girl With A Dragon Tattoo"?

If so, you'll like what happens
</post>
<post author="Stratos" datetime="2012-02-03T12:18:00" id="p25">
<quote orig_author="Tommyjw">
The average rape is never as bad as the average murder, how ****ing ridiculous.

</quote>

Definitely, I much rather get raped 100's of times instead of getting killed. My life is the most important thing to me, what does it matter if they penetrate my anus!?
</post>
<post author="int92" datetime="2012-02-03T12:23:00" id="p26">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
i think rape is just as bad a murder (if not worse) because it is someone using another human being as a means to satisfy a disgusting desire of pleasure or power from someone being degraded, exploited etc.. (not in all cases ofcourse).
I would like opinions on my views:
1.People who commite rape (particularly more vile rapes) should be put to death.
2.People who rape should be castrated and imprisoned.

Now obviously theres the arguement that you can't prove it, but lets say all rapes were true.
Do you agree with my views?

EDIT: I didnt specify what situations:

I don't think someone who is drunk and gets taken advantage off is as bad a crime as if a girl is kidnapped and subject to sexual abuses/rape. It's rather the latter example where my view applies, the former is still disgusting to me and he should be punished so severly but its not as bad.

<a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/crime/9039015/Rapist-who-struck-to-teach-women-a-lesson.html">http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/ukne...-a-lesson.html</a> &lt; where my view applies.

</quote>

in a perfect world yes...but alot of bitches lie
</post>
<post author="cambio wechsel" datetime="2012-02-03T12:26:00" id="p27">
Criminology 101 says that the punishment for rape must be significantly lighter than that for murder. Otherwise the rapist has no disincentive to murder the accuser and star witness.
</post>
<post author="Radioactive_Banana" datetime="2012-02-03T12:29:00" id="p28">
So you think a rapist deserves to be executed....?! What right do you think you have to take another's life? Sure their acts are deplorable but they should be given a chance to redeem themselves and once again become a member of society.
</post>
<post author="458driver" datetime="2012-02-03T12:30:00" id="p29">
I would rather be raped than murdered!

So no - they are not the same and it is ridiculous to say they are frankly.
</post>
<post author="pedobear" datetime="2012-02-03T12:41:00" id="p30">
It's not rape if you yell surprise first.......SURPRISE!!!
</post>
<post author="Apeiron" datetime="2012-02-03T12:44:00" id="p31">
It's stupid. Any victim of rape would just be murdered. Next question.
</post>
<post author="Merell" datetime="2012-02-03T12:45:00" id="p32">
Any man found guilty of rape before the court on more than one occasion should have his dick lopped off. Simple as.
</post>
<post author="Aspiringlawstudent" datetime="2012-02-03T13:17:00" id="p33">
Capital punishment isn't appropriate for any offence.

The entire idea of 'killing is bad, so we're going to kill you for it' is ridiculous.

Castration does not seem to be required, and it is not even clear if it would prevent the desire to offend.

The appropriate dispensation is imprisonment.
</post>
<post author="Historophilia" datetime="2012-02-03T14:15:00" id="p34">
I don't agree witht he death panalty for anything, no state should have the right to take the life of it's citizens and I think that however awful a criminal is, you do not have the right to take away a another human beings life.

However I think rape sould be a life sentance since it is pretty much the worst crime for reoffending, all sexual offences are.
</post>
<post author="ForKicks" datetime="2012-02-03T14:46:00" id="p35">
Castrated AND a life sentence? lol. I think you will find they are the ones getting raped in prison
</post>
<post author="Claudine" datetime="2012-02-03T14:50:00" id="p36">
I dont think rape is as bas as murder, but I think that they should be castrated and imprisoned
</post>
<post author="IB_19" datetime="2012-02-03T14:54:00" id="p37">
I definitely agree with you that rape is absolutely disgusting, however I can't see how the death penalty is justifiable. Isn't it better to isolate them in prison (for life depending on the case), as opposed to giving them an easy way out? Therefore, they may face hostility in prison and time to reflect upon what they did and change. Clearly anyone who commits rape has issues that need to be dealt with and resorting to the death penalty will not solve that.

As for castration, again, it depends on the case and how long they're imprisoned for.
</post>
<post author="TurboCretin" datetime="2012-02-03T15:05:00" id="p38">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
i think rape is just as bad a murder (if not worse) because it is someone using another human being as a means to satisfy a disgusting desire of pleasure or power from someone being degraded, exploited etc.. (not in all cases ofcourse).
I would like opinions on my views:
1.People who commite rape (particularly more vile rapes) should be put to death.
2.People who rape should be castrated and imprisoned.

Now obviously theres the arguement that you can't prove it, but lets say all rapes were true.
Do you agree with my views?

EDIT: I didnt specify what situations:

I don't think someone who is drunk and gets taken advantage off is as bad a crime as if a girl is kidnapped and subject to sexual abuses/rape. It's rather the latter example where my view applies, the former is still disgusting to me and he should be punished so severly but its not as bad.

<a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/crime/9039015/Rapist-who-struck-to-teach-women-a-lesson.html">http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/ukne...-a-lesson.html</a> &lt; where my view applies.

</quote>

There are swathes of your post which are vague and confusing. Would you prefer them to be castrated then killed, or killed then castrated?

I don't support your views I'm afraid. Rapists should be imprisoned. I dont support capital punishment and I see no justification for castration of rapists beyond brute retribution. Your sanctions strike me as capricious rather than judicious, in that they have been made apparently without consideration of the purposes of punishment.
</post>
<post author="abc:)" datetime="2012-02-03T15:22:00" id="p39">
I don't understand which of the views you actually mean...it can't be both? Would it depend on the severity of the rape? Because that would be very hard to quantify
</post>
<post author="Arekkusu" datetime="2012-02-03T15:22:00" id="p40">
Obviously there is a huge difference in degree between rape that occurs as a result of gentle coercion or being drunk and the sort you're talking about where women are physically attacked, subjugated and then violently raped. Note that the coercion one may be perpetrated equally between women and men because it is more psychological than physical in nature. Any rape allegations that might be brought from an incident like the first one are probably going to result from shame rather than trauma (mental and physical) as occurs in the second type.

We have to stop thinking sex is in any way particularly special, mind you, as compared with other violations against the person. High degree of assault shouldn't be any more or less serious as a high degree of rape as it will result in trauma and physical harm just the same.

Wave above me was talking about how what a sexual attack is is an effect of the culture you live in, and it depends what way you think about it. Greater focus on "rape" as a cultural meme or semantic category is going to lead to greater levels of trauma if sexual assault actually happens; it's the same with mental illness. The label throws you in with all the terrible stories you've heard and increases the perceived harm, surely?

This increased trauma isn't fake or invalid, so it is important to provide women who have been raped with legal protection and moral support and so on. However it is really over-reacting to say rapists should be castrated or put to death, you wouldn't say an assaulter should have his hands cut off or be put to death, or indeed anything remotely near that, and that's because the severity of rape is highlighted more in our culture.
</post>
<post author="bulgy" datetime="2012-02-03T15:24:00" id="p41">
even if it was as bad as murder then the last time i looked, the death penalty still doesnt apply
</post>
<post author="Kater Murr" datetime="2012-02-03T15:27:00" id="p42">
That's a good view you've got there - can I have a look?
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-03T16:01:00" id="p43">
<quote orig_author="SilverArch">
I hate rape but I hate the death penalty even more. Castration no because people's bodies are also their own, and the government can't choose to chop off your limbs any more than they can choose to kill you or enslave you

However, life imprisonment with no parole..hell yes!! No way should serial rapists ever be back in society. And I want longer sentences for rape across the board

</quote>

<quote orig_author="Radioactive_Banana">
So you think a rapist deserves to be executed....?! What right do you think you have to take another's life? Sure their acts are deplorable but they should be given a chance to redeem themselves and once again become a member of society.

</quote>

<quote orig_author="Aspiringlawstudent">
Capital punishment isn't appropriate for any offence.

The entire idea of 'killing is bad, so we're going to kill you for it' is ridiculous.

Castration does not seem to be required, and it is not even clear if it would prevent the desire to offend.

The appropriate dispensation is imprisonment.

</quote>

<quote orig_author="Historophilia">
I don't agree witht he death panalty for anything, no state should have the right to take the life of it's citizens and I think that however awful a criminal is, you do not have the right to take away a another human beings life.

However I think rape sould be a life sentance since it is pretty much the worst crime for reoffending, all sexual offences are.

</quote>

I would certainly be happy to an extent if rapists who commit particularly vile rapes are imprisoned for life but the sentances for rape in this country are outragously short. 4 years for essentially ruining a persons life is crazy. Hence why my views are so... lets say 'retributionist' because the sentancing is already weak.
i guess my next question is why don't we have much harsher imprisonment sentances?
</post>
<post author="Tommyjw" datetime="2012-02-03T16:03:00" id="p44">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
I would certainly be happy to an extent if rapists who commit particularly vile rapes are imprisoned for life but the sentances for rape in this country are outragously short. 4 years for essentially ruining a persons life is crazy. Hence why my views are so... lets say 'retributionist' because the sentancing is already weak.
i guess my next question is why don't we have much harsher imprisonment sentances?

</quote>

Are the average sentences not closer to 8 years?..
</post>
<post author="Merell" datetime="2012-02-03T16:05:00" id="p45">
<quote orig_author="Arekkusu">
Obviously there is a huge difference in degree between rape that occurs as a result of gentle coercion or being drunk and the sort you're talking about where women are physically attacked, subjugated and then violently raped. Note that the coercion one may be perpetrated equally between women and men because it is more psychological than physical in nature. Any rape allegations that might be brought from an incident like the first one are probably going to result from shame rather than trauma (mental and physical) as occurs in the second type.

We have to stop thinking sex is in any way particularly special, mind you, as compared with other violations against the person. High degree of assault shouldn't be any more or less serious as a high degree of rape as it will result in trauma and physical harm just the same.

Wave above me was talking about how what a sexual attack is is an effect of the culture you live in, and it depends what way you think about it. Greater focus on "rape" as a cultural meme or semantic category is going to lead to greater levels of trauma if sexual assault actually happens; it's the same with mental illness. The label throws you in with all the terrible stories you've heard and increases the perceived harm, surely?

This increased trauma isn't fake or invalid, so it is important to provide women who have been raped with legal protection and moral support and so on. However it is really over-reacting to say rapists should be castrated or put to death, you wouldn't say an assaulter should have his hands cut off or be put to death, or indeed anything remotely near that, and that's because the severity of rape is highlighted more in our culture.

</quote>

I respectfully disagree. Physical assault alone is generally not as mentally or emotionally scarring as rape, as there are factors to sexual violence that are simply not a part of external bodily violence. Think about it in terms of external and internal injury. If you are torched or beaten, you can wash the blood off- so to speak; external wounds will heal and if it scars others can see and acknowledge it but for the most part you can hope to eventually move on. When you are raped that person is inside you and you can not get rid of them. Psychologically you can not get rid of them and you feel disgusting and dirty and violated and repulsed at your own skin because you can't get them out. You carry it with you for the rest of your life inside of your body. Sex is- for the vast majority of violent rape victims- incredibly physically painful and uncomfortable- so what, a rapist has now deprived them of intimacy for the rest of their life? That's without even discussing the emotional and trust implications of rape when it comes to trying to function socially with any kind of normality.

TL;DR When somebody is raped, it has the base potential to ruin more aspects of their life than GBH alone.

*For the purposes of this discussion, I'm talking about irrefutable, violence-driven rape cases here. Not fuzzy was it/wasn't it shame-based accusations.
</post>
<post author="thelooby94" datetime="2012-02-03T16:20:00" id="p46">
<quote orig_author="ChunkyFudgeLover101">
I'm not really for the death penalty, here or anywhere...
In this case the person is found guilty of rape.
-What happens if we execute them? What good comes out of it? The criminal doesn't have to actually live with what they've done.
They get a quick root out. i'd rather they stayed incarcerated for the rest of their lives or for a very long time.
I don't think solving violence with violence helps. What lesson is learned?
What about when the innocent is found guilty? It's to risky.
And Castrated- again, with the whole innocent thing... risky

</quote>

But then how much money gets spent on keeping them alive in jail <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/confused.gif" alt=":confused:"/>
</post>
<post author="The Phelps" datetime="2012-02-03T16:53:00" id="p47">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
i think rape is just as bad a murder (if not worse) because it is someone using another human being as a means to satisfy a disgusting desire of pleasure or power from someone being degraded, exploited etc.. (not in all cases ofcourse).
.

</quote>

Isn't that essentially the way our Western economies work. To satisfy our want for pleasure/power at the cost of someone being degraded, exploited!

I'm sorry, but death is worse than rape. Death is end game if you're an atheist like me. Whereas rape is traumatic, but life goes on. If you can't live with the rape hanging over your life you can commit suicide. Murder has no choice for the victim at least rape has some.
</post>
<post author="ChunkyFudgeLover101" datetime="2012-02-03T17:51:00" id="p48">
<quote orig_author="thelooby94">
But then how much money gets spent on keeping them alive in jail <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/confused.gif" alt=":confused:"/>

</quote>

The death penalty does too, have a lot of expenses.
<a href="http://www.amnestyusa.org/our-work/issues/death-penalty/us-death-penalty-facts/death-penalty-cost">http://www.amnestyusa.org/our-work/i...h-penalty-cost</a>

A lot of money would be spent on killing people, than on helping people...
If we want to make them suffer for what they did, and treat them too, badly- then i guess hard labour is fair..
</post>
<post author="Scoobiedoobiedo" datetime="2012-02-03T18:03:00" id="p49">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
I would like opinions on my views:
1.People who commite rape (particularly more vile rapes) should be put to death.

</quote>

If you have a death penalty for rape, I would assume there is also one for murder? If the sentence for rape and murder are the same then rapists will probably just murder their victims to lessen the chance of being caught.

I think it would just result in the poor victims being raped then murdered.

Perhaps a more fitting sentence would be life without parole and a raping, perhaps a rape for each rape the rapist committed. It could be done by a big raping machine or something.
</post>
<post author="LETSJaM" datetime="2012-02-03T18:06:00" id="p50">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
i think rape is just as bad a murder (if not worse) because it is someone using another human being as a means to satisfy a disgusting desire of pleasure or power from someone being degraded, exploited etc.. (not in all cases ofcourse).
I would like opinions on my views:
1.People who commite rape (particularly more vile rapes) should be put to death.
2.People who rape should be castrated and imprisoned.

</quote>

Agreed. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/yes.gif" alt=":yes:"/>

&lt;3 x
</post>
<post author="Scoobiedoobiedo" datetime="2012-02-03T18:07:00" id="p51">
<quote orig_author="The Phelps">
I'm sorry, but death is worse than rape. Death is end game if you're an atheist like me. Whereas rape is traumatic, but life goes on. If you can't live with the rape hanging over your life you can commit suicide. Murder has no choice for the victim at least rape has some.

</quote>

WOW....
</post>
<post author="~Kat~" datetime="2012-02-03T18:07:00" id="p52">
Huh, you have exactly the same views as my Mum, and I agree to some extent.
</post>
<post author="ChunkyFudgeLover101" datetime="2012-02-03T18:08:00" id="p53">
<quote orig_author="OMG TOOTHBRUSH">
They would have a 0 chance of raping anyone else.

</quote>

Locking them inside for the rest of their lives will ensure they harm no other person.

Death penalty doesn't stop other people from committing these heinous crimes.
If it was going to be used as a way to deter these kinds of crime, then it would have to be implemented in every case- To make sure people don't feel they can get away with these kind of crimes.
So, that being said- we can assume that the crime rate will go down, every person convicted of rape and murder will be executed.
Despite this- The problem isn't solved. People still will commit crimes...
Mistakes will be made... People will lie... We can't bring back those who we've murdered.
It's just too much in my opinion, yes these people are vile beings who don't deserve sympathy or kindness, so why let them escape life? I want them to have to feel the guilt everyday till they die. Why let them not see the damage that is done.
People want the right to die, (own choice) because they're suffering.
Why should these abominable people be able to release themselves from this life, they've not suffered enough for their crimes..
</post>
<post author="Steezy" datetime="2012-02-03T18:13:00" id="p54">
I beleive there are some acceptable reasons for murder (basically some people deserve to be murdered, e.g. rapists). But there is never an acceptable reason for rape.
</post>
<post author="Troll_Account" datetime="2012-02-03T18:20:00" id="p55">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
i think rape is just as bad a murder (if not worse) because it is someone using another human being as a means to satisfy a disgusting desire of pleasure or power from someone being degraded, exploited etc.. (not in all cases ofcourse).
I would like opinions on my views:
1.People who commite rape (particularly more vile rapes) should be put to death.
2.People who rape should be castrated and imprisoned.

Now obviously theres the arguement that you can't prove it, but lets say all rapes were true.
Do you agree with my views?

EDIT: I didnt specify what situations:

I don't think someone who is drunk and gets taken advantage off is as bad a crime as if a girl is kidnapped and subject to sexual abuses/rape. It's rather the latter example where my view applies, the former is still disgusting to me and he should be punished so severly but its not as bad.

<a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/crime/9039015/Rapist-who-struck-to-teach-women-a-lesson.html">http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/ukne...-a-lesson.html</a> &lt; where my view applies.

</quote>

Lets not complicate things.

If someone commits rape --&gt; automatic death penalty. Humanity does not come into this. The rapist WILLINGLY raped the woman. If the death penalty was put in place the rapist would KNOW what he was doing was a death penalty punishable offence. If he decides to commit rape thats him giving his permission to himself being killed.

Rehabilitation with rapists NEVER works. Almost ALL of them go on to commit the crime AGAIN.
</post>
<post author="Aspiringlawstudent" datetime="2012-02-03T18:34:00" id="p56">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
I would certainly be happy to an extent if rapists who commit particularly vile rapes are imprisoned for life but the sentances for rape in this country are outragously short. 4 years for essentially ruining a persons life is crazy. Hence why my views are so... lets say 'retributionist' because the sentancing is already weak.
i guess my next question is why don't we have much harsher imprisonment sentances?

</quote>

I would suggest that you read the official reports from the sentencing council. It may go some way to explain why sentences of such lengths are handed down.

The law provides for sentences of significantly longer lengths than four years to be handed down for rape.

The individual circumstances of each case will of course have an impact upon any sentence to be imposed in the event of a conviction.
</post>
<post author="Troll_Account" datetime="2012-02-03T18:35:00" id="p57">
<quote orig_author="tuckla07">
Yes, but how can you PROVE that it was rape? I agree if there's conclusive proof but it's one of the hardest crimes to prove

</quote>

DNA evidence, forensic evidence (the clitoris is very sensitive and any shear applied force or forced sexual tears proves that rape has occured). Studies have shown that raped women tend to have lots of shear stress tears whereas normal women don't who've just had sex with their partner.

(I'm a mechanical engineering student <img src="images/smilies/tongue.png"/> )
</post>
<post author="Casshern1456" datetime="2012-02-03T18:36:00" id="p58">
You are a hypocrite you say you hate rapists but say if the Girl is drunk outside a club and is then taken advantage off it's not as bad. Seriously wtf.

I know your post is meant to be serious and I completely agree with how rapist should be killed for their crime but you've got to look at yourself and think of the suffering girls raped or sexually harassed whilst on alcohol/drugs it's the same as being sober and raped.
</post>
<post author="Apeiron" datetime="2012-02-03T18:40:00" id="p59">
<quote orig_author="Troll_Account">
DNA evidence, forensic evidence (the clitoris is very sensitive and any shear applied force or forced sexual tears proves that rape has occured). Studies have shown that raped women tend to have lots of shear stress tears whereas normal women don't who've just had sex with their partner.

(I'm a mechanical engineering student <img src="images/smilies/tongue.png"/> )

</quote>

Well named account. <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>
</post>
<post author="Troll_Account" datetime="2012-02-03T18:41:00" id="p60">
<quote orig_author="tuckla07">
wow... i'm starting to regret applying if there's a rape module XD and is it seriously 100% accurate? I'm sure the DNA is, but I mean in refernece to the consentual/ non issue

</quote>

Science never lies. Think about it. Would a partner thrust THAT hard to cause so much pain REPEATEDELY.

They use this kind of science on kids who've been raped. They must be absolutely sure their vagina hasn't torn because of an accident say playing on a bike because thats the most common argument used by child rapists.

And no lol there is no rape module in Mech Eng. My professor was telling us he's been working rape cases because now you can tell a lot from shear stress tears from the lining of the clitoris.
</post>
<post author="Troll_Account" datetime="2012-02-03T18:43:00" id="p61">
<quote orig_author="Apeiron">
Well named account. <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>

</quote>

I hate the fact so many of my opinions are not taken seriously because of the name of this account.

sigh...
</post>
<post author="muse_of_fire" datetime="2012-02-03T19:02:00" id="p62">
<quote orig_author="Troll_Account">
Science never lies. Think about it. Would a partner thrust THAT hard to cause so much pain REPEATEDELY.

They use this kind of science on kids who've been raped. They must be absolutely sure their vagina hasn't torn because of an accident say playing on a bike because thats the most common argument used by child rapists.

And no lol there is no rape module in Mech Eng. My professor was telling us he's been working rape cases because now you can tell a lot from shear stress tears from the lining of the clitoris.

</quote>

Um, either you weren't listening properly or your grasp of female anatomy is really shoddy: the clitoris is not, NOT, what/where you think it is.
</post>
<post author="Apeiron" datetime="2012-02-03T19:03:00" id="p63">
<quote orig_author="Troll_Account">
I hate the fact so many of my opinions are not taken seriously because of the name of this account.

sigh...

</quote>

&gt;Lets not complicate things.

Actually, it's not just the name of the account. <img src="images/smilies/colondollar.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-03T20:24:00" id="p64">
<quote orig_author="Scoobiedoobiedo">
If you have a death penalty for rape, I would assume there is also one for murder? If the sentence for rape and murder are the same then rapists will probably just murder their victims to lessen the chance of being caught.

I think it would just result in the poor victims being raped then murdered.

Perhaps a more fitting sentence would be life without parole and a raping, perhaps a rape for each rape the rapist committed. It could be done by a big raping machine or something.

</quote>

Good point, but i just don't believe that will ever happen, ever. The DP is somewhat a realistic possibility. Otherwise i would love for them to be locked up for life and raped themselves.
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-03T20:26:00" id="p65">
<quote orig_author="Troll_Account">
Science never lies. Think about it. Would a partner thrust THAT hard to cause so much pain REPEATEDELY.

They use this kind of science on kids who've been raped. They must be absolutely sure their vagina hasn't torn because of an accident say playing on a bike because thats the most common argument used by child rapists.

And no lol there is no rape module in Mech Eng. My professor was telling us he's been working rape cases because now you can tell a lot from shear stress tears from the lining of the clitoris.

</quote>

Are you being serious?
Seriously, is that the truth, i just want to know (i study mech eng myself and that is interesting if true)
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-03T20:30:00" id="p66">
<quote orig_author="LETSJaM">
Agreed. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/yes.gif" alt=":yes:"/>

&lt;3 x

</quote>

Finally someone! <img src="images/smilies/colondollar.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Scoobiedoobiedo" datetime="2012-02-03T20:31:00" id="p67">
<quote orig_author="Troll_Account">
you can tell a lot from shear stress tears from the lining of the clitoris.

</quote>

Did you miss female anatomy 101?
</post>
<post author="takethyfacehence" datetime="2012-02-03T21:22:00" id="p68">
<quote orig_author="Wave">
Yeah but in my post I said what really cosnstitutes sexual abuse?

And as for killing people for their beliefs (racists) that is an abhorrent idea. If a guy is going around saying how much he hates black people and whatever that's his personal beliefs and he should not be so much as arrested for it. Educated yes but certainly not punished. It should only become criminal if he abuses or harms someone else because of his beliefs.

</quote>

Oh no, oops, I mistyped and wrote 'racist' instead of 'rapist'. Totally agree with you on that!

As for what constitutes as sexual abuse.. well I get your point that there must be some blurry lines but on the whole I think most people understand why it's particularly traumatic to get raped...
</post>
<post author="Milney1992" datetime="2012-02-03T21:34:00" id="p69">
What happens if the girl cry's rape but she wasn't raped. Is it the same punishement for her or does the guy just get killed.
</post>
<post author="Scoobiedoobiedo" datetime="2012-02-03T21:39:00" id="p70">
<quote orig_author="Milney1992">
What happens if the girl cry's rape but she wasn't raped.

</quote>

Then she is an evil bitch. Not just for putting the man she accuses through the whole ordeal, but just as much for undermining the credibility of women who are raped and aren't taken seriously because of the women who make it up.
</post>
<post author="james22" datetime="2012-02-03T21:41:00" id="p71">
<quote orig_author="Troll_Account">
Lets not complicate things.

If someone commits rape --&gt; automatic death penalty. Humanity does not come into this. The rapist WILLINGLY raped the woman. If the death penalty was put in place the rapist would KNOW what he was doing was a death penalty punishable offence. If he decides to commit rape thats him giving his permission to himself being killed.

Rehabilitation with rapists NEVER works. Almost ALL of them go on to commit the crime AGAIN.

</quote>

Source for the last bit please.
</post>
<post author="Apeiron" datetime="2012-02-04T09:49:00" id="p72">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
Good point, but i just don't believe that will ever happen, ever. The DP is somewhat a realistic possibility. Otherwise i would love for them to be locked up for life and raped themselves.

</quote>

Of course it will happen: dead people don't talk. You are condemning rape victims to death. You seem to think that justice and vengeance are identical.
</post>
<post author="Converse" datetime="2012-02-04T10:38:00" id="p73">
<quote orig_author="Goody2Shoes-x">
What about statutory rape, involving a boy over 16, and a 15 year old girl?

</quote>

That is not statutory rape. Statutory rape is when the younger person is younger than 13.

<quote orig_author="Merell">
Any man found guilty of rape before the court on more than one occasion should have his dick lopped off. Simple as.

</quote>

You do realise that chopping off his penis does not restrict his ability to commit these acts. He'll just use other things to penetrate his victim. Possibly something that causes more pain and damage than a penis.

Also, what do you think should be done about any woman who commits these kinds of atrocities more than once?
</post>
<post author="navarre" datetime="2012-02-04T12:45:00" id="p74">
Your views on rape are stupid, frankly. What civilised society proscribes a punishment that is harsher than the crime? Surely it'd make sense if the punishment matched the crime?

Murder should be the only crime worthy of the death penalty, and even then, only in extreme cases.
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-04T14:43:00" id="p75">
<quote orig_author="Apeiron">
Of course it will happen: dead people don't talk. You are condemning rape victims to death. You seem to think that justice and vengeance are identical.

</quote>

Am i?
I said it'd be good if they were locked up for life but for some reason it doesn't happen.
And they are more similar then you think.
And rapists are not uncommonly serial rapists.
</post>
<post author="FrigidSymphony" datetime="2012-02-04T15:14:00" id="p76">
There was a case back in the south of Switzerland a few years back that I remember, a high school student (I think, may have been at uni) was accused of raping a girl from his social circle or peer group or whatever, and everyone went all lynch mob calling for his head and whatnot. What turned out to be the case was that she had happily slept with after a night out, but upon being teased by her friends for sleeping with someone who apparently was less-than-hip, she changed her tune and accused him raping her.

Somehow I find cases like this almost equally disgusting.
</post>
<post author="FrigidSymphony" datetime="2012-02-04T15:16:00" id="p77">
<quote orig_author="Troll_Account">
Lets not complicate things.

If someone commits rape --&gt; automatic death penalty. Humanity does not come into this. The rapist WILLINGLY raped the woman. If the death penalty was put in place the rapist would KNOW what he was doing was a death penalty punishable offence. If he decides to commit rape thats him giving his permission to himself being killed.

Rehabilitation with rapists NEVER works. Almost ALL of them go on to commit the crime AGAIN.

</quote>

You really know **** all about pretty much everything.
</post>
<post author="Callipygian" datetime="2012-02-04T15:17:00" id="p78">
There have been cases where people have been convicted of rape, and then it turns out the girl just got a bit drunk and then the next day thought "i would never have slept with that guy i must have been raped"
</post>
<post author="Converse Rocker" datetime="2012-02-04T15:27:00" id="p79">
What about those convicted of rape, and then later found not guilty?

This is the major issue with capital punishment; even cases that seemed certain have been proven to be false.
</post>
<post author="limetang" datetime="2012-02-04T15:27:00" id="p80">
Putting someone to death for a crime is not solving the issue. It is just an act of revenge. Nothing more.

I admit this is probably a controversial view, but. With anyone as messed up as a rapist would have to be our first response would almost always be trying to help this person. Yet after their being messed up has harmed someone we treat them with contempt, and as someone who is beyond a cure.

Just because they have harmed someone it doesn't mean they are in any less need of our help. Should they be imprisoned? Of course. They are a danger to society. But the current attitude towards rapists isn't going to solve the issue.
</post>
<post author="Troll_Account" datetime="2012-02-04T15:44:00" id="p81">
<quote orig_author="FrigidSymphony">
You really know **** all about pretty much everything.

</quote>

I do indeed. Isn't that cool?
</post>
<post author="AwsomePossum" datetime="2012-02-04T15:49:00" id="p82">
<quote orig_author="OMG TOOTHBRUSH">
I don't think it's as bad as murder, at least a rape victim has the chance to recover from the crime. Some people have never recovered from it and have committed suicide because of it though so I'd say it's almost as bad a crime.

In hypothetical situations where guilt is certain I would agree with your opinions on the punishment. I'm torn between life imprisonment and putting them to death though.

</quote>

what about ten years then hanging? plenty of time to appeal and to be sure of the rapists guilt?
</post>
<post author="OMG TOOTHBRUSH" datetime="2012-02-04T17:30:00" id="p83">
<quote orig_author="AwsomePossum">
what about ten years then hanging? plenty of time to appeal and to be sure of the rapists guilt?

</quote>

That sounds like a good compromise <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/top.gif" alt=":top:"/>
</post>
<post author="xDave-" datetime="2012-02-04T17:34:00" id="p84">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
i think rape is just as bad a murder (if not worse)

</quote>

What a ridiculous thing to say.
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-04T17:54:00" id="p85">
<quote orig_author="xDave-">
What a ridiculous thing to say.

</quote>

Not really.
1. Its my opinion
2. It's really not ridiculous
</post>
<post author="carehow" datetime="2012-02-04T18:00:00" id="p86">
Where's the love for rehabilitation?
</post>
<post author="Tahooper" datetime="2012-02-04T18:06:00" id="p87">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
i think rape is just as bad a murder (if not worse) because it is someone using another human being as a means to satisfy a disgusting desire of pleasure or power from someone being degraded, exploited etc.. (not in all cases ofcourse).
I would like opinions on my views:
1.People who commite rape (particularly more vile rapes) should be put to death.
2.People who rape should be castrated and imprisoned.

Now obviously theres the arguement that you can't prove it, but lets say all rapes were true.
Do you agree with my views?

EDIT: I didnt specify what situations:

I don't think someone who is drunk and gets taken advantage off is as bad a crime as if a girl is kidnapped and subject to sexual abuses/rape. It's rather the latter example where my view applies, the former is still disgusting to me and he should be punished so severly but its not as bad.

<a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/crime/9039015/Rapist-who-struck-to-teach-women-a-lesson.html">http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/ukne...-a-lesson.html</a> &lt; where my view applies.

</quote>

Nobody should be put to death by the government. Although I believe a life sentence should actually mean they spend the rest of their life in prison.

Rapists should not be castrated, this isn't Guantanamo Bay, we shouldn't use torture to satisfy a disgusting desire - which would be hypocritical seeing as that is exactly what rapists are doing.
</post>
<post author="Dr Good Manners" datetime="2012-02-04T18:06:00" id="p88">
Its very bad but its not as bad as murder. To suggest its worse is pure retardation. Also the fact you think alcohol mitigates the crime just shows how misguided your overall view on this subject is.

And don't get me started on the bull**** logic of naming men in rape cases before they're even found guilty or innocemt. Thats a truely abhorrent practice and just gives women power to destroy a mans life by lying about being raped, knowing they'll never be called on it unless they confess. I think thats as bad as rape itself imo
</post>
<post author="lauren_a" datetime="2012-02-04T18:10:00" id="p89">
I think rapists are among some of the most vile people on the planet. However, I certainly don't agree that they should get the death penalty. Firstly, you state that rape is on the same level as murder. If you feel so strongly about murder, why do you deem it acceptable when it is institutional rather than individual? Killing someone who committed a crime you consider on the same level as killing is surely illogical. Secondly, the fact is, the death penalty is an easy way out. Rapists (especially child molesters or pedophiles) have an extremely difficult time in prison. Why give them the escape of death?

It's also important to remember that some sexual offenders are mentally unwell. Although, depending on the degree of mental illness, this may not necessarily suffice an excuse, it is still important that these people get help.
</post>
<post author="lauren_a" datetime="2012-02-04T18:12:00" id="p90">
<quote orig_author="Dr Good Manners">
Its very bad but its not as bad as murder. To suggest its worse is pure retardation. Also the fact you think alcohol mitigates the crime just shows how misguided your overall view on this subject is.

And don't get me started on the bull**** logic of naming men in rape cases before they're even found guilty or innocemt. Thats a truely abhorrent practice and just gives women power to destroy a mans life by lying about being raped, knowing they'll never be called on it unless they confess. I think thats as bad as rape itself imo

</quote>

Completely agree with the second part of this. It's insane to suggest that all men convicted of rape should be 'named and shamed' as if they are automatically guilty. That means every false accusation would essentially result in a man's life being ruined.
</post>
<post author="Apeiron" datetime="2012-02-04T18:13:00" id="p91">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
Not really.
1. Its my opinion
2. It's really not ridiculous

</quote>

I'm laughing at you. Therefore, it's ridiculous. Please keep them coming. <img src="images/smilies/tongue.png"/>
</post>
<post author="xDave-" datetime="2012-02-04T18:14:00" id="p92">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
Not really.
1. Its my opinion
2. It's really not ridiculous

</quote>

And you've just said another ridiculous thing. Can opinions not be ridiculous then?

How can ending someone's life be even remotely comparable to a rape... You can recover from a rape, you can't un-die. I suppose you think being raped is worse than being maimed too? And you probably consider imprisonment and torture as a lesser crime too?

I'm not saying rape isn't a serious crime, but come off it. Anyone that would rather any of that over rape doesn't value themselves very highly.
</post>
<post author="Soulscare" datetime="2012-02-04T18:20:00" id="p93">
No one will really agree with me on this, but I think there are two types of people that make me physically sick; Rapist and Pedophiles. Pedophiles deserve to die, but as for Rapists... When someone stole something years ago, there was only one way to assure they wouldn't do it again, cut off there hands. So there's only one way to stop Rapists from doing it again...
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-04T18:32:00" id="p94">
Rape is hugely 'overrated' in this country due to feminism. Yes it's a crime, but logically nowhere near as 'bad' as murder. In other countries rape isn't put on such a great pedestal because the level of feminism and westernisation is less.

The 'trauma' comes from the cultural notions of what rape means; women are meant to have sexual power and if a man takes it, it's major taboo. Without the power inequality the taboo lessens and the psychological trauma, based on a society's beliefs, decreases. So that's quite a grey area. The victim isn't physically impaired and can potentially lead a normal life; many rape victims DO eventually get over it and lead a normal life; try convincing them murder is as bad as rape.

As someone in the thread said, they'd rather get raped than have a snake in their bed; try telling them rape = murder. Heck, some women have fantasies of being raped, even gang raped, there are many books on this subject. Try telling them rape = murder. The 'trauma' is a reaction to having power stripped away. Is stripping power away from a banker/lawyer/doctor etc equal to murder?
</post>
<post author="Kerrias" datetime="2012-02-04T19:03:00" id="p95">
Whilst, of course, I do not condone rape in any way, shape or form and consider it one of the most evil things a person could do, at times exceeding murder imo (Somebody could be deranged with emotion and in the heat of the moment, stick a knife in someone, this is still wrong and evil but to rape a person is usually a planned and conscious decision to inflict such trauma on someone) I cannot agree with the death penalty for anybody. Not even Hitler. (I know many people will disagree with this). In my opinion the death penalty is just an evil crime as murder and nobody has the right to take the life of anyone else. We are all humans. Some of us may behave like animals but we are all people with lives and families and childhoods and histories and what gives anybody the right to destroy that. I say lock rapists up and throw away the key. But take it upon ourselves as a society to murder them, no.
</post>
<post author="sapphiregold" datetime="2012-02-04T19:09:00" id="p96">
i agree with you to some extent but i don't think anyone should be killed because i believe every1 has a right to live and if they committ something utterly horrific such as rape i think it would be a enough punishment that they are living with the guilt in prison but i don't think they should be killed because then the person who killed the rapist is just bad too for taking a life
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-04T19:13:00" id="p97">
<quote orig_author="sapphiregold">
i agree with you to some extent but i don't think anyone should be killed because i believe every1 has a right to live and if they committ something utterly horrific such as rape i think it would be a enough punishment that they are living with the guilt in prison but i don't think they should be killed because then the person who killed the rapist is just bad too for taking a life

</quote>

What is they feel no guilt?
Some guy recently raped 4 woman for being on the street at night to 'teach them a lesson' i doubt he feels guilty.
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-04T19:15:00" id="p98">
<quote orig_author="xDave-">
And you've just said another ridiculous thing. Can opinions not be ridiculous then?

How can ending someone's life be even remotely comparable to a rape... You can recover from a rape, you can't un-die. I suppose you think being raped is worse than being maimed too? And you probably consider imprisonment and torture as a lesser crime too?

I'm not saying rape isn't a serious crime, but come off it. Anyone that would rather any of that over rape doesn't value themselves very highly.

</quote>

Yeah but your being an arogant hypocrite, this is your opinion too. I wasn't even saying opinions can't be ridiculous but it's my opinion so it may seem ridiculous (in your own opinion <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/> ). Your the only person who has said its a completely ridiculous idea.
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-04T19:17:00" id="p99">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
Rape is hugely 'overrated' in this country due to feminism. Yes it's a crime, but logically nowhere near as 'bad' as murder. In other countries rape isn't put on such a great pedestal because the level of feminism and westernisation is less.

The 'trauma' comes from the cultural notions of what rape means; women are meant to have sexual power and if a man takes it, it's major taboo. Without the power inequality the taboo lessens and the psychological trauma, based on a society's beliefs, decreases. So that's quite a grey area. The victim isn't physically impaired and can potentially lead a normal life; many rape victims DO eventually get over it and lead a normal life; try convincing them murder is as bad as rape.

As someone in the thread said, they'd rather get raped than have a snake in their bed; try telling them rape = murder. Heck, some women have fantasies of being raped, even gang raped, there are many books on this subject. Try telling them rape = murder. The 'trauma' is a reaction to having power stripped away. Is stripping power away from a banker/lawyer/doctor etc equal to murder?

</quote>

So your saying in Afganistan a woman being raped.... she doesn't really care because she has no power?
Even without sexual power a woman can still be humiliated and degraded by this.
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-04T19:19:00" id="p100">
<quote orig_author="Dr Good Manners">
Its very bad but its not as bad as murder. To suggest its worse is pure retardation. Also the fact you think alcohol mitigates the crime just shows how misguided your overall view on this subject is.

And don't get me started on the bull**** logic of naming men in rape cases before they're even found guilty or innocemt. Thats a truely abhorrent practice and just gives women power to destroy a mans life by lying about being raped, knowing they'll never be called on it unless they confess. I think thats as bad as rape itself imo

</quote>

Tell that to most of the other people posting on this thread and they'll disagree.
Derp
</post>
<post author="duharvalgt" datetime="2012-02-04T19:24:00" id="p101">
are you including statutory aswell?
</post>
<post author="Nelson94" datetime="2012-02-04T19:31:00" id="p102">
I cant put anymore negatives on your comments...

Unless you have been raped you would never know the experiences to come from such a horrific situation. For example a rape victim is said to go to bed most nights thinking and being scared of the thoughts which they have scarred into their memory.

I would rather die than be continuously raped and for all the members who have put anything different you are stupid and should think about what you write.

For every rapist who they can definitely prove to be rapists! should be put in a room full of sexually fustrated people and raped themselves until they cant move.

Amen.
</post>
<post author="sapphiregold" datetime="2012-02-04T19:37:00" id="p103">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
What is they feel no guilt?
Some guy recently raped 4 woman for being on the street at night to 'teach them a lesson' i doubt he feels guilty.

</quote>

i understand were your coming from and if he doesn't feel guilt then he knows he's done bad and i think that a person who rapes is only raping someone to get attention and a boosted confidence
so people shouldn't put them selves at risk and go out late

but i think its still sad that people can think to rape someone because the same thing could happen to their mothers,daughters, sisters and they wouldn't like it
</post>
<post author="xDave-" datetime="2012-02-04T19:40:00" id="p104">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
Yeah but your being an arogant hypocrite, this is your opinion too. I wasn't even saying opinions can't be ridiculous but it's my opinion so it may seem ridiculous (in your own opinion <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/> ). Your the only person who has said its a completely ridiculous idea.

</quote>

I didn't say it's not my opinion? I just said yours is ridiculous and explained why.

I think the amount of neg rep you've gotten suggests there are many people that agree.
</post>
<post author="TheDubs" datetime="2012-02-04T19:44:00" id="p105">
So you want to put them to death, then castrate their bodies.

Harsh.
</post>
<post author="XxelliexX" datetime="2012-02-04T19:48:00" id="p106">
I personally don't think rape is as bad as murder.
If you were to ask rape victims 'would you rather have been murdered?' I would assume that most of them would say no.
Of course, this is just an assumption, and I could be wrong.

I do not believe that rapists should be put to death. Rehabilitation, forgiveness and all that. I do not think the death penalty is ever justified.

Castration on the other hand is a good idea. The story is indeed sickening, but does not justify death.
</post>
<post author="carehow" datetime="2012-02-04T19:49:00" id="p107">
<quote orig_author="Nelson94">
I cant put anymore negatives on your comments...

Unless you have been raped you would never know the experiences to come from such a horrific situation. For example a rape victim is said to go to bed most nights thinking and being scared of the thoughts which they have scarred into their memory.

I would rather die than be continuously raped and for all the members who have put anything different you are stupid and should think about what you write.

For every rapist who they can definitely prove to be rapists! should be put in a room full of sexually fustrated people and raped themselves until they cant move.

Amen.

</quote>

Don't think every rape victim thinks that way. I was raped, albeit years ago, and whilst society's revenge is definitely important, I still believe the most important thing for every criminal (including rapists) is rehabilitation.

I do, however, completely understand your opinion.
</post>
<post author="cl_steele" datetime="2012-02-04T19:56:00" id="p108">
i really cant possibly see how rape is worse than murder... if youre killed thats it no chance of recovery whilst rape might be mentally traumatising you can come back from it, you can still walk breathe and love...
and as for executing or castrating all rapists... what about the ones whove had sex with a lady and she only decides the next morning its rape? what about the ones who cry rape to get back at someone ?
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-04T20:08:00" id="p109">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
So your saying in Afganistan a woman being raped.... she doesn't really care because she has no power?
Even without sexual power a woman can still be humiliated and degraded by this.

</quote>

On average she'll care less yes, because the power inequality isn't as big in Afghanistan, so the psychological trauma she's conditioned to feel won't be as great. That's why women get raped in the East and continue with normal lives and make less of a fuss. My mum is pretty lax about rape e.g.) "she wasn't so innocent, she was a bitch." Basically, she's conditioned to not believe women should be entitled to large levels of power, nor have a pedestal via the topic of rape.

Some women fantasise about getting gang raped by black guys, it's horses for courses really. One woman suffers trauma because feminism conditioned her to feel like a princess with utmost power that shouldn't be removed. Another might dust herself off and get on with life, after grieving for a few days. Another might fantasize about it and write a book.

Anyway, it's obviously nowhere near as bad as murder, fetishists (?) view it as good. Certainly a grey area, so I deffo wouldn't apply the death penalty to it.
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-04T20:53:00" id="p110">
<quote orig_author="xDave-">
I didn't say it's not my opinion? I just said yours is ridiculous and explained why.

I think the amount of neg rep you've gotten suggests there are many people that agree.

</quote>

Logical to just ignore the fact theres more positive then negative rep in this thread <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/>
</post>
<post author="fizz113" datetime="2012-02-04T20:57:00" id="p111">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
i think rape is just as bad a murder (if not worse) because it is someone using another human being as a means to satisfy a disgusting desire of pleasure or power from someone being degraded, exploited etc.. (not in all cases ofcourse).
I would like opinions on my views:
1.People who commite rape (particularly more vile rapes) should be put to death.
2.People who rape should be castrated and imprisoned.

Now obviously theres the arguement that you can't prove it, but lets say all rapes were true.
Do you agree with my views?

EDIT: I didnt specify what situations:

I don't think someone who is drunk and gets taken advantage off is as bad a crime as if a girl is kidnapped and subject to sexual abuses/rape. It's rather the latter example where my view applies, the former is still disgusting to me and he should be punished so severly but its not as bad.

<a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/crime/9039015/Rapist-who-struck-to-teach-women-a-lesson.html">http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/ukne...-a-lesson.html</a> &lt; where my view applies.

</quote>

1.People who commite rape (particularly more vile rapes) should be put to death.

2.People who rape should be castrated and imprisoned.

<img src="http://static.themetapicture.com/media/funny-surprised-owl-WHAT.jpg"/>

You want to do both?

I believe for your view to be implemented, there has to be sufficient evidence.

As in, PROPER evidence.

Usually, rapists feel no remorse for their actions, so I would agree.
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-04T20:57:00" id="p112">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
On average she'll care less yes, because the power inequality isn't as big in Afghanistan, so the psychological trauma she's conditioned to feel won't be as great. That's why women get raped in the East and continue with normal lives and make less of a fuss. My mum is pretty lax about rape e.g.) "she wasn't so innocent, she was a bitch." Basically, she's conditioned to not believe women should be entitled to large levels of power, nor have a pedestal via the topic of rape.

Some women fantasise about getting gang raped by black guys, it's horses for courses really. One woman suffers trauma because feminism conditioned her to feel like a princess with utmost power that shouldn't be removed. Another might dust herself off and get on with life, after grieving for a few days. Another might fantasize about it and write a book.

Anyway, it's obviously nowhere near as bad as murder, fetishists (?) view it as good. Certainly a grey area, so I deffo wouldn't apply the death penalty to it.

</quote>

I think there's major problems with your views. It certainly sounds like you regard rape as a minor crime. The amount of women who fantasize about being raped isn't large and even so having a fantasy is completely different from actually being raped. Just because a woman fantasizes about it doesn't mean anything close to actually wanting be raped.
</post>
<post author="Steevee" datetime="2012-02-04T21:14:00" id="p113">
I personally think you're views are ill thought out.

I mean your first point, using someone to fufill a desire, that essentially encompasses a huge amount of crime. Theft falls under that catagory. I also think you are having a very emotional reaction to rape, which is never a good basis for law.

And if you're outrage is based on the degredation of other people, then shouldn't people who backbite, humiliate and bitch be subject to harsh punishment?

What about when a woman takes advantage of a man?

Personally I think rape should be treated as a form of assault, as it is at the moment, not given it's own special catagory because of moral outrage.
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-04T21:52:00" id="p114">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
I think there's major problems with your views. It certainly sounds like you regard rape as a minor crime. The amount of women who fantasize about being raped isn't large and even so having a fantasy is completely different from actually being raped. Just because a woman fantasizes about it doesn't mean anything close to actually wanting be raped.

</quote>

What makes rape 'bad' is the social construct surrounding it though, which is a grey area. Cavewomen didn't kick up as much of a fuss about it, eastern women don't. Why aren't they as traumatised by it? You're looking at rape mixed with western society's views, making a bad mix. However, getting killed or tortured is universally disdained and hurts people equally, so that's more clearcut to me (hence it's easier to punish). Rape was eventually 'made' very harmful, post feminism. The fetishists and eastern women get on with it, so that inconsistency =&gt; grey area. I think rape is a fairly serious crime, but it doesn't endanger anyone's life and the social mantras of society help to instill this 'trauma' that is supposedly 'caused' by rape.
</post>
<post author="goape" datetime="2012-02-04T21:57:00" id="p115">
I disagree with your views as i believe people should be given a chance to reform themselves. I would be content with a life sentence for a reoffending rapist though.
</post>
<post author="SilverArch" datetime="2012-02-04T22:11:00" id="p116">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
Some women fantasise about getting gang raped by black guys, it's horses for courses really. One woman suffers trauma because feminism conditioned her to feel like a princess with utmost power that shouldn't be removed. Another might dust herself off and get on with life, after grieving for a few days. Another might fantasize about it and write a book.

</quote>

Having a rape fantasy is totally different from wanting to be raped!! People fantasize about being choked and they don't want to die in reality!

In a fantasy, you have ultimate control over what is happening. You can stop it at any time, you can do whatever you like. You created it so you want it to happen. Real rape does not work like that. You have no control, maybe no idea whether you'll even survive or not, and guess what you don't get to choose your rapist either. Actually, I can't believe I have to point out the difference.

And as for dusting off and moving on with no ill effects...I don't believe that. Certain cultures have a big shame thing going on, so it's not acceptable to talk about it or even acknowledge it exists. I read a very sad article where rape victims in an African country were interviewed. Rape was a taboo subject so they just outwardly carried on with their lives afterwards. They gave no indication anything had ever happened it them. But inside they were suffering enormous pain and trauma effects. They asked for help. But they couldn't get help or ask for it from anyone in their own commnunity so they pretended nothing was wrong. Just because somebody acts like they are fine...does NOT mean they are really fine. Sometimes they just have no other option. You just believe that if they don't show it, they don't feel it, which is totally FALSE

And what the hell do you mean by 'utmost power'? If you mean the right to not get raped then yes I damn well do believe women have the right to consent to sex, or to NOT consent, and nobody has the right to rape another person ever
</post>
<post author="yomomalomo" datetime="2012-02-04T22:44:00" id="p117">
Rather a difficult subject, as all crimes and their respective punishments are when you begin to look at them properly.

If there was definite proof, then I would be inclined to say, from instinct, that the person should severely punished. However, on further thought, you realise that generally, the rape was most likely the result of some other issues or problems that the rapist had experienced at some point in his life (e.g being sexually abused himself). So then I would be inclined to say that they should be locked in prison for a long number of years (safety of the public), however, while in prison I believe much time should be focused on rehabilitating them.

Finally, you come to the problem of psychopathic and serial rapists, with whom no amount of rehabilitation will work, because their brain function is not comparable with ours. This may be due to some brain damage or could be genotypical. This is where the decision is hardest. Do we bother to spend great amounts of time and money on the issue, and treat these rapists through gene therapy or brain surgery? Or should we simply kill them?

The former will require resources, but will not stop, nor deter the crime. If we continue the process of the former, we may end up in a pit fall, where babies are tested at birth for certain mutant genes that are linked with psychopathy, murder, rape etc These babies would then be treated to replace these genes with normal ones. Of course you can see the problem here - it may lead us to the point where we are continually artificially altering our genotype and completely changing our race to create some sort of super or higher humanoid.

The latter, even though the initial outcome/resolution seems very different, ultimately ends in a similar problem. So we execute all of these serial rapists. We do the same for serial murderers and paedophiles. We begin to then be artificially selecting what person, or what DNA is allowed to pass on, based on the actions of the specific individual. Rather than sort the problem out or issue out, we simply remove it, quickly and efficiently. What do we do to prevent the crime further, using some foreknowledge? Do we again test babies, or foetuses for specific genes and then terminate them? If so, we end up with nearly the exact, but probably less effective, result as the former solution.

So really, I think that certain issues like these should be seriously excogitated and debated, before any decision or new change is made. I think that one idea is quite good: all our stats and knowledge on rapists and rape crime should be disclosed to the accepting public. Having looked through the information and coming to an informed decision, we should then have a referendum. There is no perfect or right solution, however, we should strive to provide the best solution which appeases the majority of the country at that specific time - holding a referendum seems to do that quite well, though there are of course other options...
</post>
<post author="Like a BAWS" datetime="2012-02-04T22:46:00" id="p118">
In some cases, rapists DO deserve more severe punishments than murderers.

For instance, a father discovers that a man kidnapped and raped his daughter. With uncontrollable anger, he finds and murders the rapist.

Although obviously not condoning such behaviour, I don't think the father in that case should have such a severe punishment as the rapist.
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-04T23:01:00" id="p119">
<quote orig_author="SilverArch">
Having a rape fantasy is totally different from wanting to be raped!! People fantasize about being choked and they don't want to die in reality!

In a fantasy, you have ultimate control over what is happening. You can stop it at any time, you can do whatever you like. You created it so you want it to happen. Real rape does not work like that. You have no control, maybe no idea whether you'll even survive or not, and guess what you don't get to choose your rapist either. Actually, I can't believe I have to point out the difference.

And as for dusting off and moving on with no ill effects...I don't believe that. Certain cultures have a big shame thing going on, so it's not acceptable to talk about it or even acknowledge it exists. I read a very sad article where rape victims in an African country were interviewed. Rape was a taboo subject so they just outwardly carried on with their lives afterwards. They gave no indication anything had ever happened it them. But inside they were suffering enormous pain and trauma effects. They asked for help. But they couldn't get help or ask for it from anyone in their own commnunity so they pretended nothing was wrong. Just because somebody acts like they are fine...does NOT mean they are really fine. Sometimes they just have no other option. You just believe that if they don't show it, they don't feel it, which is totally FALSE

And what the hell do you mean by 'utmost power'? If you mean the right to not get raped then yes I damn well do believe women have the right to consent to sex, or to NOT consent, and nobody has the right to rape another person ever

</quote>

But many women (especially in non-westernised/feminised) nations get over it without much long term damage and don't think it's as bad as death. I believe women were conditioned in recent decades to react the way they do; rape hasn't always been seen in the same light and the psychological traumas haven't always been as bad. I think there needs to be a consensus reached about what kind and of what scale the mental trauma is due to rape alone; not a western woman talking about having 'power stripped away'. I HATE IT when women talk like that; instead of caring about health, dignity or degradation they care about 'power'. That only backs what I say; foreign women don't have that power inequality conditioning instilled into them by society, so it ain't as big of a deal to them.
</post>
<post author="XO*" datetime="2012-02-04T23:04:00" id="p120">
And you get more years for dealing cocaine than committing rape. Pathetic justice system in the UK we have :/
</post>
<post author="Snagprophet" datetime="2012-02-04T23:06:00" id="p121">
Tbh, we should be doing whatever is cheapest. If shooting someone in the head will stop them from raping people and committing other victimful crimes, then that's what I think should happen.
</post>
<post author="SaySaam" datetime="2012-02-04T23:07:00" id="p122">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
I don't think someone who is drunk and gets taken advantage off is as bad a crime as if a girl is kidnapped and subject to sexual abuses/rape. It's rather the latter example where my view applies, the former is still disgusting to me and he should be punished so severly but its not as bad.

</quote>

Rape is rape.
</post>
<post author="carehow" datetime="2012-02-04T23:10:00" id="p123">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
What makes rape 'bad' is the social construct surrounding it though, which is a grey area. Cavewomen didn't kick up as much of a fuss about it, eastern women don't. Why aren't they as traumatised by it? You're looking at rape mixed with western society's views, making a bad mix. However, getting killed or tortured is universally disdained and hurts people equally, so that's more clearcut to me (hence it's easier to punish). Rape was eventually 'made' very harmful, post feminism. The fetishists and eastern women get on with it, so that inconsistency =&gt; grey area. I think rape is a fairly serious crime, but it doesn't endanger anyone's life and the social mantras of society help to instill this 'trauma' that is supposedly 'caused' by rape.

</quote>

So, in your opinion, the only thing that makes rape harmful/wrong is the stripping away of the victim's power? If the victim has little power to begin with, it's not harmful?

EDIT: Do you view the stripping away of power through rape wrong in itself, disregarding feminism in modern society?
</post>
<post author="Historophilia" datetime="2012-02-04T23:10:00" id="p124">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
What makes rape 'bad' is the social construct surrounding it though, which is a grey area. Cavewomen didn't kick up as much of a fuss about it, eastern women don't. Why aren't they as traumatised by it? You're looking at rape mixed with western society's views, making a bad mix. However, getting killed or tortured is universally disdained and hurts people equally, so that's more clearcut to me (hence it's easier to punish). Rape was eventually 'made' very harmful, post feminism. The fetishists and eastern women get on with it, so that inconsistency =&gt; grey area. I think rape is a fairly serious crime, but it doesn't endanger anyone's life and the social mantras of society help to instill this 'trauma' that is supposedly 'caused' by rape.

</quote>

I have been trying to restrain myself but I can't anymore.

Your views are genuinely the most morally abhorrent that I ever encountered.
</post>
<post author="SilverArch" datetime="2012-02-04T23:17:00" id="p125">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
But many women (especially in non-westernised/feminised) nations get over it without much long term damage and don't think it's as bad as death. I believe women were conditioned in recent decades to react the way they do; rape hasn't always been seen in the same light and the psychological traumas haven't always been as bad. I think there needs to be a consensus reached about what kind and of what scale the mental trauma is due to rape alone; not a western woman talking about having 'power stripped away'. I HATE IT when women talk like that; instead of caring about health, dignity or degradation they care about 'power'. That only backs what I say; foreign women don't have that power inequality conditioning instilled into them by society, so it ain't as big of a deal to them.

</quote>

But they DON'T get over it without long term damage!!! Did you not read the whole of my last post? I already responded to this. Not talking about it =/= forgetting about it, or being unscathed. A culture of silence does not mean the women are not hurt. If anything I would argue they are more affected because they can't get help, so their trauma doesn't get addressed. Rape is a BIG deal and your views really are nasty as well as misinformed <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/mad.gif" alt=":mad:"/>
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-04T23:19:00" id="p126">
<quote orig_author="carehow">
So, in your opinion, the only thing that makes rape harmful/wrong is the stripping away of the victim's power? If the victim has little power to begin with, it's not harmful?

</quote>

My view is the opposite; some of the the trauma attributed to rape is really due to social conditioning empowering women in recent decades, hence why other women are less affected if they aren't conditioned that way. I can accept degradation, physical pain, health issues, trust issues etc as that's something closer to universal; but the 'power strip' issues modern western women cry about is another 'problem'. That's the one many seem to care about most, too.
</post>
<post author="tompy123" datetime="2012-02-04T23:19:00" id="p127">
However, some victims might feel even worse if their offender was killed, instead of being imprisoned and rehabilitated.
</post>
<post author="catoswyn" datetime="2012-02-04T23:21:00" id="p128">
<quote orig_author="carehow">
So, in your opinion, the only thing that makes rape harmful/wrong is the stripping away of the victim's power? If the victim has little power to begin with, it's not harmful?

EDIT: Do you view the stripping away of power through rape wrong in itself, disregarding feminism in modern society?

</quote>

How do you come to the conclusion that eastern women are not as traumatised and accept rape? My experience of living in the east is that this is not the case at all. Have you seen some of the punishments for rape in other countries? I have seen a man being executed by crucifixtion in public for being a rapist. How do you possibly know what a cavewoman felt about anything? Maybe it would help you if you just accepted that for most rational people rape IS a form of torture... nothing to do with feminism.. the same applies to male rape.
</post>
<post author="carehow" datetime="2012-02-04T23:24:00" id="p129">
<quote orig_author="catoswyn">
How do you come to the conclusion that eastern women are not as traumatised and accept rape? My experienceof living in the east is that this is not the case at all. How do you possibly know what a cavewoman felt about anything? You really are a popularist of the worst order.

</quote>

Don't understand why I was quoted, I don't think this at all? <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/confused.gif" alt=":confused:"/>
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-04T23:26:00" id="p130">
<quote orig_author="SilverArch">
But they DON'T get over it without long term damage!!! Did you not read the whole of my last post? I already responded to this. Not talking about it =/= forgetting about it, or being unscathed. A culture of silence does not mean the women are not hurt. If anything I would argue they are more affected because they can't get help, so their trauma doesn't get addressed. Rape is a BIG deal and your views really are nasty as well as misinformed <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/mad.gif" alt=":mad:"/>

</quote>

You're making this up as you go along, you can't mind read what they think, nor is it fair to map how western women would feel under silence to how other women may feel. Other women tend to get on with their life and I've never read anything about great depression, suicide rates etc in eastern nations. If that exists, I'll take notice. If they're getting on with life and it's you speaking on behalf of them, well...
</post>
<post author="carehow" datetime="2012-02-04T23:28:00" id="p131">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
My view is the opposite; some of the the trauma attributed to rape is really due to social conditioning empowering women in recent decades, hence why other women are less affected if they aren't conditioned that way. I can accept degradation, physical pain, health issues, trust issues etc as that's something closer to universal; but the 'power strip' issues modern western women cry about is another 'problem'. That's the one many seem to care about most, too.

</quote>

Thankyou for clarifying - I must emphasize what you said though, only some of the trauma attributed to rape is due to social conditioning. Rape is traumatising in any culture. I think women deserve the power over their own body, so I personally think that trauma is justified, although I do accept the allocation of power - to anything - is due to the society a person is living in.
</post>
<post author="littleangel9914" datetime="2012-02-04T23:28:00" id="p132">
<quote orig_author="sapphiregold">
i understand were your coming from and if he doesn't feel guilt then he knows he's done bad and i think that a person who rapes is only raping someone to get attention and a boosted confidence
so people shouldn't put them selves at risk and go out late

but i think its still sad that people can think to rape someone because the same thing could happen to their mothers,daughters, sisters and they wouldn't like it

</quote>

So because he doesn't feel any guilt he knows he done wrong
How does that make any sense as far as he concerned he thinks he should be praised for teaching them a lesson
Also you make it sound like you feel that these women are somewhat at fault for being out late when they did nothing wrong
</post>
<post author="Snagprophet" datetime="2012-02-04T23:31:00" id="p133">
Tbh, OP, I have to say you're the most forward thinking person I've ever seen on a forum.
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-04T23:31:00" id="p134">
<quote orig_author="carehow">
Thankyou for clarifying - I must emphasize what you said though, only some of the trauma attributed to rape is due to social conditioning. Rape is traumatising in any culture. I think women deserve the power over their own body, so I personally think that trauma is justified, although I do accept the allocation of power - to anything - is due to the society a person is living in.

</quote>

Yep, I agree, it's a bad crime. But it gets 'over-egged' in the West because of social conditioning, which is another problem in itself. That's what I was writing about.
</post>
<post author="littleangel9914" datetime="2012-02-04T23:32:00" id="p135">
<quote orig_author="tompy123">
However, some victims might feel even worse if their offender was killed, instead of being imprisoned and rehabilitated.

</quote>

You obviously don't understand what it's like to be the victim of a horrific crime
</post>
<post author="catoswyn" datetime="2012-02-04T23:32:00" id="p136">
The problem for me is the rehabilitation aspect. Sex criminals are hard to re-habilitate under our current regime and often go on to re-offend. In Denmark treatment is much more pro-active and can involve medication to control beahviour and dangerous urges. We don't allow that here and I think we should. No rapist should be released until it is clear that they have undergo such treatment that they will no longer pose a danger.
</post>
<post author="catoswyn" datetime="2012-02-04T23:35:00" id="p137">
<quote orig_author="carehow">
So, in your opinion, the only thing that makes rape harmful/wrong is the stripping away of the victim's power? If the victim has little power to begin with, it's not harmful?

EDIT: Do you view the stripping away of power through rape wrong in itself, disregarding feminism in modern society?

</quote>

Sorry, I attached my last comment to you by mistake!
</post>
<post author="catoswyn" datetime="2012-02-04T23:37:00" id="p138">
<quote orig_author="carehow">
Don't understand why I was quoted, I don't think this at all? <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/confused.gif" alt=":confused:"/>

</quote>

Sorry, my mistake, got the wrong person!
</post>
<post author="carehow" datetime="2012-02-04T23:39:00" id="p139">
<quote orig_author="catoswyn">
Sorry, I attached my last comment to you by mistake!

</quote>

No worries <img src="images/smilies/tongue.png"/>
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-04T23:40:00" id="p140">
<quote orig_author="catoswyn">
How do you come to the conclusion that eastern women are not as traumatised and accept rape?

</quote>

They make little fuss about it, they get on with their lives, they don't go insane or kill themselves, there aren't documented reports of widespread depression problems. If there are, I want to see them.

<quote orig_author="catoswyn">
My experience of living in the east is that this is not the case at all.

</quote>

My experience is that it is. Living =/= being, either. They see rape differently.

<quote orig_author="catoswyn">
Have you seen some of the punishments for rape in other countries? I have seen a man being executed by crucifixtion in public for being a rapist. How do you possibly know what a cavewoman felt about anything? Maybe it would help you if you just accepted that for most rational people rape IS a form of torture... nothing to do with feminism.. the same applies to male rape.

</quote>

Exactly, the variance means rape is still a grey area and we don't really know HOW people are affected SOLELY by the rape. That's one of my key points, hence why it's not on-a-par with death. It's one person's fantasy and another's worst form of torture. For law, there needs to be more clarity.
</post>
<post author="catoswyn" datetime="2012-02-04T23:41:00" id="p141">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
On average she'll care less yes, because the power inequality isn't as big in Afghanistan, so the psychological trauma she's conditioned to feel won't be as great. That's why women get raped in the East and continue with normal lives and make less of a fuss. My mum is pretty lax about rape e.g.) &amp;quot;she wasn't so innocent, she was a bitch.&amp;quot; Basically, she's conditioned to not believe women should be entitled to large levels of power, nor have a pedestal via the topic of rape.

Some women fantasise about getting gang raped by black guys, it's horses for courses really. One woman suffers trauma because feminism conditioned her to feel like a princess with utmost power that shouldn't be removed. Another might dust herself off and get on with life, after grieving for a few days. Another might fantasize about it and write a book.

Anyway, it's obviously nowhere near as bad as murder, fetishists (?) view it as good. Certainly a grey area, so I deffo wouldn't apply the death penalty to it.

</quote>

How do you come to the conclusion that all eastern women are not as traumatised and accept rape? My experience of living in the east is that this is not the case at all. Have you seen some of the punishments for rape in other countries? I have seen a man being executed by crucifixtion in public for being a rapist. How do you possibly know what a cavewoman felt about anything? Maybe it would help you if you just accepted that for most rational people rape IS a form of torture... nothing to do with feminism.. the same applies to male rape. Don't draw all your conclusions from your mother's point of view. There is also the issue of deflection and methods of coping. You are looking at the surface only and have no idea of what it meant to that woman you see as 'dusting herself down and getting on with it'.

Yours is the type of view held by rapists themselves... some women won't be affected so much... they are black or poor or slaves or servants or working class or they were asking for it.... in your case its they come from non-western cultures. Apparently that makes rape less of an issue for them. Complete and utter tosh. Go do some reading of case studies and victim profiles and survivor reports.
</post>
<post author="chocoholic." datetime="2012-02-04T23:42:00" id="p142">
I agree with you on the castration, but it depends how 'brutal' the act was for the rapist to be sentenced to death.
</post>
<post author="chocoholic." datetime="2012-02-04T23:46:00" id="p143">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
They make little fuss about it, they get on with their lives, they don't go insane or kill themselves, there aren't documented reports of widespread depression problems. If there are, I want to see them.

My experience is that it is. Living =/= being, either. They see rape differently.

Exactly, the variance means rape is still a grey area and we don't really know HOW people are affected SOLELY by the rape. That's one of my key points, hence why it's not on-a-par with death. It's one person's fantasy and another's worst form of torture. For law, there needs to be more clarity.

</quote>

The reason they don't make a 'fuss' of it is because they are scared what their community would think of them or the punishment they would get if they couldn't prove the rape. We are talking about the Middle East here women are treated poorly. They don't tell through fear, just because they don't tell people dpesn't mean they aren't suffering.
</post>
<post author="Chloe xxx" datetime="2012-02-04T23:47:00" id="p144">
All rapist are warped individuals that should be anally crucified.
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-04T23:47:00" id="p145">
<quote orig_author="catoswyn">
How do you come to the conclusion that all eastern women are not as traumatised and accept rape? My experience of living in the east is that this is not the case at all. Have you seen some of the punishments for rape in other countries? I have seen a man being executed by crucifixtion in public for being a rapist. How do you possibly know what a cavewoman felt about anything? Maybe it would help you if you just accepted that for most rational people rape IS a form of torture... nothing to do with feminism.. the same applies to male rape. Don't draw all your conclusions from your mother's point of view. There is also the issue of deflection and methods of coping. You are looking at the surface only and have no idea of what it meant to that woman you see as 'dusting herself down and getting on with it'.

</quote>

Don't annoy me with that 'all' line of argument, that's a waste of time isn't it. I replied to the rest already. Regarding the last part... the fact there's so little clarity about the actual trauma caused by rape validates why it's not on-a-par with death. It's nowhere near in my own view, it doesn't endanger a person's life and they DO have a chance to recover and lead a normal life. Many do and that's a good thing.

Women are told to recover from rape and get on with life, that it's not the end, they can recover, etc. Yet on the flipside, they're told it's the worst crime ever. That's a contradiction, as the worst crimes don't give you the gift of a potentially fairly 'normal' life. Or any life whatsoever i.e.) death. These are the ills of social conditioning, which rapists also take blame for.
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-04T23:50:00" id="p146">
<quote orig_author="chocoholic.">
The reason they don't make a 'fuss' of it is because they are scared what their community would think of them or the punishment they would get if they couldn't prove the rape. We are talking about the Middle East here women are treated poorly. They don't tell through fear, just because they don't tell people dpesn't mean they aren't suffering.

</quote>

Yet with all that bottling up, they aren't going crazy, killing themselves or having severe breakdowns or depression; none that's been widely documented anyway. So it's inconclusive, a greay area, as I said. The biggest fuss about rape is made in the West, especially post feminism.
</post>
<post author="catoswyn" datetime="2012-02-04T23:52:00" id="p147">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
They make little fuss about it, they get on with their lives, they don't go insane or kill themselves, there aren't documented reports of widespread depression problems. If there are, I want to see them.

My experience is that it is. Living =/= being, either. They see rape differently.

Exactly, the variance means rape is still a grey area and we don't really know HOW people are affected SOLELY by the rape. That's one of my key points, hence why it's not on-a-par with death. It's one person's fantasy and another's worst form of torture. For law, there needs to be more clarity.

</quote>

I think you are confusing the public face with the private reality. In your culture perhaps depression is not advertised by the authorities rather than it doesn't exist for example.
</post>
<post author="chocoholic." datetime="2012-02-04T23:56:00" id="p148">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
Yet with all that bottling up, they aren't going crazy, killing themselves or having severe breakdowns or depression; none that's been widely documented anyway. So it's inconclusive, a greay area, as I said. The biggest fuss about rape is made in the West, especially post feminism.

</quote>

You've got to be kidding me. Do you know how difficult it is to prove Adultery or rape in countries like Saudi? For stuff like that 3 witnesses are required, who also must see the pair in the act, this means not just lying in bed together, but the actual act. If someone accuses someone of adultery without evidence they receive 60 lashes, if someone accuses a man of rape without proof they get 100 lashes. The thought of that shuts quite a few women up. Just because these suicides, breakdowns and depressions are not made public does not mean women in the Middle East do not suffer as much.
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-04T23:56:00" id="p149">
<quote orig_author="catoswyn">
I think you are confusing the public face with the private reality. In your culture perhaps depression is not advertised by the authorities rather than it doesn't exist for example.

</quote>

But you're only guessing how they may feel, and it ain't bad enough to lead to widespread documented cases of depression, suicide, etc; with all that 'bottling' up. There needs to be a universal appreciation of what the sole effects of rape are, before it gets the brand of being worse than death. The varying impact from one culture to the next only puts a Q mark over the topic.
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-05T00:00:00" id="p150">
<quote orig_author="chocoholic.">
You've got to be kidding me. Do you know how difficult it is to prove Adultery or rape in countries like Saudi? For stuff like that 3 witnesses are required, who also must see the pair in the act, this means not just lying in bed together, but the actual act. If someone accuses someone of adultery without evidence they receive 60 lashes, if someone accuses a man of rape without proof they get 100 lashes. The thought of that shuts quite a few women up. Just because these suicides, breakdowns and depressions are not made public does not mean women in the Middle East do not suffer as much.

</quote>

You don't know how they feel, which is the whole frigging point. All you've been doing is speaking on their behalf and mapping western women's feelings regarding rape onto eastern women. It's flawed, it's a grey area, it's massively debatable.
</post>
<post author="catoswyn" datetime="2012-02-05T00:02:00" id="p151">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
They make little fuss about it, they get on with their lives, they don't go insane or kill themselves, there aren't documented reports of widespread depression problems. If there are, I want to see them.

My experience is that it is. Living =/= being, either. They see rape differently.

Exactly, the variance means rape is still a grey area and we don't really know HOW people are affected SOLELY by the rape. That's one of my key points, hence why it's not on-a-par with death. It's one person's fantasy and another's worst form of torture. For law, there needs to be more clarity.

</quote>

Ah I see. All this only applies if the punishment should reflect the level of distress experienced by the victim rather than the absolute moral code violated in law. I'm an absolutist on this. I don't care if the victim were to skip away singing 'what a beautiful morning' (unlikely!) Rape is rape. It is dangerous behaviour. The next victim might not 'skip away' at all. The perpertrator should be imprisoned and treated; they should not be released until we are certain that they will not repeat their behaviour. If you come from a culture where rape is accepted as a norm even by its women then I ask you to think about working to change that rather than buying into it.
</post>
<post author="catoswyn" datetime="2012-02-05T00:05:00" id="p152">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
But you're only guessing how they may feel, and it ain't bad enough to lead to widespread documented cases of depression, suicide, etc; with all that 'bottling' up. There needs to be a universal appreciation of what the sole effects of rape are, before it gets the brand of being worse than death. The varying impact from one culture to the next only puts a Q mark over the topic.

</quote>

I don't think its worse than death! I'm not arguing for that at all. The worse than death argument is what causes some women to kill themselves after rape rather than live with the 'shame'.
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-05T00:05:00" id="p153">
<quote orig_author="catoswyn">
Ah I see. All this only applies if the punishment should reflect the level of distress experienced by the victim rather than the absolute moral code violated in law. I'm an absolutist on this. I don't care if the victim were to skip away singing 'what a beautiful morning' (unlikely!) Rape is rape. It is dangerous behaviour. The next victim might not 'skip away' at all. The perpertrator should be imprisoned and treated; they should not be released until we are certain that they will not repeat their behaviour. If you come from a culture where rape is accepted as a norm even by its women then I ask you to think about working to change that rather than buying into it.

</quote>

Yes, fair enough then, I do care about the level of punishment inflicted solely by rape, hence the grey area problem. It is a bad crime and dangerous, obviously. But my point is that if some people DO skip away singing laa laa after it, then it's very hard to make the case of rape being on-a-par with death.
</post>
<post author="chocoholic." datetime="2012-02-05T00:06:00" id="p154">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
You don't know how they feel, which is the whole frigging point. All you've been doing is speaking on their behalf and mapping western women's feelings regarding rape onto eastern women. It's flawed, it's a grey area, it's massively debatable.

</quote>

You make no sense.

That argument could go either I could say the same to you that you are making all Eastern women sound as though they accept rape.
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-05T00:09:00" id="p155">
<quote orig_author="catoswyn">
I don't think its worse than death! I'm not arguing for that at all. The worse than death argument is what causes some women to kill themselves after rape rather than live with the 'shame'.

</quote>

Yes, but my other point is that the feeling of shame or feeling suicidal is largely inflicted by social conditioning, not the act of rape itself. It's society that causes women to feel x, y, z post-rape; they instilled that type of thinking. It's not a healthy one either in my view. That's a problem, isn't it?
</post>
<post author="catoswyn" datetime="2012-02-05T00:09:00" id="p156">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
You don't know how they feel, which is the whole frigging point. All you've been doing is speaking on their behalf and mapping western women's feelings regarding rape onto eastern women. It's flawed, it's a grey area, it's massively debatable.

</quote>

I understand about the 'mapping western experience' onto Eastern women but I just don't agree. I've lived there, talked with the women, heard their views, listened to their experiences. Are you male or female? If male how do you know what is talked about between the women other than your family members? How do you know what they say about depression and rape and men generally. It doesn't make pretty listening. Anyway, its all opened up a debate on the absolute crime v the cultural context so very interesting!
</post>
<post author="Dippy Dip" datetime="2012-02-05T00:12:00" id="p157">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
i think rape is just as bad a murder (if not worse) because it is someone using another human being as a means to satisfy a disgusting desire of pleasure or power from someone being degraded, exploited etc.. (not in all cases ofcourse).
I would like opinions on my views:
1.People who commite rape (particularly more vile rapes) should be put to death.
2.People who rape should be castrated and imprisoned.

Now obviously theres the arguement that you can't prove it, but lets say all rapes were true.
Do you agree with my views?

EDIT: I didnt specify what situations:

I don't think someone who is drunk and gets taken advantage off is as bad a crime as if a girl is kidnapped and subject to sexual abuses/rape. It's rather the latter example where my view applies, the former is still disgusting to me and he should be punished so severly but its not as bad.

<a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/crime/9039015/Rapist-who-struck-to-teach-women-a-lesson.html">http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/ukne...-a-lesson.html</a> &amp;lt; where my view applies.

</quote>

As I completely disagree with the death sentence, think castration is far, far worse than death, and generally think prison is a place for rehabilitating people and not punishing them, I would say that I completely disagree with how you'd punish rape. Capital punishment is just a way for the self-proclaimed innocents to convey their sadistic fantasies. I agree with you that rape is worse than murder though.
</post>
<post author="chocoholic." datetime="2012-02-05T00:15:00" id="p158">
<quote orig_author="Dippy Dip">
As I completely disagree with the death sentence, think castration is far, far worse than death, and generally think prison is a place for rehabilitating people and not punishing them, I would say that I completely disagree with how you'd punish rape. Capital punishment is just a way for the self-proclaimed innocents to convey their sadistic fantasies. I agree with you that rape is worse than murder though.

</quote>

Why would castration be worse than murder?
</post>
<post author="Physics Enemy" datetime="2012-02-05T00:16:00" id="p159">
<quote orig_author="catoswyn">
I understand about the 'mapping western experience' onto Eastern women but I just don't agree. I've lived there, talked with the women, heard their views, listened to their experiences. Are you male or female? If male how do you know what is talked about between the women other than your family members? How do you know what they say about depression and rape and men generally. It doesn't make pretty listening.

</quote>

I don't believe they were chronic depressed to the point of not getting on with life, or trying to kill themselves, or mentally 'ill', over rape. It's not even close to death. The fact some over-egg rape to make it as bad as death is only an insult to victims; their traumas don't need embellishing, it should have weight by itself.

I feel this is going round in circles now, since we both agree rape is not on a par with death, or even near. We also acknowledge the grey areas over rape and how culture plays a big factor. So let's leave it there.
</post>
<post author="xev bellringer" datetime="2012-02-05T00:20:00" id="p160">
I'm all for the castration of rapists except statutory rape provided the male is under 20 and the female lied about her age.

I'd want the death penalty for (vicious) spousal rape,war rape,acquaintance rape and institutional rape ie in hospital or nursing home.

Why would/should a man force his penis inside someone else.Only a monster would do such a thing and they deserve nothing short of death.

Women in wartime face a horrendous time what with the festive gangrapes and putting guns in female genitals and pulling the trigger.
</post>
<post author="xev bellringer" datetime="2012-02-05T00:24:00" id="p161">
I'm all for the castration of rapists except statutory rape provided the male is under 20 and the female lied about her age.

I'd want the death penalty for (vicious) spousal rape,war rape,acquaintance rape and institutional rape ie in hospital or nursing home.

Why would/should a man force his penis inside someone else.Only a monster would do such a thing and they deserve nothing short of death.

Women in wartime face a horrendous time what with the festive gangrapes and putting guns in female genitals and pulling the trigger.
</post>
<post author="catoswyn" datetime="2012-02-05T00:41:00" id="p162">
<quote orig_author="xev bellringer">
I'm all for the castration of rapists except statutory rape provided the male is under 20 and the female lied about her age.

I'd want the death penalty for (vicious) spousal rape,war rape,acquaintance rape and institutional rape ie in hospital or nursing home.

Why would/should a man force his penis inside someone else.Only a monster would do such a thing and they deserve nothing short of death.

Women in wartime face a horrendous time what with the festive gangrapes and putting guns in female genitals and pulling the trigger.

</quote>

Very clear set of guidelines. Good to see a male actually taking a strong anti-rape stance. I was beginning to worry until I read you and Chocaholic! I'm not for the death penalty myself as I can't condone institualised murder. However I do think much more severe punishments are needed including life imprisonment and I'm all for chemical castration (ie the compulsory use of medications) I agree with you about war rape. Some of the most harrowing stories I have read on line are from war zones. Must come under the code of war crimes surely?
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-05T01:19:00" id="p163">
<quote orig_author="Dippy Dip">
As I completely disagree with the death sentence, think castration is far, far worse than death, and generally think prison is a place for rehabilitating people and not punishing them, I would say that I completely disagree with how you'd punish rape. Capital punishment is just a way for the self-proclaimed innocents to convey their sadistic fantasies. I agree with you that rape is worse than murder though.

</quote>

When you say this are you refering to me?
Or the victims?

I just think rape is an extremely disgusting crime and should be dealth with iron fist.
</post>
<post author="xev bellringer" datetime="2012-02-05T01:21:00" id="p164">
<quote orig_author="catoswyn">
Very clear set of guidelines. Good to see a male actually taking a strong anti-rape stance. I agree with you about war rape. Some of the most harrowing stories I have read on line are from war zones. Must come under the code of war crimes surely?

</quote>

Whoa there....I have a vagina LOL...sorry not a male.I too have to watch my back when walking down dark streets and make sure I watch my drink.A couple of my friends have been spiked at uni.

Most men are good honest and trustworthy.Its just the few who give the rest a bad name.
</post>
<post author="Dippy Dip" datetime="2012-02-05T01:24:00" id="p165">
<quote orig_author="chocoholic.">
Why would castration be worse than murder?

</quote>

I strongly oppose castration. Our sexuality is something that follows us our whole lives, and it's a big part of us. I'm fortunate to not have experienced castration, but in my opinion, living without a functioning set of genitals is the very definition of hell - too much of you has been taken away to make life worth living. To quote the great philosopher Donnie Darko (:P), ''what's the point in living, if you don't have a dick?''. That's only in my opinion, and I feel the same way about losing a penis as I do losing sight, arms, or the ability to function mentally.

Granted, our freedom is something that the state gives us, so I understand imprisonment. Your genitals, however, are nobody's business to tamper with.
</post>
<post author="Philbert" datetime="2012-02-05T01:28:00" id="p166">
<quote orig_author="Dippy Dip">
I strongly oppose castration. Our sexuality is something that follows us our whole lives, and it's a big part of us. I'm fortunate to not have experienced castration, but in my opinion, living without your penis is the very definition of hell - too much of you has been taken away to make life worth living. To quote the great philosopher Donnie Darko (:P), ''what's the point in living, if you don't have a dick?''. That's only in my opinion, and I feel the same way about losing a penis as I do losing sight, arms, or the ability to function mentally.

Granted, our freedom is something that the state gives us, so I understand imprisonment. A penis however is something nobody should be allowed to take away from you.

</quote>

Castration =/= penectomy.
</post>
<post author="Dippy Dip" datetime="2012-02-05T01:36:00" id="p167">
<quote orig_author="Philbert">
Castration =/= penectomy.

</quote>

Sorry for that. I'm aware they're not the same, but I always see loss of function of genitals and losing them altogether to be one in the same. I'll change it so it doesn't make me sound like an idiot.
</post>
<post author="DalimIrubab" datetime="2012-02-05T01:39:00" id="p168">
I don't agree with the death penalty simply because my mind cannot accept that a perfectly healthy human being is put to death by a government that is supposed to set a good example for all. How does murder set a good example?
</post>
<post author="Dippy Dip" datetime="2012-02-05T01:40:00" id="p169">
<quote orig_author="DdotT">
When you say this are you refering to me?
Or the victims?

I just think rape is an extremely disgusting crime and should be dealth with iron fist.

</quote>

I'm referring to anybody who agrees with capital punishment. Victims of crimes get a bit more leeway here, but the people who only read about it in the newspaper or hear stories don't.

I don't disagree that rape is horrendous either, but the idea of just killing off all the wrongdoers, to me, is idiotic as well as sadistic.
</post>
<post author="SubAtomic" datetime="2012-02-05T01:49:00" id="p170">
Why feed and water someone who has completely wrecked another human beings life in a very bad way? Waste of space money and all the rest, if someone has without a doubt commited the act then bye bye forever, but maybe have them raped first so they know how it feels <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/eek.gif" alt=":eek:"/> then bullet straight in the head none of this death row last meal and all that long wait
</post>
<post author="umarrehman187" datetime="2012-02-05T01:56:00" id="p171">
welcome to the shariah law well its not eactly like tht but along the same lines
</post>
<post author="SubAtomic" datetime="2012-02-05T02:01:00" id="p172">
Yes there are some parts of foreign land laws that I would see as acceptable for certain crimes, problem being the innocent who are found guilty.
Example, man caught in the act raping a male or female, instant death no trial no problem. Or woman caught fiddling with a kid(not the violin) same punishment, instant death no time for trial just enough time to say bye
</post>
<post author="DdotT" datetime="2012-02-05T02:23:00" id="p173">
<quote orig_author="Dippy Dip">
I'm referring to anybody who agrees with capital punishment. Victims of crimes get a bit more leeway here, but the people who only read about it in the newspaper or hear stories don't.

I don't disagree that rape is horrendous either, but the idea of just killing off all the wrongdoers, to me, is idiotic as well as sadistic.

</quote>

The thing is i'd rather argue for Capital Punishment rather then stick by - Capital punishment is just sadistic and is no better then the person who committed the crime, but then that just leaves a void where no justice has been served. The Justice system will let them get out after a short sentance. So i'd rather argue for capital punishment, because atleast justice has been served.
</post>
<post author="Blazara" datetime="2012-02-05T02:33:00" id="p174">
<quote orig_author="Wave">
I dont condone rape but I do believe the "it's on the level of murder" type of revulsion against rape is just a human cultural thing. If I attacked a woman and forced my finger up her nose should I be put to death as a rapist? I could of got tons of sexual satisfaction out of it, the woman could of been intensly traumatised by it. But if I were to shove a different body part up her nose then suddenly it's on par with murder? Even forcing your finger up someone's anus is entrely subjective to the culture as to whether that is actually a sexual attack (the anus is as much of a sexual organ as the nostril is). Again of course rape is abominable but it is in no way worse than murder. Your family never see you again. You never get to live again, god knows what happens to you when you die it could be horrifically awful..

</quote>

Your post is wrong in so many ways and shows absolutely zero understanding of what 'rape' actually is.

By statute rape is: The use of a penis in the penetration of a vagina, anus or mouth, without consent of the other person.

That's it. Anything else is a different sexual offence. Sticking a finger up your nose is a battery, little else - the objective observer would not believe it to be a sexual act, so it wouldn't be a sexual offence.

Anus is a sexual organ, it's well known that the existence of an 'anal g-spot' exists and it is a commonly used orifice for sexual gratification. Saying otherwise is absurd.

Re other issues - the use of force is irrelevant. Rape is about consent, and very little else. The drunk girl who is too drunk to respond (and hence isn't physically held down) is as much raped as the girl with a gun to her head.
</post>
<post author="Stasiaxx" datetime="2012-02-05T02:38:00" id="p175">
<quote orig_author="Physics Enemy">
But many women (especially in non-westernised/feminised) nations get over it without much long term damage and don't think it's as bad as death. I believe women were conditioned in recent decades to react the way they do; rape hasn't always been seen in the same light and the psychological traumas haven't always been as bad. I think there needs to be a consensus reached about what kind and of what scale the mental trauma is due to rape alone; not a western woman talking about having 'power stripped away'. I HATE IT when women talk like that; instead of caring about health, dignity or degradation they care about 'power'. That only backs what I say; foreign women don't have that power inequality conditioning instilled into them by society, so it ain't as big of a deal to them.

</quote>

"were conditioned" is not an argument people used to be beheaded and hung in public... You are also assuming you know how women who were raped feel,you don't.

You sound like a sick individual, stay inside.
</post>
<post author="Wave" datetime="2012-02-05T02:39:00" id="p176">
<quote orig_author="Blazara">
Your post is wrong in so many ways and shows absolutely zero understanding of what 'rape' actually is.

By statute rape is: The use of a penis in the penetration of a vagina, anus or mouth, without consent of the other person.

That's it. Anything else is a different sexual offence. Sticking a finger up your nose is a battery, little else - the objective observer would not believe it to be a sexual act, so it wouldn't be a sexual offence.

Anus is a sexual organ, it's well known that the existence of an 'anal g-spot' exists and it is a commonly used orifice for sexual gratification. Saying otherwise is absurd.

Re other issues - the use of force is irrelevant. Rape is about consent, and very little else. The drunk girl who is too drunk to respond (and hence isn't physically held down) is as much raped as the girl with a gun to her head.

</quote>

The anus is a sexual organ? where did you learn biology? I have one sexual organ...my penis. Anal g-spot? what is this i dont even...
</post>
<post author="Blazara" datetime="2012-02-05T02:42:00" id="p177">
<quote orig_author="Wave">
The anus is a sexual organ? where did you learn biology? I have one sexual organ...my penis. Anal g-spot? what is this i dont even...

</quote>

Firstly; herp attack one point which you think is wrong and ignore rest of statement - best rebuttal ever.

Secondly:

<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sexual_organ">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sexual_organ</a> - See list of male, 'prostate' is there.

See this article - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anal_sex">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anal_sex</a> "Many people find anal sex pleasurable, and some may reach orgasmthrough stimulation of the prostate in men,".
</post>
<post author="Wave" datetime="2012-02-05T03:14:00" id="p178">
<quote orig_author="Blazara">
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sexual_organ">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sexual_organ</a> - See list of male, 'prostate' is there.

See this article - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anal_sex">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anal_sex</a> "Many people find anal sex pleasurable, and some may reach orgasmthrough stimulation of the prostate in men,".

</quote>

Hmm but is it as good as vaginal sex? I'm still sure that a penis up my ass would just hurt and not be too pleasurable.
</post>
<post author="catoswyn" datetime="2012-02-05T07:45:00" id="p179">
<quote orig_author="xev bellringer">
Whoa there....I have a vagina LOL...sorry not a male.I too have to watch my back when walking down dark streets and make sure I watch my drink.A couple of my friends have been spiked at uni.

Most men are good honest and trustworthy.Its just the few who give the rest a bad name.

</quote>

woops! Sorry!
</post>
<post author="xev bellringer" datetime="2012-02-05T09:43:00" id="p180">
<quote orig_author="catoswyn">
woops! Sorry!

</quote>

Lol no apology necessary...Its the Keanu Reeves avatar that confuses people.

Rape is a sickness that needs to be cut out or off people. How many women rape men compared to the reverse???
</post>
</doc>
