<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-201-185522-17204046">
<headline>
Female abusers, predators, and enablers
</headline>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-13T03:42:00" id="p1">
I've been watching a lot on the news about the Penn. State rape cases, and one thing that bothers me is the cavalier way males are portrayed: only men abuse, only men cover for other men, and only men rape. These are factually false, and the portrayal not only harms innocent men it allows female predators to walk free. It's time for the war of the sexes to take a back seat. Time for us to realize it's not male or female, but that we're all individuals. I see three problem areas in society that allow for this to continue: the media, the justice system, and our gender stereotypes.

The media seems to continually forget the large number of female predators and how society ignores them. Often ostracizing, even villainizing, those men/boys who claim abuse by women. How they, the press, conveniently forget the women who stand aside, knowingly, and enable all of these crimes to take place. Many times the press even downplays abuse by females, creating a million and one excuses for the female perpetrator's actions, which they would never allow if the abuser was male. Sometimes they even joke about the torture and mutilation of men by women ( <a href="http://www.avoiceformen.com/mens-rights/how-funny-is-a-mutilated-vagina/">Link</a> ).

The court often treats women and men differently in terms of sentences and respect for victims (many shield laws only cover females). Courts have been know to force male rape victims to pay child support for the offspring of their rape (the youngest was 12). The court system in many cases has given lighter sentences to female perpetrators of sexual abuse. Even the FBI/DOJ statistics on rape (the oft cited 99% of rapists are male) create a distorted view of reality, especially if you know the <a href="http://www.fbi.gov/about-us/cjis/ucr/additional-ucr-publications/ucr_handbook.pdf">definition</a> all the statistics are base from:
<quote>
Forcible rape, as defined in the FBIs Uniform Crime Reporting (UCR) Program, is the carnal knowledge of a female forcibly and against her will. Attempts or assaults to commit rape by force or threat of force are also included; however, statutory rape (without force) and other sex offenses are excluded. Carnal knowledge is defined by Blacks Law Dictionary, 6th ed.as the act of a man having sexual bodily connections with a woman; sexual intercourse. There is carnal knowledge if there is the slightest penetration of the sexual organ of the female (vagina) by the sexual organ of the male (penis).

</quote>
The 1% is when a female participate in helping a male rape another female. This completely ignores female perpetrators and male victims skewing the statistics horribly. Domestic violence is no better. The DOJ explicitly refuses to fund research on male victims of domestic violence as stated on <a href="http://www.ncjrs.gov/pdffiles1/nij/sl000734.pdf">page 8 section K sub-section 4</a>. In general, 86% of the victims of female sexual predators aren't believed, so the crimes go unreported and don't get prosecuted ( <a href="http://www.canadiancrc.com/Female_Sex_Offenders-Female_Sexual_Predators_awareness.aspx">Link</a> ).
<quote>
According to David Finkelhor, director of the Crimes Against Children Research Center at the University of New Hampshire, U.S.A. and stated in one of the largest newspapers in the U.S.A., the rise in recognition and prosecution of female sexual predators is due at least in part to the increased number of female police officers. Apparently, this results in prosecution of female sexual predators for their crimes without the police being labelled misogynistic.

</quote>
And lastly, we have an equal enforcement problem, just look at these cases: 11 year-old Florida boy stripped naked and filmed by three bullying 14 year old girls then posted to YouTube, and police do nothing calling it a prank( <a href="http://health.fox4now.com/story/14821011/11-year-old-stripped-naked-bullied-on-video">Link</a> ). No charges were ever pressed. A 13-year-old student at Wilson Middle School arrested, for misdemeanor battery, after pulling a prank on a fellow student. He walked up behind the girl pulling down her shorts and accidentally her underwear also came off in the process totally exposing her( <a href="http://www.koat.com/news/25677371/detail.html">Link</a> ). No disparity in justice there. Lets also look at the case of 2 boys arrested for sexual abuse at age 13 ( <a href="http://sexoffenderissues.blogspot.com/2007/07/or-unruly-schoolboys-or-sex-offenders.html">Here</a> and <a href="http://boards.askmen.com/showthread.php?74520-Anyone-else-see-this-About-some-boys-in-Oregon">Here</a> ).

Finally, we have the biggest problem, our own gender stereotypes. Take the 11-year old boy stripped in public, he had to deal with things like this ( <a href="http://boston.barstoolsports.com/random-thoughts/11-year-old-nancy-boy-cries-like-a-baby-when-2-girls-try-to-have-threesome-with-him/">Link</a> ). In general, men are stereotyped as physically tough, the family bread winners, and are never allowed to show weakness. Women have their own stereotype problems: women are not considered mentally or physically strong enough to attack a man, they're not mentally or physically capable of being sexual (they just take it for procreation), women are too weak to be held accountable for their own actions, and are commonly not considered individuals but women (especially by other women).

I will say that men seem to hold their own stereotypes much more rigidly. This could be because the newer generations of women have been trying to shed their stereotypes in the righteous quest for equality. While young men are feeling lost about their own place in our currently evolving society. As women are now taking on more roles, men are no longer the bread winners alone. So, in search of an identity they cling to anything, even outdated stereotypes, afraid there is little place for them (as men) in modern society.

When it comes to female on male sexual assault and rape there are many misconceptions. Here are some links to help others look into the issues:
<a href="http://www.female-offenders.com/">Female Sex Offenders</a>
<a href="http://www.jimhopper.com/male-ab/#fem">Female Predators</a>
<a href="http://www.articlesaboutmen.com/2010/09/top-ten-myths-about-female-sex-offenders-911/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+ArticlesAboutMen+%28Articles+About+Men%29">Top Ten Myths about Female Sex Offenders</a>
<a href="http://www.menshealthaustralia.net/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=341&amp;Itemid=95">Pressured Into Sex</a>
<a href="http://femalesexoffenders.com/fso/index.php">Female Sex Offenders</a>
I have more links, but I think these will do for now. Any comments, facts, or arguments welcome as this is just my first small sketch of this subject. <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/cool.gif"/>

[Note: Before the standard MRA Ad Hominem attacks start -- I am not, have not, and never plan to be an MRA group member of any type. I'm politically egalitarian, not pro-feminist, but not anti-feminism.

On another side note, I would like to know where the men look out for other men myth came from. Every guy I know looks out for their friends, male and female. No boys club. No 'we are men', like women look out for other women. It's quite common, in my experience, for men to screw each other over quite frequently for their own benefit. And I see very little concern by men for other mens problems: high suicide rates, violence against men, prostate cancer, etc... Until just very recently I'd never even heard of a crisis center that would even talk to a male victim <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/confused.gif"/>. So, where did this idea come from and is there any real proof or just anecdotal evidence?] Okay, now I'm off to bed...
</post>
<post author="Dancing David" datetime="2011-11-13T05:28:00" id="p2">
Yup there are female sexual offenders...
</post>
<post author="Alt+F4" datetime="2011-11-13T05:36:00" id="p3">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
I've been watching a lot on the news about the Penn. State rape cases, and one thing that bothers me is the cavalier way males are portrayed: only men abuse, only men cover for other men, and only men rape.

</quote>
Could you link to some of these news stories that say only men abuse?
</post>
<post author="Bikewer" datetime="2011-11-13T05:49:00" id="p4">
Been in police work for 40 years. Have never handled a single case involving a female abuser. Do such things occur? Sure. Undereported? Sure.

But still.....
</post>
<post author="sgtbaker" datetime="2011-11-13T06:54:00" id="p5">
These threads rarely take off into 20 page discussions because there is nothing controversial about the majority opinion on JREF. I have yet to see one person defend the disparity in the recognition between female and male victims of sexual abuse. If there was, I probably just assumed it was a parody or sarcasm. The fact is, not enough public attention is brought to the issue. The only time it seems to make big news is if it is an adult male abusing a boy. Of course, there is the occassional story like the school teacher and the 13 year old boy (names escape me), but didn't she get a whopping year and a half on house arrest?
</post>
<post author="AlaskaBushPilot" datetime="2011-11-13T07:00:00" id="p6">
As the physically weaker sex, women specialize in mental rather than physical abuse.
</post>
<post author="epepke" datetime="2011-11-13T07:08:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="sgtbaker">
These threads rarely take off into 20 page discussions because there is nothing controversial about the majority opinion on JREF. I have yet to see one person defend the disparity in the recognition between female and male victims of sexual abuse. If there was, I probably just assumed it was a parody or sarcasm.

</quote>
Rather a strange comment coming on the heels of @Bikewer's comment. I think you're blind or in denial.

I think this whole issue is like racism. In about a quarter century, people have gone from vigorously defending it to pretending like it never existed. It hasn't been too long since Suzanne Steinmetz received a bomb thread for speaking on domestic violence against men.
</post>
<post author="sgtbaker" datetime="2011-11-13T07:16:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="epepke">
Rather a strange comment coming on the heels of @Bikewer's comment. I think you're blind or in denial.

I think this whole issue is like racism. In about a quarter century, people have gone from vigorously defending it to pretending like it never existed. It hasn't been too long since Suzanne Steinmetz received a bomb thread for speaking on domestic violence against men.

</quote>
I am sorry, I am not understanding your comment. Could you tell me what I am missing?
</post>
<post author="Alt+F4" datetime="2011-11-13T07:31:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="sgtbaker">
Of course, there is the occassional story like the school teacher and the 13 year old boy (names escape me), but didn't she get a whopping year and a half on house arrest?

</quote>
If you are referring to Mary Kay Letourneau, she served 7 1/2 years in prison.
</post>
<post author="sgtbaker" datetime="2011-11-13T07:34:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="Alt+F4">
If you are referring to Mary Kay Letourneau, she served 7 1/2 years in prison.

</quote>
That was after she was caught violating her parole. Her first sentence was a joke.
</post>
<post author="Cainkane1" datetime="2011-11-13T07:56:00" id="p11">
Ok a woman coercing a boy into sex isn't as physically destructive as a man coercing an underage girl into sex. This si especially true if the victim is an under 12 child. A man coercing a little boy for sex is ever more destructive physically. Especially the type of sex the coach is accused of doing.

Female sex abuse gets swept under the rug because usually no one gets hurt physically. I'm not saying female abusers shouldn't be punished what I am saying is the injuries if any are usually not as bad as grown man little girl or boy criminal acts.
</post>
<post author="TragicMonkey" datetime="2011-11-13T07:58:00" id="p12">
<quote orig_author="Cainkane1">
Ok a woman coercing a boy into sex isn't as physically destructive as a man coercing an underage girl into sex. This si especially true if the victim is an under 12 child. A man coercing a little boy for sex is ever more destructive physically. Especially the type of sex the coach is accused of doing.

Female sex abuse gets swept under the rug because usually no one gets hurt physically. I'm not saying female abusers shouldn't be punished what I am saying is the injuries if any are usually not as bad as grown man little girl or boy criminal acts.

</quote>
It's not about physical injury.
</post>
<post author="Safe-Keeper" datetime="2011-11-13T08:03:00" id="p13">
Agree with this in theory -- I hate the ridiculous and unjustified "us vs. them" attitude on abuse, too, but it should be pointed out that 90-95% of sexual abuse is perpetrated by guys.

<quote>
On another side note, I would like to know where the men look out for other men myth came from. Every guy I know looks out for their friends, male and female. No boys club. No 'we are men', like women look out for other women.

</quote>
Anecdote alert.

<quote>
Ok a woman coercing a boy into sex isn't as physically destructive as a man coercing an underage girl into sex. This si especially true if the victim is an under 12 child. A man coercing a little boy for sex is ever more destructive physically. Especially the type of sex the coach is accused of doing.

Female sex abuse gets swept under the rug because usually no one gets hurt physically. I'm not saying female abusers shouldn't be punished what I am saying is the injuries if any are usually not as bad as grown man little girl or boy criminal acts.

</quote>
There's no physical injury from death threats, groping, or stalking either. So <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/confused.gif"/> ?

<quote>
I think this whole issue is like racism.

</quote>
Yup, definitely. One group fights for its rights so effectively that the other group is completely forgotten, or branded as the "bad guys" in that classic us vs. them mentality.
</post>
<post author="Caper" datetime="2011-11-13T08:15:00" id="p14">
I just can't take female sex abuse on teenagers as serious as I do for men..... I'm talking 14 plus.... I just can't take it as serious. I'm sure I should....but I can't. The idea of a large man walking into a shower after a 14 year old girl is far more horrifying the a woman walking in after a 14 year old boy.
</post>
<post author="epepke" datetime="2011-11-13T08:16:00" id="p15">
<quote orig_author="sgtbaker">
I am sorry, I am not understanding your comment. Could you tell me what I am missing?

</quote>
I can try. I cannot guarantee success.

Which part are you having difficulty with? Is it that @Bikewer is expressing dismissive attitudes? Do you not understand how only a male victim who is not a masochist would never report something to an Old Guard Cop of four decades who just doesn't see this as part of his world? These seem to me fairly obvious things, as obvious as that water is wet, and I probably lack the creativity to educate you in an engaging and exciting fashion. Throw me a bone here.

I was sexually battered by a woman a mere quarter century ago. The actual damage of the battery pales into insignificance compared to the fact that nobody would even talk to me. All of the helplines were hostile. So were, of course, the police. It would have benefited me a great deal simply to have a sympathetic ear, but none existed. The kind of @Bikewer culture was a big part of the problem, and nobody like that ever realized that if they were to drop their wunnerful "experienced-based" prejudice, more men might come out.

I did not die (I hope you can figure that out), though I had to spend quite a few years working through anger and shame. Alone, of course, because as I said, there was no help for the likes of me and a significant amount of hostility. This process, which I had to go alone but succeeded at, did have the effect of denying me a family, at least one during normal child-bearing years, though at the age of 50, I am still fighting fate. A stupid and futile exercise, perhaps, and one I would not be surprised to hear brings a smile to your lips.

And so, when you declare that everyone is agreed that men can be victims and that it matters, so casually, I think that you are no better than a white person in a racist society declaring that racism is not a problem because you are personally not in a position to be at the receiving end of it. Or perhaps declaring that all that racism stuff was settled in 1987 when all the effects went entirely away.

So, nice to know that everything has been all ******** settled whilst I was fighting for my basic self-respect, alone. I guess we have a Mars base and warp drive technology, too, right?
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-13T08:37:00" id="p16">
<quote orig_author="Cainkane1">
Ok a woman coercing a boy into sex isn't as physically destructive as a man coercing an underage girl into sex. This si especially true if the victim is an under 12 child. A man coercing a little boy for sex is ever more destructive physically. Especially the type of sex the coach is accused of doing.

Female sex abuse gets swept under the rug because usually no one gets hurt physically. I'm not saying female abusers shouldn't be punished what I am saying is the injuries if any are usually not as bad as grown man little girl or boy criminal acts.

</quote>
No one ever caused me any pain, not in eight years of sexual abuse, all at the hands of middle-aged men. I didn't even lose my virginity until I was 15, and with a boy my own age. And yet, I was still hurt by this abuse.

While physical abuse is horrible, we should note that the mental and emotional pain never goes away. You never forget it.

You already know this, Cain. I've seen your threads on bullies and bullying, and even at your age, you still remember what you went through, and vividly. It still disturbs you, still haunts you, still bothers you. Whatever physical pain you may have endured is long over with. But the mental scars...you'll always carry those, right?

That a boy being abused by a grown woman doesn't necessarily experience the physical pain/trauma of a vaginal or anal rape doesn't mean the boy wasn't harmed in other ways.

It's belittling to say that boys being sexually assaulted by women aren't suffering the same kind of harm as boys or girls being abused by men. Men don't always penetrate their victims. They are no less victims because of that. If that were so, then by that metric, I wasn't harmed by sexual abuse, even though it was grown men preying on a little girl.

Well, I've got news for you....
</post>
<post author="Trakar" datetime="2011-11-13T08:42:00" id="p17">
<quote orig_author="Bikewer">
Been in police work for 40 years. Have never handled a single case involving a female abuser. Do such things occur? Sure. Undereported? Sure.

But still.....

</quote>
Due primarily to physical differences between men and women, it is more difficult for women abusers to physically abuse men, and due to the psychological deck our society constructs it is more difficult for men to admit and acknowledge that they have been abused by a woman.

But of course, physical abuse is is not the only type of abuse.

In any case of abuse the psychological damage tends to be the longest lasting and most permanent aspect. Men who have been psychologically damaged by the female abusers in their lives seldom if ever recover fully, because neither they nor society easily recognizes or acknowledges that the damages are the result of abuse. Additionally, there are very few societal checks on female psychological abuse of males, in some sectors it seems to be almost promoted and encouraged. And even when "looked down upon" it is certainly not punished or treated as a crime.
</post>
<post author="sgtbaker" datetime="2011-11-13T08:51:00" id="p18">
<quote orig_author="epepke">
I can try. I cannot guarantee success.

Which part are you having difficulty with? Is it that @Bikewer is expressing dismissive attitudes? Do you not understand how only a male victim who is not a masochist would never report something to an Old Guard Cop of four decades who just doesn't see this as part of his world? These seem to me fairly obvious things, as obvious as that water is wet, and I probably lack the creativity to educate you in an engaging and exciting fashion. Throw me a bone here.

</quote>
From the bottom of my heart, I am so sorry that it progressed in that way. I wasn't adding to, agreeing with, or arguing Bikewer's post because I took it at face value. I was confused that you even drew a connection between his post and mine, that's all. I thought he was saying that there is not a whole lot law can do to fight unreported crimes. I didn't disagree with my interpretation of his statement but if I am wrong about what he meant or if that is what he meant, and that is wrong, I would be open to discuss it.

<quote>
I was sexually battered by a woman a mere quarter century ago. The actual damage of the battery pales into insignificance compared to the fact that nobody would even talk to me. All of the helplines were hostile. So were, of course, the police. It would have benefited me a great deal simply to have a sympathetic ear, but none existed. The kind of @Bikewer culture was a big part of the problem, and nobody like that ever realized that if they were to drop their wunnerful "experienced-based" prejudice, more men might come out.

I did not die (I hope you can figure that out), though I had to spend quite a few years working through anger and shame. Alone, of course, because as I said, there was no help for the likes of me and a significant amount of hostility. This process, which I had to go alone but succeeded at, did have the effect of denying me a family, at least one during normal child-bearing years, though at the age of 50, I am still fighting fate. A stupid and futile exercise, perhaps, and one I would not be surprised to hear brings a smile to your lips.

</quote>
Given the situation you experienced and the emotional toll it took on you, I am not going to get offended at being accused of enjoying your suffering but that is completely unecessary. I typically regard your posts, even when I disagree with you, as reasonable so it's more upsetting to me that I said something to inspire this type of personal attack, so again, I apologize.

<quote>
And so, when you declare that everyone is agreed that men can be victims and that it matters, so casually, I think that you are no better than a white person in a racist society declaring that racism is not a problem because you are personally not in a position to be at the receiving end of it. Or perhaps declaring that all that racism stuff was settled in 1987 when all the effects went entirely away.

So, nice to know that everything has been all ******** settled whilst I was fighting for my basic self-respect, alone. I guess we have a Mars base and warp drive technology, too, right?

</quote>
I did not say that everyone is agreed, I said the majority on this forum recognize the disparity. Now, apparently a few posts after, I learn that at least one member thinks it's all about the physical damage, which, in itself makes me completely wrong about the lack of disagreement but the impression I got from the thread about the act and effects of male rape in Africa is that there doesn't seem to be a whole lot of disagreement in the damage that rape can do to a male. The thread died off quickly because it was a whole lot of people agreeing that it was aweful and a few suggestions of where the idea that men are not victims, comes from.

epepke, in all sincerity, I am sorry for offending you.
</post>
<post author="MontagK505" datetime="2011-11-13T09:45:00" id="p19">
<quote orig_author="epepke">
I can try. I cannot guarantee success.

Which part are you having difficulty with? Is it that @Bikewer is expressing dismissive attitudes? Do you not understand how only a male victim who is not a masochist would never report something to an Old Guard Cop of four decades who just doesn't see this as part of his world? These seem to me fairly obvious things, as obvious as that water is wet, and I probably lack the creativity to educate you in an engaging and exciting fashion. Throw me a bone here.

I was sexually battered by a woman a mere quarter century ago. The actual damage of the battery pales into insignificance compared to the fact that nobody would even talk to me. All of the helplines were hostile. So were, of course, the police. It would have benefited me a great deal simply to have a sympathetic ear, but none existed. The kind of @Bikewer culture was a big part of the problem, and nobody like that ever realized that if they were to drop their wunnerful "experienced-based" prejudice, more men might come out.

I did not die (I hope you can figure that out), though I had to spend quite a few years working through anger and shame. Alone, of course, because as I said, there was no help for the likes of me and a significant amount of hostility. This process, which I had to go alone but succeeded at, did have the effect of denying me a family, at least one during normal child-bearing years, though at the age of 50, I am still fighting fate. A stupid and futile exercise, perhaps, and one I would not be surprised to hear brings a smile to your lips.

And so, when you declare that everyone is agreed that men can be victims and that it matters, so casually, I think that you are no better than a white person in a racist society declaring that racism is not a problem because you are personally not in a position to be at the receiving end of it. Or perhaps declaring that all that racism stuff was settled in 1987 when all the effects went entirely away.

So, nice to know that everything has been all ******** settled whilst I was fighting for my basic self-respect, alone. I guess we have a Mars base and warp drive technology, too, right?

</quote>
As a matter of information I was sexually abused as a child by my mother. When I was a teenager she frequently acted seductively. I found out years later she was molested by her grandfather.

Obviously, this sort of thing would get under reported. Most men even in the context of this forum probably wouldn't feel comfortable talking about it.
</post>
<post author="Professor Yaffle" datetime="2011-11-13T10:34:00" id="p20">
A website that may be of interest (which suggests that about a quarter of child sex offenders are women):

<a href="http://www.canadiancrc.com/Female_Sex_Offenders-Female_Sexual_Predators_awareness.aspx">http://www.canadiancrc.com/Female_Se...awareness.aspx</a>

I do notice a different attitude with regards to female perpetrators of sexual assault or violence and male victims. There is often a suggestion that the males are harmed less (or not harmed at all) by this - especially if the boy is a teenager. It is usually laughed off as a dream scenario for a teenage boy. And there is a similar trend wrt to domestic violence. A case involving a man mutilating the genitals of a woman would be taken very seriously, but as we saw on this forum recently the reverse scenario is just the trigger for a load of cock and ball jokes. Interestingly, in my experience (though I accept this may not be representative) it has been men that have displayed these sorts of attitudes more than women have.
</post>
<post author="Bikewer" datetime="2011-11-13T10:48:00" id="p21">
In no way do I intend to be dismissive. I'm certain that the damage caused by abuse is just as horrific regardless of which sex the perpetrator is.
However, I do wonder about the frequency.

Much as in the case of the "one in four" statistic put out regarding rape/sexual assault...Seems by any reasonable metric to be wildly exaggerated. This statistic is posted prominently around our university, and by any reasonable calculation involving the lowest mentioned reporting rate, we should be getting some dozens of reports per year. This is not the case, however. In fact, only two in the last 10 years...

It's difficult to come to any strong conclusion lacking some sort of valid metrics. Admittedly female exploitation of juicy-but-underage young men may be more common than we'd think and indeed vastly under-reported as many of these young men would not see this activity as abuse.
We know that "enablers" exist and are fairly common in situations where the male perpetrator is essentially ignored by the wife/girlfriend for various reasons.

For many years, police agencies and social workers have striven to make rape reporting less traumatizing for the victim and prosecution of rapists (and other sex offenders) easier and less traumatic.
Perhaps there needs to be some sort of program to properly identify the actual incidence of female-perpetrators and to encourage reporting by male victims. To date, I am not familiar with any such.
</post>
<post author="Professor Yaffle" datetime="2011-11-13T10:56:00" id="p22">
Might be worth trying to track down some of the studies mentioned here:

<quote>
Two retrospective studies of adult populations are frequently quoted by researchers and child advocates. The Los Angeles Times survey, conducted in 1985, found that seven percent of the abuse reported by male and female participants in the study was perpetrated by women. Sociologist Diana Russell's 1978 San Francisco-based study revealed that four percent of the women who reported having been abused indicated that the perpetrators were female.

The Times survey and the Russell study were based on a random selection of participants. Other retrospective studies focusing on narrower populations have found much higher rates of female perpetration, although some of these findings have yet to be replicated. In a 1981 study, 60 percent of 412 male and 10 percent of 540 female undergraduate psychology students at the University of Washington who recalled childhood sexual contact with a post-pubescent person at least five years older than themselves said their abusers were female. (Fritz, G., Stoll, K., and Wagner, N. "A Comparison of Males and Females Who Were Sexually Molested as Children," Journal of Sex and Marital Therapy, 1981, vol. 7,54-59.)

In another study, doctors at a New Jersey medical clinic found that 11 out of 25 teenage males who revealed that they had been sexually molested named females (ages 16 to 36) as their assailants. These perpetrators were "usually acquaintances of the victims -- most often a neighbor, baby-sitter, or other trusted adolescent or young adult." (Johnson, R., and Shrier, D. "Past Sexual Victimization by Females of Male Patients in an Adolescent Medicine Clinic Population," American Journal Of Psychiatry, 1987, vol. 144,650-662.)

Finally, a study of 582 college men found that up to 78 percent of those abused as children had been abused by females. ( Fromuth, M., and Burkhart, B. "Childhood Sexual Victimization Among College Men: Definitions and Methodological Issues," Violence and Victim, 1987, vol. 2, no. 4, 241-253.)

Researchers do not know why some studies uncover a higher rate of female perpetration than others, but The National Resource Center on Child Sexual Abuse ( NRCCSA ) asserts that because of a lack of standardization in reporting and inconsistencies in research methods and definitions of sexual abuse, "the firm statistics everyone desires" on the prevalence of abuse "simply are not available." ( NRCCSA News, May-June 1992, vol. 1, no. 1.)

</quote>
<a href="http://www.canadiancrc.com/Newspaper_Articles/MovingF_Female_perpetrators_Child_sexual_abuse_JUL94.aspx">http://www.canadiancrc.com/Newspaper...use_JUL94.aspx</a>
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-13T13:57:00" id="p23">
<quote orig_author="Bikewer">
Been in police work for 40 years. Have never handled a single case involving a female abuser. Do such things occur? Sure. Undereported? Sure.

But still.....

</quote>
But still what? I really would like to know...
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-13T14:10:00" id="p24">
<quote orig_author="sgtbaker">
These threads rarely take off into 20 page discussions because there is nothing controversial about the majority opinion on JREF....[snip]...

</quote>
I disagree. I believe that the attitude is, 'yea, it's wrong but so what?' People commonly say they agree because society pushes them to agree, but then you find the piling of exceptions. Well not really that, is that really rape here, and I can't see it happening there. I think very much like race its mentally accepted as wrong, but no one really cares about the subject until they're affected by it. If it came right down to it, the reason the previous threads have died is because people don't really care about male victims. It shows in our research, our TV shows, and accepted attitudes.

Heck, the truth is, it's hard to get men who were abused to see themselves as victims, why would others be able to do it when those involved themselves can't. I know men who were abused and they laugh it off. They've never really told anyone and probably will never see how their attitudes, their lives are affected by ignoring their own abuse. We, as a society, do not know how to cope with male victims. But until we push it into the forefront we'll never address the issue.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-13T14:18:00" id="p25">
<quote orig_author="Cainkane1">
Ok a woman coercing a boy into sex isn't as physically destructive as a man coercing an underage girl into sex. This si especially true if the victim is an under 12 child. A man coercing a little boy for sex is ever more destructive physically. Especially the type of sex the coach is accused of doing.

Female sex abuse gets swept under the rug because usually no one gets hurt physically. I'm not saying female abusers shouldn't be punished what I am saying is the injuries if any are usually not as bad as grown man little girl or boy criminal acts.

</quote>
Right here is one of the problems. The attitude and the denial of real harm. In studies of abused men, most found that the abuse by women was much worse on the boys than even that of abuse by older men. A boy finds his whole identity is shaken when abused by a woman. A boy/man does not know how he can still call himself a man in the face of being abused by a woman. Males are strong and tough and no weak woman should ever be able to hurt them. But, when it does happen, who are they? How can they admit they aren't even a man anymore? Suicide rates are higher in those boys abused by females. Of course though, no real harm done.
</post>
<post author="Professor Yaffle" datetime="2011-11-13T14:26:00" id="p26">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Right here is one of the problems. The attitude and the denial of real harm. In studies of abused men, most found that the abuse by women was much worse on the boys than even that of abuse by older men. A boy finds his whole identity is shaken when abused by a woman. A boy/man does not know how he can still call himself a man in the face of being abused by a woman. Males are strong and tough and no weak woman should ever be able to hurt them. But, when it does happen, who are they? How can they admit they aren't even a man anymore? Suicide rates are higher in those boys abused by females. Of course though, no real harm done.

</quote>
And as I linked to in another thread, children abused by women are more likely to go on to become abusers when they grow up than children abused by men.
</post>
<post author="Safe-Keeper" datetime="2011-11-13T14:29:00" id="p27">
Once in high school there was a girl who basically bragged about beating up her male ex and causing him permanent scars by putting out cigarettes on his face. I went down to the office and informed the staff about her, and she never showed up at the school again. Yes, there are dangerous girls out there, and they're just as damaging, if not more, as male abusers.

Mind you, I would have done the same if it were a guy bragging about abusing a girl. I've got a female friend who was raped on the street only months ago... it ticks me off big time, pardon the vulgarity, and all the work done to combat physical and sexual violence against females is wonderful and sorely needed. All I'm saying is it needs to be a two-way street, because I'm seriously growing tired of feminists ranting on about how we guys need to "take responsibility" and "work on our attitudes", when I know that statistically, when it comes to attitudes and knowledge about violence against the opposite sex... we're miles ahead of them.

<quote>
I just can't take female sex abuse on teenagers as serious as I do for men..... I'm talking 14 plus.... I just can't take it as serious. I'm sure I should....but I can't. The idea of a large man walking into a shower after a 14 year old girl is far more horrifying the a woman walking in after a 14 year old boy.

</quote>
...which is part of why abuse is mentally more damaging for guys than girls.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-13T14:30:00" id="p28">
<quote orig_author="Safe-Keeper">
Agree with this in theory -- I hate the ridiculous and unjustified "us vs. them" attitude on abuse, too, but it should be pointed out that 90-95% of sexual abuse is perpetrated by guys.

</quote>
I call BS unless you quote a reputable source that takes into account that most men/boys raped by women never report and that even those that do are routinely sent away as not being credible. As I've shown the official statistics are so skewed, by bad criteria, as to be useless for a true unbiased understanding of the phenomena.

<quote orig_author="Safe-Keeper">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
On another side note, I would like to know where the men look out for other men myth came from. Every guy I know looks out for their friends, male and female. No boys club. No 'we are men', like women look out for other women.

</quote>
Anecdote alert.

</quote>
I do not claim that this is not anecdotal evidence, it is. But, I have seen no actual research or proof of the opposite claim, which also seems based on anecdote plus rhetoric.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-13T14:48:00" id="p29">
<quote orig_author="Caper">
I just can't take female sex abuse on teenagers as serious as I do for men..... I'm talking 14 plus.... I just can't take it as serious. I'm sure I should....but I can't. The idea of a large man walking into a shower after a 14 year old girl is far more horrifying the a woman walking in after a 14 year old boy.

</quote>
And here's another problem. If we can't even accept that a teenage boy can be raped, how will we ever get to the point where a man can come forward when he's raped. The attitude is as much a part of the problem as our denial to accept it when it does happen. How can a man or even a teenager come forward when he really is raped, when almost everyone says, it's not really rape, he just got what he wanted.

When did men fall into the class of unthinking animals that have no control over their libido or actions? Yes, no man would ever turn down sex. Last time I checked, I want to choose my partners, not have them forced upon me. The irrational idea that men crave sex 24/7 with any woman out there really needs to have horrible and painful death. I choose my partners, and I consent when I want to. Why is consent gender specific <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/mazeguyemotions/boggled.gif"/> ?

You can't take it seriously... really? I feel sorry for you and for all the people you've just marginalized as unimportant.
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-13T15:01:00" id="p30">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
On another side note, I would like to know where the men look out for other men myth came from. Every guy I know looks out for their friends, male and female. No boys club. No 'we are men', like women look out for other women.

</quote>
Wait...so it's a stereotype when applied to men, but it's truth when applied to women?

Did you really mean to say that? Because I can't remember ever being part of that "we are women" club, myself. What I do recall are the vicious bitches I've had the misfortune to have to deal with, especially in positions of authority. Why? Because if they don't constantly prove they've got just as big a pair as their male counterparts, they won't have that position for long, and everyone knows it.

If there's no such "club" for men, you can rest assured it doesn't exist for women, either.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-13T15:04:00" id="p31">
<quote orig_author="Bikewer">
...[snip]...For many years, police agencies and social workers have striven to make rape reporting less traumatizing for the victim and prosecution of rapists (and other sex offenders) easier and less traumatic.
Perhaps there needs to be some sort of program to properly identify the actual incidence of female-perpetrators and to encourage reporting by male victims. To date, I am not familiar with any such.

</quote>
I would like an honest answer to this question: if a college guy came up to you and told you he was raped (vaginal sex) by a woman would you take it seriously, especially if he showed no signs of physical trauma or those of being drugged?

I'm not going to judge you. I have a friend that is a police officer and I asked him the same question. He responded of course he would, but days later, after he really thought about it, he had a different answer. If some guy came up to him out of the blue, he would have likely said, you just got laid and you're complaining, get out here, I've got real work to do. He's not a bad cop. But, his attitude reflects that of society. (Of course this is anecdotal and I only know him on-line, so he could be lying. But, I believe he's a credible source, as he's told me about things that have later come out as news. Plus, other things lead me to believe he's a real police officer that I won't go into).
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-11-13T15:05:00" id="p32">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
&lt;snip&gt;

Last time I checked, I want to choose my partners, not have them forced upon me. The irrational idea that men crave sex 24/7 with any woman out there really needs to have horrible and painful death. I choose my partners, and I consent when I want to. Why is consent gender specific <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/mazeguyemotions/boggled.gif"/> ?

&lt;snip&gt;

</quote>
The game is usually played such that a man approaches a woman and the woman chooses whether or not to have sex with him. If she turns him down he moves onto another woman. This is why women are invited to join some dating sites free of charge and why some bars offer women a free drink during happy hour.
</post>
<post author="Checkmite" datetime="2011-11-13T15:09:00" id="p33">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
I've been watching a lot on the news about the Penn. State rape cases, and one thing that bothers me is the cavalier way males are portrayed: only men abuse, only men cover for other men, and only men rape.

</quote>

I've been watching the coverage heavily, and have noticed no such thing. Only men are being discussed because only men are involved in this case.
Of course there are women guilty of abuse, of covering up abuse, and enabling abuse. Of the 20 folks recently nabbed in a ICAC/sheriff's department child porn crackdown in my county, 4 of them were women.

However, the tactics women use to meet, groom, and molest boys are often markedly different from those used by men. For one thing, the exact same social pressure that often makes boys too ashamed to admit to being raped or molested works the opposite way when the perp is female; they instead feel pressured to go along with it, and their shame comes not from having been molested but from not liking it or considering it a bad thing, which is contrary to society's cavalier attitude toward such situations and makes victims feel like there's something wrong with them if they didn't "love it".
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-13T15:10:00" id="p34">
<quote orig_author="slingblade">
Wait...so it's a stereotype when applied to men, but it's truth when applied to women?...[snip]...

</quote>
You're totally right <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/mazeguyemotions/blush.gif"/>, I stand corrected!
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-13T15:20:00" id="p35">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
You're totally right <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/mazeguyemotions/blush.gif"/>, I stand corrected!

</quote>
Aw, shucks, if that doesn't happen to you at least once here, you're not really part of the gang.

Welcome to the gang! <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-13T15:21:00" id="p36">
<quote orig_author="Alt+F4">
Could you link to some of these news stories that say only men abuse?

</quote>

<quote orig_author="Checkmite">
I've been watching the coverage heavily, and have noticed no such thing. Only men are being discussed because only men are involved in this case.
Of course there are women guilty of abuse, of covering up abuse, and enabling abuse. Of the 20 folks recently nabbed in a ICAC/sheriff's department child porn crackdown in my county, 4 of them were women.

</quote>
Sorry, I forgot to address this earlier. I can not give specific examples as I watch a lot of news (insomniac) and have seen the attitude pop up multiple times. Usually it's in phrases like: men need to be watched more carefully when they're in charge of children (this assumes that the same is not needed for females). If even one woman was involved in this case it would of been dealt with sooner (women are more responsible when dealing with abuse). There are others but I'll have to think about it awhile and try to write them down when I see them. Also, it wasn't just this case that I'm thinking of, back when some of the teachers were accused of rape and many in the press had an overall attitude of so what its not real rape.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-13T15:28:00" id="p37">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
My point is that it's sometimes better to learn and move on from bad experiences rather than become a victim of them.

</quote>
While I believe you can never really move on until you deal with things that have happened to you. Particularly, something so traumatic.
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-13T15:38:00" id="p38">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
My point is that it's sometimes better to learn and move on from bad experiences rather than become a victim of them.

</quote>
"Become a victim?" So the kid in the shower chose to become a victim, and that's how this happened?

Or was the kid victimized by that man, and now has to deal with the aftermath?

It's really a nice, fluffy world in which we can choose every time what victimizes us and what doesn't. I don't think I'd try that psychology on the next child rape....well, gee, I was going to say victim, but apparently that word's been co-opted now, and I can't call them that anymore.

How about "subject?" That's nice and blame-free, isn't it?

Sure, tell that to the next child rape subject.
</post>
<post author="sgtbaker" datetime="2011-11-13T16:25:00" id="p39">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
I disagree. I believe that the attitude is, 'yea, it's wrong but so what?' People commonly say they agree because society pushes them to agree, but then you find the piling of exceptions. Well not really that, is that really rape here, and I can't see it happening there. I think very much like race its mentally accepted as wrong, but no one really cares about the subject until they're affected by it. If it came right down to it, the reason the previous threads have died is because people don't really care about male victims. It shows in our research, our TV shows, and accepted attitudes.

Heck, the truth is, it's hard to get men who were abused to see themselves as victims, why would others be able to do it when those involved themselves can't. I know men who were abused and they laugh it off. They've never really told anyone and probably will never see how their attitudes, their lives are affected by ignoring their own abuse. We, as a society, do not know how to cope with male victims. But until we push it into the forefront we'll never address the issue.

</quote>
I don't disagree that such an attitude exists in the law, media, and general public opinion, I just don't think it's the majority opinion, here. As to your second paragraph, I agree 100%
</post>
<post author="Safe-Keeper" datetime="2011-11-13T16:50:00" id="p40">
<quote>
My point is that it's sometimes better to learn and move on from bad experiences rather than become a victim of them.

</quote>
Right. Stupid survivors choosing to suffer from bousts of nightmares, panic attacks and all kinds of other symptoms of PTSD. They're about as dumb and self-destructive as all those idiots who decide to turn gay.

Look... I have a friend who survived a rape as a 15 year old. Today, at 24, she struggles horribly with the after-effects of the assault itself, the ridiculously low punishment of the perp, and (guess what) people remaining friends with the perpetrator and telling her to suck it up and move on. She currently lives in a psychiatric hospital, in which she's been staying since spring. That's been her life for nine years -- self-mutilation, sleep disorders, suicide attempts, social isolation, self-loathing, depression. She has an incredible blog about her life at <a href="http://www.mereteisabell.com">www.mereteisabell.com</a>, which I suggest you fire up Google Translate and read.

The point is... I don't think anyone chooses this kind of existence. When you've survived a sexual assault, or for that matter any kind of horrific traumatizing event, you don't decide to spend the next decade waging a war on your after-effects.

Living with traumas is a lot like living with an allergy. In both cases, exposure to the right triggers sets off a reaction. Let's say you're strongly allergic to canines -- if you find yourself in a room with a dog, you suffer a strong allergic reaction, possibly an asthma attack. Traumatic effects are like that... sometimes when you have a "PTSD attack" it comes out of the blue and surprises the heck out of you, regardless of how well you think you're doing or how well you would expect to cope with the situation.

Yes, if you get an allergic reaction you can "suck it up". You can try to go on about your day as best you can. But you still suffer the reaction itself. Telling yourself to "suck it up" doesn't help you cope with the symptoms of PTSD or allergy. There are methods for coping with both, and pretending your problem doesn't exist is not one of them.

This has been a public service announcement <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>.
Pardon my mood. I generally try to not engage in this kind of debate for this exact reason, I tend to handle them poorly emotion-wise <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/tongue.gif"/>.
</post>
<post author="PhantomWolf" datetime="2011-11-13T19:11:00" id="p41">
There is a major issue here in how society thinks. Most men tend to be of the idea of how cool it would be to be "seduced" by a woman, and any man that doesn't like the idea of some woman who is gagging for it forcing herself onto him must be some sort of gay pansy. This seems to be the whole "every man wants to have sex 24/7 and so should be happy when he gets it on a platter" mindset.

The problem is for many men the idea of a woman doing that is a sort of fantasy, it turns them on and they can't understand why others would consider it abuse. After all, how many male students didn't fantasize about their hot female teacher coming into the locker room showers and teaching them a lesson, or about having their friend's hot mum checking out their equipment? The idea that these are actually rape fantasies fails to click in the majority of men. This leads to the whole idea that when two girls hold you down and strip you, the manly thing is to wave your parts in the air, get it up and get it on, even if you are just 11. The idea that for an 11 year old kid, or even many adults such an action would be terrifying and humiliating just doesn't seem to register with them.

Another issue is the flawed believe by some that males can't "get it up" if they are scared and being abused. It wasn't that long ago that these was discussed rather figously here as a certain (female) poster refused to believe other (male) posters about how their bodies reponded, and that getting erect is an entirely involuntary reaction of the body.

Until we get past these failings in our minds, and realise that the idea of an adult female following a 14-year old boy into the showers is as disgusting as that of an adult male following a 14-year old girl into the showers, things aren't going to change.
</post>
<post author="Robrob" datetime="2011-11-13T21:59:00" id="p42">
<quote>
The media seems to continually forget the large number of female predators and how society ignores them.

</quote>
Unless you have some amazing evidence I'm not aware of, I'm going to have to disagree with both your contentions here.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-13T23:19:00" id="p43">
<quote orig_author="Robrob">
Unless you have some amazing evidence I'm not aware of, I'm going to have to disagree with both your contentions here.

</quote>
Obviously, you read 0% <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/mazeguyemotions/jaw-dropping.gif"/> of the information that I posted.

Here are just a few quick quotes (with links):

<quote>
One in six adult men reported being sexually molested as children, and -- in a surprise finding -- nearly 40 percent of the perpetrators were female, a new study found.

Women fared even worse, with one in four reporting childhood molestation, in almost all cases perpetrated by males.

Both male and female victims had higher rates of substance abuse, mental illness and troubled marriages. The findings are contained in a study of more than 17,000 California residents that appears in the June issue of the American Journal of Preventive Medicine.( <a href="http://news.healingwell.com/?p=news1&amp;id=525818">Link</a> )

</quote>
This correlated with other earlier studies.

<quote>
In cases of daycare molestation, more than 60% of children who were molested, were molested by women. ( <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/10766112">Link</a> )

</quote>

<quote>
Approximately 95% of all youth reporting staff sexual misconduct said they had been victimized by female staff. In 2008, 42% of staff in state juvenile facilities were female. ( <a href="http://bjs.ojp.usdoj.gov/index.cfm?ty=pbdetail&amp;iid=2113">Link</a> )

</quote>
Look at the links I provided in my first post there's a lot of good data and links to scientific and federal studies.

ETA: Just as anecdotal evidence -- since I'm sure you've never heard any of this I'd say the media isn't keeping you informed <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>.
</post>
<post author="Darat" datetime="2011-11-14T02:59:00" id="p44">
<quote orig_author="PhantomWolf">
...snip...

Until we get past these failings in our minds, and realise that the idea of an adult female following a 14-year old boy into the showers is as disgusting as that of an adult male following a 14-year old girl into the showers, things aren't going to change.

</quote>
Good post but I want to pick up on one thing that I think tends to get lost in this type of discussion here and that is the age of the victim. There can be a grey area in the teens when some kids will be becoming sexually active themselves when it becomes harder to state with certainty that harm is being done. But when we look at the ages of many (if not most?) of the victims of sexual abuse they are not even teenagers but pre-pubescent boys and girls and there is no grey area.
</post>
<post author="catsmate1" datetime="2011-11-14T05:23:00" id="p45">
<quote orig_author="Robrob">
Unless you have some amazing evidence I'm not aware of, I'm going to have to disagree with both your contentions here.

</quote>
Well according to <a href="http://www.ed.gov/rschstat/research/pubs/misconductreview/report.pdf">this</a> report on 'Educator Sexual Misconduct' 57.2 percent of all sexually exploited students report a male offender and 42.4 percent a female offender.

Then there's the take of the (US) National Center on Child Abuse and Neglect

<quote>
The sexual abuse of children by women, primarily mothers, once thought to be so rare it could be ignored, constituted 25% (approximately 36 000 children) of the sexually abused victims. This statistic is thought to be underestimated due to the tendency of non-disclosure by victims.

</quote>
Then there's these two papers:
<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/10766112">Psychological profile of pedophiles and child molesters</a> and <a href="http://www.springerlink.com/content/wu6xlp6kv86733u3/">Heterosexual and homosexual coercion, sexual orientation and sexual roles in medical students</a>

<quote>
Womens sexual abuse of children may be much more serious than mens because women are more likely to have abused more children for a longer period of time, are more intrusive, and more likely to use higher rates of force than men.

</quote>

<quote>
In cases of daycare molestation, more than 60% of children who were molested, were molested by women.

</quote>

<quote>
.....relatively comparable proportions of men and women were victims of coercive experiences: 35% of women and 30% of men experiencing constant physical attempts to have sexual activity. Forms of coercion not involving threat or use of force were more common, more exclusively heterosexual, and carried out by more equivalent percentages of men and women.
Threat or use of force to attempt to or to obtain intercourse were employed by 4% of men and 2% of women and experienced by 5% of both sexes. Half the male victims and female aggressors and a quarter of the male aggressors and female victims who reported such coercion stated it was homosexual.

</quote>

<a href="http://bjs.ojp.usdoj.gov/index.cfm?ty=pbdetail&amp;iid=2113.">This</a> report from the US DoJ ('Sexual Victimization in Juvenile Facilities') states:
<quote>
Approximately 95% of all youth reporting staff sexual misconduct said they had been victimized by female staff. In 2008, 42% of staff in state juvenile facilities were female.

</quote>
<a href="http://www.cdc.gov/ncipc/dvp/CM_Data_Sheet.pdf">This</a> datasheet from the CDC ('Child Maltreatment: Facts at a Glance') states:

<quote>
More women (58%) than men (42%) are perpetrators of all forms of child maltreatment.

</quote>
<a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15894146">This</a> study ('Long-term consequences of childhood sexual abuse by gender of victim') also from the CDC states:

<quote>
One in six adult men reported being sexually molested as children, and -- in a surprise finding -- nearly 40 percent of the perpetrators were female, a new study found.

</quote>
and

<quote>
In a study of 17,337 survivors of childhood sexual abuse, 23% had a female-only perpetrator and 22% had both male and female perpetrators.

</quote>
The Dunedin study ( <a href="http://www.ncjrs.gov/pdffiles1/170018.pdf">link</a> ) showed that:
<quote>
About 27 percent of women and 34 percent of men among the Dunedin study members reported they had been physically abused by their partner. About 37 percent of women and 22 percent of men said they had perpetrated the violence.

</quote>
Then there's the Canadian UBC <a href="http://www.nursing.ubc.ca/PDFs/ItsNotWhatYouThink.pdf">report:</a>

<quote>
One unexpected finding was that women also sexually exploit adolescents. The common stereotype is its nearly always men who are exploiting youth, whether as pimps or as Johns, the so-called clients who actually pay for sexual activity with money or goods, Saewyc said. But among youth who told us the genders of the people who exploit them, nearly half of the teens had exchanged sex with at least one female. Indeed, nearly 1 in 3 youth had been exploited only by women, while half of youth had been exploited solely by men.

</quote>
</post>
<post author="Safe-Keeper" datetime="2011-11-14T06:58:00" id="p46">
I'm sure I don't have to tell anyone this, but you have to keep in mind when reading child abuse statistics that women spend more time with kids than men do. For example, the daycare centre figure shouldn't surprise anyone given that females are overrepresented as daycare centre workers.
</post>
<post author="Checkmite" datetime="2011-11-14T08:32:00" id="p47">
The notion that survivors of sexual abuse should be able to, like flipping a switch, "turn off" their negative view of a thing that happened in their past (thereby 'turning off' the negative after effects) is nearly impossible for the rational or logical mind. By definition, the person against whom a bad act is perpetrated is the victim of that act. Therefore logically, a person must reject that what happened to them was a bad or illegal act in order to stop being a victim.

Frankly I have to reject any treatment that involves intentionally creating and reinforcing delusional thinking.
</post>
<post author="Professor Yaffle" datetime="2011-11-14T09:11:00" id="p48">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
What are the stats for long-term harm from sexual abuse in childhood?

Does culture have an effect on the prevalence of long-term harm from sexual abuse in childhood?

</quote>
I haven't checked out the references yet, but:

<quote>
Asymptomatic children
40% of sexually abused children present with few or no symptoms
‘sleeper effects’: 10-20% will deteriorate over the next 12 to 18 months
Need to be evaluated for additional risk factors
Symptomatic children
62.8% qualify for at least one psychiatric diagnosis
29.5% qualify for 2 or more psychiatric diagnoses
Cognitive behavioral therapy is affective for some symptoms of child sexual abuse
Appropriately treat for psychiatric diagnoses

</quote>
<a href="http://www.childadvocate.net/child_sexual_abuse.htm">http://www.childadvocate.net/child_sexual_abuse.htm</a>

ETA: Here is the paper the data the figures are taken from:
<a href="http://www.nctsnet.org/nctsn_assets/Articles/1.pdf">http://www.nctsnet.org/nctsn_assets/Articles/1.pdf</a>
</post>
<post author="Dancing David" datetime="2011-11-14T09:24:00" id="p49">
<quote orig_author="Bikewer">
Been in police work for 40 years. Have never handled a single case involving a female abuser. Do such things occur? Sure. Undereported? Sure.

But still.....

</quote>
Ad I was very young and my abuser was a first degree relative, I did not report the Lexus abuse, they were female.
</post>
<post author="Dancing David" datetime="2011-11-14T09:26:00" id="p50">
<quote orig_author="Caper">
I just can't take female sex abuse on teenagers as serious as I do for men..... I'm talking 14 plus.... I just can't take it as serious. I'm sure I should....but I can't. The idea of a large man walking into a shower after a 14 year old girl is far more horrifying the a woman walking in after a 14 year old boy.

</quote>
What is she has genital herpes and looks like Jaba the Hutt, or are you stuck in that as a fantasy as well?
</post>
<post author="Darat" datetime="2011-11-14T09:32:00" id="p51">
<quote orig_author="Caper">
I just can't take female sex abuse on teenagers as serious as I do for men..... I'm talking 14 plus.... I just can't take it as serious. I'm sure I should....but I can't. The idea of a large man walking into a shower after a 14 year old girl is far more horrifying the a woman walking in after a 14 year old boy.

</quote>
I'm male - if a female teacher had done that to me at age 14 I am sure I would have been very traumatised.
</post>
<post author="Schrodinger's Cat" datetime="2011-11-14T10:54:00" id="p52">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
The media seems to continually forget the large number of female predators and how society ignores them. Often ostracizing, even villainizing, those men/boys who claim abuse by women. How they, the press, conveniently forget the women who stand aside, knowingly, and enable all of these crimes to take place. Many times the press even downplays abuse by females, creating a million and one excuses for the female perpetrator's actions, which they would never allow if the abuser was male....

</quote>
In addition to the points you've already made, I would also add women who chose abusive partners over their children.

I've done quite a bit of work with at risk teens and runaways, and there are cases of mothers discovering that their partners have sexually abused their children, only to blame the child for "seducing" their partner and throwing the child out on the street. Also cases in which her partner is physically (but not sexually) abusing the child and the abuse is escalating, and the mother's response is to evict the child from the home and not the abusive partner.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-14T12:09:00" id="p53">
<quote orig_author="Schrodinger's Cat">
In addition to the points you've already made, I would also add women who chose abusive partners over their children.

I've done quite a bit of work with at risk teens and runaways, and there are cases of mothers discovering that their partners have sexually abused their children, only to blame the child for "seducing" their partner and throwing the child out on the street. Also cases in which her partner is physically (but not sexually) abusing the child and the abuse is escalating, and the mother's response is to evict the child from the home and not the abusive partner.

</quote>
I agree that this is also a majorly overlooked problem, so it's hard to find statistics on. Usually, when an woman is an enabler she's considered another victim and not part of the problem; even when she's also involved in perpetrating the abuse. As a society, we seem to more easily place women in the victim category than the abuser one. If we would actually prosecute those women instead of giving them a free pass, it might help stop, or at least end more quickly, those abuses.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-14T19:25:00" id="p54">
<quote orig_author="Schrodinger's Cat">
In addition to the points you've already made, I would also add women who chose abusive partners over their children.

I've done quite a bit of work with at risk teens and runaways, and there are cases of mothers discovering that their partners have sexually abused their children, only to blame the child for "seducing" their partner and throwing the child out on the street. Also cases in which her partner is physically (but not sexually) abusing the child and the abuse is escalating, and the mother's response is to evict the child from the home and not the abusive partner.

</quote>
If anyone knows of any research in this area pleas post links to it. I have no real information in this area and would like to get some idea to its prevalence. Thanks.
</post>
<post author="L.Y.S." datetime="2011-11-14T21:31:00" id="p55">
<quote orig_author="Dancing David">
Yup there are female sexual offenders...

</quote>
Actually law enforcement believes that there are perhaps several times the numbers of female sexual offenders (according to law) than are reported. Most of them your neighborhood Mrs. Robinsons porking 15 year old boys. People talk about the number of scandals with female high school teachers, when really this stuff has been around for decades. Law enforcement has largely turned a blind eye to the issue until fairly recent.

Although, to be honest I could care less if a 16 year old kid is porking a 27 year old adult so long as no one got hurt from the ordeal. I am curious as to how things work in Europe since most places in Western Europe have age of consent laws below the age of 17. Is there a higher rate of sexual assaults and abuses? I'm thoroughly convinced that it is not directly destructive for a child of high school age to have sex with an adult. So long as the adult is not in a position of authority over them; or the minor in question does not depend on that adult in any way, shape, or form.
</post>
<post author="Checkmite" datetime="2011-11-14T21:35:00" id="p56">
<quote orig_author="L.Y.S.">
Actually law enforcement believes that there are perhaps several times the numbers of female sexual offenders (according to law) than are reported. Most of them your neighborhood Mrs. Robinsons porking 15 year old boys.

</quote>
Which law enforcement?

I have no doubt such cases are under-reported; but I'm not convinced it's by a factor of "several times".
</post>
<post author="L.Y.S." datetime="2011-11-14T22:00:00" id="p57">
<quote orig_author="Checkmite">
Which law enforcement?

I have no doubt such cases are under-reported; but I'm not convinced it's by a factor of "several times".

</quote>
I am convinced it is by "several times". I believe the social taboo of an older woman having any sort of relations with a younger men is what keeps the issue a quiet. In fact it’s an almost certainty that <a href="http://female-offenders.com/Safehouse/2010/09/toptenmythsaboutfemalesexoffenders.html">less than 10%</a> of female sex with minors is reported each year in the U.S.

I actually saw some of what I wrote on MSNBC "how to catch a predator". Chris Hansan and law enforcement officials actually talked a few minutes about why there are so few female sexual predators on the show. To make a long story short, they said that women who have sex with teenagers are much less likely to travel and expose themselves for sex. They often find local "sources" for sex. And often they do not abuse their partners in the traditional sense. For this reason most of these incidents go unreported unless they are "caught" or someone truly gets abused.
</post>
<post author="Checkmite" datetime="2011-11-15T09:58:00" id="p58">
<quote orig_author="L.Y.S.">
I am convinced it is by "several times". I believe the social taboo of an older woman having any sort of relations with a younger men is what keeps the issue a quiet. In fact its an almost certainty that <a href="http://female-offenders.com/Safehouse/2010/09/toptenmythsaboutfemalesexoffenders.html">less than 10%</a> of female sex with minors is reported each year in the U.S.

</quote>
It always makes me curious how people figure what percentage of a particular crime goes unreported each year.
</post>
<post author="Professor Yaffle" datetime="2011-11-15T10:02:00" id="p59">
<quote orig_author="Checkmite">
It always makes me curious how people figure what percentage of a particular crime goes unreported each year.

</quote>
Some figures can be estimated using surveys such as the British crime Survey.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-15T14:14:00" id="p60">
<quote orig_author="Checkmite">
It always makes me curious how people figure what percentage of a particular crime goes unreported each year.

</quote>
Many schools and colleges do anonymous questionnaires on the subject. Many scientific studies do polling and generic tests during studies. Also, police use anonymous reporting and public questionnaires. With things like polling they take samples from multiple diverse areas and extrapolate based on that data.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-15T14:37:00" id="p61">
<quote orig_author="L.Y.S.">
...[snip]... Although, to be honest I could care less if a 16 year old kid is porking a 27 year old adult so long as no one got hurt from the ordeal....[snip]...

</quote>
The problem is defining hurt. When it comes down to it, its all about consent. Many young boys and men feel pressure to give in to sexual requests. The women manipulate and use social pressures and passive threats to force them to comply with their requests. Using social pressures like if you don't sleep with me you're obviously gay and I'm sure that information will just happen to get out. Now to adults this doesn't sound all that horrible, but to a teen who know little to nothing about the real world, who's whole world is in fact school and his peers, this is a devastating threat. Most of us don't understand how teens, who are still basically kids, are manipulated so easily. But, just think back to your own past, as a school child, and how your peers held such an important place in your life that to loose them would be worse than death. We also have to realize that many of these people are in positions of power and just looking at studies like the Stanford Prison Experiment and the Milgram Experiment we can see how susceptible people are to figures of authority (children even more so). Our lack of caring and our social propensity for dismissing the effects of this kind of abuse just undermines our ability to get victims to step forward.
</post>
<post author="Checkmite" datetime="2011-11-15T14:51:00" id="p62">
I'm not referring to female sex offenses in general; I'm referring to the claim that the majority of them are "neighborhood Mrs Robinsons porking 15-year-old boys" — which as an aside is the first time I've seen "porking" used to describe something a female does to a male, but nevermind; that particular claim does not seem supported at all. Given that it seems to me greater numbers of females that work around or have access to minors, have access to younger children rather than teenagers, I'm more inclined to believe most molestations perpetrated by females involve younger children.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-15T15:20:00" id="p63">
@Checkmite: Sorry, I misunderstood what you meant. And generally I would agree with that assessment. Though, there do seem to be quite a female teachers doing these kind of things: <a href="http://www.wnd.com/news/article.asp?ARTICLE_ID=53859">The Big List</a>.
</post>
<post author="Checkmite" datetime="2011-11-15T15:45:00" id="p64">
Well, lately it's just become easier for those sorts of abuses to make news. One thing I've noticed lately when it comes to female teachers who abuse boys is that often the situation was brought to light when the parents checked the cell phone bill and find dozens of texts daily from the teacher's number to their child's phone and demanded an explanation.

But, and it's a big one, there have been cases where the situation was exposed by the teenage boy involved reporting it to his parents or police. And it has happened that these victims give impact statements at the end of the trial describing the abuse as being emotionally damaging. It happens; which is why attitudes like LYS's that such cases don't deserve to be taken seriously are an obstacle to getting those particular victims to speak up. Imagine being a genuinely straight boy who has to tell the world he didn't like having sex with a woman, when men you otherwise look up to and admire are telling you that it should be making you feel lucky and "manly".
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-15T16:02:00" id="p65">
As a side note, abuse and humiliation are not just happening to children. Society has double standards for sexual harassment like in this case:
<quote>
Dr. Twana Sparks, who was accused of performing non-authorized genital exams on male patients without their consent while they were under anesthesia, will not lose her medical license and has signed an agreement with the New Mexico Medical Board that allows her to continue to practice, but with numerous restrictions.( <a href="http://www.fabulousnurse.com/nurse-fired-for-reporting-physician-unethical-behavior/">Link</a> )

</quote>
Do you think a male doctor would keep his license? Also there's proof, though most of the articles on this are gone or hard to find, that those involved kept silent and even found it amusing as the practice continued for years. The nurse who turned in this doctor was fired, so much for justice.

And, where's the moral outrage for cases like these: date rape drug used on men <a href="http://www.marieclaire.com/world-reports/news/hong-kong-date-rape-drug-rohypnol-men">Link</a> and <a href="http://dimewars.com/Video/MEN-GETTING-DATE-RAPED--Miami-Women-Have-Mastered-The-Art-Of-Slipping-Mickeys-And-Robbing-Men-Blind.aspx?bcmediaid=01bd171d-0505-4809-a729-24b820344022">Video Link</a>. Now in both cases sexual abuse probably did not happen, but if there were cases where it did who would come forward? I read a study that showed that a significant percentage [2% to 5%] of college men had been dosed with the date rape drug (and not for theft) at some time and never reported it. Those are just the ones willing to admit it, how many others are there out there?

One of the reasons I bring up male rape and abuse is because I believe by showing that anyone can be effected by this we will start taking all claims more seriously. Too many people believe its not their problem, on both sides of the gender spectrum. Abuse is abuse, no perpetrator deserves a pass, and all victims deserve justice.
</post>
<post author="ChristineR" datetime="2011-11-15T16:12:00" id="p66">
Actually if you look at females who are actually prosecuted for rape, the majority were assisting a male rapist somehow. I don't know how this relates to the actual incident of females who rape since as pointed out female-on-male statutory rape is often not prosecuted even when it comes to the attention of law enforcement.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-15T19:23:00" id="p67">
<quote orig_author="ChristineR">
Actually if you look at females who are actually prosecuted for rape, the majority were assisting a male rapist somehow. I don't know how this relates to the actual incident of females who rape since as pointed out female-on-male statutory rape is often not prosecuted even when it comes to the attention of law enforcement.

</quote>
Can you post statistics or any recent research that shows this?
</post>
<post author="ChristineR" datetime="2011-11-15T21:10:00" id="p68">
Well, this wasn't the study I originally saw, but here's a sample of 18 Canadian women in prison--90% or sixteen had a male co-offender.

<a href="http://www.csc-scc.gc.ca/text/pblct/so/female/female-05-eng.shtml#P224_33932">http://www.csc-scc.gc.ca/text/pblct/...tml#P224_33932</a>
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-15T23:20:00" id="p69">
@ChristineR: While I agree that the majority of those arrested are co-abusers, I believe that there's a large percentage of just female abusers out there. According to studies one reason for this discrepancy is:
<quote>
Beliefs and perceptions at the macro level can, in turn, influence the perspectives and responses at a more micro level. Indeed, there is evidence that broader cultural biases play a role in the willingness of various criminal justice and treatment professionals to acknowledge female sex offending (see, e.g., Becker et al., 2001; Denov, 2004). For example, researchers found that training for law enforcement officers tends to be geared exclusively around men as sex offenders and women as victims. In combination with the sex role stereotypes that exist within society, this impacts the responses of law enforcement to female-perpetrated sex crimes (Denov, 2004). Specifically, the research revealed that police officers reacted with disbelief to allegations involving women, minimized the seriousness of the reports, viewed the female suspects as less dangerous and harmful, and were prone toward labeling the cases as unfounded (Denov, 2004).( <a href="http://www.csom.org/pubs/female_sex_offenders_brief.pdf">Link</a> )

</quote>
Even when women are co-abusers they're likely to face no consequences for their actions.
<quote>
There is some evidence that females are more likely to be involved with co-abusers, typically a male, though studies report a range from 25% to 77% (Faller, 1987; Kaufman et al., 1995; McCarty, 1986). However, Mayer (1992), in a review of data on 17 adolescent female sex offenders, found that only 2 were involved with male co-perpetrators. She also found that the young women in this study knew their victims and that none experienced legal consequences for their actions.( <a href="http://www.canadiancrc.com/Female_Sex_Offenders-Female_Sexual_Predators_awareness.aspx">Link</a> )

</quote>
The general idea that females only commit sexual abuse when forced by a male is a myth.
<quote>
Although it is found that sexual abuse that involve females sometimes happen with the involvement of a male co-offender, the majority of sexual violent crimes reported that imply women, have female perpetrators only with no male involvement. This does not say that sexual offences by females are not coerced by men, but it was found that women are more likely to be equal partners in the abuse and at times females are coercing the sexual abuse. ( <a href="http://securitynews.hubpages.com/hub/Top-Ten-Misconceptions-on-Female-Sex-Offenders">Link</a> )

</quote>

<quote>
Numerous studies have shown that females sexually abuse others alone as well as with co-offenders. The Dube et al. (2005) study found that 23% reported female only perpetrators. Other studies have claimed higher and lower rates.

It is true that some female sex offenders sexually abuse because they are being coerced. It is also true that sometimes they are an equal partner in the offending and sometimes they are the ones doing the coercing.( <a href="http://www.articlesaboutmen.com/2010/09/top-ten-myths-about-female-sex-offenders-911/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+ArticlesAboutMen+%28Articles+About+Men%29">Link</a> )

</quote>

Also, at one point, there was a very negative response by womens groups, early into the push to recognize sexual crimes, against women being classified as predators. Many of the groups claimed rape and sexual abuse were gendered issues, privileged males against unprivileged females, thus the response by local and federal government agencies. Making female on male abuse a mostly ignored offense.
<quote>
86% of the victims of female sexual predators aren't believed, so the crimes go unreported and don't get prosecuted.

Considering these facts, arrest statistics for child sexual offenders by gender are meaningless.( <a href="http://www.canadiancrc.com/Female_Sex_Offenders-Female_Sexual_Predators_awareness.aspx">Link</a> )

</quote>
Mentioned earlier is that the DOJ refuses to fund any research in the area of male abuse. Until we fix the social and legal biases I doubt we'll find the real scope of female perpetrators.
</post>
<post author="sadhatter" datetime="2011-11-16T06:52:00" id="p70">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
As a side note, abuse and humiliation are not just happening to children. Society has double standards for sexual harassment like in this case: Do you think a male doctor would keep his license? Also there's proof, though most of the articles on this are gone or hard to find, that those involved kept silent and even found it amusing as the practice continued for years. The nurse who turned in this doctor was fired, so much for justice.

And, where's the moral outrage for cases like these: date rape drug used on men <a href="http://www.marieclaire.com/world-reports/news/hong-kong-date-rape-drug-rohypnol-men">Link</a> and <a href="http://dimewars.com/Video/MEN-GETTING-DATE-RAPED--Miami-Women-Have-Mastered-The-Art-Of-Slipping-Mickeys-And-Robbing-Men-Blind.aspx?bcmediaid=01bd171d-0505-4809-a729-24b820344022">Video Link</a>. Now in both cases sexual abuse probably did not happen, but if there were cases where it did who would come forward? I read a study that showed that a significant percentage [2% to 5%] of college men had been dosed with the date rape drug (and not for theft) at some time and never reported it. Those are just the ones willing to admit it, how many others are there out there?

One of the reasons I bring up male rape and abuse is because I believe by showing that anyone can be effected by this we will start taking all claims more seriously. Too many people believe its not their problem, on both sides of the gender spectrum. Abuse is abuse, no perpetrator deserves a pass, and all victims deserve justice.

</quote>
With all the talk of the underage being molested i would like to bring to light the fact that same age rape does happen as well. And the reaction of society in general is a hand wave at best, and mocking at worst.

Personally it was a female friend, after a night of partying, like many other times we slept in the same room. Now for those that don't know the natural reaction when sleeping for a male is an erection.

There may have been no damage, but to wake up and have someone who you have told " sorry, but i don't want to have sex with you." having sex with you, is a distinct violation. Then being male, one actually has to think " How do i stop this without harming the assailant.", because if harm comes, the situation could easily be told in reverse.

Then there is the issue of no protection being used, a fun couple of months wondering if the girl got pregnant, or if you received some kind of std. Not to mention everyone reacting like " what is the issue?" when you avoid this person, and treating you with disdain once you explain the issue. Acting as if your in the wrong for not wanting to be around the person.

I am no Tom Cruise ( that is me in my pic.) but in my life this has happened twice, and the act, and the reaction were some of the worst experiences in my life. Male victims may have different kinds of trauma but they are just as serious, as that of females.
</post>
<post author="Checkmite" datetime="2011-11-16T09:02:00" id="p71">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Also, at one point, there was a very negative response by womens groups, early into the push to recognize sexual crimes, against women being classified as predators. Many of the groups claimed rape and sexual abuse were gendered issues, privileged males against unprivileged females, thus the response by local and federal government agencies. Making female on male abuse a mostly ignored offense. Mentioned earlier is that the DOJ refuses to fund any research in the area of male abuse. Until we fix the social and legal biases I doubt we'll find the real scope of female perpetrators.

</quote>
Whatever the reason, the fact remains that males as victims is of negligible concern in society, and males as victims of females are a negligible percentage of that. Reports and papers compiled by law enforcement agencies (the FBI, for instance) almost exclusively discuss child sex abuse as an issue of girls being molested by men; on rare occasions they may mention boys, but always again as victims of men. It seems most authors of these reports, if they bother to address the situation at all, feel that a sentence to the effect of "some children report female perpetrators" is all the attention the topic deserves.

Further, community outreach and crisis programs are geared exclusively towards women who have been victimized by men. Very few support groups and resources are available for male victims, whether of male or female abusers. Most of the support groups that do exist are informal and organized by the victims themselves because the professional and social motivation and concern simply isn't there.
</post>
<post author="Checkmite" datetime="2011-11-16T10:19:00" id="p72">
Is this the part of the discussion where somebody mentions that sex between adults and children was tolerated by another (long dead) civilization over a thousand years ago, and by this one animal species on an island somewhere, and therefore it obviously can't be intrinsically harmful? Because that's the part where I'm done with the discussion.
</post>
<post author="AvalonXQ" datetime="2011-11-16T11:11:00" id="p73">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Mentioned earlier is that the DOJ refuses to fund any research in the area of male abuse.

</quote>
Yeah, you're overstating. What you showed is that the DOJ is not looking for research on male or underaged female victims in order to provide further data on the specific subject of study you quoted. In other words, for expanding that specific research, they're only interested in study proposals that involve adult female victims. That doesn't mean they ignore the category in general.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-16T14:38:00" id="p74">
<quote orig_author="AvalonXQ">
Yeah, you're overstating. What you showed is that the DOJ is not looking for research on male or underaged female victims in order to provide further data on the specific subject of study you quoted. In other words, for expanding that specific research, they're only interested in study proposals that involve adult female victims. That doesn't mean they ignore the category in general.

</quote>

I was not overstating. The DOJ had previously refused to pay for research into domestic violence against male victims. The link I posted was to the "The National Institute for Justice (DOJ): Solicitation for Proposals on Justice Responses to Intimate Partner Violence and Stalking." It was to look into the problem of domestic violence, which at the time was considered solely a female issue. And to back my claim:
<quote>
For years, the DOJ has explicitly refused to fund studies that investigate domestic violence against men. According to specialists in this field, the DOJ recently agreed to cover this problem -- as long as researchers give equal time to addressing violence against women.( <a href="http://www.dailyfinance.com/2010/01/30/a-hidden-crime-domestic-violence-against-men-is-a-growing-probl/">Link</a> )

</quote>
Even now they will not fund studies that research just male victims of domestic violence. And while I provide evidence to back my claim where is yours (that they were funding studies on the subject of male victims of domestic violence)? I'd be happy to hear it, because I've seen none before the recent policy change.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-16T16:05:00" id="p75">
<quote orig_author="Checkmite">
Whatever the reason, the fact remains that males as victims is of negligible concern in society, and males as victims of females are a negligible percentage of that. Reports and papers compiled by law enforcement agencies (the FBI, for instance) almost exclusively discuss child sex abuse as an issue of girls being molested by men; on rare occasions they may mention boys, but always again as victims of men. It seems most authors of these reports, if they bother to address the situation at all, feel that a sentence to the effect of "some children report female perpetrators" is all the attention the topic deserves.

Further, community outreach and crisis programs are geared exclusively towards women who have been victimized by men. Very few support groups and resources are available for male victims, whether of male or female abusers. Most of the support groups that do exist are informal and organized by the victims themselves because the professional and social motivation and concern simply isn't there.

</quote>
Just as a note, I find the word negligible in terms of any abuse as offensive. What's the point you're trying to make in the above quote?

Myself, I'm pointing out facts and looking for opinions on how to change societies view. I know that many abuse support and advocacy groups are moving in the direction of recognizing male victims of female abuse (if they have not already) and that spreading knowledge of the problem is the only way to get more support. Knowledge is power and I'm always looking to expand my base and that of others. Spreading what I know is one of the few ways I can help. And I disagree that the problem is negligible, because we have no real idea how large the real problem is.
</post>
<post author="Checkmite" datetime="2011-11-16T17:02:00" id="p76">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Just as a note, I find the word negligible in terms of any abuse as offensive. What's the point you're trying to make in the above quote?

Myself, I'm pointing out facts and looking for opinions on how to change societies view. I know that many abuse support and advocacy groups are moving in the direction of recognizing male victims of female abuse (if they have not already) and that spreading knowledge of the problem is the only way to get more support. Knowledge is power and I'm always looking to expand my base and that of others. Spreading what I know is one of the few ways I can help. And I disagree that the problem is negligible, because we have no real idea how large the real problem is.

</quote>
Perhaps I worded that wrong. I suppose a better way to write that would have been "society's concern for males as victims is negligible". It certainly doesn't deserve to be that way; in fact it's a moral tragedy. When I cite the scarce mention of male victims in literature and scant resources for the few male victims society does acknowledge, I'm doing so with disdain.
</post>
<post author="jj" datetime="2011-11-16T19:38:00" id="p77">
<quote orig_author="Bikewer">
Been in police work for 40 years. Have never handled a single case involving a female abuser. Do such things occur? Sure. Undereported? Sure.

But still.....

</quote>
Um.

My experience, some 30 years old, was that a male victim got laughed at by the PD when he complained. I was witness to one such outburst of laughter. The victim got nothing but ridicule.
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-16T20:22:00" id="p78">
<quote orig_author="jj">
Um.

My experience, some 30 years old, was that a male victim got laughed at by the PD when he complained. I was witness to one such outburst of laughter. The victim got nothing but ridicule.

</quote>
Then all I can think of to do is change the attitudes by shining a light on it they can't ignore, can't keep laughing at.

A few of the ones who can do it, who are able to speak up, are going to have to, loud and long. After all, women didn't get what they have now by waiting for it. They had to fight, and it was dirty and ugly and hurtful. They had to be the change they wanted to see, they had to yell and holler and protest and get out there. Take the name-calling and the laughter and the digs and insults. Years of it.

No, not everyone can do that, not by a long shot. And for many, even trying would harm them even further. But it's not going to change on its own. It just isn't. Someone has to speak.

It sounds as if I'm saying it's someone else's job, not mine, but people are already largely in agreement that girls shouldn't be sexually abused. To get them to understand about boys, some really tough work has to be done, and it has to be done by some of those once-boys.

There have to be posters and commercials and PSAs. It has to get on talk shows and documentaries...The Cry of the Unheard has to ring out until it's all we can hear and we help these boys, these men. People have to be made to take this seriously.

If anything good at all can come out of this Penn State mess, it's awareness. But it can't end here or it'll just end. It's a tough row to hoe, but someone's got to.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-16T21:44:00" id="p79">
<quote orig_author="L.Y.S.">
In a perfect world high school aged teenagers wouldn't seek out older people for sex. Unfortunately it isn't a perfect world. I would never justify sex with a child, but a (late-staged) teenager is already a curious creature, forming their own sexual identities. With all the tragic stories being told, I suppose I should tell my own....[snip]...

</quote>
I think that we're talking past each other here. I believe consensual sex at the 'age of consent' is okay. My problem is, that those boys in their teen years basically forced into sex through blackmail, position of authority, or coercion are basically considered to have consented by gender. If you're male, you've automatically consented. Because we all know, if you're a guy you always want sex. That's where my problem lies. No one believes a teenage boy who says he was coerced into sex. And a man... forget about it.

Just want to add, I think that an adult is obligated to wait until the age of consent that's what being an adult means: acting like an adult.
</post>
<post author="L.Y.S." datetime="2011-11-16T23:26:00" id="p80">
What specific age are we talking? When you say "teenaged" I have to assume you are also talking about the group I was talking about. I am making an argument for individuals 15-17, who are you making an argument for? We may not be in disagreement here like tyr_13 said. I just want to get my facts straight.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-17T00:40:00" id="p81">
<quote orig_author="L.Y.S.">
What specific age are we talking? When you say "teenaged" I have to assume you are also talking about the group I was talking about. I am making an argument for individuals 15-17, who are you making an argument for? We may not be in disagreement here like tyr_13 said. I just want to get my facts straight.

</quote>
Well, when I'm talking about teenage, I mean age of consent (its by state in the US from): 16-18. But my real concern is with consent, not specific ages. Though, I do consider 15 to be too young for many reasons; one is that in most places this isn't even driving age, possibly creating a level of dependence and power with older individuals. Also, when I say consent I'm talking the boy's/man's choice to have sex not ones right to legally consent because of age.
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-17T11:24:00" id="p82">
<quote orig_author="curi0us">
Just to add to this, I was in sexual relationship when I was about 7 with a female babysitter who was twice my age. I have wondered a lot how it might have effected me, but I didn't feel victimized by it. Still don't.

</quote>

That's good, then.

But since we're not prescient, and have no way of knowing in advance which children would be harmed and which would discern no harm, then why should we allow it, knowing the high potential for harm?
</post>
<post author="BStrong" datetime="2011-11-18T04:58:00" id="p83">
I can only reference the jurisdiction where I worked - and female offenders were treated no differently than males wrt sex abuse or domestic abuse cases.

The media may ignore female offender prosecutions, but the DA's office certainly did not.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-18T09:55:00" id="p84">
@Ivor: Reading through your comments only leads me to believe that you're advocating for sex with children and let me just express my opinion: eww! Let me just reiterate - EWW!

I think the subject of the thread is proof that social mores and practices are not what causes the harm to children, but the act itself. Society usually holds that a boy who has sex with an older woman is lucky and not a victim. This causes added stress to those victimized boys as they are not allowed to feel like they were harmed and if they do then something is wrong with them. Many studies of boys of female sexual abuse, show the boys trying to claim they were not abused while suffering all the symptoms of that abuse. Society and male stereotypes push boys into a no win situation. Claiming abuse strips them of their masculinity. Its just the opposite of what you claim to be the real problem. The effects on "lucky" boys include confusion in their sexuality, self-blame, depression, drastically increased risk of suicide, and shame to name a few. How can you explain it as not intrinsic damage since society lauds the abuse of young males by females?

One of your claims is that sexual abuse is done by those not interested in the wellbeing of the child that causes the harm. This again is a ridicules claim as many female abusers think of their abuse as helping the male child reach adulthood. That their abuse is a favor; something the boy can look back fondly upon. Research (links listed in previous posts) show the damage done. Many abused boys grow up to be men with distorted negative views of women: from women are evil to the classic women are just sex objects. A lot of abused boys are distrustful of women and grow up to distant and even sometimes abusive adults. And in cases of mother-son incest the effects are profound (just do a little google searching) and easy to verify. The point is that even when the perpetrator does care about the wellbeing of the child the damage is still done nullifying your argument.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-18T11:38:00" id="p85">
<quote orig_author="Information Analyst">
The problem with much of this thread is that people are throwing the word "children" around, when there is no universal acceptance in posters' countries of origin what constitutes the upper age limit. In the UK the AoC is 16, which may freak out a lot of Americans, but in some European countries it's even lower. In my country, it may be illegal, but few would consider a 14-15 year old having consensual sex with a slightly older partner to be irrepairaby damaged. Most of my female friends certainly happily admit to having sex with older (and sometimes considerably so) boyfriends at those ages.

</quote>
I've stated, just recently in a previous post, what I think of age and how each age group should be treated by the law. The real focus of this thread has nothing to do with age really but consent and social stereotypes about female on male abuse, sexual or otherwise.
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-11-18T11:54:00" id="p86">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
@Ivor: Reading through your comments only leads me to believe that you're advocating for sex with children and let me just express my opinion: eww! Let me just reiterate - EWW!

I think the subject of the thread is proof that social mores and practices are not what causes the harm to children, but the act itself. Society usually holds that a boy who has sex with an older woman is lucky and not a victim. This causes added stress to those victimized boys as they are not allowed to feel like they were harmed and if they do then something is wrong with them. Many studies of boys of female sexual abuse, show the boys trying to claim they were not abused while suffering all the symptoms of that abuse. Society and male stereotypes push boys into a no win situation. Claiming abuse strips them of their masculinity. Its just the opposite of what you claim to be the real problem. The effects on "lucky" boys include confusion in their sexuality, self-blame, depression, drastically increased risk of suicide, and shame to name a few. How can you explain it as not intrinsic damage since society lauds the abuse of young males by females?

One of your claims is that sexual abuse is done by those not interested in the wellbeing of the child that causes the harm. This again is a ridicules claim as many female abusers think of their abuse as helping the male child reach adulthood. That their abuse is a favor; something the boy can look back fondly upon. Research (links listed in previous posts) show the damage done. Many abused boys grow up to be men with distorted negative views of women: from women are evil to the classic women are just sex objects. A lot of abused boys are distrustful of women and grow up to distant and even sometimes abusive adults. And in cases of mother-son incest the effects are profound (just do a little google searching) and easy to verify. The point is that even when the perpetrator does care about the wellbeing of the child the damage is still done nullifying your argument.

</quote>
A problem with the research is that it's self-selecting for the problem cases.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-18T12:24:00" id="p87">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
A problem with the research is that it's self-selecting for the problem cases.

</quote>
Where is your proof? Many studies that reference male victims were not looking for research on them, but on female victims. The findings were thus unintended and could not be cherry-picked as you claim. Also note, the laws are in place because it affects the majority that way and the laws should not be changed for the few exceptions. If you have proof otherwise provide it, until then I say it's just your opinion with no factual backing. You give no examples of this mythical non-harmful sexual interaction with children for us to refute. In fact, you make no claims that hard data has not otherwise disproved. If you want to argue bring your facts to bear. If you really wish to provide a meaningful conversation on the subject baseless speculation is of little value except for ones own self-serving justification. Without some form of proof you're suggesting removing legal protections from children that took decades to put in place leaving them open to no recourse when abused. How anyone can justify that is beyond me.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-18T12:39:00" id="p88">
<quote orig_author="curi0us">
Just to add to this, I was in sexual relationship when I was about 7 with a female babysitter who was twice my age. I have wondered a lot how it might have effected me, but I didn't feel victimized by it. Still don't.

</quote>
I'm glad that you don't feel abused, but I don't know you. Many men/boys don't think of themselves as abused but show all the classic signs: depression, anxiety, and many other mental problems. Do you have problems? How do you treat women and what is your attitude about them? I'm not saying you were effected, but sometimes it takes an outside person to see what we can't. Most alcoholics don't think they are, but reality shows us the opposite. Self-delusion is common human failing, one I see in myself all the time <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/mazeguyemotions/blush.gif"/>. My point is, if you ever need to talk I'm willing to listen. There are also many people out there willing to talk to you on that subject. I can send you some links if you want.

I'll list just a few here (just in case):
<a href="http://www.malesurvivor.org/">Male Survivor</a>
<a href="http://www.rainn.org/">RAINN</a>
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-11-18T15:40:00" id="p89">
This should set the cat amongst the pigeons:

<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rind_et_al._controversy">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rind_et_al._controversy</a>

<quote>
The Rind et al. controversy was a unique historical debate in scientific literature, public media, and the US government, regarding a 1998 peer reviewed paper on child sexual abuse (CSA) that conducted a meta-analysis of several samples of college students.[1] The paper was written by researchers Bruce Rind (PhD), Philip Tromovitch and Robert Bauserman, following a related 1997 meta-analysis by Rind and Tromovitch in the Journal of Sex Research.[2] The debate resulted in the unprecedented condemnation of the paper by the United States House of Representatives and concern in the social science research community over the chilling effect the resolution may have on publication of controversial research results.

The authors' stated goal was "...to address the question: In the population of persons with a history of CSA [child sexual abuse], does this experience cause intense psychological harm on a widespread basis for both genders?" Some of the authors' more controversial conclusions were that child sexual abuse does not necessarily cause intense, pervasive harm to the child;[3] that the reason the current view of child sexual abuse was not substantiated by their empirical scrutiny was because the construct of CSA was questionably valid; and that the psychological damage caused by the abusive encounters depends on whether the encounter was consensual or not.[1]

Rind et al. concluded with a statement that even though CSA may not result in harm, this does not mean it is not wrong or morally repugnant behavior and denied that their findings implied current moral and legal prohibitions against CSA should be changed.[1] Numerous age of consent reform organizations have quoted the paper in support of their efforts to lower or rescind age of consent laws, and defense attorneys have used the study to argue for minimizing harm in child sexual abuse cases.[4][5]

</quote>
And a New York Magazine article on the subject of the OP:

<a href="http://nymag.com/news/features/17064/">http://nymag.com/news/features/17064/</a>

<quote>
...

Jason stayed in school for just three weeks in Jacksonville before he dropped out. He says he will join the Marines after he gets his GED, but just for the money. He doesnt miss DeMartini-Scully, he says, who by the end was suggesting she wanted to marry him. But he also says he doesnt feel raped. I just, I dont know, I feel weird. She was 30 years older than me, so I feel a little bit taken advantage of. If I was a girl, I probably wouldnt talk to you about it, but a female cant really rape a guy, you know?

Jason says he would not have given a statement to the Long Island police incriminating DeMartini-Scully if he hadnt been under pressure. They said if I didnt they were gonna press charges on me because I was with Dianes daughter, who is only 14, and now Jason is 17, thus making him guilty of sexual misconduct himself. As of his last birthday, Jasons relationships switched status in the eyes of the law: Sex with the then-44-year-old school psychologist who had been after him since he was 16 became okay; sex with her teenage daughter became a crime.

...

</quote>
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-18T16:28:00" id="p90">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
This should set the cat amongst the pigeons:
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rind_et_al._controversy">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rind_et_al._controversy</a>
<a href="http://nymag.com/news/features/17064/">http://nymag.com/news/features/17064/</a>

</quote>
As to the first study I think the bias is clear (included in your own linked article):
<quote>
Stephanie Dallam and Anne Salter have pointed out that Rind and Bauserman have had associations with age of consent reform organizations. In the years before the paper was written, both Rind and Bauserman had published articles in Paidika, a defunct non-scholarly journal whose purpose was "to demonstrate that paedophilia has been, and remains, a legitimate and productive part of the totality of human experience." In addition, shortly after the paper's publication, Rind and Bauserman were keynote speakers at a pedophile advocacy conference occurring in the Netherlands.

</quote>
The second proves nothing as it is a single case, and he's still young. Who knows how he'll feel in the years to come. He shows his own confusion already about it here:
<quote>
I just, I dont know, I feel weird. She was 30 years older than me, so I feel a little bit taken advantage of. If I was a girl, I probably wouldnt talk to you about it, but a female cant really rape a guy, you know?

</quote>
Typical social stereotype making it hard for him to even admit he was victimized. If he really didn't feel that way why would he even mention rape. It's a classic psychological dodge: he's confused and looking for others to justify it one way or another for him.
</post>
<post author="Checkmite" datetime="2011-11-19T08:15:00" id="p91">
Interesting, this thread. First the premise of how society reacts to or approaches female child abusers was redirected into a focus on whether edge cases can be interpreted as not abusive, and when consensus was tentatively reached on that point it was used as a foot in the door to question the immorality of child sexual abuse as a whole.

These may seem like fascinating issues that are fun to explore to those without any emotional skin in the game. For me, I'm afraid the question is quite horrific. It's a shame that people like us theoretically have a special perspective which allows us to make crucial contributions to the discussion, but the fact of how we came by that perspective in the minds of many obviously disqualifies us as unobjective.

Well, have fun with your explorations, as long as they remain confined to thoughts and words.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-19T13:16:00" id="p92">
I agree with Checkmite we are getting a bit off-topic here.

Okay, so, time to turn it back somewhat to the subject of this thread. Lets say we have a 30 year old having sex with a 15 year old. Now, if you thought of the 30 year old as male you probably thought: the old pervert taking advantage of that innocent young girl. If you thought of a female as the 30 year old you probably thought: lucky young guy. First thing, in this odd double standard, is the cognitive disconnect. We assume that girls mature faster than boys, so a 15 year old girls should be much more capable of choosing her partner than a 15 year old boy. Why the disconnect? Second part, of the double standard, is consent. We assume that the girl can not or would not consent and that the boy would and does always consent. Why is consent gender specific? I know this is what is considered the fringe of the subject, but I want to understand what biases exist to help me tackle them. So, any opinions?

Side Note:

I think we should show more respect to the people's opinions who have actually gone through these experiences themselves than we have been. Real life experience is the base of all science. If we can not learn from the experiences of others, it says very little of us as a species. And yes, I know as skeptics we have to take things with a grain of salt, but that does not mean discounting them completely.

To show my own biases, I will state my own experience: I know very little of sexual abuse, except from friends. In fact, I know very little about sex as I've ever only reached 3rd base, in my singular serious relationship. So, I have no real experience or bias on the subject. I'm not attracted to children, and I'm not hyper sexual, though I would say I have a normal sex drive. I'm also straight. These create my base of reference. So, I go off of scientific data and others real life experiences only.
</post>
<post author="sgtbaker" datetime="2011-11-19T13:38:00" id="p93">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
I agree with Checkmite we are getting a bit off-topic here.

Okay, so, time to turn it back somewhat to the subject of this thread. Lets say we have a 30 year old having sex with a 15 year old. Now, if you thought of the 30 year old as male you probably thought: the old pervert taking advantage of that innocent young girl. If you thought of a female as the 30 year old you probably thought: lucky young guy. First thing, in this odd double standard, is the cognitive disconnect. We assume that girls mature faster than boys, so a 15 year old girls should be much more capable of choosing her partner than a 15 year old boy. Why the disconnect? Second part, of the double standard, is consent. We assume that the girl can not or would not consent and that the boy would and does always consent. Why is consent gender specific? I know this is what is considered the fringe of the subject, but I want to understand what biases exist to help me tackle them. So, any opinions?

Side Note:

I think we should show more respect to the people's opinions who have actually gone through these experiences themselves than we have been. Real life experience is the base of all science. If we can not learn from the experiences of others, it says very little of us as a species. And yes, I know as skeptics we have to take things with a grain of salt, but that does not mean discounting them completely.

To show my own biases, I will state my own experience: I know very little of sexual abuse, except from friends. In fact, I know very little about sex as I've ever only reached 3rd base, in my singular serious relationship. So, I have no real experience or bias on the subject. I'm not attracted to children, and I'm not hyper sexual, though I would say I have a normal sex drive. I'm also straight. These create my base of reference. So, I go off of scientific data and others real life experiences only.

</quote>
If you want opinions, mine would be very biased because I have a 15 year old daughter (she turns 15 next month, actually). 15 year old's, male or female, look like children to me. She is open with me, she asks me questions about things her friends talk about at the lunch table. Even with their heightened sexuality, their expressions and interests are still childlike. It's not shocking that they, themselves, are sexually curious but it is shocking to think that someone in my age group would want to play a role in that exploration.

I guess because remember knowing guys who opted not to have sex, I don't fall victim to the idea that a teenage boy would never not want to have sex, when given the opportunity.
</post>
<post author="myowninvention" datetime="2011-11-19T15:27:00" id="p94">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
I agree with Checkmite we are getting a bit off-topic here.

Okay, so, time to turn it back somewhat to the subject of this thread. Lets say we have a 30 year old having sex with a 15 year old. Now, if you thought of the 30 year old as male you probably thought: the old pervert taking advantage of that innocent young girl. If you thought of a female as the 30 year old you probably thought: lucky young guy. First thing, in this odd double standard, is the cognitive disconnect. We assume that girls mature faster than boys, so a 15 year old girls should be much more capable of choosing her partner than a 15 year old boy. Why the disconnect? Second part, of the double standard, is consent. We assume that the girl can not or would not consent and that the boy would and does always consent. Why is consent gender specific? I know this is what is considered the fringe of the subject, but I want to understand what biases exist to help me tackle them. So, any opinions?

</quote>
I think it's another aspect of the (much more acknowledged) social stigma that makes a promiscuous woman a slut, where a man would be a stud...player...whatever. We have as a society, an established notion of the man as the one in persuit, the woman the persued. Things that go against this notion are viewed negitively: a woman who persues sex is a slut, a man who has sex forced on him must be a pussy, less of a man, or he must have actally wanted it. Compound that with the fact that coerced sex and non-violent (that is, physically violent) sexual abuse is already much more difficult to prosicute even when the victim is a woman, and male victims have a lot going against them.

Unfortunatly, the only solution I can offer is the ever-present 'raise awareness'. Fighting long established gender stereotypes takes a long time and a lot of voices.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-19T16:41:00" id="p95">
<quote orig_author="myowninvention">
I think it's another aspect of the (much more acknowledged) social stigma that makes a promiscuous woman a slut, where a man would be a stud...player...whatever. We have as a society, an established notion of the man as the one in persuit, the woman the persued. Things that go against this notion are viewed negitively: a woman who persues sex is a slut, a man who has sex forced on him must be a pussy, less of a man, or he must have actally wanted it. Compound that with the fact that coerced sex and non-violent (that is, physically violent) sexual abuse is already much more difficult to prosicute even when the victim is a woman, and male victims have a lot going against them.

Unfortunatly, the only solution I can offer is the ever-present 'raise awareness'. Fighting long established gender stereotypes takes a long time and a lot of voices.

</quote>
I think this is a good point as it shows why a boy/man might try to play it off as positive, while a girl/woman would be predisposed to seeing it as negative. But is this stereotype as pervasive today? Many women and men think of "cougars" in a positive instead of negative light. The stereotype that promiscuity is negative in women has become less common, and, with the prevalence of AIDS and other diseases, promiscuity in men has become just the opposite.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-19T17:03:00" id="p96">
<quote orig_author="sgtbaker">
...[snip]... She is open with me, she asks me questions about things her friends talk about at the lunch table. Even with their heightened sexuality, their expressions and interests are still childlike....[snip]...

</quote>
I find it interesting that you talk with your daughter about such things. My sex education was my father walked in and said, "I know you're going to have sex, so when you do wear a condom.", then just walked out. Never mentioned or talked about it again. Of course, I think it's a good thing and should be more common. One thing I wonder about, is she childlike or is that just your perception of her? Just so you know, I'm not really questioning your opinion it was just a thought that came to me <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>. I know some parents who still see their children as kids even though they're in their late 20s. Is curiosity considered to be a childlike quality?

<quote orig_author="sgtbaker">
I guess because remember knowing guys who opted not to have sex, I don't fall victim to the idea that a teenage boy would never not want to have sex, when given the opportunity.

</quote>
I've know some also, myself included. I've always thought of sex as an act between to people who really love each other (no religious reasons) -- I'm a romantic, I know. I wonder where the stereotype that those guys who are not promiscuous are either gay or unmanly came from, any ideas?
</post>
<post author="sgtbaker" datetime="2011-11-19T17:55:00" id="p97">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
I find it interesting that you talk with your daughter about such things. My sex education was my father walked in and said, "I know you're going to have sex, so when you do wear a condom.", then just walked out. Never mentioned or talked about it again. Of course, I think it's a good thing and should be more common. One thing I wonder about, is she childlike or is that just your perception of her? Just so you know, I'm not really questioning your opinion it was just a thought that came to me <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/smile.gif"/>. I know some parents who still see their children as kids even though they're in their late 20s. Is curiosity considered to be a childlike quality?

</quote>
It's not like I sit around and share sex stories with her but if she has a question, I will answer it. Some of her friends are having sex (at least one, I know for sure) so she is asking me a lot of first time questions. As to why I may see her like a child, I take no offense to that. I admitted right off the bat that I have a bias because I have a 15 year old. She will forever seem like a child, to me.

When I say I see the youthfulness, though, it's in the way they talk and act in the crowd. She's got the friend who always finds a way to draw some parallel between the current conversation and some tragedy she's experienced, there's always a reason to feel sorry for her. She's got another friend who loves the drama; every guy she dates is "the one" for about an hour. When they talk to me, I can hear the way they mimick adult conversations without fully understanding how the language actually applies. She's got this one guy friend that comes over. He's a polite kid, he always makes it a point to come in and say hello to me, have a brief conversation and then he's off. Referring to my son he will say things like, "Yeah, I remember when I was that age." Oh that whole year and a half ago?

<quote>
I've know some also, myself included. I've always thought of sex as an act between to people who really love each other (no religious reasons) -- I'm a romantic, I know. I wonder where the stereotype that those guys who are not promiscuous are either gay or unmanly came from, any ideas?

</quote>
I can't say where everyone else got the idea that teenage boys only want sex but I can say that I got that idea from my mother. What she said, though, and what I experienced were two different things.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-20T13:41:00" id="p98">
<quote orig_author="curi0us">
I think there may be a core misunderstanding going here about something that can be highlighted with a simple question:

What percentage of sexually active college age women do you think have said "no" to sex when they actually meant "yes"?

(How one determined that answer is a good follow up question.)

</quote>
Okay, I'll play your game, just to see where this is going. I would say about 5% to 10% of women have said no when they meant yes at least once in their lives (this is just a guess based on anecdotal evidence). Just to be clear it doesn't matter what the woman meant it's what she said that counts. A 'no' is where it ends always, no matter what she meant. Also, I think when/if a woman says no but means yes what she really wants is for the man to woo her more, not force himself on her.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-20T15:17:00" id="p99">
<quote orig_author="tyr_13">
...[snip]... But this thread is was about female abuses and enablers....[snip]...

</quote>
Sorry, I'm trying to get it back on topic.

Here are a few things to discuss:

<quote>
In a 2004 study Myriam Denov also found that "emerging studies have revealed that the general public and professionals working in the area of child welfare perceive sexual abuse by women as relatively harmless as compared to sexual abuse by men."... She (Denov) further stated "that professional minimization or disbelief of victims' allegations of female perpetrated sexual abuse may actually exacerbate the negative effects of the sexual abuse, ultimately inciting secondary victimization."... 29% reported having sexually abused children at some point in their lives. The men were charged and convicted. The sexual abuse by the women was never reported.( <a href="http://jiv.sagepub.com/content/19/10/1137.short">Link</a> )

</quote>

<quote>
A study of 518 university students found that 38.8% of men and 47.9% of women reported being pressured into a range of sexual activity, from kissing and cuddling to intercourse and oral sex.... Of all males who have experienced sexual assault since the age of 15, the vast majority (63.9%) were assaulted by a female in the most recent incident.( <a href="http://www.menshealthaustralia.net/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=341&amp;Itemid=95">Link</a> )

</quote>

<quote>
Canada's largest study into the sexual exploitation of street kids and runaways has shattered the myths and stereotypes about who the abusers are, the most surprising finding being that many are women seeking sex with young males.

"I must admit it wasn't something we were expecting," said Elizabeth Saewyc, associate professor of nursing at the University of B.C. and principal investigator for the study, conducted by Vancouver's McCreary Centre Society.

"Some youth in each gender were exploited by women, with more than three out of four sexually exploited males reporting exchanging sex for money or goods with a female," she said.( <a href="http://www.canada.com/vancouversun/news/story.html?id=79708ae2-1dbf-4bdf-a9fe-83b65df121c1">Link</a> )

</quote>
</post>
<post author="AvalonXQ" datetime="2011-11-20T16:23:00" id="p100">
<quote orig_author="curi0us">
I think there may be a core misunderstanding going here about something that can be highlighted with a simple question:

What percentage of sexually active college age women do you think have said "no" to sex when they actually meant "yes"?

(How one determined that answer is a good follow up question.)

</quote>
From anecdotal experience, I'd ballpark 50%.
</post>
<post author="gumboot" datetime="2011-11-21T03:52:00" id="p101">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Okay, so, time to turn it back somewhat to the subject of this thread. Lets say we have a 30 year old having sex with a 15 year old. Now, if you thought of the 30 year old as male you probably thought: the old pervert taking advantage of that innocent young girl. If you thought of a female as the 30 year old you probably thought: lucky young guy. First thing, in this odd double standard, is the cognitive disconnect. We assume that girls mature faster than boys, so a 15 year old girls should be much more capable of choosing her partner than a 15 year old boy. Why the disconnect? Second part, of the double standard, is consent. We assume that the girl can not or would not consent and that the boy would and does always consent. Why is consent gender specific? I know this is what is considered the fringe of the subject, but I want to understand what biases exist to help me tackle them. So, any opinions?

</quote>

To be completely honest, my own personal immediate reaction is that each situation is equally creepy and sick. But at the same time I recognise your point, which is that the majority of the population would react the way you describe.

Simply put, I think the reason is that the overwhelming majority of people are sexist. They perceive specific gender roles for men and women at some level, and those gender roles dictate how they react to the scenarios.

What's remarkable, to me, is what's happening in my own country. New Zealand is quite unique. Not only do New Zealand women have the highest number of sexual partners in the world, but we are the only country in the world where women have more sexual partners than men.

Young women here are actually more likely to display typical "young guy" behaviour than the males are. We're not just talking promiscuity and predatory sex (by this I don't mean necessarily sexual assaults but rather going out with the specific intention of finding someone to have sex with) but also drinking behaviour and culture - for example rates of young female drink driving have sky-rocketed in recent years from when it was practically unheard of to now where it's starting to overtake male drink driving.

If there was any country where you'd expect attitudes to female sexual abusers to be catching up with reality it's here, but if anything the opposite is true. The depth of gender bias in all aspects of domestic and sexual violence in New Zealand is unbelievable.

What's perhaps the most alarming is that as young women here become increasingly assertive and aggressive, they're nonetheless well aware of their perceived "victim" status and will exploit that to their advantage. Rates of false sexual assault accusation are phenomenal. My own friend recently got a sexual abuse and child abuse accusation thrown at him in the midst of a custody dispute. Of course the accusation was utterly baseless and nothing came of it but the automatic reaction of the authorities was to believe it and what he had to go through was utterly repugnant. Was his ex in any way reprimanded for her false accusations (which included perjury)? No.

This reflects a deeply engrained form of sexism, that is based on baseless 19th Century notions of gender role. The simple fact is that women are just as violent, abusive, and cruel as men.
</post>
<post author="Safe-Keeper" datetime="2011-11-21T07:12:00" id="p102">
<quote>
What percentage of sexually active college age women do you think have said "no" to sex when they actually meant "yes"?

</quote>
Why do you ask? I'm afraid I don't get your point and I'm sincerely curious.

ETA: of course, even though it needs not be said, I of course agree 100% with this:

<quote>
Okay, I'll play your game, just to see where this is going. I would say about 5% to 10% of women have said no when they meant yes at least once in their lives (this is just a guess based on anecdotal evidence). Just to be clear it doesn't matter what the woman meant it's what she said that counts. A 'no' is where it ends always, no matter what she meant. Also, I think when/if a woman says no but means yes what she really wants is for the man to woo her more, not force himself on her.

</quote>
</post>
<post author="curi0us" datetime="2011-11-21T10:42:00" id="p103">
<quote orig_author="tyr_13">
No I can't answer as it's a relatively unknowable number. But this thread is was about female abuses and enablers. Unless you're trying to out enablers, it doesn't matter.

</quote>
As far as being "unknowable" like many sociological statistics it is a number that is difficult to know with precision but scientific research is commonly performed to answer similar questions and one could certainly state a number with confidence if they were aware of such research. A person might also just have enough empathy and experience to make an educated guess based on what they have encountered. Or one might have done personal research where they make an effort of engaging people on the topic in informal interviews.

As far as relevance it goes to the heart of the idea of the social contract. The gender and sex theory that was pushed on me as youth was dependent upon the number being zero. Just questioning if the number was zero was enough to get one labeled as a some sort of misogynist predator. What Epeke described earlier in regards to the insane amount of sexism he had to deal with wasn't limited to Just the reporting of female predators. It came up any time someone went against the prevailing doctrine.

<quote orig_author="AvalonXQ">
From anecdotal experience, I'd ballpark 50%.

</quote>
Thankyou for the reply.

<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Okay, I'll play your game, just to see where this is going. I would say about 5% to 10% of women have said no when they meant yes at least once in their lives (this is just a guess based on anecdotal evidence).

</quote>
I would say the number is dramatically higher than 5%-10%. I will write more on this in a later post but I am still curious to hear different peoples thoughts on the matter.

<quote>
Just to be clear it doesn't matter what the woman meant it's what she said that counts. A 'no' is where it ends always, no matter what she meant.

</quote>
That doesn't really make sense if you think about it clearly. If someone means "yes" and the other person understands that accurately then there is no harm in treating the "no" as a "yes"in that instance. In fact, in that instance doing so would be a demonstration of empathy.

There is an obvious problem here in that what I am saying means in some situation there is a total breakdown of the definition of rape to the point that a person might commit what looks like an illegal sexual assault but do so in a manner that is ethical and actually desired by "victim". A point you might not have realized is that if a women says "no" and means "yes" and the guy treats it as a "yes" she may not even register it as any sort of transgression at all. If a women doesn't feel victimized by behavior that legally looks like rape is she still a victim? Would it be ethical to convince her she really was victimized if she doesn't feel that way?

<quote>
Also, I think when/if a woman says no but means yes what she really wants is for the man to woo her more, not force himself on her.

</quote>
There is certainly a multitude of reasons why a person might say "no" when they mean "yes" but there is definitely a subset that wants to be violently overpowered. I would argue that there is something like a sexual orientation in regards to aggressiveness and that some people are just into sex that freaks other people out. You need a way to separate the actual traumatized victims from the people that would be victimized if they had the same emotional set as someone else. The inverse argument will also help your OP position IMO, maybe some of those guys who make lighthearted jokes about female predators really wouldn't have minded but that doesn't alter someone else feeling victimized.

<quote orig_author="Safe-Keeper">
Why do you ask? I'm afraid I don't get your point and I'm sincerely curious.

ETA: of course, even though it needs not be said, I of course agree 100% with this: (Naive1000's reply to me)

</quote>
Thank you for the reply, are you in agreement about the 5%-10% number as well? I will write more but I hope I somewhat addressed your question with my reply to Naive100. A general point I am making is that an overeagerness to see men as victimizers without regard to reality or common sense has been such a prevalent problem in society (at least mine) that a reluctance to see women that way may be actually a healthy counter reaction.

Consider these ads for a state where underage means under 18:

<a href="http://lvkr.ru/6uS2VR.jpg">http://lvkr.ru/6uS2VR.jpg</a>
<a href="http://lvkr.ru/PxWGpr.jpg">http://lvkr.ru/PxWGpr.jpg</a>

Edited by LashL: Changed hotlinks to regular links. Please see Rule 5.

Would progress be having similar ads targeting women "rapists" as well?
</post>
<post author="Mark6" datetime="2011-11-21T13:40:00" id="p104">
<quote orig_author="curi0us">
<a href="http://lvkr.ru/PxWGpr.jpg">http://lvkr.ru/PxWGpr.jpg</a>
Would progress be having similar ads targeting women "rapists" as well?

</quote>
I don't quite understand the point of this second ad.
</post>
<post author="tyr_13" datetime="2011-11-21T21:34:00" id="p105">
<quote orig_author="curi0us">
As far as being "unknowable" like many sociological statistics it is a number that is difficult to know with precision but scientific research is commonly performed to answer similar questions and one could certainly state a number with confidence if they were aware of such research. A person might also just have enough empathy and experience to make an educated guess based on what they have encountered. Or one might have done personal research where they make an effort of engaging people on the topic in informal interviews.

</quote>
To what end? Just to prove it's a non-zero number? That's a given.

<quote>
As far as relevance it goes to the heart of the idea of the social contract. The gender and sex theory that was pushed on me as youth was dependent upon the number being zero.

</quote>
I highly doubt that it was. Maybe that's how you understood it, but it's much more likely that the theory was dependent on things working best if people behave as if that number is zero to prevent 'accidental' rape. This may have been a time where all sorts of things, such as short skirts or even just going to certain bars, was consider 'consent' overriding even the woman saying 'no'.

<quote>
Just questioning if the number was zero was enough to get one labeled as a some sort of misogynist predator. What Epeke described earlier in regards to the insane amount of sexism he had to deal with wasn't limited to Just the reporting of female predators. It came up any time someone went against the prevailing doctrine.

</quote>
Perhaps because you misunderstood what they were actually advocating and thus misinterpreted what you were actually questioning.

<quote>
snip

If someone means "yes" and the other person understands that accurately then there is no harm in treating the "no" as a "yes"in that instance. In fact, in that instance doing so would be a demonstration of empathy.

</quote>
And if someone says 'no' and means no and the other person inaccurately understands it as 'yes' that would be demonstrating rape. Is it more important that one be able to 'demonstrate empathy' or to be able to accurately identify if you're raping someone or not?

<quote>
There is an obvious problem here in that what I am saying means in some situation there is a total breakdown of the definition of rape to the point that a person might commit what looks like an illegal sexual assault but do so in a manner that is ethical and actually desired by "victim". A point you might not have realized is that if a women says "no" and means "yes" and the guy treats it as a "yes" she may not even register it as any sort of transgression at all. If a women doesn't feel victimized by behavior that legally looks like rape is she still a victim? Would it be ethical to convince her she really was victimized if she doesn't feel that way?

</quote>
And if that is the case, then there won't be a damn problem at all. One wouldn't be accused of rape in that case. However, one can't even assume that just because a woman doesn't accuse a man of rape after he continued past a no that she didn't see it as rape.

<quote>
There is certainly a multitude of reasons why a person might say "no" when they mean "yes" but there is definitely a subset that wants to be violently overpowered. I would argue that there is something like a sexual orientation in regards to aggressiveness and that some people are just into sex that freaks other people out.

</quote>
Then it is incumbent upon them to make that clear. They aren't wrong or dirty to have the preference, but it would be wrong and damaging to society as a whole to assume that any given woman has that preference.

<quote>
You need a way to separate the actual traumatized victims from the people that would be victimized if they had the same emotional set as someone else.

</quote>
Where do you believe this is not being done?

<quote>
The inverse argument will also help your OP position IMO, maybe some of those guys who make lighthearted jokes about female predators really wouldn't have minded but that doesn't alter someone else feeling victimized.

</quote>
This is true.

<quote>
Thank you for the reply, are you in agreement about the 5%-10% number as well? I will write more but I hope I somewhat addressed your question with my reply to Naive100. A general point I am making is that an overeagerness to see men as victimizers without regard to reality or common sense has been such a prevalent problem in society (at least mine) that a reluctance to see women that way may be actually a healthy counter reaction.

Consider these ads for a state where underage means under 18:
<a href="http://lvkr.ru/6uS2VR.jpg">http://lvkr.ru/6uS2VR.jpg</a>
<a href="http://lvkr.ru/PxWGpr.jpg">http://lvkr.ru/PxWGpr.jpg</a>
Would progress be having similar ads targeting women "rapists" as well?

</quote>
That's the excluded middle fallacy right there.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-21T23:03:00" id="p106">
<quote orig_author="curi0us">
...[snip]... As far as relevance it goes to the heart of the idea of the social contract. The gender and sex theory that was pushed on me as youth was dependent upon the number being zero. Just questioning if the number was zero was enough to get one labeled as a some sort of misogynist predator. What Epeke described earlier in regards to the insane amount of sexism he had to deal with wasn't limited to Just the reporting of female predators. It came up any time someone went against the prevailing doctrine.

</quote>
I also have lived through the era of the gender feminists and know what you're talking about. From personal experiences I have a real dislike for the feminist movement -- that's why I'm an egalitarian. But, I have not let a few bad apples change my view on women, justice, or equality.

<quote orig_author="curi0us">
I would say the number is dramatically higher than 5%-10%. I will write more on this in a later post but I am still curious to hear different peoples thoughts on the matter.

<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Just to be clear it doesn't matter what the woman meant it's what she said that counts. A 'no' is where it ends always, no matter what she meant.

</quote>
That doesn't really make sense if you think about it clearly. If someone means "yes" and the other person understands that accurately then there is no harm in treating the "no" as a "yes"in that instance. In fact, in that instance doing so would be a demonstration of empathy.

There is an obvious problem here in that what I am saying means in some situation there is a total breakdown of the definition of rape to the point that a person might commit what looks like an illegal sexual assault but do so in a manner that is ethical and actually desired by "victim". A point you might not have realized is that if a women says "no" and means "yes" and the guy treats it as a "yes" she may not even register it as any sort of transgression at all. If a women doesn't feel victimized by behavior that legally looks like rape is she still a victim? Would it be ethical to convince her she really was victimized if she doesn't feel that way?

There is certainly a multitude of reasons why a person might say "no" when they mean "yes" but there is definitely a subset that wants to be violently overpowered. I would argue that there is something like a sexual orientation in regards to aggressiveness and that some people are just into sex that freaks other people out. You need a way to separate the actual traumatized victims from the people that would be victimized if they had the same emotional set as someone else. The inverse argument will also help your OP position IMO, maybe some of those guys who make lighthearted jokes about female predators really wouldn't have minded but that doesn't alter someone else feeling victimized.

</quote>
I'm sorry, I think you're very very confused. What you're advocating here is rape pure and simple. You can never be positive what she really means and that is a mistake no man should ever make. Many raped women never report the crime so just claiming she didn't report makes it okay is whole levels of creepy rape justification. Empathy is a great thing but as far as I know no one is a mind reader. Just the possibility that you could be raping someone should preclude you from ever doing something like that. I'm disturbed that you can't see that. Maybe you should checkout the sites I listed in one my earlier replies to you. And for those who have victim fantasies they have the option to play them out as planned activities. No one has the right to decided what the other person wants, EVER ! I can see no compromise on this principle.

<quote orig_author="curi0us">
...[snip]... A general point I am making is that an overeagerness to see men as victimizers without regard to reality or common sense has been such a prevalent problem in society (at least mine) that a reluctance to see women that way may be actually a healthy counter reaction...[snip]... Would progress be having similar ads targeting women "rapists" as well?

</quote>
I agree that we do see men as victimizers, but that's because we've decided that women can't be. Once we balance things out and we see it's not men vs women, but non-abusers vs abusers we'll be much better off. And yes, I do think having reverse gender adds like those would help: disabusing people of their gender bias is always a good thing.
</post>
<post author="Information Analyst" datetime="2011-11-22T06:05:00" id="p107">
<quote orig_author="curi0us">
Consider these ads for a state where underage means under 18:
<a href="http://lvkr.ru/6uS2VR.jpg">http://lvkr.ru/6uS2VR.jpg</a>
<a href="http://lvkr.ru/PxWGpr.jpg">http://lvkr.ru/PxWGpr.jpg</a>

</quote>
Words fail.

Actually, no, I could say that that creation of the second image (and it's stable-mates, by the look of them), would probably be counted as a criminal offences in the UK. Just goes to show....

I see that Wisconsin has an AoC of 18, and appears to be fairly draconian in it's lack of flexibilty. In that context the content of these posters "makes sense," because they reflect the law, but on the other hand it is a perfect example of the ridiculousness of the motion that a "child" is anyone up to the age of 17 years and 364 days.
</post>
<post author="Safe-Keeper" datetime="2011-11-22T06:35:00" id="p108">
<quote>
That doesn't really make sense if you think about it clearly. If someone means "yes" and the other person understands that accurately then there is no harm in treating the "no" as a "yes"in that instance. In fact, in that instance doing so would be a demonstration of empathy.

</quote>
Wow, a "no means yes"-er in 2011. Thought you guys had died out a long time ago.

It's this simple, as others have pointed out to you: given how you can't read minds, and that guesswork inevitably will lead to rapes, "no means no" is the only reasonable position to take.

If you remain unconvinced, read up on the psychological effects of sexual abuse. It ain't pretty.

<quote>
Thank you for the reply, are you in agreement about the 5%-10% number as well? I will write more but I hope I somewhat addressed your question with my reply to Naive100. A general point I am making is that an overeagerness to see men as victimizers without regard to reality or common sense has been such a prevalent problem in society (at least mine) that a reluctance to see women that way may be actually a healthy counter reaction.

</quote>
I don't detect an overeagerness to portray men as victimizers anywhere, and never have. In any society.

<quote>
Would progress be having similar ads targeting women "rapists" as well?

</quote>
If we decided that sex with anyone under 18 is rape and we uncovered statistics that showed females perpetrated such offenses often enough for a campaign to be warranted, then yes, yes, it would. Why <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/confused.gif"/> ?
</post>
<post author="Mark6" datetime="2011-11-22T07:34:00" id="p109">
<quote orig_author="Checkmite">
I imagine that not having society's approval when lusting after teenagers probably really sucks for some people. *shrug*

</quote>
Considering that the poster you were replying to lives in Sweden (age of consent: 15), your post is a serious fail.

And I agree that Wisconsin law (18, no provisions for age gap) and other laws like that are absurd. The posters may serve the function of informing people about the law, but that does not make the law itself just. FYI, I have no personal stake in this, as I do not "lust after teenagers"; the only time in my life I had sex with a teenager was when I was a teenager myself.
</post>
<post author="Arcade22" datetime="2011-11-22T14:01:00" id="p110">
<quote orig_author="Checkmite">
I imagine that not having society's approval when lusting after teenagers probably really sucks for some people. *shrug*

</quote>
But what self-respecting human being would care about what other people think about their own sexuality?

I'll just paraphrase William S. Burroughs: I dont care if people hate my guts; I assume most of them do. The important question is whether they are in a position to do anything about it.
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-23T13:23:00" id="p111">
Tired of it.

Ivor, your arguments have no relevance. I hope and intend to be done with them.

Now, on to something that does have relevance.

Here's a story from a UK source that shows fairly well the stigma of female-on-male sexual assault/abuse, the attitudes in the recent past to it, and the current attitudes today. Again, since we can't repost copyrighted material in its entirety, I instead post snippets here, with the understanding you'll go read it yourself and get the entire article.

<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-1042506/A-cloned-dog-Mormon-mink-lined-handcuffs-tantalising-mystery.html">http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/ar...g-mystery.html</a> (7th August 2008)

Yes, I understand the reputation of the Daily Fail. Its veracity is not at question here; only its treatment of the topic. (i.e. even if this is all a lie, it's the language used to tell it, not the story itself that's at question, okay? So, please spare me the "poor source" laughter; it doesn't apply to my point.)

The article is, for all intents and purposes, a "hey, lookie who we found!" type of thing. I cite here only the bits that are pertinent to this thread:

Background: a California woman made the news by paying several thousand dollars to have her beloved dog cloned. In the original article, her picture appeared. The writer of this article seems to have recognized her from another story, long ago:

<quote>
The face was familiar, albeit older and heavier. The surname was the same.

</quote>
Whom did he believe her to be?

<quote>
In 1978, Joyce McKinney jumped bail and disappeared after being charged with kidnapping a 17-stone male Mormon missionary, whom she had chained to a Devon cottage bed with mink handcuffs and forced to have sex.

</quote>
In the previous paragraph, the writer describes the above incident thusly:

<quote>
Surely it wasn't? Could the new owner of the world's first commercially cloned pups be the same woman who had gone on the run from British justice 30 years ago, having been the star of one of the most bizarre, entertaining and downright saucy court cases in living memory?

</quote>
Interesting, is it not, that a case of female-on-male rape is described in such a way?

It was entertaining ? Oh, gee, it was even saucy !

I wonder, seriously, if a case of male-on-female kidnapping, assault, imprisonment, and multiple rapes would earn such a lighthearted and fun description?

More backstory: this woman was apparently obsessed with the young Mormon man. She said she had an affair with him; that he impregnated her; that she miscarried. The young man, Kurt Anderson, sought the advice of his bishop and was advised to leave Utah and cease all contact with her. Which he tried to do. She hired detectives to find him. He'd fled all the way to Surrey. She flew to the UK with a male companion. They stalked and then kidnapped Anderson, chloroforming him and stuffing him into the trunk of their car. They then took him to a rented cottage.

<quote>
May chained the prisoner to a bed. For two days, McKinney tried to persuade the missionary to marry her and father her children. She even read Scriptures with him in bed.
When this failed to melt his opposition, McKinney reverted to Plan B.
This involved slipping into a 'see-through nightie', playing a cassette of 'romantic music', having Anderson 'spread- eagled' and sexually stimulating him.
She claimed this was a bondage 'game' played with his full consent.
He later told a court: 'I couldn't move. She grabbed the top of my pyjamas and tore them from my body until I was naked.
'I didn't wish it to happen. I was extremely depressed and upset after being forced to have sex.'

</quote>
It's what this article says next that made me know it was a subject for this thread:

<quote>
This 'rape' occurred three times.

</quote>
Note the word rape is in challenge quotes. The author is more than suggesting this event "wasn't really rape." How can we tell? Oh, it gets better:

<quote>
Fearing he would be kept prisoner for weeks (later there would be a body of male opinion which felt pangs of severe jealousy at his plight), Anderson promised to marry her.
But after she loosened his chains, he escaped and went straight to the police.

</quote>
Hmmm. I thought it was women who supposedly have "rape fantasies."

<quote>
There was an entertaining, if not downright titillating, committal hearing at Epsom Magistrates' Court, during which her counsel said of Anderson: 'Methinks the Mormon doth protest too much... you have seen the size of Mr Anderson and you have seen the size of my client.'

</quote>
And now it's cast as entertaining and titillating. Also, we're to understand that a weak, tiny, helpless woman can't possibly overpower a man, even though she's got chloroform and can drug him into unconsciousness, and has the help of another man, at that!

It brings me shame to see another writer do this to someone who can't really fight back or defend himself. If Anderson is still living, he's just been violated again, in public, again.

This is horribly wrong. This is why the stigma is still so strong, and a reason for why it still exists, as has been noted before. It's why Naive1000 started the thread, and good on him for doing so.

This does need to change. But as I said before, it's going to need a concerted, protracted campaign of awareness to even begin to begin to change it. Just like the one women had to wage to get people to see that we don't ask for it, that it's not about how we dress or where we go or what time of night we're out and about.

Rape is rape. Rape is wrong. Rape happens to women and to men.

But men are getting the same horrible, unfair, inaccurate, damaging treatment we women used to get. Well, we know how to stop that, or at least slow it considerably.

And that's what we have to do again.
</post>
<post author="bookitty" datetime="2011-11-23T13:37:00" id="p112">
<quote orig_author="slingblade">
Tired of it.

Ivor, your arguments have no relevance. I hope and intend to be done with them.

Now, on to something that does have relevance.

Here's a story from a UK source that shows fairly well the stigma of female-on-male sexual assault/abuse, the attitudes in the recent past to it, and the current attitudes today. Again, since we can't repost copyrighted material in its entirety, I instead post snippets here, with the understanding you'll go read it yourself and get the entire article.

<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-1042506/A-cloned-dog-Mormon-mink-lined-handcuffs-tantalising-mystery.html">http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/ar...g-mystery.html</a> (7th August 2008)

</quote>
That article is absolutely disgusting. The glee with which the reporter discusses the details of Mr. Anderson's rape and abuse is sadistic. I'm too angry to say more.
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-11-23T14:00:00" id="p113">
<quote orig_author="slingblade">
&lt;snip&gt;

Yes, I understand the reputation of the Daily Fail. Its veracity is not at question here; only its treatment of the topic. (i.e. even if this is all a lie, it's the language used to tell it, not the story itself that's at question, okay? So, please spare me the "poor source" laughter; it doesn't apply to my point.)

&lt;snip&gt;

</quote>
So you think the attitude expressed in the Daily Mail accurately represents the attitude of the population in the UK?

However, you will have noticed the woman (who sounds mentally ill, BTW) fled while on bail. I.e. she was charged with a crime by the police and was going to trial. Which refutes the OP's claim that the police don't take reports of assaults by women on men seriously.

Not a very good example, IMO.
</post>
<post author="Schrodinger's Cat" datetime="2011-11-23T14:05:00" id="p114">
<quote orig_author="bookitty">
That article is absolutely disgusting. The glee with which the reporter discusses the details of Mr. Anderson's rape and abuse is sadistic. I'm too angry to say more.

</quote>
It's especially disgusting how the author puts the word "rape" in quotation marks, as if being tied up and forced to have sex isn't really rape...presumably for no other reason than the victim is male and the assailant attractive at the time of the attack.
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-11-23T14:12:00" id="p115">
<quote orig_author="Schrodinger's Cat">
It's especially disgusting how the author puts the word "rape" in quotation marks, as if being tied up and forced to have sex isn't really rape...presumably for no other reason than the victim is male and the assailant attractive at the time of the attack.

</quote>
A less dramatic explanation for the use of quotes could be to avoid being charged with libel.
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-23T14:46:00" id="p116">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
A less dramatic explanation for the use of quotes could be to avoid being charged with libel.

</quote>
Really? Ivor, are you just new to critical thinking?

Do the use of challenge quotes prevent a charge of libel in the UK?
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-11-23T14:52:00" id="p117">
<quote orig_author="slingblade">
&lt;snip&gt;

Why, because there were no six-year-olds involved?

</quote>
No, because the police believed the man when he said he was attacked by the woman, which is why they charged her. She escaped after being in prison for 3 month and let out on police bail because her mental health had deteriorated.
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-23T14:55:00" id="p118">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
No, because the police believed the man when he said he was attacked by the woman, which is why they charged her. She escaped after being in prison for 3 month and let out on police bail because her mental health had deteriorated.

</quote>
You have proven to all that you have missed every bit of the point I made very clearly.
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-11-23T15:00:00" id="p119">
<quote orig_author="slingblade">
Really? Ivor, are you just new to critical thinking?

Do the use of challenge quotes prevent a charge of libel in the UK?

</quote>
No idea.
</post>
<post author="gumboot" datetime="2011-11-23T15:01:00" id="p120">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
However, you will have noticed the woman (who sounds mentally ill, BTW) fled while on bail. I.e. she was charged with a crime by the police and was going to trial. Which refutes the OP's claim that the police don't take reports of assaults by women on men seriously.

</quote>

She was eventually sentenced in absentia to one year. How much do you think a man would have got for a similar crime? Remember, this wasn't just an assault or a sexual assault. This man was abducted, bound, and repeatedly raped. The matter was considered so unimportant the UK government couldn't even be bothered seeking extradition.

Can you honestly say with a straight face that one year is a reasonable sentence for this crime? Can you honestly say with a straight face that you'd expect a man, doing the same thing to a woman, to likewise get a one year sentence? To be left free in their own country?
</post>
<post author="gumboot" datetime="2011-11-23T15:02:00" id="p121">
<quote orig_author="slingblade">
Really? Ivor, are you just new to critical thinking?

Do the use of challenge quotes prevent a charge of libel in the UK?

</quote>

The simple fact is she was convicted, so she'd have an impossible task arguing libel anyway.
</post>
<post author="gumboot" datetime="2011-11-23T15:05:00" id="p122">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
No, because the police believed the man when he said he was attacked by the woman, which is why they charged her. She escaped after being in prison for 3 month and let out on police bail because her mental health had deteriorated.

</quote>

Since we're going down this route, what did they charge her with, and what does that say about society's attitude to male rape victims?
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-23T15:09:00" id="p123">
<quote orig_author="gumboot">
The simple fact is she was convicted, so she'd have an impossible task arguing libel anyway.

</quote>
True, but Ivor's a past-master at dancing away to ask yet another question, especially if you don't confront him directly with his poor argumentation. So, I did.

And he can't answer it, because it has no answer that applies to his so-called premise.

I only wanted him to show it. He rewarded my efforts well.
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-11-23T15:10:00" id="p124">
<quote orig_author="gumboot">
The simple fact is she was convicted, so she'd have an impossible task arguing libel anyway.

</quote>
She was not convicted of rape.
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-23T15:16:00" id="p125">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
She was not convicted of rape.

</quote>
WHAT SHE WAS CONVICTED OF IS NOT THE BLOODY POINT.

It's the tone of the article, the way in which the writer handles his subject.

PLEASE GET THIS CORRECT.

It is not what she was charged with, not what she was convicted of, that matters to the point but THE TONE THE ARTICLE TAKES IN DEALING WITH IT.

Man, you make me sorry as hell I ever took you off ignore.
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-11-23T15:23:00" id="p126">
<quote orig_author="slingblade">
WHAT SHE WAS CONVICTED OF IS NOT THE BLOODY POINT.

It's the tone of the article, the way in which the writer handles his subject.

PLEASE GET THIS CORRECT.

It is not what she was charged with, not what she was convicted of, that matters to the point but THE TONE THE ARTICLE TAKES IN DEALING WITH IT.

Man, you make me sorry as hell I ever took you off ignore.

</quote>
It is as far as gumboot's point about her being convicted (of crimes other than rape) meaning that an article making a claim she committed rape is not libellous.
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-23T15:27:00" id="p127">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
It is as far as gumboot's point about her being convicted (of crimes other than rape) meaning that an article making a claim she committed rape is not libellous.

</quote>
YOU BROUGHT UP LIBEL IN THE FIRST DAMNED PLACE!

He's only responding to your derailing non-sequitur dance and you jolly well know it.

Yep, you're doing a lot of things here. Trolling, devil's advocate, derailing, advocating child sexual abuse...there's enough here for four or five hat-tricks.
</post>
<post author="gumboot" datetime="2011-11-23T16:01:00" id="p128">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
She was not convicted of rape.

</quote>

And why not?
</post>
<post author="The Norseman" datetime="2011-11-23T16:09:00" id="p129">
<quote orig_author="bookitty">
That article is absolutely disgusting. The glee with which the reporter discusses the details of Mr. Anderson's rape and abuse is sadistic. I'm too angry to say more.

</quote>
At times, I feel the same way. I wanted to post in a thread a few months back regarding the low reporting of males being physically and emotionally abused in relationships due to some of the same attitudes, but I couldn't because I was too pissed off.
</post>
<post author="brodski" datetime="2011-11-23T16:11:00" id="p130">
<quote orig_author="Schrodinger's Cat">
It's especially disgusting how the author puts the word "rape" in quotation marks, as if being tied up and forced to have sex isn't really rape...presumably for no other reason than the victim is male and the assailant attractive at the time of the attack.

</quote>
Much as I hate to defend the mail in general and that disgusting article in particular, when discussing a court case it is worth keeping in mind legal terms, as distinct from the colloquial use. In the UK only men can be charge with rape, as rape is defined as the non consensual insertion of a penis into another person.

In 2003 there was legislation which would have changed this, but it was amened to retain the idea that only men can rape. The MP who amended the bill even made a joke with the wording of her amendment, it was tabled as"remove genitals and insert penis".
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-23T16:25:00" id="p131">
<quote orig_author="brodski">
Much as I hate to defend the mail in general and that disgusting article in particular, when discussing a court case it is worth keeping in mind legal terms, as distinct from the colloquial use. In the UK only men can be charge with rape, as rape is defined as the non consensual insertion of a penis into another person.

In 2003 there was legislation which would have changed this, but it was amened to retain the idea that only men can rape. The MP who amended the bill even made a joke with the wording of her amendment, it was tabled as"remove genitals and insert penis".

</quote>
Doesn't matter, though I appreciate your taking the time to explain.

I doubt strongly that challenge quotes would prevent one from being charged with libel. Can't answer as to conviction/guilty finding, but I doubt it would save you.

The point is that the tone of the article makes it all sound like such good fun, such great entertainment, and seems to ignore or at least make light of the fact that a man was drugged, kidnapped, imprisoned and repeatedly raped.

And it does speak to the fact that female-on-male rape is a joke to many, even to the courts and law enforcement.

I'm just not going to let Ivor play his game anymore, and I'd hope no one else will let him, either.
</post>
<post author="brodski" datetime="2011-11-23T16:37:00" id="p132">
<quote orig_author="slingblade">
I doubt strongly that challenge quotes would prevent one from being charged with libel. Can't answer as to conviction/guilty finding, but I doubt it would save you.

</quote>
They can help, maybe, if (as is the case here) someone had been convicted of a crime which could reasonably (by a lay person) be described as rape. If you were to call them a rapist they could use as part of their argument that they weren't a rapist, just a sex offender. Calling them a "rapist" otoh, indicating the a wider use of the term than the narrow legal definition, may be deemed to be fair comment.
If she had been convicted of rape then the fact she is a rapist who committed at least one rape would be a matter of public record and reporting such could not be libellous.

<quote>
The point is that the tone of the article makes it all sound like such good fun, such great entertainment, and seems to ignore or at least make light of the fact that a man was drugged, kidnapped, imprisoned and repeatedly raped.

And it does speak to the fact that female-on-male rape is a joke to many,

</quote>
agreed

<quote>
even to the courts and law enforcement.

</quote>
my point was that to the English criminal justice system it is not a joke, it does not exist women cannot be charged with rape here and attempts to change that lead to jokes in parliament and a maintaining of the staus quo.
</post>
<post author="Last of the Fraggles" datetime="2011-11-24T02:56:00" id="p133">
Edited by Locknar: Content removed, breach of rule 11.

<quote orig_author="slingblade">
Got anything to say about female-on-male rape, Ivor? If so, can you manage to apply it to adults and teens?

</quote>
I'm going to be honest and say as a man I think there is a difference somewhere between male on female rape and female on male. I'm not quite sure where it is and maybe I'm only speaking for myself and not for men in general so we'll class this as 'personal opinion, formed without the benefit of experience'

Maybe it's not that rape is different but the threshold for what I would consider rape of me is different to what I have gathered from conversations with women over the years that they would class as rape.

If it gets to the chloroform, knife-point, bundled in the boot of a car and tied up for weeks stage then I'm pretty clear that's equally bad for men and women.

Where I am less clear is on the 'went out got a bit drunk, woke up in bed with someone that I didn't really want to sleep with' or 'changed my mind at the last minute' type situations.

Even where coercion was used (say a power imbalance) or there was weird harassment/stalkery stuff involved I'd be more annoyed and upset by that aspect than the sexual content.

That may well make me weird, and I might be the only one that feels like that, and I might even feel differently if it actually happened to me, but its honestly where I am at right now.
</post>
<post author="jhunter1163" datetime="2011-11-24T06:02:00" id="p134">
<img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/misc/modred.gif" alt="Mod Warning"/> Thread closed pending Mod Team review/cleanout. Posted By:jhunter1163
</post>
<post author="Locknar" datetime="2011-11-27T12:54:00" id="p135">
<img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/misc/modred.gif" alt="Mod Warning"/> I've gone through and removed over 500 posts that were in breach of rule 0, rule 11, rule 12. These posts are in Deep Storage, where they are likely to remain.

Thread has been re-opened in Moderated Status (for now); please keep the discussion on topic, civil/polite and address the arguement vs attack the arguer. Posted By:Locknar
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-11-28T03:29:00" id="p136">
<quote orig_author="slingblade">
The point is that the tone of the article makes it all sound like such good fun, such great entertainment, and seems to ignore or at least make light of the fact that a man was drugged, kidnapped, imprisoned and repeatedly raped.

</quote>
Was that ever actually established, or is it just an allegation that was never properly tested in court? McKinney certainly denies it.
</post>
<post author="zooterkin" datetime="2011-11-28T04:45:00" id="p137">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Was that ever actually established, or is it just an allegation that was never properly tested in court? McKinney certainly denies it.

</quote>
I haven't seen it yet, but the story (including the press coverage of it) is the subject of the documentary <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1704619/">Tabloid</a>, which features Joyce McKinney herself, though not Kirk Anderson.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-11-28T06:51:00" id="p138">
<quote orig_author="zooterkin">
I haven't seen it yet, but the story (including the press coverage of it) is the subject of the documentary <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1704619/">Tabloid</a>, which features Joyce McKinney herself, though not Kirk Anderson.

</quote>
I've seen it, which is how I know that McKinney denies it.
</post>
<post author="whatthebutlersaw" datetime="2011-11-28T08:51:00" id="p139">
If I understand correctly, the McKinney case happened in 1977 at which point the law did not make provisos for female-on-male rape. Which would be why there is no conviction of rape. There was, however, scope for an indictment of indecent assault.

It is not an exaggeration to say that the British tabloid press handled the story like a Carry On-movie. Wiki says: "Brian Whitaker observes that the case provided "light relief" for the newspaper reading public, from more serious stories about politicians.[15] Roger Wilkes states that the coverage of the case "cheered Britain up no end."[16]".

As late as 1984, McKinney was still stalking Anderson at his workplace. Anyone who has been stalked know how devastating that is. It does make me slightly nauseous to read about the flippant attitude that was taken regarding this case.

I wish I could say that the tabloids would do better if this happened now. I fear they wouldn't but I do believe that the law now has scope to punish predators like McKinney properly.
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-28T10:55:00" id="p140">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Was that ever actually established, or is it just an allegation that was never properly tested in court? McKinney certainly denies it.

</quote>
I'm not trying to establish her guilt or innocence.

I'm attempting to show one example of how the subject of female-on-male rape is perceived.

My claim is that the subject is treated with levity, and less seriously than male-on-female rape. That women are perceived as aggrieved victims of a crime, where men are perceived as lucky recipients of something enjoyable.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-11-28T13:18:00" id="p141">
<quote orig_author="slingblade">
I'm not trying to establish her guilt or innocence.

I'm attempting to show one example of how the subject of female-on-male rape is perceived.

My claim is that the subject is treated with levity, and less seriously than male-on-female rape. That women are perceived as aggrieved victims of a crime, where men are perceived as lucky recipients of something enjoyable.

</quote>
I take your point, but think that a better example to use would be one where the fact of rape was actually established.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-28T14:51:00" id="p142">
<quote orig_author="brodski">
...[snip]... my point was that to the English criminal justice system it is not a joke, it does not exist women cannot be charged with rape here and attempts to change that lead to jokes in parliament and a maintaining of the staus quo.

</quote>
Is this still true or has the law been changed since?

<quote orig_author="whatthebutlersaw">
...[snip]... Wiki says: "Brian Whitaker observes that the case provided "light relief" for the newspaper reading public, from more serious stories about politicians.[15] Roger Wilkes states that the coverage of the case "cheered Britain up no end."[16]".
...[snip]... I wish I could say that the tabloids would do better if this happened now. I fear they wouldn't but I do believe that the law now has scope to punish predators like McKinney properly.

</quote>
Well, if what brodski said above is still true and raping a male is not even a crime I have some doubts that the tabloids, much less the regular press, would treat it with any of severity it actually deserves.

In another thread, "Female gang rapes men in Zimbabwe", you can already see similar attitudes. To some it's just a joke and to others it's likely just an excuse for using prostitutes. I find it sad that they're not even given the benefit of the doubt. Zimbabwe also lacks any laws pertaining to raping a male, sexual assault is the best they can do.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-28T15:05:00" id="p143">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
I take your point, but think that a better example to use would be one where the fact of rape was actually established.

</quote>

I think that it was pretty clear since in the end she was convicted of the only applicable law available because of her gender.

<quote>
A few days later a freed Anderson made a report to the police that he had been abducted, driven to Devon, and imprisoned against his will, chained to a bed in a cottage, where he alleged that Joyce Bernann McKinney (b. August 1949), a former Miss Wyoming World had abducted, attempted to seduce, and then raped him. ( <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mormon_sex_in_chains_case">Link</a> )

</quote>

<quote>
Under the then-Sexual Offences Act 1956, due to the victim's gender, there was no crime of rape committed, though indecent assault of a man applied. ( <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mormon_sex_in_chains_case">Link</a> )

</quote>
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-28T19:33:00" id="p144">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
I take your point, but think that a better example to use would be one where the fact of rape was actually established.

</quote>
I don't agree. I think the tone of the particular article was what matters to the discussion, and was why I cited it.

You can feel free to keep arguing that the point is about her guilt or innocence. It may be your point. It isn't and was never mine.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-11-28T23:33:00" id="p145">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
I think that it was pretty clear since in the end she was convicted of the only applicable law available because of her gender.

</quote>
I'm unclear as to exactly what she was convicted of, but whatever it was, it seems to have happened at a trial at which she was not present and at which she was not properly represented. I don't know why everyone is so keen to ignore her side of the story - perhaps because she's a woman?
</post>
<post author="gumboot" datetime="2011-11-29T00:10:00" id="p146">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
In another thread, "Female gang rapes men in Zimbabwe", you can already see similar attitudes. To some it's just a joke and to others it's likely just an excuse for using prostitutes. I find it sad that they're not even given the benefit of the doubt. Zimbabwe also lacks any laws pertaining to raping a male, sexual assault is the best they can do.

</quote>

I was just thinking of this. I was trying to frame a response in that thread and just gave up in disgust. Let's just label it exhibit A.
</post>
<post author="brodski" datetime="2011-11-29T03:04:00" id="p147">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Is this still true or has the law been changed since?
.

</quote>

the sexual offences act 2003 defines rape like this

<quote>
Rape

(1)
A person (A) commits an offence if
(a)
he intentionally penetrates the vagina, anus or mouth of another person (B) with his penis,
(b)
B does not consent to the penetration, and
(c)
A does not reasonably believe that B consents.
(2)
Whether a belief is reasonable is to be determined having regard to all the circumstances, including any steps A has taken to ascertain whether B consents.
(3)
Sections 75 and 76 apply to an offence under this section.
(4)
A person guilty of an offence under this section is liable, on conviction on indictment, to imprisonment for life.

</quote>
the law as originally drafted was intend to make rape gender neutral, an amendment was tabled which inserted the reference to a penis. This is still the legislation which covers the crime of rape.
</post>
<post author="brodski" datetime="2011-11-29T07:39:00" id="p148">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
I'm unclear as to exactly what she was convicted of, but whatever it was, it seems to have happened at a trial at which she was not present and at which she was not properly represented. I don't know why everyone is so keen to ignore her side of the story - perhaps because she's a woman?

</quote>
Beceause her side of the story is not relivant to the broarder cultural point we are making, that the manner in which this story was treated, and the ongoing legal discrimination and cultural attitudes explain why female abuses are not reported.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-29T10:56:00" id="p149">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
I'm unclear as to exactly what she was convicted of, but whatever it was, it seems to have happened at a trial at which she was not present and at which she was not properly represented. I don't know why everyone is so keen to ignore her side of the story - perhaps because she's a woman?

</quote>
I'm starting to wonder if you're trolling me here. Did you not follow the links I provided and the citations given on the Wiki page? She was charged with "intercourse by force, intimidation, etc." In fact, she was still harassing the poor man in 1984 after married and having 3 kids.

Also, I have to wonder why you're so keen to believe her. If it was a woman who charged a man with rape would you be saying the same? A man is usually ridiculed for bringing charges like these against a woman, and the law has very little sympathy for abused men. I've previously provided many links to information on the subject. Female on male rape is hard to prosecute because most people don't even believe it's possible. I find it odd that we can't seem to get our heads, as a society, around the idea that women are individuals too and thus just as capable of assault, sexual or otherwise, as men.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-29T11:01:00" id="p150">
<quote orig_author="brodski">
...[snip]... This is still the legislation which covers the crime of rape.

</quote>
Thanks.

So much for the progressive Europeans. I thought the US was backwards on the subject, but now most states have gender neutral laws on rape (not that we're likely to use them). I'm guessing there's no push to revamp the law, right?
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-11-29T15:54:00" id="p151">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
I'm starting to wonder if you're trolling me here. Did you not follow the links I provided and the citations given on the Wiki page? She was charged with "intercourse by force, intimidation, etc." In fact, she was still harassing the poor man in 1984 after married and having 3 kids.

</quote>
Yes, and I found them unconvincing.

<quote>
Also, I have to wonder why you're so keen to believe her.

</quote>
It's a little thing called "presumption of innocence".
</post>
<post author="Safe-Keeper" datetime="2011-11-29T16:49:00" id="p152">
<quote>
<quote>
Also, I have to wonder why you're so keen to believe her. If it was a woman who charged a man with rape would you be saying the same? A man is usually ridiculed for bringing charges like these against a woman, and the law has very little sympathy for abused men. I've previously provided many links to information on the subject. Female on male rape is hard to prosecute because most people don't even believe it's possible. I find it odd that we can't seem to get our heads, as a society, around the idea that women are individuals too and thus just as capable of assault, sexual or otherwise, as men.

</quote>
It's a little thing called "presumption of innocence".

</quote>
After she's been convicted. Okay.
</post>
<post author="sgtbaker" datetime="2011-11-29T16:53:00" id="p153">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Yes, and I found them unconvincing.

It's a little thing called "presumption of innocence".

</quote>
The point of sharing the article is not to discuss innocence or guilt. Who cares; we are not discussing the credibility of the accuser. The story could be a complete and total fabrication (not likely if you read the whole article) and it wouldn't change the actual relavence of this article.

If you want to discuss guilt or innocents, feel free to start another thread and ask for opinions.

Imagine a woman claiming to be the victim of a rape/kidnapping. Her claims are that she wasdrugged, chained to a bed for two days, spread eagle, and raped multiple times. You would need nanoseconds to accurately measure how fast a reporter would be fired for referring to the victims testimony as "entertaining and downright titilating."
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-29T17:56:00" id="p154">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Yes, and I found them unconvincing.

</quote>
Well, that's your prerogative, it's not my job to convince you. As I said previously, 86% of the victims of female sexual predators aren't believed. Do you believe any man can be the victim of rape by a woman?

<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
It's a little thing called "presumption of innocence".

</quote>
I also believe in the presumption of innocence, but she was found guilty (after fleeing the country while out on bail). And, as I asked before would you hold the same view if the genders were reversed? If so, good. If not, why?
</post>
<post author="slingblade" datetime="2011-11-29T20:22:00" id="p155">
<quote orig_author="sgtbaker">
The point of sharing the article is not to discuss innocence or guilt. Who cares; we are not discussing the credibility of the accuser. The story could be a complete and total fabrication (not likely if you read the whole article) and it wouldn't change the actual relavence of this article.

If you want to discuss guilt or innocents, feel free to start another thread and ask for opinions.

Imagine a woman claiming to be the victim of a rape/kidnapping. Her claims are that she wasdrugged, chained to a bed for two days, spread eagle, and raped multiple times. You would need nanoseconds to accurately measure how fast a reporter would be fired for referring to the victims testimony as "entertaining and downright titilating."

</quote>
Yes, yes, yes, exactly so. This is my point: how the topic was treated in the press, at least in this single article. The idea of rape, whether it occurred or not, would likely not be characterized in this manner if the alleged victim were female, but with this man as alleged victim, it was all so very amusing.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-11-30T01:40:00" id="p156">
<quote orig_author="Safe-Keeper">
After she's been convicted. Okay.

</quote>
Convicted of what? Please direct me to a definitive answer to this question and I may well change my mind. However, it does seem like whatever she was convicted of, it happened at a trial at which she was not present, and probably not properly represented. Hence my presumption of innocence.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-11-30T01:41:00" id="p157">
<quote orig_author="sgtbaker">
The point of sharing the article is not to discuss innocence or guilt.

</quote>
I didn't bring up the subject of her guilt - someone else did. I'm just commenting on it.

<quote>
Who cares

</quote>
Anybody discussing it.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-11-30T01:43:00" id="p158">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Well, that's your prerogative, it's not my job to convince you. As I said previously, 86% of the victims of female sexual predators aren't believed. Do you believe any man can be the victim of rape by a woman?

</quote>
Of course. Why wouldn't I?

as I asked before would you hold the same view if the genders were reversed? [/quote]

Yes. I don't see why it would make any difference if the genders were reversed. Can you explain why it might?
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-11-30T03:11:00" id="p159">
Firstly, take into account the era the crime took place at. A man could not be convicted of raping his wife in the 1970's. Robin Askwith was staring in films such as Confessions of a Window Cleaner. Sexually assertive women are a male fantasy because they are unusual.

Secondly, the crime took place over 30 years ago. We tend to take things that happened a long time ago less seriously than those that happened last week.

Thirdly, despite the claims of some posters, many men do want sex with young attractive women a lot of the time. This inclination is so ingrained in our society that most women expect the men to do the chasing because they consciously or unconsciously realise men want sex with women more than women want sex with men. Because of this, the idea that a young, sexy woman who many other men desire is lusting after you is a huge turn on for most men, so they find it hard to understand how a man could feel particularly bad if he's lucky enough to be the object of such a woman's desire.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-30T14:29:00" id="p160">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Of course. Why wouldn't I?

</quote>
As I said, there are many people who don't believe a man can be raped by a woman. I was just trying to see what your point of view was before I continued on.

<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Yes. I don't see why it would make any difference if the genders were reversed. Can you explain why it might?

</quote>
Well, it makes a lot of difference. To many people, if a woman claims rape the man is guilty no matter the evidence. A woman's word is sacrosanct. Even when a man is proven innocent it's the system keeping women down: now I'm not claiming this doesn't happen, just that it's not every time, or even common, as some claim. If a man makes this type of claim something fishy is up. He's obviously doing something underhanded or plotting something because women don't do those things. These are common views, at least here in the US.

Ultimately, I'm just trying to find your point of reference. Arguing against someone who takes these views is much harder and sometimes even pointless. As with religion, logic and evidence are not considered valid arguments. Of course, I guess without a transcript of the court case we can not make truly informed opinions, and I have no idea how to even find how one would get that kind of thing in Europe. Still I guess this is getting off topic with what Slingblade was saying which was about public attitude, not about the legal response.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-11-30T15:16:00" id="p161">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
...[snip]... Thirdly, despite the claims of some posters, many men do want sex with young attractive women a lot of the time....[snip]...

</quote>
Your argument here is really just silly. Many people like to fantasize but that does not equate to wanting it in real life. Many women and men have been shown to have rape fantasies that doesn't mean they want it to really happen. Even I've thought of strangling someone to death because they've hurt me in some way, but I would never do it as I'm pretty much a pacifist (also, I would feel bad if anything really happened to them). Only the delusional have a problem differentiating between their fantasies and reality. No man or woman wants their right to choose taken from them.

You mention media bias as if it doesn't still happen, so just for reference: <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/RapeIsOkWhenItIsFemaleOnMale">Rape Is Ok When It Is Female On Male</a>

Also, you keep bringing up that a husband couldn't be charged for raping his wife, this is red herring, and has nothing to do with the subject at all. It seem like an attempt to derail the thread which you have done before and I would appreciate you not doing it again, thanks.
</post>
<post author="Information Analyst" datetime="2011-11-30T16:24:00" id="p162">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Was that ever actually established, or is it just an allegation that was never properly tested in court? McKinney certainly denies it.

</quote>
Given that McKinney was sentenced in her absence to a year in prison, I would suggest it certainly was tested in court.
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-12-01T01:13:00" id="p163">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
&lt;snip&gt;

Well, it makes a lot of difference. To many people, if a woman claims rape the man is guilty no matter the evidence. A woman's word is sacrosanct.

&lt;snip&gt;

</quote>
What's the conviction rate for male on female rape in the USA?
</post>
<post author="Mid" datetime="2011-12-01T01:23:00" id="p164">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Convicted of what? Please direct me to a definitive answer to this question and I may well change my mind. However, it does seem like whatever she was convicted of, it happened at a trial at which she was not present, and probably not properly represented. Hence my presumption of innocence.

</quote>
Do you hold the attitude that if a defendant refuses to cooperate with their defence at a trial and is then found guilty they should be presumed innocent? Or is it only when they skip bail and are found guilty in their absence?
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-01T02:19:00" id="p165">
<quote orig_author="Information Analyst">
Given that McKinney was sentenced in her absence to a year in prison, I would suggest it certainly was tested in court.

</quote>
If she wasn't present, how was her side of the story put forward? Do you know? If so, please tell me.
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-12-01T02:56:00" id="p166">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Your argument here is really just silly. Many people like to fantasize but that does not equate to wanting it in real life.

&lt;snip&gt;

</quote>
In the experiments conducted in <a href="http://www.elainehatfield.com/79.pdf">this study</a>, not a single woman accepted the offer to have sex. The great majority of men did (and note the confederates were only of average attractiveness).

<quote>
Also, you keep bringing up that a husband couldn't be charged for raping his wife, this is red herring, and has nothing to do with the subject at all. It seem like an attempt to derail the thread which you have done before and I would appreciate you not doing it again, thanks.

</quote>
It was not an attempt to derail the thread, rather an attempt to provide context to explain the attitudes expressed at the time about the crime and the lenient sentences.

As for the Daily Mail article: The paper is well know for complaining about the sexualisation of society on one page and on the next printing tits and ass shots of young female celebrities.

Here's the Guardian's report on the same news story:

<a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2008/aug/08/usa">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2008/aug/08/usa</a>

<quote>
Now she has her pit bull cloned. But once she manacled a Mormon for sex

Beauty queen who fled UK while on bail resurfaces with her five puppies

Utter the name Joyce McKinney to Britons of a certain age, and you are inevitably rewarded with the briefest flash of incomprehension, followed by a gasp as their memories take them tumbling back to the dark days of early autumn, 1977.

It was a miserable time: there were clashes on the picket line at Grunwick, inflation was sprinting away at 13%, Elvis had just died and a band called Baccara were at Number One with Yes Sir, I Can Boogie. And then, as if to lift the spirits of a nation, along came the most unlikely, the most baffling, the most downright weird news story.

A Mormon missionary from Utah called Kirk Anderson, who was going door-to-door in Ewell, Surrey, was kidnapped at gunpoint by McKinney, a former cheerleader and beauty queen from North Carolina. With the help of a friend, Keith May, McKinney drugged Anderson with chloroform and drove him to a rented 17th century cottage near Okehampton, Devon. There the unfortunate young man was chained, spreadeagled, to a bed, with several pairs of mink-lined handcuffs, and over the next few days he was repeatedly required to have sex with McKinney, who later explained that she had been keen to bear his child.

Eventually the missionary wriggled free, dashed from the cottage and alerted police, who set up roadblocks around Okehampton, capturing both beauty queen and friend. The pair were charged with false imprisonment and possession of an imitation.38 revolver, and brought before Epsom magistrates.

McKinney explained at the commital proceedings that she had fallen head over heels for Anderson when they were at college together in Utah, adding: "I loved him so much that I would ski naked down Mount Everest in the nude with a carnation up my nose if he asked me to." She had hired a private detective, tracked Anderson down and came to Britain with May.

...

</quote>
</post>
<post author="brodski" datetime="2011-12-01T03:33:00" id="p167">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
If she wasn't present, how was her side of the story put forward? Do you know? If so, please tell me.

</quote>

If she had have been present but had refused to enter a plea or offer a defence, would you still claim that the charges had not been tested in court?
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-12-01T05:13:00" id="p168">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
In the experiments conducted in <a href="http://www.elainehatfield.com/79.pdf">this study</a>, not a single woman accepted the offer to have sex. The great majority of men did (and note the confederates were only of average attractiveness).

</quote>
Been there seen that. This still has little to do with non-consensual activities. Besides the study was redone in a more modern context: <a href="http://www.feministcritics.org/blog/2011/03/11/gender-differences-accepting-casual-sex-proposals-noh/">Gender Differences Accepting Casual Sex Proposals</a>.
<quote orig_author="Terri Conley of the University of Michigan">
Overall findings suggest that the large gender differences Clark and Hatfield observed in acceptance of the casual sex offer may have more to do with perceived personality characteristics of the female versus male proposers than with gender differences among Clark and Hatfields participants and that sexual pleasure figures largely in womens and mens decision making about casual sex.

</quote>

<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
It was not an attempt to derail the thread, rather an attempt to provide context to explain the attitudes expressed at the time about the crime and the lenient sentences.

</quote>
You can claim that, but the gender stereotypes at the time were the primary cause. Women quite commonly got lighter sentences because of their gender. It was even in sentencing guidelines until the SCOTUS struck it down, and all the way into 2005 it was still found to be a problem:
<quote>
Our results indicate that women receive more lenient sentences even after controlling for circumstances such as the severity of the offense and past criminal history. ( <a href="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=999358">Link</a> )

</quote>
And yes I know that it happened in Europe but I have no doubt they suffer the same problem. Like here -- Judges told: 'be more lenient to women criminals' ( <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/law-and-order/7995844/Judges-told-be-more-lenient-to-women-criminals.html">Link</a> ) [sexist if you ask me].

<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
As for the Daily Mail article: The paper is well know for complaining about the sexualisation of society on one page and on the next printing tits and ass shots of young female celebrities.

Here's the Guardian's report on the same news story:

<a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2008/aug/08/usa">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2008/aug/08/usa</a>

</quote>
I know very little about the media in the UK, but I do know that people would be calling for someone's head, at the time, if the genders had been reversed pretty much anywhere in western society.
</post>
<post author="sgtbaker" datetime="2011-12-01T07:13:00" id="p169">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
What's the conviction rate for male on female rape in the USA?

</quote>
He said "to many people" not to the law. It's very true, at least in the US. A man need only to be accused to rape and his life is ruined.
</post>
<post author="gumboot" datetime="2011-12-01T12:35:00" id="p170">
<quote orig_author="sgtbaker">
He said "to many people" not to the law. It's very true, at least in the US. A man need only to be accused to rape and his life is ruined.

</quote>

My friend had shared custody of his child stripped from him because of a false rape accusation. No charges ever laid. Even after his accuser admitted they made it up, he still had to have a social worker present when he spent time with his child for a number of months.

"Innocent until proven guilty" applies in the courts, but sadly that's the only place it applies.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-01T14:52:00" id="p171">
<quote orig_author="Mid">
Do you hold the attitude that if a defendant refuses to cooperate with their defence at a trial and is then found guilty they should be presumed innocent?

</quote>

No, not necessarily.

<quote>
Or is it only when they skip bail and are found guilty in their absence?

</quote>
No, not necessarily.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-01T14:55:00" id="p172">
<quote orig_author="brodski">
If she had have been present but had refused to enter a plea or offer a defence, would you still claim that the charges had not been tested in court?

</quote>
No, not necessarily. The thing here is that she has a different story about the whole event than he does, and I don't know if the court heard it. In a case which is basically one person's word against another's the court needs to hear both sides in order to decide who they believe. If someone refuses to put their side of the story then it's reasonable to decide against them, as seems to have happened in this case. But that doesn't mean that the court might not have come to a different decision if they'd been able to hear McKinney.
</post>
<post author="brodski" datetime="2011-12-02T01:49:00" id="p173">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
No, not necessarily. The thing here is that she has a different story about the whole event than he does, and I don't know if the court heard it. In a case which is basically one person's word against another's the court needs to hear both sides in order to decide who they believe. If someone refuses to put their side of the story then it's reasonable to decide against them, as seems to have happened in this case. But that doesn't mean that the court might not have come to a different decision if they'd been able to hear McKinney.

</quote>
they did hear her side of the story it was "screw you, I don't have to answer for this."
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-12-02T03:27:00" id="p174">
I wonder how much the disparity in the feelings about female on male (F-o-M) rape compared to male of female (M-o-F) rape has to do with the perceived motive? I.e. When a man rapes a woman, it is perceived that his objective is to use her body to sexually stimulate himself to reach orgasm. When a woman rapes a man, it is perceived that her objective is to sexually stimulate the man until he has an orgasm.

As orgasms are associated with pleasure, the fact that a F-o-M rape is associated with the aim making a man come seems less bad to an outside observer than a M-o-F (or M-o-M) rape in which the perpetrator is perceived as being focused on his own orgasm and indifferent about whether the woman (or other man) comes.
</post>
<post author="Safe-Keeper" datetime="2011-12-02T07:05:00" id="p175">
<quote orig_author="gumboot">
My friend had shared custody of his child stripped from him because of a false rape accusation. No charges ever laid. Even after his accuser admitted they made it up, he still had to have a social worker present when he spent time with his child for a number of months.

"Innocent until proven guilty" applies in the courts, but sadly that's the only place it applies.

</quote>
I don't see a problem with taking a child away from a suspected sex offender as a preventive measure. Of course, had he been an actual rapist, I suspect there would've been an outcry if no action had been taken. Damned if you do, damned if you don't.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-02T13:57:00" id="p176">
<quote orig_author="brodski">
they did hear her side of the story it was "screw you, I don't have to answer for this."

</quote>
Yes, that's one way of looking at it.
</post>
<post author="brodski" datetime="2011-12-03T06:04:00" id="p177">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Yes, that's one way of looking at it.

</quote>
What us the other way? You have said that you may not feel the same way if she had been in court for her conviction even if she had offered no defence, so why should her skipping bail make her later protestations of innocence more readily belived?
</post>
<post author="Wildy" datetime="2011-12-03T06:58:00" id="p178">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
I'm unclear as to exactly what she was convicted of, but whatever it was, it seems to have happened at a trial at which she was not present and at which she was not properly represented.

</quote>
Since she willingly chose to not be at her trial by jumping bail and fleeing the country I don't think you can really say that she wasn't "properly represented".

<quote>
I don't know why everyone is so keen to ignore her side of the story - perhaps because she's a woman?

</quote>
Why are you so keen to believe that she's innocent - perhaps because she's a woman?
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-03T08:47:00" id="p179">
<quote orig_author="brodski">
What us the other way?

</quote>
I believe I've already posted another way of looking at things.

<quote>
You have said that you may not feel the same way if she had been in court for her conviction even if she had offered no defence, so why should her skipping bail make her later protestations of innocence more readily belived?

</quote>
There is a difference between sitting in court and presenting no case, and being convicted in absentia.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-03T08:50:00" id="p180">
<quote orig_author="Wildy">
Since she willingly chose to not be at her trial by jumping bail and fleeing the country I don't think you can really say that she wasn't "properly represented".

</quote>
Who represented her, and how did they do it? Was her story put at trial? How was this done? I ask because I do not know the answers to these questions.

<quote>
Why are you so keen to believe that she's innocent - perhaps because she's a woman?

</quote>
I would not call myself "keen" to believe she's innocent. I'm just not as keen as some seem to believe her guilty. I've heard her side of the story and found it somewhat convincing. I haven't heard his side of the story beyond some rather sparse Wikipedia articles, but I could easily be convinced he is right and she is wrong. However, he seems to be keeping quiet on the matter.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-12-03T18:45:00" id="p181">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
...[snip]... I haven't heard his side of the story beyond some rather sparse Wikipedia articles, but I could easily be convinced he is right and she is wrong. However, he seems to be keeping quiet on the matter.

</quote>
Yes, because rape victims, especially publicly ridiculed ones, are keen on placing themselves in front of the press to have their lives ruined even more. I'm sorry, but fleeing the country instead of facing her accuser in court is tantamount to a guilty plea. I would say the evidence would have to be pretty clear, or her partner was willing to confess to get a lighter or no sentence. Heck, it was likely she would get off if she just went to court, as most find the idea of a woman raping a man, in and of itself, patently ridiculous. Even more so, at that time in our culture. Plus, she was famous for being a beauty queen which would push most men, at least, to believing her side. It's quite common for men to say they would love to be raped by a beautiful woman: just look at the "Female gang rapes men in Zimbabwe" thread there's at least one there. They pop up in every female-on-male rape thread trying to claim themselves as proof that this phenomena doesn't really exist.
</post>
<post author="brodski" datetime="2011-12-04T01:58:00" id="p182">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
I believe I've already posted another way of looking at things.

There is a difference between sitting in court and presenting no case, and being convicted in absentia.

</quote>
can you explain what the important difference is? or, if you think you already have done so, quote the post.
</post>
<post author="bookitty" datetime="2011-12-04T11:23:00" id="p183">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Who represented her, and how did they do it? Was her story put at trial? How was this done? I ask because I do not know the answers to these questions.

I would not call myself "keen" to believe she's innocent. I'm just not as keen as some seem to believe her guilty. I've heard her side of the story and found it somewhat convincing. I haven't heard his side of the story beyond some rather sparse Wikipedia articles, but I could easily be convinced he is right and she is wrong. However, he seems to be keeping quiet on the matter.

</quote>
Having this case die down and be forgotten might have been the best thing that happened to him. No matter what his side of the story is, people will form their own opinions and worse, they'll be more than happy to let him know what those opinions are.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-05T12:45:00" id="p184">
<quote orig_author="brodski">
can you explain what the important difference is? or, if you think you already have done so, quote the post.

</quote>
If you can't already see a difference between sitting in court and refusing to present a defence, and being convicted by a court when you are elsewhere and unable to present a defence, then I suspect that nothing I can say will make you see one.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-05T13:05:00" id="p185">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Yes, because rape victims, especially publicly ridiculed ones, are keen on placing themselves in front of the press to have their lives ruined even more.

</quote>
I think you meant to say "Yes, because rape victims are not keen..." etc. Otherwise your sentence doesn't make sense! Of course, people making false accusations of rape are also not keen on placing themselves in front of the press, so I'm not sure that refusal to speak about the matter helps us in determining the truth or otherwise of their accusations.

<quote>
I'm sorry, but fleeing the country instead of facing her accuser in court is tantamount to a guilty plea.

</quote>
Yes, that's one point of view.

<quote>
Heck, it was likely she would get off if she just went to court, as most find the idea of a woman raping a man, in and of itself, patently ridiculous. Even more so, at that time in our culture. Plus, she was famous for being a beauty queen which would push most men, at least, to believing her side.

</quote>
If you are correct and fleeing the country is tantamount to a guilty plea, then that would explain why she was found guilty - simply because she presented no defence. It seems you agree with me that if she had been properly represented she would have been found "not guilty". Given that you think she would have been acquitted at a proper trial, why should I be convinced that she is guilty?
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-12-05T16:19:00" id="p186">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
I think you meant to say "Yes, because rape victims are not keen..." etc. Otherwise your sentence doesn't make sense! Of course, people making false accusations of rape are also not keen on placing themselves in front of the press, so I'm not sure that refusal to speak about the matter helps us in determining the truth or otherwise of their accusations.

</quote>
Now I'm wondering if you're being intentionally obtuse. It was sarcasm... it's a fairly commonly used rhetorical device. Also, false rape claims are rare and usually in cases where the victim has something to gain. In this case the victim can gain nothing but unwanted public scrutiny and ridicule.

<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
If you are correct and fleeing the country is tantamount to a guilty plea, then that would explain why she was found guilty - simply because she presented no defence. It seems you agree with me that if she had been properly represented she would have been found "not guilty". Given that you think she would have been acquitted at a proper trial, why should I be convinced that she is guilty?

</quote>
Really?? <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/confused.gif"/> That's what you got from my statement? I think she was guilty, but society hates males claiming to be any type of victim. Thus, they would have likely let her go. Just because you're found "not guilty", doesn't mean you are not guilty. The legal system is usually more lenient (if not downright unbalanced) when it comes to female offenders, as I've cited proof of earlier.

I'm trying to figure out the meaning in your argument. What point are you trying to get across? You seem to believe she's innocent, fine thats your opinion. What relevance does this have in the broader context of this thread? The story was brought up because of the poor way it was handled by the press, not for any other reason. I no longer see any reason to debate this subject, so I'm moving on now.
</post>
<post author="PhantomWolf" datetime="2011-12-05T16:58:00" id="p187">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Given that you think she would have been acquitted at a proper trial, why should I be convinced that she is guilty?

</quote>
Wow, I just realised that O.J was innocent after all....
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-12-06T04:25:00" id="p188">
<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2070510/Caroline-Flack-breaks-silence-One-Direction-toyboy-Harry-Styles.html">Female predator?</a>
</post>
<post author="brodski" datetime="2011-12-06T04:44:00" id="p189">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
If you can't already see a difference between sitting in court and refusing to present a defence, and being convicted by a court when you are elsewhere and unable to present a defence, then I suspect that nothing I can say will make you see one.

</quote>

She was perfectly able to present a defence, she chose not to do so. In what way does her physical location make a difference?
How about if she had been denied bail, but had escaped, would that mean that she had not been properly convicted as well?
</post>
<post author="Wildy" datetime="2011-12-06T06:28:00" id="p190">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
If you can't already see a difference between sitting in court and refusing to present a defence, and being convicted by a court when you are elsewhere and unable to present a defence, then I suspect that nothing I can say will make you see one.

</quote>
But the later isn't even the case in this instance. She was perfectly able to present a defence but instead she fled the country. If anything her actions have far more in common with the former than the latter.

<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
I think you meant to say "Yes, because rape victims are not keen..." etc. Otherwise your sentence doesn't make sense!

</quote>
I think he was being sarcastic there.

<quote>
Of course, people making false accusations of rape are also not keen on placing themselves in front of the press, so I'm not sure that refusal to speak about the matter helps us in determining the truth or otherwise of their accusations.

</quote>
What evidence do you have that his accusation was a false one?

<quote>
Yes, that's one point of view.

</quote>
And what other points of view are there? What reason would she have to flee.

<quote>
It seems you agree with me that if she had been properly represented she would have been found "not guilty".

</quote>
But how do you know that she wasn't properly represented? Are you saying that she wasn't given proper representation when before she decided to jump bail and flee the country?

<quote>
Given that you think she would have been acquitted at a proper trial, why should I be convinced that she is guilty?

</quote>
If you really think that she would have been found "not guilty" why exactly do you think she fled?
</post>
<post author="Darat" datetime="2011-12-06T06:39:00" id="p191">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2070510/Caroline-Flack-breaks-silence-One-Direction-toyboy-Harry-Styles.html">Female predator?</a>

</quote>
Interesting story given this thread, one of the comments really helps to demonstrate the double standards:

<quote>
I have no problem with large age gaps, but Harry isn't even an adult yet for god's sake....snip... And no, I wouldn't think any different if it was a 32 year old man and a 17 year old girl...it is still wrong for someone who is very much into adulthood like this to go out with a minor.

...snip...

</quote>
Note they make it very clear that the gender of the two involved is not the issue however look how they end their comment:

<quote>
I also think X Factor need to do something about this as what if a male presenter decides that a young girl on the show is easy pickings after this? It sets an awful precedent

</quote>
Now that of course may just be bad wording but I think it shows the subtle way the double standard can show itself.
</post>
<post author="Ivor the Engineer" datetime="2011-12-06T07:47:00" id="p192">
<quote orig_author="Darat">
&lt;snip&gt;

Now that of course may just be bad wording but I think it shows the subtle way the double standard can show itself.

</quote>
Perhaps it has something to do with what I suggested in post #174 (which was delayed an inordinate time for moderation, BTW. Anyone would think moderators had lives outside the forum and/or Christmas shopping to do <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/smile.gif"/> ). I.e. It is perceived that the penetrative male always gets something nice out of sex (i.e. an orgasm), whereas the receptive partner may or may not be having a good time.

A line in The National Anthem the other night also hinted at this type of thinking:

"Don't get it over too quickly, sir, otherwise, the public will think you are enjoying it rather too much."
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-06T12:42:00" id="p193">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Also, false rape claims are rare and usually in cases where the victim has something to gain. In this case the victim can gain nothing but unwanted public scrutiny and ridicule.

</quote>
What brings you to that conclusion? Didn't the complainant have a very good motive to accuse his lover of kidnapping him?

<quote>
Really?? <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/confused.gif"/> That's what you got from my statement? I think she was guilty, but society hates males claiming to be any type of victim. Thus, they would have likely let her go. Just because you're found "not guilty", doesn't mean you are not guilty. The legal system is usually more lenient (if not downright unbalanced) when it comes to female offenders, as I've cited proof of earlier.

I'm trying to figure out the meaning in your argument. What point are you trying to get across? You seem to believe she's innocent, fine thats your opinion. What relevance does this have in the broader context of this thread? The story was brought up because of the poor way it was handled by the press, not for any other reason. I no longer see any reason to debate this subject, so I'm moving on now.

</quote>
OK. No point in answering any of your questions then.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-06T12:43:00" id="p194">
<quote orig_author="PhantomWolf">
Wow, I just realised that O.J was innocent after all....

</quote>
Not sure I get where you're going with this, or how it is relevant to a discussion about female on male rape. In fact, it seems like a derail.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-06T12:45:00" id="p195">
<quote orig_author="brodski">
She was perfectly able to present a defence, she chose not to do so. In what way does her physical location make a difference?
How about if she had been denied bail, but had escaped, would that mean that she had not been properly convicted as well?

</quote>
I guess it would depend on what happened at the trial. Do you know what happened at the trial?
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-06T12:51:00" id="p196">
<quote orig_author="Wildy">
But the later isn't even the case in this instance. She was perfectly able to present a defence but instead she fled the country. If anything her actions have far more in common with the former than the latter.

</quote>
Once she'd fled the country she was no longer able to present a defence.

<quote>
I think he was being sarcastic there.

</quote>
Thanks for the info.

<quote>
What evidence do you have that his accusation was a false one?

</quote>
Her account of the whole affair.

<quote>
And what other points of view are there? What reason would she have to flee.

</quote>
To avoid being convicted of a crime, whether or not she actually committed it.

<quote>
But how do you know that she wasn't properly represented? Are you saying that she wasn't given proper representation when before she decided to jump bail and flee the country?

</quote>
I don't know. I keep asking people how she was represented and whether her side of the story was put before the jury or judge, but nobody knows or is answering.

<quote>
If you really think that she would have been found "not guilty" why exactly do you think she fled?

</quote>
I've already answered this question. Also, she and I are not the same person, so whether I think she would have been found not guilty is not relevant to what she was thinking. I think it was Naive1000 who first put forward the idea that she would have been found "not guilty" at a trial at which she was present, and I agreed with him/her then. But I possibly should have thought about that a bit more, because Naive1000 could well be wrong.
</post>
<post author="Wildy" datetime="2011-12-06T16:24:00" id="p197">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Once she'd fled the country she was no longer able to present a defence.

</quote>
You do understand that just saying this doesn't affect my point in any way whatsoever. Do you not understand that her fleeing the country while on bail is choosing not to present a defence, not her being unable to present one.

<quote>
Her account of the whole affair.

</quote>
So why do you believe her account over his account? We do know his account by the way, it's the one that the media have spent their time basically mocking him over.

<quote>
I don't know. I keep asking people how she was represented and whether her side of the story was put before the jury or judge, but nobody knows or is answering.

</quote>
Well I've tried to find court documents but I don't know what I'm looking for, or whether it's even online.
</post>
<post author="gumboot" datetime="2011-12-07T02:26:00" id="p198">
<quote orig_author="Safe-Keeper">
I don't see a problem with taking a child away from a suspected sex offender as a preventive measure. Of course, had he been an actual rapist, I suspect there would've been an outcry if no action had been taken. Damned if you do, damned if you don't.

</quote>

I just noticed that I failed to mention the accusation was historic, and his accuser was the mother of the child, and they were in the middle of a custody dispute (initiated by her) after several years of problem-free custody sharing. It would have taken a social worker with half a brain about 5 seconds to determine the rape accusation was fake.

But as Naive1000 pointed out, for many people if a woman accuses a man of rape, no matter the context, she's believed without a doubt. And that's a fact that some women take advantage of; a false rape accusation can be an incredibly powerful weapon.
</post>
<post author="Mark6" datetime="2011-12-07T08:04:00" id="p199">
<quote orig_author="Ivor the Engineer">
I wonder how much the disparity in the feelings about female on male (F-o-M) rape compared to male of female (M-o-F) rape has to do with the perceived motive? I.e. When a man rapes a woman, it is perceived that his objective is to use her body to sexually stimulate himself to reach orgasm. When a woman rapes a man, it is perceived that her objective is to sexually stimulate the man until he has an orgasm.

</quote>
Bolded part NEVER even occurred to me. Inasmuch as I thought about such things at all, I always assumed that woman raping a man is interested in her pleasure -- exclusively, or at least primarily. Maybe my thinking is unusual, but I doubt it.

In short, my answer to Ivor's question is -- "perceived motive" has little or nothing to do with disparity in the feelings.
</post>
<post author="rustypouch" datetime="2011-12-07T11:38:00" id="p200">
Just for a recent example of a woman raping a boy, there's this:

<a href="http://blogs.houstonpress.com/hairballs/2011/12/heather_daughdrill_busted_for.php">http://blogs.houstonpress.com/hairba...busted_for.php</a>

If you don't think there's a double standard between the genders, read the comments.

Now if the genders were reversed, think how the public response would be.
</post>
<post author="Aurelian" datetime="2011-12-07T11:43:00" id="p201">
I would venture a guess that if a man is being raped, it's about power and likely humiliation, whether the aggressor is male or female.

We are discussing crimes and situations of non-consent, right? Not plots in blue films?
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-07T11:59:00" id="p202">
[quote=Wildy;7821728]You do understand that just saying this doesn't affect my point in any way whatsoever.{/quote]

Yes, I understand. But your point is not the same as my point.

<quote>
Do you not understand that her fleeing the country while on bail is choosing not to present a defence, not her being unable to present one.

</quote>
Yes, but that doesn't mean her defence has no relevance in trying to figure out if she did it or not.

<quote>
So why do you believe her account over his account?

</quote>
Why do you believe his account over her account?

<quote>
Well I've tried to find court documents but I don't know what I'm looking for, or whether it's even online.

</quote>
Me either. I guess I'll have to reserve judgment on this case then.
</post>
<post author="Aurelian" datetime="2011-12-07T12:05:00" id="p203">
There is a big difference between sexual assault criminal allegations that do not result in a conviction because the claim was unsubstantiated. Does that mean that the claim was false? NO. Most of these events occur in private areas, including residences, with a lack of witnesses.

So when we hear of someone who is not convicted, it may not mean that they were without predatory or sexual inappropriate behavior. Should the public run around stating that they KNOW what happened? No. But they do. It sells media. I hate it.

What does it look like from the other side? If a sexual assault occurred, that's one violation that will affect the victim for a long, long time. If the victim steps forward to report it, that's another area where it impacts the victim's life as well as the accused. People talk about the accused having a record of the complaint - let's look at the mental health of a victim whose report did not result in a conviction for any number of technical reasons. S/he had a nervous breakdown and didn't report it for 4-5 days. S/he invited someone over for dinner just.for.dinner. and the megaphone of victim-blaming goes up.

It's a terrible situation. I wish there was more privacy in the process. Most people can handle the situation of the judge, jury and even the lawyers asking appropriate questions - it's the tsunami of babbling, bobbing heads that make this so, so much worse for the many, many female victims, as well as the male victims.

So when we talk about accused people with "permanent records" there are many, many reporting victims who suffer from PTSD, have severe mental health issues, and who commit suicide. It's just not as easy to look up as a criminal verdict and sentence for the 5% of matters that result in a conviction in my neck of the US

A.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-12-07T14:02:00" id="p204">
<quote orig_author="Mark6">
Bolded part NEVER even occurred to me. Inasmuch as I thought about such things at all, I always assumed that woman raping a man is interested in her pleasure -- exclusively, or at least primarily. Maybe my thinking is unusual, but I doubt it.

In short, my answer to Ivor's question is -- "perceived motive" has little or nothing to do with disparity in the feelings.

</quote>
I've never thought of rape as a tool of pleasure, but one of control and power. The pleasure is just a bonus for the rapist. What they're really after is the total domination of the other persons psyche. They've changed, influenced, and created a permanent place in their victims minds. Empowerment through vile acts. I won't claim that pleasure has no bearing on motive, but I think its ancillary.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-12-07T14:16:00" id="p205">
<quote orig_author="rustypouch">
...[snip]... Now if the genders were reversed, think how the public response would be.

</quote>
Looking through the responses I see the normal for these cases. If the victim is a boy there's no harm, and people claim that reversing the gender is just silly because its not the same thing. It makes me wonder about our ability to think as a people. We too often accept stereotypes and fantasy bluster as reality. You also get one who goes look it didn't affect me, but often if you look at their attitudes you find just the opposite. Its sad really.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-12-07T16:05:00" id="p206">
Time to add a little more wood on the fire. Lets look at the least likely women to be considered abusers -- mothers. Mothers like this are a very small percentage (like with male abusers), but we should still be conscious of everyone that has the opportunity to abuse children.

Here are a few examples:

<quote>
The boy, who officials say escaped the next day, told investigators the beating was the latest incident in a three-year pattern of mistreatment. Authorities say the boy had bruises on nearly every part of his body, a broken right forearm and lacerations on his buttocks so severe he couldn't sit. ( <a href="http://www.tampabay.com/news/courts/criminal/article982729.ece">Link</a> )

</quote>

<quote>
The Beersheba District Court sentenced a 40-year-old woman from Netivot to eight years in jail and one years probation, after finding her guilty of sexually abusing two of her eight sons, aged eight and 11.( <a href="http://female-offenders.com/Safehouse/2010/01/mother-gets-8-years-for-sexually-abusing-sons.html">Link</a> )

</quote>

<quote>
Mother jailed after abusing ten children ( <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-1380793/Haringey-mother-jailed-abusing-10-children-area-Baby-P-Victoria-Climbi.html">Lnk</a> )

</quote>

<quote>
Dutton told the boys that everyday things such as touching a bird, getting sneezed on, eating vegetables and exposure to sunlight could kill them, prosecutors claimed. To safeguard them, she made them wear surgical masks when they went out in public and sent them to school with lunches of strained baby food. ( <a href="http://www.theledger.com/article/20030517/NEWS/305170384">Link</a> )

</quote>

<quote>
Initially hospitalized Tuesday in Lincoln, the baby was taken to Children's Hospital in Omaha with seven to 10 fractures of his ribs, arms and legs, Flood said. Lincoln police got word of his injuries from the Omaha Police Department, Flood said. ( <a href="http://journalstar.com/news/local/crime-and-courts/mother-suspected-of-abusing--month-old-son/article_1fec9b74-4a48-5b55-959c-963838f60463.html">Link</a> )

</quote>

<quote>
the boy remains in hospital where he is being treated for serious injuries including burns to his hands and body and a broken tooth with a nerve exposed. ( <a href="http://www.streetgangs.com/features/two-lesbian-women-charged-in-boys-torture">Link</a> )

</quote>

<quote>
Three-year-old boy tortured and left for dead after his babysitter sold him for sex in exchange for meth and his mother did nothing to stop it ( <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2009142/Oklahoma-boy-3-sold-sex-babysitter-Jennifer-Chapman-exchange-meth.html">Link</a> )

</quote>
</post>
<post author="rustypouch" datetime="2011-12-07T17:10:00" id="p207">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Looking through the responses I see the normal for these cases. If the victim is a boy there's no harm, and people claim that reversing the gender is just silly because its not the same thing. It makes me wonder about our ability to think as a people. We too often accept stereotypes and fantasy bluster as reality. You also get one who goes look it didn't affect me, but often if you look at their attitudes you find just the opposite. Its sad really.

</quote>
And that's the issue.

In any hetero encounter, it seems that the attitude of society is that males cannot, by default, be victims.
</post>
<post author="PhantomWolf" datetime="2011-12-07T22:49:00" id="p208">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Didn't the complainant have a very good motive to accuse his lover of kidnapping him?

</quote>
Because she followed to another country, had him kidnapped at gunpoint, chained to a bed and then assaulted him? I'd say that was a pretty good reason.

<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Not sure I get where you're going with this

</quote>
And there is your problem entirely, you don't get it.
</post>
<post author="Wildy" datetime="2011-12-08T01:24:00" id="p209">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Yes, but that doesn't mean her defence has no relevance in trying to figure out if she did it or not.

</quote>
Well clearly she decided that it doesn't matter considering that she decided to flee instead of staying and presenting a defence.

<quote>
Why do you believe his account over her account?

</quote>
Perhaps you should actually answer the question I presented to you instead of trying to turn the question back on me.

<quote>
I guess I'll have to reserve judgment on this case then.

</quote>
You say that but it seems that you've already passed judgement on this case.
</post>
<post author="gumboot" datetime="2011-12-08T01:56:00" id="p210">
<quote orig_author="Aurelian">
There is a big difference between sexual assault criminal allegations that do not result in a conviction because the claim was unsubstantiated. Does that mean that the claim was false? NO. Most of these events occur in private areas, including residences, with a lack of witnesses.

So when we hear of someone who is not convicted, it may not mean that they were without predatory or sexual inappropriate behavior. Should the public run around stating that they KNOW what happened? No. But they do. It sells media. I hate it.

What does it look like from the other side? If a sexual assault occurred, that's one violation that will affect the victim for a long, long time. If the victim steps forward to report it, that's another area where it impacts the victim's life as well as the accused. People talk about the accused having a record of the complaint - let's look at the mental health of a victim whose report did not result in a conviction for any number of technical reasons. S/he had a nervous breakdown and didn't report it for 4-5 days. S/he invited someone over for dinner just.for.dinner. and the megaphone of victim-blaming goes up.

It's a terrible situation. I wish there was more privacy in the process. Most people can handle the situation of the judge, jury and even the lawyers asking appropriate questions - it's the tsunami of babbling, bobbing heads that make this so, so much worse for the many, many female victims, as well as the male victims.

So when we talk about accused people with "permanent records" there are many, many reporting victims who suffer from PTSD, have severe mental health issues, and who commit suicide. It's just not as easy to look up as a criminal verdict and sentence for the 5% of matters that result in a conviction in my neck of the US

A.

</quote>

I can't speak for the US, but in New Zealand victims of sexual assault have automatic name suppression.

The fact is that the overwhelming majority of rape cases come down to whether there was consent or not. In such a situation a low conviction rate is going to be inevitable because it comes down to the word of the victim versus the word of the defendant. Where the defendant's explanation is reasonable, a jury has no choice but to find them not-guilty.
</post>
<post author="sgtbaker" datetime="2011-12-08T05:56:00" id="p211">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
Time to add a little more wood on the fire. Lets look at the least likely women to be considered abusers -- mothers. Mothers like this are a very small percentage (like with male abusers), but we should still be conscious of everyone that has the opportunity to abuse children.

Here are a few examples:

</quote>
I want to make it clear that I don't disagree with your premise that male victims are more likely to be dismissed or treated appropriately in sex abuse and spousal abuse cases. I do, however, know that the mother is the first to be investigated when it comes to suspicious injuries on children.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-08T08:27:00" id="p212">
<quote orig_author="PhantomWolf">
Because she followed to another country, had him kidnapped at gunpoint, chained to a bed and then assaulted him? I'd say that was a pretty good reason.

</quote>
Maybe she did, maybe she didn't.

<quote>
And there is your problem entirely, you don't get it.

</quote>
Wow. Deep.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-08T08:29:00" id="p213">
<quote orig_author="Wildy">
Well clearly she decided that it doesn't matter considering that she decided to flee instead of staying and presenting a defence.

</quote>
Clearly? Maybe she decided that, maybe she had other reasons.

<quote>
Perhaps you should actually answer the question I presented to you instead of trying to turn the question back on me.

</quote>
Why? Turning the question back to you is a perfectly reasonable rhetorical device that, in this case, is meant to make you reconsider whether you should be as certain as you seem to be. Plainly it didn't work.

<quote>
You say that but it seems that you've already passed judgement on this case.

</quote>
I'm reserving judgment.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-12-08T17:43:00" id="p214">
<quote orig_author="sgtbaker">
I want to make it clear that I don't disagree with your premise that male victims are more likely to be dismissed or treated appropriately in sex abuse and spousal abuse cases. I do, however, know that the mother is the first to be investigated when it comes to suspicious injuries on children.

</quote>
I agree, but I saw over and over again comments about mothers being given the chance to do it again when a father would not. Our culture says that women don't do that and we keep putting children back with abusive mothers just because they are mothers. Doesn't make much sense to me. So many judges and social service people refuse to see what's clearly in front of them. In the comments on many of those articles people ask why no one did anything, and family or friends come on and say people did. But, the authorities never really listened and kept giving the children back. How is that protecting the children. That's really my point.
</post>
<post author="Wildy" datetime="2011-12-08T20:50:00" id="p215">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Clearly? Maybe she decided that, maybe she had other reasons.

</quote>
Such as?

<quote>
Why? Turning the question back to you is a perfectly reasonable rhetorical device that, in this case, is meant to make you reconsider whether you should be as certain as you seem to be. Plainly it didn't work.

</quote>
It's also a way to avoid answering questions which is what you have done here.
</post>
<post author="sgtbaker" datetime="2011-12-09T04:59:00" id="p216">
<quote orig_author="Naive1000">
I agree, but I saw over and over again comments about mothers being given the chance to do it again when a father would not. Our culture says that women don't do that and we keep putting children back with abusive mothers just because they are mothers. Doesn't make much sense to me. So many judges and social service people refuse to see what's clearly in front of them. In the comments on many of those articles people ask why no one did anything, and family or friends come on and say people did. But, the authorities never really listened and kept giving the children back. How is that protecting the children. That's really my point.

</quote>
I know from experience that this happens with both mother and father abuse/neglect cases. Children and Family Services are reluctant to take the child[ren] away and the decision to remove children from the situation is based on the severity of the abuse/neglect and the level of threat to the children, not the gender of the parent.

I do not have any evidence to counter the claim that a woman gains trust with children faster than a man, it seems very plausible. I wouldn't doubt the suggestion that the public is less likely to believe sexual abuse allegations against a woman, rather than a man. It's certainly true that the biological mother has greater odds of gaining custody of children, in custody disputes. I just know that when it comes to abuse allegations, CFS does not sexually discriminate.
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-10T13:19:00" id="p217">
<quote orig_author="Wildy">
Such as?

</quote>
Maybe she didn't trust the justice system to produce the correct result. It's not like miscarriages of justice are completely unheard of, after all. Maybe she had other reasons that I am not aware of. Your position seems to be that there is only one reason to avoid a trial - because you actually are guilty. That seems like a rather unimaginative way of looking at things.

<quote>
It's also a way to avoid answering questions which is what you have done here.

</quote>
Physician, heal thyself.
</post>
<post author="tyr_13" datetime="2011-12-10T20:10:00" id="p218">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Maybe she didn't trust the justice system to produce the correct result. It's not like miscarriages of justice are completely unheard of, after all. Maybe she had other reasons that I am not aware of. Your position seems to be that there is only one reason to avoid a trial - because you actually are guilty. That seems like a rather unimaginative way of looking at things.

Physician, heal thyself.

</quote>
Alright, let us assume that she was actually innocent of the crime she was convicted of, that she decided not to defend herself of, and that was discussed in the media.

What does that have to do with the comments about the claimed rape? How does that affect public perception and reaction about female rapists? What does it have to do with the topic?
</post>
<post author="Matthew Best" datetime="2011-12-10T22:21:00" id="p219">
<quote orig_author="tyr_13">
Alright, let us assume that she was actually innocent of the crime she was convicted of, that she decided not to defend herself of, and that was discussed in the media.

What does that have to do with the comments about the claimed rape? How does that affect public perception and reaction about female rapists? What does it have to do with the topic?

</quote>
Damned if I know. Why are you asking me, anyway? I'm just responding to posts other people have made.
</post>
<post author="Naive1000" datetime="2011-12-13T07:30:00" id="p220">
<quote orig_author="Matthew Best">
Damned if I know. Why are you asking me, anyway? I'm just responding to posts other people have made.

</quote>
Well, I can respect arguing for the sake of arguing <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/biggrin.gif"/>.

Now, onto a new subject. I've decided to ask a question here instead of in a <a href="showthread.php?t=225749">related thread</a> as I do not want to derail it. So, would you find it easier to forgive a female child sex abuser over a male child sexual abuser? Please tell why you would feel this way.

Sadly, I would probably forgive a female sex offender and hold her to a lighter standard than a man. Yes, I know this is sexist and illogical. For some reason, personally, I find it hard to hate woman, any woman. Possibly this is biological, I have no idea. It could be that I am effected by the social stereotypes of men and women and thus unintentionally hold women as more valuable than men. Any which way, I would not hold them to the same standards even though I know this is wrong. Guess I need to fix that part of myself. <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/mazeguyemotions/blush.gif"/>
</post>
</doc>
