<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-199-192783-6886870">
<headline>
Supreme Court Resignations Requested from the Lord?
</headline>
<post author="PDiddie" datetime="2003-05-20T02:58:00" id="p1">
This came from cbsnews.com's "Washington Wrap; I have excerpted most of it below:

<quote>
Citing unnamed but "well-informed court observers," New York Newsday says there could be as many as two Supreme Court resignations next month. Chief Justice " Rehnquist 's resignation is considered likely though not certain and Sandra Day O'Connor 's is considered likely by some court observers but less likely by others." And yet another seat could open if Justice John Paul Stevens, 83, retires; though that is considered "unlikely."

There has been no change in the court since President Clinton appointed Justice Stephen Breyer in 1994 -- the longest period without turnover in 180 years -- and partisans on both sides are getting ready for a fierce battle.

Conservatives are split between Justices Antonin Scalia and Clarence Thomas to fill the chief justice's slot, and over the question of whether potential nominee White House counsel Alberto Gonzales has a strong enough anti-abortion record.

Democrats are gearing up, as well. DNC Chairman Terry McAuliffe, in a speech on Saturday night at the Ohio Jefferson-Jackson Dinner, talked about the potential resignations as "sounding bugles in a tremendous struggle." He said President Bush's judicial nominees shared a common goal of wanting to take the U.S. back to 1952. "The term right-wing extremists doesn't even begin to capture how out of the mainstream these folks are... and George Bush wants to put them on the highest Court of the land."
</quote>

How do you feel about Bush potentially nominating three Supreme Court justices before the election in 2004? Will we see the destruction of Roe v. Wade ? Will the erosion of civil liberties (such as Patriot II) increase?

Weigh in, please...

(Titled edited for topicality...)
</post>
<post author="BumbleBeeBoogie" datetime="2003-05-20T09:16:00" id="p2">
What are the top 6 reasons you vote for a president?
It's not enough to vote for a president because of Supreme Court candidates (although that is my own personal first criteria), there are other issues that should be of concern to all citizens.

What are the top 6 reasons you vote for a presidential candidate? Is you vote based solely on political party or on issues?

My presidential voting record reflects my civil rights and social justice concerns for my country.

!. SUPREME COURT NOMINATIONS (and Federal Judge nominations.)

2. Is the candidate a uniter or divider of the American people?

3. Appointments to the National Labor Relations Board.

4. Appointments to the Environmental Protection Agency and the Federal Communications Commission.

5. Appointments to the Treasurery Department.

6. Appointments to the FBI and CIA.

If a president performs well in these six areas, almost everything else will be protected.

-----BumbleBeeBoogie
</post>
<post author="babsatamelia" datetime="2003-05-20T18:32:00" id="p3">
I have to admit that the Supreme Court appointments
are SO HUGE on my agenda of what's important about
who is in office - I would LOVE to see Sandra O'Connell
resign, but that's doubtful. I thought these appointments
were generally for life - and many members never leave
the Supreme Court until they are put in a pine box.
I would hate to see ANY Supreme Court openings until
we have a different president in office. Who the Pres.
appoints to other key positions is critical also, but then
at least THESE can change with whoever is in office,
whereas a Supreme Court Judge is for life, if they want
it. We already have a highly conservative panel of SC
judges.... I would just shudder to think of the persons
who Bush et al might consider as possibilities. I don't
think that a sufficient number of Americans are given
sufficient education about the immensity of importance
about WHO gets Supreme Court appointments. Based on
who gets appointed to this the highest of all courts, we
will ALL have to live with "their version" or interpretation
of our Constitution for as long as they live in many cases
&amp; that can be a very, very long time.
</post>
<post author="edgarblythe" datetime="2003-05-28T21:30:00" id="p4">
I will be supremely disappointed if the Democrats hand Bush what he wants in this matter.
</post>
<post author="NeoGuin" datetime="2003-05-29T06:37:00" id="p5">
edgar:

If Owen and Estrada are any indication, Jusidical nominatios are one of the few areas where Democrats have shown a real consistent SPINE!

I wonder if we're helping!
</post>
<post author="mamajuana" datetime="2003-05-29T12:54:00" id="p6">
And Souter did not turn out as Bush (senior) expected.
</post>
<post author="babsatamelia" datetime="2003-05-29T17:02:00" id="p7">
Since the Supreme Court decision on Roe vs Wade,
it doesn't seem very likely or intelligent to bring up
this issue again at THIS late date. There will always
be anti abortionists, just like there will always be
PLENTY of unwanted children who are out there, as
we speak - unfed, uncared for, abused, BUT unless a
move is made to stop these daily horror stories, I
truly do doubt that a move on Bush's part to appoint
someone with a strong anti abortion history will not
pass... even WITH congress in his corner in some
ways. There are too many women who are pro choice,
but who, unlike their opposition, simply are not prone
to commit violent &amp; illegal acts to prove it. The fact
that WE are out here in vast numbers isn't a fact that
is lost on anyone in Washington. The fact that we do
not bomb buildings or kill people to assert our position
simply shows who is more intelligent and far larger
in numbers of voters. As I always say when it comes
to this topic... there is only ONE THING that will make
a believer out of me that these antiabortionists are
truly following a just cause - and that will be the day
when they START ADOPTING ALL OF THESE UNWANTED
KIDS, for whom our country can't even find enough
foster homes for, let alone permanent homes...even if
the child is beaten at home - chances are that kid is
STILL safer at home than he/she would be in a foster
home situation. So, YES by all means - get on out
there and SHOW US THAT YOU CAN PUT YOUR MONEY
WHERE YOUR MOUTH IS- and the only way to do that
in MY book, is for these fervent antiabortionists to
start adopting all of these unwanted children.
Otherwise - shut the he** up!
</post>
<post author="edgarblythe" datetime="2003-05-29T17:05:00" id="p8">
double hockey sticks
</post>
<post author="sweetcomplication" datetime="2003-06-06T14:04:00" id="p9">
yes, BBB, your list is great, but who do you believe fits that bill among the current crop of pretenders to the throne of the Shrub?
</post>
<post author="BumbleBeeBoogie" datetime="2003-06-06T14:43:00" id="p10">
Who should/could beat W?
SC, who should (not could) beat President Bush in 2004? My first choice would be Main Governor Howard Dean. I think he has the courage to take on Bush et al as the best representative of the Democratic wing of the Democratic party.

John Kerry would be my second choice because he has enough name recognition and some courage to take on and beat Bush.

However, the Democrats would have to demonstrate to me that they are returning to the heart and soul of the Democratic Party before they would have my support. Yet I'm not sure that sufficient numbers of political independents are ready to support those true democratic party positions. I'm afraid too many people have swallowed the Bush myths and vote against their self-interests by manipulation based on devisive wedge political issues that have nothing to do with governing.

I've not voted for democrats or republications in the last two presidential elections.

---BumbleBeeBoogie
</post>
<post author="sweetcomplication" datetime="2003-06-07T23:31:00" id="p11">
BBB: In both 1996 and 2000 I voted for Nader, but I am so afraid of what has happened already and what is quite possibly in store for our 'future' that I am just about to the point where I am willing to suck it up and just vote Democratic. I don't think you should be pessimistic about Dean's chances; at this early point, he is ahead in state polling and we do vote state by state. When they do a nationwide poll, he drops. I don't have the reasoning behind that, but hey, I saw it on the news so it must be true <img src="http://cdn2.able2know.org/images/v5/emoticons/icon_rolleyes.gif" alt="Rolling Eyes"/>.
</post>
<post author="BumbleBeeBoogie" datetime="2003-06-08T16:52:00" id="p12">
Zogby Poll re Democratic Candidates
Massachusetts Senator John Kerry is the most popular Democratic presidential candidate in New Hampshire polling by Zogby International for the state's primary election next January, followed closely by former Vermont Governor Howard Dean, 25% - 22%. Connecticut Senator Joseph Lieberman was a distant third at 10%.

Missouri Congressman Richard Gephardt, regarded as likely to win the Democratic caucus in Iowa, finished fourth in New Hampshire polling with 7%. North Carolina Senator John Edwards and Ohio Congressman Dennis Kucinich each earned 2% of the vote, and the three remaining declared candidates, Florida Senator Bob Graham, civil rights activist Rev. Al Sharpton, and former Illinois Senator Carol Mosely Braun, tallied less than one percent each. More than one in four (27%) likely voters remain undecided.

More than three-fourths (76%) of the likely Democratic primary voters said they think it is very likely (34%) or somewhat likely (42%) that President George W. Bush will be re-elected, regardless of how they intend to vote.
</post>
<post author="PDiddie" datetime="2003-06-08T17:30:00" id="p13">
Opposing armies gird their loins for battle:

<quote>
</quote>

<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2003/06/08/politics/08COUR.html">Lobbying Starts as Groups Foresee Supreme Court Vacancy</a>
</post>
<post author="mamajuana" datetime="2003-06-28T23:44:00" id="p14">
Wll, PD - the summer session has ended, and all nine justices have indicated they will be returning for the fall session. Not only that; they have handed down some decisions that had to be a surprise to the WH, all things considered.

Is the situation changed? Have they - O'Connor and Rehnquist - decided to stay on because of changed attitudes? Is Scalia disappointed not that it looks like he won't be appointed Chief Justice soon?

What a difference a day makes.
</post>
<post author="PDiddie" datetime="2003-06-29T06:16:00" id="p15">
Let's just hope no one kicks suddenly...
</post>
<post author="PDiddie" datetime="2003-06-29T06:52:00" id="p16">
I found a great essay by Mark Steyen at the Chicago Sun-Times. Here's a small piece of it:

<quote>
The correct term is ''racial quotas,'' but that's too bald, too clear. So its proponents came up with the coy evasion of ''affirmative action.'' But over the years that also became tarnished. Hence the invention of ''diversity.'' Who could be against ''diversity''? Who wouldn't want to celebrate it? It's the perfect enlightened vapidity.

But whoever thought it'd fly as a legal concept? Last week, the court had before it two models of University of Michigan diversity: In the first version--the undergraduate school's system--they give you 20 points for being black. You need 150 points to get in. So, by being born black, you're 13 percent of the way there.

Tough for whitey, but he knows the rules. If Albert Gore IV wants to get into the joint, he understands Jesse Jackson XXVII has got a head start and he's gonna have to make up those 20 points somewhere else. Being a scion of the first Android American to run for president is not an approved minority group. Nor is being a Jew or Asian or a Pacific islander from Tuvalu.

Cruel, but it's all there in the fine print. Down the road at the Law School, the same thing goes on in practice, but it's all swathed and swaddled in vague, soothing multiculti mumbo-jumbo and is ''flexible enough to consider all pertinent elements of diversity in light of the particular qualifications of each applicant, and to place them on the same footing for consideration, although not necessarily according them the same weight,'' whatever that means. But whatever it means, it's less vulgar than handing out points for pigmentation.

As Swingin' Sandra put it, approvingly, the Law School (like Sandra) ''engages in a highly individualized, holistic review... flexible, non-mechanical... soft variable... nuanced judgment... potential to enrich...'' Zzzzzzzz.

Which is the point. The court's message is: As long as we don't see how the sausage is made, you're OK. Take your ''soft variables'' into the smoke-filled room. Worse, the court has dignified ''diversity''--a flag of activist convenience, a wily obfuscation--as a compelling state interest, and on its promoters' terms.
</quote>

<a href="http://www.suntimes.com/output/steyn/cst-edt-steyn29.html">Here's the rest of it.</a>
</post>
<post author="sweetcomplication" datetime="2003-06-29T09:51:00" id="p17">
Wow, PDiddie, I read the entire article and that is a good one!

Wanna get ill? Go to "Should Bush Be Punished", start from page 10 and read through to the end. (sorry I didn't get the link, but I'm fairly certain it's under Politics...) It was enough for me to change my usual Dubya signature quotes to what I now have, at least for a while...
</post>
<post author="PDiddie" datetime="2003-06-29T10:01:00" id="p18">
I'm not touching that thread, sweetie...
</post>
<post author="sweetcomplication" datetime="2003-06-29T10:03:00" id="p19">
if only I hadn't acted on the PM I received... if only... now Sweetie's hurting...
</post>
<post author="mamajuana" datetime="2003-06-29T11:44:00" id="p20">
Sweetie - there are many difficult threads. And some of the worst are the ones where people speak up as self-proclaimed experts wishing for the role of phrophet. After long experience with abuzz (on which so many here participated), it's better to keep one's distance from those threads, unless............ But you do learn some basic opinions of people. Some are eye-opening. Some are surprises on the other side. But sooner or later, they tend to get nasty.
</post>
<post author="PDiddie" datetime="2003-06-29T17:28:00" id="p21">
Why does it matter so much, and what are the implications for the American people? Some of the Court's recent decisions vividly show what is at stake. Take for example the case of Patricia Garrett, a nurse in Birmingham, Alabama, and mother of three. She was the director of neonatal services for the University of Alabama when she was diagnosed with breast cancer, and she took a leave of absence to undergo surgery and radiation treatments. Patricia Garrett survived breast cancer, but when she returned to work her employer demoted her. She sued in federal court under the Americans with Disabilities Act, which was passed by Congress to defend the rights of every American who suffers from a disabling illness. Alabama challenged that federal law as an infringement of its power. In 2001, in a 5-4 decision, Chief Justice Rehnquist wrote that Congress had acted beyond its power and that States could not be sued for damages in federal court for discriminating against people with disabilities. Had just one of the five majority Justices voted the other way, States would have been prevented by federal law from firing or demoting people like Patricia Garrett for getting cancer, and this key provision of the Americans with Disabilities Act would have been upheld.

That case is part of a recent trend in which a narrow majority of the Supreme Court creates new restrictions on federal rights and protections, in accord with new legal theories being promoted by a cadre of dedicated conservative activists, often in alliance with powerful and wealthy special interests.

---Senator Patrick Leahy, ranking Democrat on the Senate Judiciary Committee, in remarks to the National Press Club, June 25, 2003

<a href="http://www.salon.com/opinion/feature/2003/06/28/leahy/index.html">Averting judicial "Armageddon"</a>
</post>
<post author="PDiddie" datetime="2003-07-08T09:00:00" id="p22">
Thank goodness Justice O'Connor didn't get hit in the head by that beam in Philly over the holiday weekend.

IMHO she is the one in charge of the nation.

Did anyone see the interview on Snuffleluffagus's Sunday morning chat with her and Justice Breyer?
</post>
<post author="PDiddie" datetime="2003-07-15T12:19:00" id="p23">
Religious broadcaster Pat Robertson urged his nationwide audience Monday to pray for God to remove three justices from the Supreme Court so they could be replaced by conservatives.

"We ask for miracles in regard to the Supreme Court," Robertson said on the Christian Broadcasting Network's "The 700 Club."

Robertson has launched a 21-day "prayer offensive" directed at the Supreme Court in the wake of its 6-3 June vote that decriminalized sodomy. Robertson said in a letter on the CBN Web site that the ruling "has opened the door to homosexual marriage, bigamy, legalized prostitution and even incest."

The same letter targets three justices in particular: "One justice is 83-years-old, another has cancer and another has a heart condition. Would it not be possible for God to put it in the minds of these three judges that the time has come to retire?"

Judging from the descriptions, Robertson was referring to Justice John Paul Stevens, who was born in 1920, and Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg, who had colon cancer surgery in 1999. The identity of the third justice was unclear.

<a href="http://www.abcnews.go.com/wire/Politics/ap20030714_1993.html">ABC News.com</a>

And here's Betty Bowers' "I Got Your Back, Pat" prayer:

Dear Mercurially Merciful Lord:

O Lord, we come before You today because we are sure that, by now, You know that Brother Pat Robertson has turned to You in solemn Christian prayer to beseech You to kill off a few Supreme Court justices that have rudely treated folks Pat hates with some respect. With atypical candor, Brother Pat is calling this a "prayer offensive." Indeed it is difficult to imagine a more offensive prayer, O Lord. Ever helpful, Brother Pat hints: "One justice is 83 years old, another has cancer and another has a heart condition."

Call us timid, O Lord, but it makes us rather nervous when a man who just went through a bout of prostate cancer himself thinks it wise to ask his Creator to go on a killing rampage, targeting people with cancer and heart conditions. After all, who will run the country if You take Dick Cheney from us? We are further concerned that You might respond to Brother Pat's imprecatory prayers in that mischievous, ironic way of Yours and, well, kill him, too. It is that delicious penchant of Yours of giving people what they pray for in others that we grow concerned for Brother Pat's safety.

If indeed You are again mulling over killing Pat (and second-guessing why You didn't act when You had the chance the first time), we are renewing the prayer we made when You first tried to kill Brother Pat Robertson with prostate cancer:

O Lord, we know that You have your reasons for lifting Your veil of protection away from Brother Pat's sin-and-cancer-filled prostate gland. Apparently he has said or done something to vex You and provoke Your famously itchy trigger finger.

While many might assume that it was Brother Pat's profitable career of putting words in Your mouth that got under Your skin, perhaps Brother Pat simply looked at You the wrong way. Any reader of the Bible knows that it is difficult to gauge exactly what will set You off. For example, we know that You turned Moses' yenta sister into a leper for simply asking a pesky question You found mildly intrusive, so there is a very good chance that Brother Pat has no idea what oversight led You turning on him and now wanting him dead.

We recall, O Lord, how You told Oral Roberts years ago that if he didn't come up with one million dollars, You would call him Home. Perhaps You struck a similar bargain with Brother Pat. Only this time, out of Your understandable frustration over Brother Roberts beating You in Your own bet, You raised the stakes to such lofty levels that it was too much money for even Brother Pat to cough up without having to sell his beloved race horses or investments in Liberian gold mines.

Nevertheless, we ask, O Lord, that You spare Brother Pat from Your wrath. In lieu of that, we ask Jesus that You allow Brother Pat's illness to be prolonged enough to allow him to become weepy in scores of telecasts of the 700 Club so that the phone banks will peal like a Christmas carillon, as sobbing homemakers in trailers throughout this glorious land send in cash to Your glory!

In Your glorious name Lord Jesus I pray,

Betty
</post>
<post author="sweetcomplication" datetime="2003-07-15T13:05:00" id="p24">
yes, PD, I just got that on one of my alerts, so I would greatly appreciate your not interrupting my prayer!

"prayer offensive" - love that term... <img src="http://cdn2.able2know.org/images/v5/emoticons/icon_rolleyes.gif" alt="Rolling Eyes"/>

as an aside, Senator Arlen Spector is the only member of the judiciary committe (or whatever the heck the correct title is!) not to have made up his mind on his vote re Pryor, which is to be held day after tomorrow - please call his office (doesn't matter if you're not in Pennsylvania) and give your opinions; they are tallying up the positive and negative calls; please, everyone, call him at 202-224-4254 ASAP

thank you!
</post>
<post author="BumbleBeeBoogie" datetime="2003-07-15T16:39:00" id="p25">
Betty Bowers thinks Pat Robertson's idea is a rope-a-dope
<a href="http://www.bettybowers.com/nl_prayersquad.html">http://www.bettybowers.com/nl_prayersquad.html</a>

Pat Robertson's Prayer Death Squad
Target: the Supreme Court

A "Got Your Back" Prayer
by Mrs. Betty Bowers, America's Best Christian

Dear Mercurially Merciful Lord:

O Lord, we come before you today because we are sure that, by now, you know that Brother Pat Robertson has turned to you in solemn Christian prayer to beseech you to kill off a few Supreme Court justices that have rudely treated folks Pat hates with some respect. With atypical candor, Brother Pat is calling this a "prayer offensive." Indeed, it is difficult to imagine a more offensive prayer, O Lord. Ever helpful, Brother Pat hints: ``One justice is 83-years-old, another has cancer and another has a heart condition."

Call us timid, O Lord, but it makes us rather nervous when a man who just went through a bout of prostrate cancer thinks it wise to ask his Creator to start going on a killing rampage, targeting people with cancer and heart conditions. After all, who will run the country if you take Dick Cheney from us? We are further concerned that you might respond to Brother Pat's imprecatory prayers in that mischievous, ironic way of Yours and, well, kill him, too. It is with your delicious penchant for technically giving people what they pray for in mind (like when John Kennedy, Jr. screamed: "Lord, do something to shut up that goddamned braying cokehead in Row A!") that we grow concerned for Brother Pat's safety.

If indeed you are mulling over killing Pat again (and second guessing why you didn't act when you had the chance the first time), we are renewing the prayer we made when you first tried to kill Brother Pat Robertson with prostrate cancer:

O Lord, we know that you have your reasons for lifting your veil of protection away from Brother Pat's sinful crotch. Apparently Brother Pat has said or done something to vex you and provoke your famously itchy trigger finger.

While many might assume that it was Brother Pat's profitable career of putting words in your mouth that got under your skin, perhaps, Brother Pat simply looked at you the wrong way. Any reader of the Bible knows that it is difficult to gauge exactly what will set you off. For example, we know that you turned Moses' yenta sister into a leper for simply asking a pesky question you found mildly intrusive, so there is a very good chance that Brother Pat has no idea what oversight led to the Lord turning on him and now wanting him dead.

We recall, O Lord, how you told Oral Roberts years ago that if he didn't come up with one million dollars pronto, you would break his legs and then kill or otherwise inconvenience him. Perhaps, you struck a similar bargain with Brother Pat. Only this time, out of your understandable frustration over Brother Roberts beating you in your own bet, raised the stakes to such lofty levels that it was too much money for even Brother Pat to cough up without having to sell his beloved race horses.

Nevertheless, we ask, O Lord, that you spare Brother Pat from your wrath. In lieu of that, we ask Jesus that you allow Brother Pat's illness to be prolonged enough to allow him to become weepy in scores of telecasts of the 700 Club so that the phone banks will peal like a Christmas carillon, as sobbing homemakers in trailers throughout this glorious land send in cash to your glory!

In your Glorious name Lord Jesus, this I pray.
</post>
<post author="BumbleBeeBoogie" datetime="2003-07-16T10:11:00" id="p26">
And Then Jesus Said, Shut The Hell Up, Pat
== And Then Jesus Said, Shut The Hell Up, Pat ==
San Francisco Gate

Religious broadcaster and noted hunk of old quivery penis-free sweaty cheese mold Pat Robertson urged his semi-coherent Elmer's-sniffin' nationwide audience Monday to pray for God to remove three justices from the Supreme Court so they could be replaced by conservatives.

"We ask for miracles in regard to the Supreme Court," Robertson actually
oozed on the Christian Broadcasting Network's freakish coven o' savage
karmic pain "The 700 Club."

Robertson has launched a 21-day "prayer offensive" directed at the Supreme Court in the wake of its 6-3 June vote that decriminalized sodomy. Robertson said in a letter on the CBN Web site that the ruling "has opened the door to homosexual marriage, bigamy, legalized prostitution and even incest, and probably that thing I fantasize about with the margarine and the belt sander and the garden hose."

In related news, the entire goddamn universe just launched a "Oh just shut the hell up you bickering sexless little gin-soaked faux-religious simp offensive" aimed straight at Robertson and bathtub buddy Jerry Falwell. "We know this campaign isn't really necessary given how Robertson and Falwell are essentially nothing more than temporary pimples on the great perfectly smooth round delicious ass of life, and that they have zero bearing or true lasting effect on anything you care about in any time zone or plane of existence in the known and unknown galaxy," said the Gods of Fate and Time.

"We just liked the title. P.S.; Yay sodomy!"

<a href="http://sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/n/a/2003/07/14/national2334EDT0738.DTL&amp;nl=fix">http://sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/n/a/2003/07/14/national2334EDT0738.DTL&amp;nl=fix</a>
</post>
</doc>
