<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-212-191666-3033754">
<headline>
US says it has right to kidnap foreign citizens
</headline>
<post author="vinayp" datetime="2007-12-03T05:27:00" id="p1">
<quote>
US says it has right to kidnap foreign citizens

David Leppard

The US has told Britain it can kidnap foreign citizens if they are wanted for crimes in the US. A senior lawyer for the US government told the court of appeal in London that kidnapping foreign citizens is permissible under US law because the US Supreme Court has sanctioned it.
Until now, it was assumed that US law permitted kidnapping only in the extraordinary rendition of terror suspects. The US government has, for the first time, made it clear that the law applies to anyone suspected of a crime by Washington. Legal experts confirmed this weekend that the US viewed extradition as just one way of getting foreign suspects back to face trial.
The US governments view emerged during a hearing involving Stanley Tollman, a former director of Chelsea football club and his wife Beatrice. The Tollmans, who control the Red Carnation hotel group and live in London, are wanted in the US for bank fraud. They have been fighting extradition through the British courts.
During a hearing last month, Lord Justice Moses asked US government counsel Alun Jones about the US governments treatment of Gavin, Tollmans nephew. Gavin Tollman was the subject of an attempted abduction during a visit to Canada in 2005.
Jones replied it was acceptable under US law to kidnap people if they were wanted for offences in the US. The US does have a view about procuring people to its own shores which is not shared. He said that if a person was kidnapped by the US authorities in another country and was brought back to face charges in the US, no US court could rule that the abduction was illegal and free him. If you kidnap a person outside the US and you bring him there, the court has no jurisdiction to refuse. It goes back to bounty-hunting days in the 1860s, Jones said. Justice Ouseley, a second judge, challenged Jones to be honest about (his) position. Jones replied: That is US law. SUNDAY TIMES, LONDON
UNCLE SAM WANTS YOU
Bounty hunting | A term that goes back to the 1860s. A bounty-hunter, traditionally employed by a bail bondsman, tracks down and captures outlaws for which he gets a reward
Extraordinary rendition | Term used to describe kidnapping &amp; extrajudicial transfer of a person, especially terror suspect, from one nation to another Case in Question | Former director of Chelsea football club Stanley Tollman and his wife, Beatrice, who are wanted in the US for fraud and tax evasion. US counsel justifies an abduction bid on Tollmans nephew, Gavin, in Canada in 2005 during a vacation. He was released by a Canadian court after 10 days

<a href="http://www.timesonline.co.uk/tol/news/world/us_and_americas/article2982640.ece">US says it has right to kidnap British citizens - Times Online</a>

</quote>

Any thoughts on this,
Will US care for other countries laws, before kidnapping foreign nationals?
</post>
<post author="Feanor" datetime="2007-12-03T05:33:00" id="p2">
You're kidding right?

EDIT: Isn't that grounds for a declaration of war?
</post>
<post author="Tronic" datetime="2007-12-03T05:58:00" id="p3">
Just how it should be done! Teaches criminals not to fk with the state! Now, when will our leaders grow some balls? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Feanor" datetime="2007-12-03T06:13:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="Tronic">
Just how it should be done! Teaches criminals not to fk with the state! Now, when will our leaders grow some balls? <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>

</quote>

Not at all how it should be done. This is an infringement on the sovereignity of other nations.
</post>
<post author="vinayp" datetime="2007-12-03T06:21:00" id="p5">
<quote>
Not at all how it should be done. This is an infringement on the sovereignity of other nations.
</quote>

I remember Israel did some covert operations to free hostages held in Airplanes. When Israel can do that, why not a Super Power do that.
The morality of carrying out such an operations will come next into picture.

If USA carries out such operations, what can other countries do to prevent it?
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-12-03T06:30:00" id="p6">
UK executed German war criminals after WW2 all over Europe.

Israelis did pretty much the same.

I think what we do is only in the case of the crook hiding in a country with no diplomatic relations with us. Of course that crook has to have committed some very serious crime. Normal money laundering, pyramid scheme, insider's trade, even rape and murder won't provoke us to execute an arrest order in foreign country. It'll have to be some terrorist or treasonous act.
</post>
<post author="vinayp" datetime="2007-12-03T06:38:00" id="p7">
Sir, the article says, not only terrorists or war criminals but also bank frauders, can be kidnapped and brought back to US.

<quote>
The admission will alarm the British business community after the case of the so-called NatWest Three, bankers who were extradited to America on fraud charges. More than a dozen other British executives, including senior managers at British Airways and BAE Systems, are under investigation by the US authorities and could face criminal charges in America.

Until now it was commonly assumed that US law permitted kidnapping only in the extraordinary rendition of terrorist suspects.

The American government has for the first time made it clear in a British court that the law applies to anyone, British or otherwise, suspected of a crime by Washington.
</quote>
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-12-03T07:06:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="vinayp">
Sir, the article says, not only terrorists or war criminals but also bank frauders, can be kidnapped and brought back to US.

</quote>

OK I see the misunderstanding.

We are both correct in a way.

My point is that the US government doesn't normally kidnap people wanted for crimes in another country unless it's extraordinary.

Your point is that the article says it's legal. But if you read it closely you'll notice it only says it's "legal" but doesn't say the US government does it. These crooks are captured/kidnapped by bounty hunters. They are private parties not under the control of US government.

See the difference?
</post>
<post author="Ray" datetime="2007-12-03T07:17:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="gunnut">
These crooks are captured/kidnapped by bounty hunters. They are private parties not under the control of US government.

See the difference?

</quote>

That would appear that the US authorises illegal means to be adopted, apart from being immoral, by those under the US laws.

I am sure the same would be seriously viewed by the US, if foreign bounty hunters entered the US and kidnapped US citizens who were guilty of misdemeanour in foreign nations.

Therefore, it does not appear a correct thing.

Something is wrong somewhere in this report!
</post>
<post author="Tronic" datetime="2007-12-03T07:20:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="Feanor">
Not at all how it should be done. This is an infringement on the sovereignity of other nations.

</quote>

I'm going to let you in on something. Dawood Ibrahim, India's most wanted man, who is responsible for smuggling in explosives (this is ofcourse in addition to extortion, murder, drug smuggling, pretty much running Mumbai's underworld Mafia) and providing it to certain people which caused the 1993 Mumbai serial blasts that killed hundreds of innocent people is today residing in Pakistan; at the same time has made Dubai his hub to continue his Mumbai operations. Now, ofcourse, the fact that Indian leadership has no balls is another case, but now, what do you think is the more sensible thing to do? Hunting down this criminal or respecting the sovereignty of another nation?
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-12-03T07:25:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="Ray">
What you signify means that the US authorises illegal means, apart from being immoral. by those under the US laws.

I am sure the same would be seriously viewed by the US, if foreign bounty hunters entered the US and kidnapped US citizens who were guilty of misdemeanour in foreign nations.

Therefore, it does not appear a correct thing.

</quote>

You are right sir. It is not correct.

However, I have to split hair with you here regarding what is "legal" by definition.

The ariticle states that US courts cannot declare the abduction to be illegal and free the crook. The law doesn't exactly say kidnapping is illegal. Or at least that's what I've gathered from reading the article.

I don't think we should kidnap people unless the crimes committed were extraordinary in nature, such as terrorist act or treason.
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-12-03T07:29:00" id="p12">
<quote orig_author="vinayp">
So US says, it can do it legally(under US laws), but instead of direct government involvement, it uses bounty hunters to carry out such operations.

Can we look at it this way, US backs the bounty hunters for kidnapping of foreign nationals, even if US govt does not involve directly, isnt it US govt initiates the process?

</quote>

US doesn't actually say it's legal.

From my understanding, US courts "cannot declare the kidnapping to be illegal and free the crook."

It's sort of a legal technicality here. We don't officially endorse it. We don't officially legalize it. We just don't refuse it when the opportunity presents itself.
</post>
<post author="vinayp" datetime="2007-12-03T07:39:00" id="p13">
This also has something to do with, how other countries view this kidnapping.

For example, India always claimed that Dawood Ibrahim is in Karachi. If India kidnaps him, one can assume what follows next...
</post>
<post author="Donnie" datetime="2007-12-03T08:03:00" id="p14">
<quote orig_author="Ray">
That would appear that the US authorises illegal means to be adopted, apart from being immoral, by those under the US laws.

</quote>

It's not an authorization per se.

Under the Ker-Frisbie doctrine, the laws as they are writen would not allow courts to release an individual based on how they were obtained. This goes for any type of "unauthorized" extradition, even from state to state.

If the govoner of California commited a crime in Michigan, and the sate of California didnt want to turn him over to Michigan, Michagan can kidnap him from California, plain and simple.

by no means does this mean the court authorises anything, they are just by law powerless to deny prosecution.

Say for example your a US citizen and a man rapes your daughter and take off to Canada, you go to Canada, find the guy and bring him back "kidnap" to the US. The court cannot tell you that they cant try him.

Under Ker, The Supreme Court ruled that "forcible abduction is no sufficient reason why the party should not answer when brought within the jurisdiction of the court which has the right to try him for such an offence, and presents no valid objection to his trial in such court"

Later when the US kidnapped Dr. Humberto Álvarez Machaín, the Supreme Court felt that the court could only consider the jurisdition rights of the defendant if the United States government were involved AND broke any treaty to get them.

As far as I know the US does not have a treaty with any other country that explicitly denies kidnapping.

<quote orig_author="Ray">
I am sure the same would be seriously viewed by the US, if foreign bounty hunters entered the US and kidnapped US citizens who were guilty of misdemeanour in foreign nations.

</quote>

I dont believe the US has ever kidnapped anyone over a misdemeanour.
</post>
<post author="Ray" datetime="2007-12-03T08:11:00" id="p15">
If that is the US law, then it is flawed.

Extradition is the what is the manner adopted internationally to bring criminals to justice and not through criminal activities like kidnapping, no matter how justified it appears.

Kidnapping would lead to anarchy!
</post>
<post author="Vinod2070" datetime="2007-12-03T08:27:00" id="p16">
There are two sides to this arguement. Normally this is abhorrent and should not be done among democratic and lawful countries.

But if you have terror and crime havens being provided by sovereign states (Dubai, Pakistan even UK under their peculiar brand to all kinds of Islamic terrorists) what options are available to bring terrorists and criminals to justice?

Rather than USA or any other country wishing to prosecute the criminals going to war over these criminals, rendition is a better option. Let the criminal/terror supporting country go to war over them if they are so important to these countries.
</post>
<post author="Ray" datetime="2007-12-03T08:35:00" id="p17">
Or do what happened to that character Alexander Litvinenko! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Donnie" datetime="2007-12-03T08:52:00" id="p18">
<quote orig_author="Ray">
If that is the US law, then it is flawed.

Extradition is the what is the manner adopted internationally to bring criminals to justice and not through criminal activities like kidnapping, no matter how justified it appears.

Kidnapping would lead to anarchy!

</quote>

The law has been this way since the dawn of the US, no anarchy, Yet.....

Other countries could eliminate this by signing extradition treaties that exclude kidnapping. The curts would under this cirumstance be allowed to throw out the case. That would mean of course they have to have the means to make the US want to sign it. (and this would only work for kidnappings that involve the state, not private ones, like dad kidnapping daughters rapist)
</post>
<post author="Ray" datetime="2007-12-03T09:04:00" id="p19">
And does the US law permit US citizens to be likewise kidnapped?

If so, then why the hullabaloo over the Iran hostage case?

I am sorry but I can't see the logic of kidnapping.
</post>
<post author="Feanor" datetime="2007-12-03T10:52:00" id="p20">
<quote orig_author="Ray">
Or do what happened to that character Alexander Litvinenko! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/smilies/smiles.gif"/>

</quote>

He was a criminal and got a death sentence in a closed court. Then the KGB carried out the sentence. Same logic huh....... except we didn't bother actually kidnapping him, we just carried out the sentence, since he missed his court date and was tried in absence <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>

The law is ridiculous and I wouldn't be surprised to hear some diplomatic uproar over it.
</post>
<post author="Ray" datetime="2007-12-03T10:57:00" id="p21">
<quote orig_author="Feanor">
He was a criminal and got a death sentence in a closed court. Then the KGB carried out the sentence. Same logic huh....... except we didn't bother actually kidnapping him, we just carried out the sentence, since he missed his court date and was tried in absence <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>

The law is ridiculous and I wouldn't be surprised to hear some diplomatic uproar over it.

</quote>

That too is flawed justice!
</post>
<post author="Feanor" datetime="2007-12-03T11:00:00" id="p22">
<quote orig_author="Ray">
That too is flawed justice!

</quote>

Goddamnit. I definetly need to bring back [sarcasm] brackets..... <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/frown.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Donnie" datetime="2007-12-03T15:57:00" id="p23">
<quote orig_author="Ray">
And does the US law permit US citizens to be likewise kidnapped?

</quote>

There are laws that do not allow kidnapping, you can still be prosecuted for kidnapping, look at Dog the Bounty Hunter. It just says the courts cannot deny jutice because of the means, Mexico is free to prosecute Dog for what he did. If a Mexican bounty hunter kidnapped Dog and brought him to justice, I doubt the US would make much stink about it, at least not without getting egg on thier face.

im not talking about the government back kidnappings, thats a little different and goes along with the treaties we have in place, other countries may or may not be allowed to try those kidnappers under thier own laws.

I doubt Canada, Mexico, or a whole lot of other countries have laws on the books that specificaly prevent kidnapping from another country (may be wrong, i have not done the research), since the the "crime" was commited abroad, wherever the crime was commited would be the jurisdicion they would be tried in, I know some countrys allow for trials of crimes that did not happen within thier borders, but I dont believe that is a prevelent situation.
</post>
<post author="Officer of Engineers" datetime="2007-12-03T16:04:00" id="p24">
There was a case several years ago involving a US bounty hunter getting his man in Canada. The bounty hunter was extradited back to Canada on kidnapping charges. No free lunch here.
</post>
<post author="Tronic" datetime="2007-12-03T16:10:00" id="p25">
<quote orig_author="vinayp">
For example, India always claimed that Dawood Ibrahim is in Karachi. If India kidnaps him, one can assume what follows next...

</quote>

A power struggle in D-Company? What else?
</post>
<post author="Donnie" datetime="2007-12-03T16:18:00" id="p26">
<quote orig_author="Officer of Engineers">
There was a case several years ago involving a US bounty hunter getting his man in Canada. The bounty hunter was extradited back to Canada on kidnapping charges. No free lunch here.

</quote>

Exactly my point, but the court could still try the person he kidnapped.
</post>
<post author="Ryan Bailey" datetime="2007-12-03T16:28:00" id="p27">
Friends, I must cite the somewhat incomplete, if not biased, nature of the headline &amp; refer the reader to established international treaty case law. International Diplomacy based upon the understanding of the sovereignty of nations preserves the right to detain suspects &amp; very often even to try &amp; sentence them. This is a process which affects citizens of many nations. As such this must be examined in the light of global affairs.
</post>
<post author="PowerPunch" datetime="2007-12-05T22:44:00" id="p28">
Well they should stop creating terrorists, criminals. If you look at the history starting from 1900's every unrest in every country has been the handy work of their gang called "CIA"... Korea,Iraq,Iran,Afganistan,North Africa,Vietnam,Russia(USSR), south america etc.. I can go on...so as these people who were trained by them know all their secrets and could prove dangerous to US of A and US of A cant explain to the country where those criminals are hiding why they should be handed over and get mud on their face will resort to this kind of "Kidnappings" and declare that its the law of the land....

But I think now is the time to stop entertaining US with thier fancy ideas of cleaning the world of terrorism the ones that they have created for their benefits.
</post>
<post author="Trooth" datetime="2007-12-06T00:28:00" id="p29">
The scary thing here is that the countries in the actual case where US legal counsel gave the US's position are the UK, Canada and of course the US itself.

This has nothing to do with the quality of justice and the extradition process.

I think the legal counsel is merely stating that someone being kidnapped into US jurisdication is not an automatic violation od due process.

This is hardly a new process nor something that only the US would be a party to anyway, even recently there have been very high profile examples - Adolf Eichmann is a good one.

However the US has a very hypocritical view on extradition. To the casual observer every nation, it seems, should give up its citizens on the basis of a phone call, whereas none shall have a US citizen. Just look at the nonsense over the manner in which the NatWest 3 were extradited by the UK under asymmetric extradition laws.
</post>
<post author="gamercube" datetime="2007-12-06T18:37:00" id="p30">
I agree with Feanor. This is pretty ridiculous. Not only does it undermine the sovereignty of other countries, but it could be considered an act of war.

If the US has the right to kidnap foreign citizens and try them according to US laws, then so does Saudi Arabia, China or any other country in the world. How would it go down if an American insulted Mohammad while in Saudi Arabia, and then was kidnapped by the Saudi government, brought back, and beheaded for his crime?

Or if an American journalist violated rules regarding photography in Tibet, and the Chinese kidnapped him, brought him back and sentenced him to 10 years in prison?

If every country starts following this same stupid policy, then as Ray Sir said, there would be anarchy!
</post>
<post author="omon" datetime="2007-12-06T18:47:00" id="p31">
didn,t us came for a guy that shot few ppl in their cars by cia hq? he fled to pakistan(?), us agents went to pak? and got him, and flew him back to us. it happened like 10-15 years ago.
as for letvinenko, russia and ussr has a history of doing that, remember trotcki? was axed in mexico by communist suporter. plus many other in europe.
in most cases no need to bring ppl in, there are ppl in the countries ready to do kidnapping or carry out the sentance, either for money or for ideology.
</post>
<post author="Feanor" datetime="2007-12-07T05:15:00" id="p32">
<quote orig_author="gamercube">
I agree with Feanor. This is pretty ridiculous. Not only does it undermine the sovereignty of other countries, but it could be considered an act of war.

If the US has the right to kidnap foreign citizens and try them according to US laws, then so does Saudi Arabia, China or any other country in the world. How would it go down if an American insulted Mohammad while in Saudi Arabia, and then was kidnapped by the Saudi government, brought back, and beheaded for his crime?

Or if an American journalist violated rules regarding photography in Tibet, and the Chinese kidnapped him, brought him back and sentenced him to 10 years in prison?

If every country starts following this same stupid policy, then as Ray Sir said, there would be anarchy!

</quote>

No no no. No other country will do it. America has too big of a military for it. You can only do this kind of thing to weaker nations <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/mad.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Kansas Bear" datetime="2007-12-07T05:24:00" id="p33">
<quote orig_author="omon">
as for letvinenko, russia and ussr has a history of doing that, remember trotcki? was axed in mexico by communist suporter. plus many other in europe.

</quote>

And Georgi Markov in London in 1978...
</post>
<post author="Kansas Bear" datetime="2007-12-07T05:34:00" id="p34">
<quote orig_author="PowerPunch">
Well they should stop creating terrorists, criminals. If you look at the history starting from 1900's every unrest in every country has been the handy work of their gang called "CIA"... Korea,Iraq,Iran,Afganistan,North Africa,Vietnam,Russia(USSR), south america etc.. I can go on...so as these people who were trained by them know all their secrets.....

</quote>

Wrong! <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="gunnut" datetime="2007-12-07T05:36:00" id="p35">
<quote orig_author="PowerPunch">
Well they should stop creating terrorists, criminals. If you look at the history starting from 1900's every unrest in every country has been the handy work of their gang called "CIA"... Korea,Iraq,Iran,Afganistan,North Africa,Vietnam,Russia(USSR), south america etc.. I can go on...so as these people who were trained by them know all their secrets and could prove dangerous to US of A and US of A cant explain to the country where those criminals are hiding why they should be handed over and get mud on their face will resort to this kind of "Kidnappings" and declare that its the law of the land....

But I think now is the time to stop entertaining US with thier fancy ideas of cleaning the world of terrorism the ones that they have created for their benefits.

</quote>

So CIA created Russia, North Africa, and Iraq? I think our Russian friends here will disagree with you on that.

North Africa? That's France's former colony. We didn't have much to do with it.

Do you have any knowledge of 20th century history or are you just blowing off hot gas from your exit end?
</post>
<post author="Donnie" datetime="2007-12-09T21:35:00" id="p36">
<quote orig_author="gamercube">
If every country starts following this same stupid policy, then as Ray Sir said, there would be anarchy!

</quote>

what policy? it's not a policy, all it says is that the means of extradition does not violate due process. I can almost garuntee that no other country has a law that states if the accused was kidnapped from another country then the accused cant be tried.

Would the UK allow for a trial to take place on a person who commited murder, just because someone kidnapped them and brought them back to the country? Would that violate their due process? I dont know, I'm am truly asking a question, does anyone know?
</post>
<post author="vinayp" datetime="2007-12-10T04:56:00" id="p37">
<quote orig_author="donnie">
Would the UK allow for a trial to take place on a person who commited murder, just because someone kidnapped them and brought them back to the country? Would that violate their due process? I dont know, I'm am truly asking a question, does anyone know?

</quote>

In the genuine case, I agree with you.
But there is a famous saying "One persons terrorist is another's freedom fighter".

For example, consider, China accuses a American as a guilty in some case, and American Govt and Court thinks he is innocent. What will happen in this case. Will the same ideology works in this case?
</post>
<post author="Officer of Engineers" datetime="2007-12-10T05:25:00" id="p38">
China has no extradition treaty with the US.
</post>
<post author="gamercube" datetime="2007-12-10T05:28:00" id="p39">
Donnie,

The article says:

<quote>
He said that if a person was kidnapped by the US authorities in another country and was brought back to face charges in the US, no US court could rule that the abduction was illegal and free him.
</quote>

So the person in question is being kidnapped not by some bounty hunter or some other private individual, but by agents of the state-maybe the FBI or the CIA.

If a government allows it's investigative agencies to kidnap foreign citizens, then it's a policy that it follows-a policy that basically tells the rest of the world-"we don't give a **** about your sovereignty, and we will abduct any of your citizens as and when we require it".

The world, then, could well do the same. You might have Saudi agents kidnapping US citizens for what they deem to be "crimes" committed in Saudi Arabia.
</post>
<post author="Officer of Engineers" datetime="2007-12-10T05:31:00" id="p40">
If that country has an extradition treaty with the US, those American agents would be still be sent to that country for charges.
</post>
<post author="gamercube" datetime="2007-12-10T05:45:00" id="p41">
<quote>
If that country has an extradition treaty with the US, those American agents would be still be sent to that country for charges.
</quote>

Yes, if there is an extradition treaty. In that case, it has been agreed by both countries to follow a set of rules to extradite suspects.

In the absence of such a mutual agreement, kidnapping of suspects is an assault on a country's sovereignty.
</post>
<post author="gsg9" datetime="2007-12-10T17:13:00" id="p42">
<quote orig_author="Officer of Engineers">
If that country has an extradition treaty with the US, those American agents would be still be sent to that country for charges.

</quote>

ok name but a few, <img src="http://www.worldaffairsboard.com/images/darksmiles/rolleyes.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Officer of Engineers" datetime="2007-12-10T18:17:00" id="p43">
American military personnel were stood trial for kidnapping and rape in South Korea and Okinawa. They were surrendered by the American base CO from, legally speaking, American territory.
</post>
<post author="gsg9" datetime="2007-12-10T19:18:00" id="p44">
<quote orig_author="Officer of Engineers">
American military personnel were stood trial for kidnapping and rape in South Korea and Okinawa. They were surrendered by the American base CO from, legally speaking, American territory.

</quote>

Is that it. how long, how much political pressure did the local population put on the national government and the US. How many cases of murder, rape, and all the other things that happens in and around military bases. I used to live in Hanover, Germany and in the two years of residence, there was many cases of American military personnel committing serious crimes against civilians. And in all cases the were quickly spirited out of the country. It happens with all countries, but as a democracy with such high morals, You would think the would sign up to the Hague war crimes convention.
</post>
<post author="Officer of Engineers" datetime="2007-12-10T21:04:00" id="p45">
<quote orig_author="gsg9">
Is that it. how long, how much political pressure did the local population put on the national government and the US. How many cases of murder, rape, and all the other things that happens in and around military bases. I used to live in Hanover, Germany and in the two years of residence, there was many cases of American military personnel committing serious crimes against civilians. And in all cases the were quickly spirited out of the country. It happens with all countries, but as a democracy with such high morals, You would think the would sign up to the Hague war crimes convention.

</quote>

And I was at CFB Lahrs and there were enough complaints against the Canadians too but most of it was fist fights with too much booze and not enough brains at hand.

Most of the time, both we and the local police just want the problem to disappear and we do that but when it involves rape, sorry, we tossed those jerks to the wolves.

However, you've asked for examples and you've got them.
</post>
<post author="Blademaster" datetime="2007-12-10T22:04:00" id="p46">
Murder and its various forms, rape and its various forms, kidnapping, aggravated battery causing serious injury, and swindling people out of their lifesavings, investments or money are the unforgiveable sins in my view and should be extradited in any manner. I would not mind if bounty hunters came and kidnap people who have committed those crimes. Still I would prefer going through the legal channels first and after you have exhausted all your legal options, you can still use the bounty hunting option.
</post>
</doc>
