<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-200-192446-3810563">
<headline>
Have you ever had to call 999?
</headline>
<post author="usycool1" datetime="2011-07-12T23:03:00" id="p1">
Hey everyone,
I'm not sure if this is in the right place but oh well. I was wondering if you ever had to make an emergency 999 call and what it was for.
I once had to call the police when a burglar broke into my neighbours house and I was home alone (I heard there alarm go off and I saw two people who I didn;t recognise in their back garden).
So, have you ever had a time in which you had to call 999?
</post>
<post author="Pn94" datetime="2011-07-12T23:05:00" id="p2">
Might have to call the random . For this thread.
</post>
<post author="siwelmail" datetime="2011-07-12T23:08:00" id="p3">
I was assaulted outside a kfc (sounds sad) after watching a footie match (kfc across the road from the ground) and I had coke thrown on me and hit in the face+glasses stood on

Yeah I couldn't see anything, but they left when I phoned them
</post>
<post author="Aj12" datetime="2011-07-12T23:10:00" id="p4">
Nope, my mum did a few weeks ago when the neighbour was beating his gf though
</post>
<post author="Limesasquatch" datetime="2011-07-12T23:11:00" id="p5">
I walked into my garage to see a local chav trying to steal some bags of popcorn
</post>
<post author="BritGirl" datetime="2011-07-12T23:13:00" id="p6">
Nope and I hope that I never have to
</post>
<post author="MutantGecko" datetime="2011-07-12T23:15:00" id="p7">
when i was about 7 i called 999 wondering what would happen, then i got scared and hung up. about 30 mins later a  man turned up and i was just like, it wasnt me bro.
</post>
<post author="mandn" datetime="2011-07-12T23:17:00" id="p8">
I have phoned the police 3 times, twice in one week this year both times for me getting mugged <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/> other time was when there was a massive group of people throwing things at someones house on my road.
</post>
<post author="The Patriot" datetime="2011-07-12T23:17:00" id="p9">
Nope. Hopefully I never have to either...

*subscribes to see cool stories that aren't BS* <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/ninja.gif" alt=":ninja:"/>
</post>
<post author="CD2112" datetime="2011-07-12T23:19:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="Limesasquatch">
I walked into my garage to see a local chav trying to steal some bags of popcorn

</quote>

By 'garage' I assume you mean petrol station, unless you have a garage stuffed with hundreds of bags of popcorn, which would be cool.
</post>
<post author="KJane" datetime="2011-07-12T23:20:00" id="p11">
Nearly.

I was in the house alone and wasn't expecting my parents home for a while and heard someone moving around downstairs, I went into my older brother's room and grabbed his blunt, decorative and short katana. I dialled 999 on my phone as I crept downstairs, ready to point this blunt and short katana at the intruder only to be faced with my dad with his head in the fridge.

Yeah, he got quite a telling off for scaring me and not letting me know he came back in, now he makes sure to call upstairs to let me know. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/cool.gif" alt=":cool:"/>

I mean my parents + siblings have had times where they needed to call 999 from attacks, thieves, car crashes or fights. But I've been lucky in comparison.
</post>
<post author="&gt;Anna&lt;" datetime="2011-07-12T23:20:00" id="p12">
Nope..I've called for an ambulance a couple of times, but not the police so far; I hope to never need to <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="linkdapink" datetime="2011-07-12T23:20:00" id="p13">
My housemate did when she was assaulted. But otherwise, no :/
</post>
<post author="WeekendOffender" datetime="2011-07-12T23:25:00" id="p14">
A few times, once when someone was stabbed in my street, another time when the guy across the road was beating up his girlfriend, but never for myself.
</post>
<post author="KaurPrincess" datetime="2011-07-12T23:25:00" id="p15">
only when we got burgled once when i was little - they took AGES in coming, even though we live 2 mins away!
and another time i accidentally called the police while at a family friend's house without realising...(was about 5 though!). i was asleep when they came and you can imagine how shocked i was when i woke up...i vaguely remember hiding behind a sofa at some point
</post>
<post author="WeekendOffender" datetime="2011-07-12T23:26:00" id="p16">
<quote orig_author="KJane">
Nearly.

I was in the house alone and wasn't expecting my parents home for a while and heard someone moving around downstairs, I went into my older brother's room and grabbed his blunt, decorative and short katana. I dialled 999 on my phone as I crept downstairs, ready to point the blunt and short katana at the intruder only to be faced with my dad with his head in the fridge.

</quote>

I love this.
</post>
<post author="Boom.Squish" datetime="2011-07-12T23:26:00" id="p17">
No, only the ambulance <img src="images/smilies/frown.png"/> Ended up calling them three times in one night! Bad times...
</post>
<post author="ummm" datetime="2011-07-12T23:29:00" id="p18">
Apparently I did when I was like three years old, and police came round to the house. <img src="images/smilies/colondollar.gif"/>
There was another time that I tried to, but the electricity had been cut off.

Bad, bad times. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/cry2.gif" alt=":cry2:"/>
</post>
<post author="Addzter" datetime="2011-07-12T23:29:00" id="p19">
I remember calling the police when this dog jumped over our fence and started biting my dad. In fact, looking back, I think the dog might have been biting him in the balls. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/erm.gif" alt=":erm:"/>
</post>
<post author="KJane" datetime="2011-07-12T23:32:00" id="p20">
<quote orig_author="WeekendOffender">
I love this.

</quote>

My dad had no idea how close he came to being uselessly poked with a small bit of unoffending metal. But I was desperate. <img src="images/smilies/colondollar.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="fire2burn" datetime="2011-07-12T23:34:00" id="p21">
Yes when some local chavs decided to burgle my house when I popped out to visit the shop, they kicked the door in and made off with my laptop. Thankfully them having an IQ between them roughly equivelent to a walnut meant that they fled the scene to hide in an alleyway only 7 doors down <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/> Where they were promptly apprehended by the police with my possessions still in their hands.

The funniest part is that the CPS then decided there was not enough evidence to prosecute them, even the officer in charge of my case facepalmed at that. He must've thought what's the point in doing this job if the culprits get off scot free. Ah well at least I got my laptop back.
</post>
<post author="Bella Occhi" datetime="2011-07-12T23:35:00" id="p22">
Apparently I called the firemen from my grandma's house when I was about 2 <img src="images/smilies/colondollar.gif"/> No idea what happened, though.
</post>
<post author="insignificant" datetime="2011-07-12T23:39:00" id="p23">
No not the police.. called an ambulance about ten times though.
</post>
<post author="PonchoKid" datetime="2011-07-12T23:41:00" id="p24">
twice in my first year of uni. first time the security man phoned them, and the police asked us questions about a missing flat mate.

second we found a suicide note outside our flat, so called them.

and then another time we got worken up by the police banging on a flat mates door as she was missing, we had no idea until we were woken up, wasnt amused really.
</post>
<post author="Sakura-Chan" datetime="2011-07-12T23:49:00" id="p25">
Yeah, earlier this year, for the first time!

In the middle of the night me and my flatmates heard a woman outside our halls screaming, and then saw her being totally battered by a guy she was with. We were the first and only people to bother calling the police even though the people in the flats opposite ours must have heard, and it must have been going on for a while because she looked a total mess. So sad.
</post>
<post author="usycool1" datetime="2011-07-12T23:53:00" id="p26">
<quote orig_author="fire2burn">
Yes when some local chavs decided to burgle my house when I popped out to visit the shop, they kicked the door in and made off with my laptop. Thankfully them having an IQ between them roughly equivelent to a walnut meant that they fled the scene to hide in an alleyway only 7 doors down <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/> Where they were promptly apprehended by the police with my possessions still in their hands.

The funniest part is that the CPS then decided there was not enough evidence to prosecute them, even the officer in charge of my case facepalmed at that. He must've thought what's the point in doing this job if the culprits get off scot free. Ah well at least I got my laptop back.

</quote>

Yeah, once a guy broke into my friends dads car and stole a football t-shirt and something else (I can't remeber what it was). The people were caught and my friends dad got his stuff back but the CPS decided that there was not enough evidence to prosecute so the thieves were let off unfortunately.
</post>
<post author="trojan10_om" datetime="2011-07-12T23:53:00" id="p27">
Had a car crash in the outside lane of the M25, called the police and fire service.

Someone has called an ambulance for me when I broke my leg, 2 ambulances turned up.

Last month I fell asleep with my phone in my bed, and on an Iphone the emergency call button is far too easy to press. So as I nodded off, I must have rolled onto my phone an dialed them. I woke, firstly very dozy. But suddenly in the biggest panic ever. I thought I was dreaming when I heard this seemingly distant voice repeating "what is your name, are you hurt etc". You wouldnt believe how worrying that feels. When I woke up and realised what happened I mumbled something back in apology, and their response was quite unimpressed. In fact I was on the line for over 3 mins.
</post>
<post author="fend1" datetime="2011-07-13T01:19:00" id="p28">
Nope. Ambulance and fire brigade a few times though which is never fun <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/> Had the police round a few times when family have done stupid things with the phone (if there are two 999 calls within half an hour from a landline, even if nothing is said, the police trace your landline and come round to your house to see whats up...)
</post>
<post author="Darkphilosopher" datetime="2011-07-13T10:11:00" id="p29">
My grandparents house got broke into a while ago when my family was there. When we went down and caught the guy, he said he had a crush on my aunt and had come to see her (yeh.. after breaking in through the door at 1am in the night while she happened to be away on holiday <img src="images/smilies/colonhash.gif"/> ).
The police came very quickly and within just a couple of hours we were all back to bed <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>
</post>
<post author="madders94" datetime="2011-07-13T10:20:00" id="p30">
When I was in a car accident.
</post>
<post author="Tuniar" datetime="2011-07-13T17:03:00" id="p31">
No. My mummy called an ambulance for me once because I came home really drunk when I was home from uni, and I passed out and broke my nose on the way down. Ambulances are fun.
</post>
<post author="usycool1" datetime="2011-07-13T17:07:00" id="p32">
Ok because there are so many ambulance/firebrigade posts too, I'll change the title to "Have you ever had to dial 999?"
</post>
<post author="usycool1" datetime="2011-07-13T20:31:00" id="p33">
<quote orig_author="MutantGecko">
when i was about 7 i called 999 wondering what would happen, then i got scared and hung up. about 30 mins later a police man turned up and i was just like, it wasnt me bro.

</quote>

Lol once when I was little, me and my brother were arguing about whether the number is 999 or 911 (we were very young at the time). I kept saying to my brother that it was 999. My brother didn't believe me so I was like I'll prove it to you. I then dialled 999 just to prove it to him and a few minutes later, the police turned up lol.
</post>
<post author="HJV" datetime="2011-07-13T20:34:00" id="p34">
Three times.

First time was when I was working at a supermarket and some old woman just randomly fell over and passed out, I called her an ambulance.

The second time was when I was leading a uni society, organised a big party, and someone smoked weed + drank too much so she stopped breathing normally, I called her an ambulance.

Third time was during the last Royal Wedding park party when an acquaintance of mine passed out from drinking too much vodka at the same time as a big riot started. I had a fun time trying to get her medical help when there were riot police all over the place. This time I didn't actually phone them, but found a police officer instead.
</post>
<post author="JordieJ" datetime="2011-07-13T20:41:00" id="p35">
When my phone is locked there is still an option for an emergency call. I sometimes take my phone out my pocket to see I've accidentally phoned 999 and quickly hung up :s
</post>
<post author="Phobia27" datetime="2011-07-13T20:42:00" id="p36">
<quote orig_author="HJV">
Three times.

First time was when I was working at a supermarket and some old woman just randomly fell over and passed out, I called her an ambulance.

The second time was when I was leading a uni society, organised a big party, and someone smoked weed + drank too much so she stopped breathing normally, I called her an ambulance.

</quote>

Why would you call them both an ambulance? That's not very nice.

<img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/ahee.gif" alt=":ahee:"/>
</post>
<post author="DYKWIA" datetime="2011-07-13T20:43:00" id="p37">
I witnessed a car crash a few months back and had to dial 911. I was put on hold lol. Admittedly I got an answer within a minute, which isn't bad going.
</post>
<post author="Aphotic Cosmos" datetime="2011-07-13T20:44:00" id="p38">
Nope.

Even when I got assaulted at the bus stop in sixth form, even though I was knocked cold for a few minutes (and nobody helped despite being on a main A-road in to town and right outside of school... thanks, people of Trashford) I just got on the bus and went home. I was too much in shock to remember to call the number. Went to the police a couple of days later.

I carry my Swiss knife with me everywhere now. Not that I could actually do anything with it. <img src="images/smilies/tongue.png"/>
</post>
<post author="Looose" datetime="2011-07-13T20:44:00" id="p39">
I had to call an ambulance when my brother was about 2, he was choking and had a sweet stuck in his throat. One of the most terrifying things i've ever been through :|
</post>
<post author="Martyn*" datetime="2011-07-13T20:46:00" id="p40">
I was attacked in Liverpool by four hoodies (foreigners, possibly Jamaican) one Saturday night in 2006. In retaliation I ripped one of the hoodie's coat. As the police turned up, I got cautioned for ripping the guy's coat. The guy who actually attacked me was allowed to walk-off scott-free.

In 2007 in Liverpool I confronted a hate preacher with my own banner which stated that Christianity is an immoral religion which has caused great suffering for humanity. I got arrested for incitement to religious hatred and the guy telling everyone they're going to hell was simply moved on further up the street - allowed to preach more of his hate.

After 2007 my view on the police drastically altered.
</post>
<post author="Cicerao" datetime="2011-07-13T20:58:00" id="p41">
<quote orig_author="PonchoKid">
twice in my first year of uni. first time the security man phoned them, and the police asked us questions about a missing flat mate.

second we found a suicide note outside our flat, so called them.

and then another time we got worken up by the police banging on a flat mates door as she was missing, we had no idea until we were woken up, wasnt amused really.

</quote>

Which halls are you in? They sound well dodgy. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/beard.gif" alt=":beard:"/>
</post>
<post author="defuzion" datetime="2011-07-13T21:00:00" id="p42">
As a kid I called the police and hung up and they came to my doorstep, lol
</post>
<post author="Jez RR" datetime="2011-07-13T21:17:00" id="p43">
Three times now. Ambulance after a car knocked a guy off his bike. Police after seeing an armed robbery in a KFC. And the Coastguard after seeing a bunch of distress flares going up from a small boat (turned out to be an RNLI exercise).
</post>
<post author="daisydaffodil" datetime="2011-07-13T21:22:00" id="p44">
I've called an ambulance - or been in one - for my mum 50+ times I think, I lose count. Off the top of my head, about 12 of those times have been in the last year - I've been in an ambulance, or phoned one, 3 times since June. Know all the paramedics and A&amp;E staff very well now! My mum's been in Redditch Hospital, Aberdeen Royal Infirmary/Wolmanhill/Sick Childrens/Woodend/Mental Health/Dental School (old and new), Queen Elisabeth (Gateshead), Ninewells (Dundee), Inverness, Nairn, Perth, Peterhead, Dunbar, Thurso, Dingwall, Huntly, Heathrow Terminal One Medical Centre and once a hospital in Germany - she should hold a record really <img src="images/smilies/biggrin.png"/>

Been in one three times for myself too - once the doctor called 999 when I was 4, they couldn't bring my fever down and I was rushed in, once because I broke my leg and had to be transferred from one hospital to another as the first couldn't plaster my leg, and once because I was nearly suffocated under a bouncy castle.

Calling is always very entertaining, people are always surprised at how relaxed I am. Had a paramedic out last week who was dealing with my mum, asked how long she has been ill and I replied since I was born, she turned round and said "Yes, I was confused as to why you're so calm!" They always ask so many questions as well.

I've never, touch wood, had to ask for the police or anyone else though, thank God.
</post>
<post author="PonchoKid" datetime="2011-07-14T12:27:00" id="p45">
<quote orig_author="Cicerao">
Which halls are you in? They sound well dodgy. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/beard.gif" alt=":beard:"/>

</quote>

they didnt go missing missing.
the first girl we hadnt seen for 24 hours after a night out, and she wasnt replying to texts or answering the phone, so the uni phoned the police.

the suicide note was from a flat mates ex. he was later found alive.

and the second missing girl was because she hadnt texted her parents to say she was back at uni. so at 8 in the morning we had people banging on her door and what not...

nothing serious serious.

in 1 week we had the cops up like 4 times, 2 related to our flat. it was all fun and games [=
</post>
<post author="OceanInTheSky" datetime="2011-07-14T12:31:00" id="p46">
Only when I was quite young, for a laugh. Turned out not to be funny cos I got quite told off.
</post>
<post author="Etoile" datetime="2011-07-14T12:32:00" id="p47">
Not personally but I have had an ambulance called on my behalf! Bad times...
Never called the fire service/police though.
</post>
<post author="Gofre" datetime="2011-07-14T12:34:00" id="p48">
I had to call an ambulance when my dad collapsed (ended up being severe food poisoning), but being the "sensible" 7 year old that I was, I called my mum first <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Zionic" datetime="2011-07-14T12:34:00" id="p49">
Yes. I was on a crowded bus and this lady got on the bus, tripped and cut her knee open on a vein causing blood loss. There was quite a bit of blood.

A girl in my college who knew first aid looked after her, and the bus driver asked someone to phone for an ambulance. I looked round the bus only to see people just sitting there pretending nothing happened. Adults, teenagers, elderly people, sitting there without a care in the world.

I got my phone out, phoned 999 without a clue in what I had to say, or the road we were on or anything. And despite the ambulance depot being less than a mile away, it took 40 minutes for one to arrive.

The lady recovered and I felt good that I phoned 999, but what annoyed me, and infact disgusted me, was that people just did sod all and left it to 2 teenagers to look after this poor lady.
</post>
<post author="Etoile" datetime="2011-07-14T12:36:00" id="p50">
<quote orig_author="daisydaffodil">
I've called an ambulance - or been in one - for my mum 50+ times I think, I lose count. Off the top of my head, about 12 of those times have been in the last year - I've been in an ambulance, or phoned one, 3 times since June. Know all the paramedics and A&amp;amp;E staff very well now! My mum's been in Redditch Hospital, Aberdeen Royal Infirmary/Wolmanhill/Sick Childrens/Woodend/Mental Health/Dental School (old and new), Queen Elisabeth (Gateshead), Ninewells (Dundee), Inverness, Nairn, Perth, Peterhead, Dunbar, Thurso, Dingwall, Huntly, Heathrow Terminal One Medical Centre and once a hospital in Germany - she should hold a record really <img src="images/smilies/biggrin.png"/>

Been in one three times for myself too - once the doctor called 999 when I was 4, they couldn't bring my fever down and I was rushed in, once because I broke my leg and had to be transferred from one hospital to another as the first couldn't plaster my leg, and once because I was nearly suffocated under a bouncy castle.

Calling is always very entertaining, people are always surprised at how relaxed I am. Had a paramedic out last week who was dealing with my mum, asked how long she has been ill and I replied since I was born, she turned round and said &amp;quot;Yes, I was confused as to why you're so calm!&amp;quot; They always ask so many questions as well.

I've never, touch wood, had to ask for the police or anyone else though, thank God.

</quote>

Damn, I thought I was holding the record with North Hants, Southampton General, Addenbrookes and Royal Cornwall Treliske :P
I hope your mum gets better (if it's possible?)!
</post>
<post author="TheTidders" datetime="2011-07-14T12:37:00" id="p51">
I phoned for an ambulance when my dad collapsed :'(

I was home alone with him and I was playing TF2 (as you do). I heard him shout my name and I just replied "coming", as I assumed he was just calling me down for lunch or something. He then called me a couple more imes and I came out to see him on the floor.

I still feel really guilty for ignoring him at first <img src="images/smilies/frown.png"/>

He's fine now though <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>
</post>
<post author="BenjyK" datetime="2011-07-14T12:41:00" id="p52">
Twice., though both times for an ambulance. Once when my little brother was having a seizure and foaming at the mouth, and another when I found my elderly neighbour half dead bleeding out of a head wound after falling down the stairs.

Scary ish lol
</post>
<post author="OLawyer" datetime="2011-07-14T12:43:00" id="p53">
In November 2010, in my times of boredom, studying law, on a short 10 minute break, I decided to call a random UK mobile number which I made up. Basically a prank call, having never done one.. So the person answers and I say I'm the police, the person says no ur not (i put on a really shy voice). 2 months later I receive a phone call, barred so I cant see the number. "Seargent Wendy" from th epolice station where I live, claims to have tapped phone evidence of me impersonating a police officer, which I didn't exactly do- i just said it was the police when it was obvious I was making a joke. This seargent Wendy then asks for all my personal details, uni I go to, my phone number, my address, my full name, year of birth. She then says the police are going to come over to my flat to interrogate me, and also adds that they are going to discuss this "criminal" matter with my university.
As a result I freaked out for the next 48 hours, didn't eat, drink, see friends, just stayed locked in my room imagining I would be expelled from uni and that my life would basically be over. I rang my personal tutor to warn him about this.
Turns out, I think, it was a prank call, probably from the person I'd originally called. There is indeed a Seargent Wendy in th epolice office where I live, I called the police station and they said Wendy was off the day i supposedly got the call from her... Besides, when do the police ever call you on your mobile phone.
Worst 48 hours of my life. ps: the fact the person making the prank has got and asked for all my personal details, isn't that going too far?
</post>
<post author="Jez RR" datetime="2011-07-14T12:44:00" id="p54">
<quote orig_author="OLawyer">
In November 2010, in my times of boredom, studying law, on a short 10 minute break, I decided to call a random UK mobile number which I made up. Basically a prank call, having never done one.. So the person answers and I say I'm the police, the person says no ur not (i put on a really shy voice). 2 months later I receive a phone call, barred so I cant see the number. "Seargent Wendy" from th epolice station where I live, claims to have tapped phone evidence of me impersonating a police officer, which I didn't exactly do- i just said it was the police when it was obvious I was making a joke. This seargent Wendy then asks for all my personal details, uni I go to, my phone number, my address, my full name, year of birth. She then says the police are going to come over to my flat to interrogate me, and also adds that they are going to discuss this "criminal" matter with my university.
As a result I freaked out for the next 48 hours, didn't eat, drink, see friends, just stayed locked in my room imagining I would be expelled from uni and that my life would basically be over. I rang my personal tutor to warn him about this.
Turns out, I think, it was a prank call, probably from the person I'd originally called. There is indeed a Seargent Wendy in th epolice office where I live, I called the police station and they said Wendy was off the day i supposedly got the call from her... Besides, when do the police ever call you on your mobile phone.
Worst 48 hours of my life. ps: the fact the person making the prank has got and asked for all my personal details, isn't that going too far?

</quote>

LOL - there's karma for you <img src="images/smilies/biggrin.png"/>
</post>
<post author="Torrchy" datetime="2011-07-14T12:46:00" id="p55">
nope, only had an ambulance phoned for me when I collapsed on a beam years ago (gymnastics).
</post>
<post author="e hine e" datetime="2011-07-14T12:50:00" id="p56">
Twice.

Once when our oven started smoking (a wire had apparently burnt through the wood it was standing on in the built in kitchen) so there was a little fire forming underneath it.

The second time when my sister fell unconscious at my sister's house 10 miles away. My sister rang me and asked whether she usually did that when she had a reaction to dogs, I said no and she should call an ambulance. She didn't think it was that serious, she thought she just wasn't talking because she was in a bad mood (despite her lips being swollen like balloons) as a result I had to call the ambulance and had the most confusing conversation ever with them having to explain why I was at a different address to the casualty.
</post>
<post author="Annie72" datetime="2011-07-14T12:55:00" id="p57">
I've had to phone 999 a few times

When my husband smashed his hand through a glass panel in a door ( ambulance)
When we were burgled a few years ago(police)
When I witnessed a mugging last week (police)
When my eldest son broke his elbow ( ambulance)

There may be more times, but these are just off the top of my head.
</post>
<post author="RainbowDoll" datetime="2011-07-14T14:53:00" id="p58">
I used to work in ambulance control so I have heard lots of very interesting calls, it will shock you what some people call for!
I have only ever had to ring the police myself, when a friend was attacked by a stranger.
</post>
<post author="hashman90" datetime="2011-07-14T14:59:00" id="p59">
two years ago when my house got burgled
last year when my friend got stabbed outside a club
</post>
<post author="mmmpie" datetime="2011-07-14T15:05:00" id="p60">
Twice in one night the other week. A guy had drunk too much and was alternately vomiting and passing out.

Once when I got mugged.

Once when my neighbours hedge caught fire when he was on holiday.

And once when I saw a car crash.

I think that's all of them...
</post>
<post author="D95" datetime="2011-07-14T15:05:00" id="p61">
I got an unplugged phone when I was about 3 and plugged it in to call 999. I hung up straight away then they called my mum back and asked if everything was alright.

Apparently I wasn't the only one
</post>
<post author="colmrs" datetime="2011-07-14T15:42:00" id="p62">
Once a few weeks ago whilst walking the dog saw a fire and went to go and stamp it out, but then I heard noises so I left and called the experts <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/> though i did tell them it was no hurry they came with full on blues and twos <img src="images/smilies/tongue.png"/>
</post>
<post author="Harpoon" datetime="2011-07-14T16:01:00" id="p63">
Once, an accident between a bus and a car had happened just as we came onto the road so I called for an Ambulance and was told that a few people had already rang in about it. I'm glad I did though, at least I knew that one was on the way.
</post>
</doc>
