<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-199-193201-6635179">
<headline>
man calls 911 to save him from police!
</headline>
<post author="justretta" datetime="2007-07-17T00:17:00" id="p1">
A 38-year-old man was arrested after he called 911 and told a dispatcher he was surrounded by police officers and needed help, authorities said.

Police officers met Dana Farrell Shelton after being called to investigate a disturbance at a bar on Sunday but had found no problems and told him to move along.

Shelton, who officers said appeared intoxicated, then called 911 to report he was "surrounded by Largo police," according to an arrest affidavit.

"Our officers were standing there scratching their heads. He called, standing there in their presence," Largo Sgt. Melanie Holley said. "It's one of our 'truth is stranger than fiction' cases."

Shelton was charged with misdemeanor misuse of 911. The charge carries maximum penalties of one year in jail and $1,000 in fines.
</post>
<post author="justretta" datetime="2007-07-17T12:15:00" id="p2">
If you ask me, this guy is definately not that bright.... or maybe just really drunk... I'm leaning more towards not very bright.
</post>
<post author="Chai" datetime="2007-07-17T12:38:00" id="p3">
So did he get help?
</post>
<post author="justretta" datetime="2007-07-17T13:29:00" id="p4">
He didn't need help... he was drunk and called 911 to tell them the cops were after him. So he got charged fines for calling 911 for no reason...
</post>
<post author="Francis" datetime="2007-07-17T13:32:00" id="p5">
Moral of this story: The more police around, the less you feel safe...
</post>
<post author="TTH" datetime="2007-07-17T13:34:00" id="p6">
justretta
That is too funny. <img src="http://cdn2.able2know.org/images/v5/emoticons/icon_lol.gif" alt="Laughing"/> <img src="http://cdn2.able2know.org/images/v5/emoticons/icon_lol.gif" alt="Laughing"/>
</post>
<post author="justretta" datetime="2007-07-17T13:35:00" id="p7">
At least in his case....
</post>
<post author="TTH" datetime="2007-07-17T13:45:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="justretta">
At least in his case....
</quote>
Well, he should know better. Calling 911 is not a toy and you don't play games to call them.

Where I live some reasons people have called 911:
1) To ask what time it is.
2) To ask what temperature a certain meat needs to be cooked at
3) To ask what time a football game starts
4) To hang up on the call receiver as a joke- this automatically creates a "call" for a cop to go investigate

When people do this, it isn't funny.
</post>
<post author="Chai" datetime="2007-07-17T13:49:00" id="p9">
<quote orig_author="justretta">
He didn't need help... he was drunk and called 911 to tell them the cops were after him. So he got charged fines for calling 911 for no reason...
</quote>

What do you mean he didn't need help?

There were all these policemen around him and apparantly they wouldn't let him leave.

I would have felt like I need help.
</post>
<post author="justretta" datetime="2007-07-17T13:52:00" id="p10">
TTH~ yeah those are definately NOT reasons to call 911... it's meant for emergencies and this guy didn't have an emergency either.

Chai~ He didn't need help from the police officers.. the cops were called because of him, and all they did was tell him to move along and he then proceeded to call 911. He was drunk and obviously not thinking clearly.
</post>
<post author="Chai" datetime="2007-07-17T13:58:00" id="p11">
Of course the police were called! He needed help.

jesus....try to stay on top of this willya?
</post>
<post author="justretta" datetime="2007-07-17T14:01:00" id="p12">
ohh goodness. I think the cops were called because HE was causing problems and they weren't going to arrest him, just told him to move along... and for some reason he felt the need to call 911 himself.. I think I'm starting to get confused myself! <img src="http://cdn2.able2know.org/images/v5/emoticons/icon_smile.gif" alt="Smile"/>
</post>
<post author="Chai" datetime="2007-07-17T14:15:00" id="p13">
I notice from your profile you're from Villisca Iowa.

Is that by any chance the same place the Villisca Ax Murders took place in 1912?

I'll bet those people which they had called 911. They really needed help.
</post>
<post author="Francis" datetime="2007-07-17T14:19:00" id="p14">
Yes, I think they would have wished to call the 911, which was the good thing to do.
</post>
<post author="justretta" datetime="2007-07-17T14:19:00" id="p15">
Yes, I am from Villisca and it is indeed the town where the tragic axe murder happend. Even if there was a chance for them to call 911, I don't think they could have that night. <img src="http://cdn2.able2know.org/images/v5/emoticons/icon_sad.gif" alt="Sad"/> Very tragic story.
</post>
<post author="Chai" datetime="2007-07-17T14:29:00" id="p16">
<quote orig_author="Francis">
Yes, I think they would have wished to call the 911, which was the good thing to do.
</quote>

Well, I'm glad we're on the same page with that.

Horrible tragedy,

Francis, did you know there is absolutley NO public transportation in Vallisca?

It's true. Not a bus, gondola or segway.
Taxi drivers probably won't come over from Red Oak or Atlantic unless they were going that way anyway. Plus, taxi drivers tend to be wary of towns with ax murderers.

I can't imagine how dreary life must be there.
</post>
<post author="justretta" datetime="2007-07-17T14:32:00" id="p17">
Yes, it is true... no public transportation.... it's pretty boring in this town. Not very exciting from my point of view, although, it might be because I don't really know anybody here.
</post>
</doc>
