<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-200-192448-6196046">
<headline>
Eddie Izzard as an MP/MEP?
</headline>
<post author="seanyboy501" datetime="2009-09-20T00:59:00" id="p1">
I've heard a few times that Eddie Izzard one day will try and take up public office.

What are your thoughts on this?

I personally think he can achieve alot, having a great skill in reaching out to people.

Discuss
</post>
<post author="Prudy" datetime="2009-09-20T01:01:00" id="p2">
<quote orig_author="seanyboy501">
Originally Posted by seanyboy501
I've heard a few times that Eddie Izzard one day will try and take up public office.

What are your thoughts on this?

I personally think he can achieve alot, having a great skill in reaching out to people.

Discuss

</quote>

Good luck to any member of the public wanting to go for elected office, although I can;t get any more excited that he's doing it, than anyone else. Probably best to wait until he chooses an allegiance before we judge him.
</post>
<post author="adamrules247" datetime="2009-09-20T01:04:00" id="p3">
In the words of Mrs Thatcher "No, no, no!"
</post>
<post author="seanyboy501" datetime="2009-09-20T01:04:00" id="p4">
<quote orig_author="Prudy">
Originally Posted by Prudy
Good luck to any member of the public wanting to go for elected office, although I can;t get any more excited that he's doing it, than anyone else. Probably best to wait until he chooses an allegiance before we judge him.

</quote>

Obviously things could of changed by the time he does decide...

but he has already done a Labour Euro Election broadcast.
</post>
<post author="Roquentin" datetime="2009-09-20T01:06:00" id="p5">
"Please vote for me, I'm...er.. covered in beeeeeeees"
</post>
<post author="Prudy" datetime="2009-09-20T01:06:00" id="p6">
<quote orig_author="seanyboy501">
Originally Posted by seanyboy501
Obviously things could of changed by the time he does decide...

but he has already done a Labour Euro Election broadcast.

</quote>

We can only speculate but that may be more to do with his pro EU stance as opposed to an affinity with Labour, although he has donated money to the party. Still, he may become an independant.
</post>
<post author="seanyboy501" datetime="2009-09-20T01:08:00" id="p7">
<quote orig_author="Prudy">
Originally Posted by Prudy
We can only speculate but that may be more to do with his pro EU stance as opposed to an affinity with Labour, although he has donated money to the party. Still, he may become an independant.

</quote>

hmmm yes independent would probably work.

However, everytime I read/listen to his aspirations and what he wants to do.. I reckon he'll end up in a group game.

anyways heres a link if anyone wants it

<a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture/2009/sep/16/eddie-izzard-charity-marathon-mp">http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture/20...ty-marathon-mp</a>
</post>
<post author="Mitothy" datetime="2009-09-20T01:09:00" id="p8">
He seems very intelligent and open minded even in his stand up material. He's also had a very normal life before becoming succesfull in stand up and as such I think he'd be a good voice in politics.
</post>
<post author="Ice_Queen" datetime="2009-09-20T01:09:00" id="p9">
What, is he going to offer us cake or death at the poll station?

I'm good with it.
</post>
<post author="Hylean" datetime="2009-09-20T01:18:00" id="p10">
He's also said he wants to do it within the next 10 to 15 years, so that's a long time for the political landscape to change and for his opinions to change.
</post>
<post author="Psyk" datetime="2009-09-20T13:35:00" id="p11">
I'd probably vote for him. Not just because I like his comedy, but I also agree with him on a lot of his political opinions.
</post>
<post author="duke5" datetime="2009-09-22T21:42:00" id="p12">
Eddie Izzard, like Ricky Gervais, Peter Kay and so on, is a comedian.

Occasionally, those talented enough to entertain us can often deem themselves suitable for politics because RELATIVE to their field, they consider themselves to be intelligent.

Eddie Izzard is a smart chap, but he hasn't got the first clue about the body politic, and has dedicated his life to comedy. What divine intervention makes such people decide that after all these years of success in an industry like music, art, comedy, think they can then govern the country?

Izzard, like Gervais, Clarkson, etc would fail at being a politician because they have never invested the time to take it seriously. Only in mock.
</post>
<post author="Psyk" datetime="2009-09-22T22:21:00" id="p13">
Eddie Izzard has been somewhat active in politics for a while. Anyway, who says entertainers can't make good politicians? Look at the governer of California. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/p.gif" alt=":p:"/>
</post>
<post author="Henry JW" datetime="2009-09-23T05:48:00" id="p14">
I don't think this is a good idea. If I was a Labour Party activist, gradually weaseling my way into the higher echelons of power over many years, only to find Eddie Izzard has nicked in ahead of me to be selected as a candidate for the European Parliament, well I'd be pretty pissed off. If Izzard is selected it would send out the wrong message to people who want to go into politics. Izzard may have donated some money here and there and showed up in a broadcast, but he's hardly dedicated himself to the cause.
</post>
<post author="Lucible" datetime="2009-09-24T14:33:00" id="p15">
If Eddie Izzard did go for public office I'd be worried that people were voting for him because he's a comedic legend than a person fit for helping govern the country. I'm skeptical if I'm honest. Its important people reason why MPs are there (yes I know its easy to forget) - to be an active part in parliament not to entertain us with witty remarks on Question Time.
I like him though and if he came up with substance, I'd be in favour but only if he went through the official routes to power.
</post>
<post author="Kickflip" datetime="2009-09-25T19:49:00" id="p16">
He can't decide whether he's a man or a woman, I don't want him making decisions that effect me. Why is being on telly a passport to everything? It's moronic.
</post>
<post author="CyclopsRock" datetime="2009-09-26T11:47:00" id="p17">
<quote orig_author="duke5">
Originally Posted by duke5
Izzard, like Gervais, Clarkson, etc would fail at being a politician because they have never invested the time to take it seriously. Only in mock.

</quote>

I think you're putting Gervais in slightly unreasonable company there. Clarkson rants - say what you will about his stand up material, but Gervais did do Philosophy at UCL, so whilst he may not be too versed in the practicalities of politics, I daresay he's quite familiar with the theories behind people's stances.
</post>
<post author="duke5" datetime="2009-09-26T15:11:00" id="p18">
<quote orig_author="CyclopsRock">
Originally Posted by CyclopsRock
I think you're putting Gervais in slightly unreasonable company there. Clarkson rants - say what you will about his stand up material, but Gervais did do Philosophy at UCL, so whilst he may not be too versed in the practicalities of politics, I daresay he's quite familiar with the theories behind people's stances.

</quote>

He's an actor who happens to be a graduate. Anyone can be a graduate. Just because he's got some degree in philosophy.
</post>
<post author="Mr_K_Dilkington" datetime="2009-09-26T18:12:00" id="p19">
<quote orig_author="CyclopsRock">
Originally Posted by CyclopsRock
I think you're putting Gervais in slightly unreasonable company there. Clarkson rants - say what you will about his stand up material, but Gervais did do Philosophy at UCL, so whilst he may not be too versed in the practicalities of politics, I daresay he's quite familiar with the theories behind people's stances.

</quote>

He only got a 2.2 in philosophy and I really don't think he does have a good grasp of the politics and theories behind peoples stances. Take this from a huge Ricky Gervais fan who has spent probably thousands of hours listening to his podcasts and radio shows. He is a very bright bloke, but I don't think his grasp of politics is all that great.
</post>
<post author="duke5" datetime="2009-09-26T20:55:00" id="p20">
<quote orig_author="Jay Riall">
Originally Posted by Jay Riall
He only got a 2.2 in philosophy and I really don't think he does have a good grasp of the politics and theories behind peoples stances. Take this from a huge Ricky Gervais fan who has spent probably thousands of hours listening to his podcasts and radio shows. He is a very bright bloke, but I don't think his grasp of politics is all that great.

</quote>

Agreed. He's a funny fat bloke but wisdom doesn't stop at Gervais like a lot of his fans think.

Has he got the political intellect of Vince Cable? John Redwood? No of course he hasn't, he's intellectual to his target audience.
</post>
<post author="Geritak" datetime="2009-09-26T21:42:00" id="p21">
<quote orig_author="Kickflip">
Originally Posted by Kickflip
He can't decide whether he's a man or a woman, I don't want him making decisions that effect me. Why is being on telly a passport to everything? It's moronic.

</quote>

Fair enough about TV giving you a leg-up, but why does his being an open transvestite have any effect on his politics? <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/> I wouldn't vote for him just because he's Eddie Izzard, but I wouldn't discount him if he had policies that were worth voting for, as others have said.

By the way, I watched the video in your sig. I wasn't scared. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/p.gif" alt=":p:"/>
</post>
</doc>
