<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-201-185520-350589">
<headline>
Glenn Grothman says I'm an abused child.
</headline>
<post author="jj" datetime="2012-03-03T09:06:00" id="p1">
<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/03/02/glenn-grothman-wisconsin-law-single-parenthood-child-abuse_n_1316834.html">http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/0...n_1316834.html</a>

Mr. Grothman, may now get a TV crew, proceed to Mineral Ridge, Ohio, find Kerr Cemetary, find my mom's grave, get down on your knees in the mud, and apologize to her.

Then you can stroll around that cemetary, and do the same thing to hundreds more of women's graves, most of them (not my mom, I'm not that old) WW2 widows who raised successful families that only felt the abuse of being poor, and that because women only got about 60 cents on the dollar for their work those days.

Then you can drive down Salt Springs road, up Main Street, and Town Line road to the Welsh Cemetary, and do the same thing.

Then you can do this all over the USA, Mr. Grothman.

Your insult to women should never be forgiven.

Yes, I know your bill refers to "unmarried" mothers. People whose husbands are dead are not married, Mr. Grothman.
</post>
<post author="Professor Yaffle" datetime="2012-03-03T09:09:00" id="p2">
I guess I am abusing my children too.
</post>
<post author="LibraryLady" datetime="2012-03-03T09:16:00" id="p3">
And I guess my brother who raised his children as a single parent would also be classified as abusive. Don't forget single fathers.
</post>
<post author="Redtail" datetime="2012-03-03T09:24:00" id="p4">
Oh dear, I know several abusive parents!

Clarence was killed in Iraq so Michael, Nancy, &amp; Chris are being abused by Tina.

Michelle was killed by a drunk driver so Keenan is Abusing Jeff.

There are more but I guess the saddest would be Evette because her abuse was a choice. See, she left Don... all he did was hit her a few times, &amp; choke her, so she left him. Poor Oshua.
</post>
<post author="bookitty" datetime="2012-03-03T09:31:00" id="p5">
The bill reads in part:

<quote>
In promoting those campaigns and materials, the board shall emphasize nonmarital parenthood as a contributing factor to child abuse and neglect.

</quote>
Basically Mr Grothman would really like to see his opinion plastered on billboards. I empathize with this position (Wouldn't we all like to trumpet our various pet theories to the entire populace?) but wonder if Wisconsin's budget is sound enough to afford this vile vanity project.
</post>
<post author="BStrong" datetime="2012-03-03T09:36:00" id="p6">
I guess they grow 'em stupid in Wisconsin.
</post>
<post author="MG1962" datetime="2012-03-03T09:40:00" id="p7">
In my local town a young girl will be considered to be living in an abusive relationship after her father was arrested and jailed for using her as a sex slave since the age of 11 <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/frown.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="jj" datetime="2012-03-03T09:44:00" id="p8">
<quote orig_author="MG1962">
In my local town a young girl will be considered to be living in an abusive relationship after her father was arrested and jailed for using her as a sex slave since the age of 11 <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/frown.gif"/>

</quote>
Is there a point to that? Does this excuse Grothman's tarring every war widow with kids as an abusive parent?
</post>
<post author="LibraryLady" datetime="2012-03-03T09:47:00" id="p9">
No, no, I think he's referring to the fact that she is now living alone with her mother--who is now a single parent.
</post>
<post author="jj" datetime="2012-03-03T09:52:00" id="p10">
<quote orig_author="LibraryLady">
No, no, I think he's referring to the fact that she is now living alone with her mother--who is now a single parent.

</quote>
If that's what he meant, then I apologize for misunderstanding.
</post>
<post author="crimresearch" datetime="2012-03-03T09:53:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="jj">
Is there a point to that? Does this excuse Grothman's tarring every war widow with kids as an abusive parent?

</quote>
The point is that this idiotic bill would paint everyone with the same circumstantial brush, including real victims.
</post>
<post author="jj" datetime="2012-03-03T10:07:00" id="p12">
<quote orig_author="crimresearch">
The point is that this idiotic bill would paint everyone with the same circumstantial brush, including real victims.

</quote>
Another good point. I'm sorry, that wasn't clear to me. Perhaps because I'm still seeing red from the initial insinuation on the part of the moronic legislator. (Hope he's not a member here.)
</post>
<post author="fuelair" datetime="2012-03-03T10:07:00" id="p13">
<quote orig_author="jj">
Is there a point to that? Does this excuse Grothman's tarring every war widow with kids as an abusive parent?

</quote>
No, it's a reminder that all sorts of bad things happen and there is always some anal orifice around to blame the victim. That's why my preference of ways to handle the perps and/or the malicious accuserers(not of my origination, but I have always loved that phrase).
</post>
<post author="jj" datetime="2012-03-03T10:09:00" id="p14">
<quote orig_author="fuelair">
No, it's a reminder that all sorts of bad things happen and there is always some anal orifice around to blame the victim. That's why my preference of ways to handle the perps and/or the malicious accuserers(not of my origination, but I have always loved that phrase).

</quote>
Let's let Magz answer for himself, not that I'm particularly disagreeing with you, which stands as a separate point I certainly have had past experience with.
</post>
<post author="MG1962" datetime="2012-03-03T10:10:00" id="p15">
<quote orig_author="jj">
If that's what he meant, then I apologize for misunderstanding.

</quote>
Thats okay <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/smile.gif"/> I was suggesting to Mr Grotham that the classic family unit is fraught with as many opportunities to create abusive environments as any other combination of parenting he might care to attempt to legislate against.

In some studies its been suggested that there could be as high as 15 -20% sexual abuse rates in classic households. Then we factor in general physical or mental abuse and I would suggest we are approaching extraordinary levels of dysfunctional parenting
</post>
<post author="jj" datetime="2012-03-03T10:17:00" id="p16">
<quote orig_author="MG1962">
Thats okay <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/smile.gif"/> I was suggesting to Mr Grotham that the classic family unit is fraught with as many opportunities to create abusive environments as any other combination of parenting he might care to attempt to legislate against.

In some studies its been suggested that there could be as high as 15 -20% sexual abuse rates in classic households. Then we factor in general physical or mental abuse and I would suggest we are approaching extraordinary levels of dysfunctional parenting

</quote>
Ah, ok. This I understand, although I wonder about overstatement on the part of some of the studies.

In any case, it very much reads on Grothman's imbicility.
</post>
<post author="MG1962" datetime="2012-03-03T10:37:00" id="p17">
<quote orig_author="jj">
Ah, ok. This I understand, although I wonder about overstatement on the part of some of the studies.

In any case, it very much reads on Grothman's imbicility.

</quote>
When I followed the wiki notes, even the people who produced those numbers expressed concerns they might be overstated
</post>
<post author="Elizabeth I" datetime="2012-03-03T10:40:00" id="p18">
Wow, I became an abused child at the age of eight when my mother divorced my alcoholic father. Who knew?
</post>
<post author="Firestone" datetime="2012-03-03T10:43:00" id="p19">
<quote orig_author="jj">
Let's let Magz answer for himself, not that I'm particularly disagreeing with you, which stands as a separate point I certainly have had past experience with.

</quote>
MG1962 (not Magz, a really really different kind of guy).
</post>
<post author="jj" datetime="2012-03-03T10:44:00" id="p20">
<quote orig_author="MG1962">
When I followed the wiki notes, even the people who produced those numbers expressed concerns they might be overstated

</quote>
Fair enough. If it's 1/5th of that, Grossman still looks like a (Rule_10_Obeyed).
</post>
<post author="jj" datetime="2012-03-03T10:47:00" id="p21">
<quote orig_author="Firestone">
MG1962 (not Magz, a really really different kind of guy).

</quote>
Eeeep. Yeah. Dyslexics of the world untie! Sorry.
</post>
<post author="ravdin" datetime="2012-03-03T10:51:00" id="p22">
I'm also a "victim" of single parenthood as my mother was suddenly widowed at the age of 33. She never remarried and to this day I'm not quite sure how she held it all together.

I'd be very happy to see this clown voted out of office and never again entrusted with a position of public responsibility.
</post>
<post author="The Mutha" datetime="2012-03-03T19:06:00" id="p23">
If I understood what I read of the bill, he's aiming this bill at children who's parents were never married. Parents who find themselves as single parents due to divorce or a spouse's death are somehow magically exempt from the potential of abusing their children. I fail to find any logic in the thinking, or lack thereof, in this. Btw, I read somewhere that the bill's author is unmarried and still lives with his mother. I wonder what his home life was life as a child.
</post>
<post author="keale" datetime="2012-03-03T19:30:00" id="p24">
Im sorry but this guy is a blithering idiot....straight up bleeping moron.

Conservatives out there....really? The GOP has devolved into this? How do you guys keep a straight face with guys like this and its not like hes the only one.
</post>
<post author="Puppycow" datetime="2012-03-04T00:31:00" id="p25">
How about a recall election for this moron?
</post>
<post author="Puppycow" datetime="2012-03-04T00:52:00" id="p26">
According to <a href="http://www.mcguigan.org/Column-Panzer-Grothman.html">this</a>, Grothman opposes abortion even in cases of rape or incest, so his position is that if you are a rape victim you must marry your rapist too, for the sake of the child?
</post>
<post author="eerok" datetime="2012-03-04T04:01:00" id="p27">
Rampant idiocy saddens me. That's why I don't follow politics more closely.
</post>
<post author="eeyore1954" datetime="2012-03-04T06:46:00" id="p28">
The bill says a contributing factor for child abuse is single parent families. Is the Incidence of abuse higher in families with one parent? I believe the single parent part of this bill is to educate the people who have left their families.
Of course there are any circumstances where a family is better off without both parents.
There is nothing in the bill that says what the op claims
</post>
<post author="crimresearch" datetime="2012-03-04T07:10:00" id="p29">
<quote orig_author="eeyore1954">
The bill says a contributing factor for child abuse is single parent families. Is the Incidence of abuse higher in families with one parent? I believe the single parent part of this bill is to educate the people who have left their families.
Of course there are any circumstances where a family is better off without both parents.
There is nothing in the bill that says what the op claims

</quote>
How do you 'educate' someone who has left their family by dying?

The bill doesn't say that parental abandonment is a contributing factor, it smears all custodial parents with the same blame brush.
</post>
<post author="leftysergeant" datetime="2012-03-04T08:29:00" id="p30">
Somebody may have to teach that moron that children in a family in which one or the other spouse has anger control problems is probably going to have anger control problems, too. If a girl is taught that it is wrong mommy to divorce daddy just because he comes home pissed off and takes it out on mommy, you have just raised a child who will probably die of homicidal violence at the hands of her own husband.

Are there really enough blithering idiots in the republicon party to pass some crap like this?

Or maybe it is just that turds like Grothman can't get laid because women will not put up with their crap and the self righteous jerks think that it is the women who have an atitude problem that needs adjusting.
</post>
<post author="Reginald Hobbes" datetime="2012-03-04T09:04:00" id="p31">
<quote orig_author="eeyore1954">
The bill says a contributing factor for child abuse is single parent families. Is the Incidence of abuse higher in families with one parent? I believe the single parent part of this bill is to educate the people who have left their families.
Of course there are any circumstances where a family is better off without both parents.
There is nothing in the bill that says what the op claims

</quote>
Nor does the OP have a quote or anything else to back that claim.
That being said, the senator is probably confusing correlation with causation, and this bill is a waste of time when there are more pressing matters to attend.
<a href="http://badgerherald.com/news/2012/03/01/legislators_may_take.php">Story</a> about this bill in the Badger Herald:

<quote>
CANPB, also known as the Childrens Trust Fund, is a governor-appointed board focused on reducing child maltreatment through public education and recommendations to the state government, Childrens Trust Fund Associate Director Jennifer Jones said.

If passed, the bill would require CANPB to emphasize non-marital parenthood as a contributing factor to child abuse and neglect during statewide educational and public awareness campaigns as well as when distributing information about the problems and methods of preventing child abuse and when providing informational materials to organizations that receive grants from CANPB.

Children living with two married, biological parents have the lowest rate of abuse and neglect, according to the United States Department of Department of Health and Human Services Administration for Children and Families.

Conversely, children living with a parent and unmarried partner have more than eight times the incidence of maltreatment than those living with two married biological parents, the report said.

While single parenthood is a contributing factor to child abuse and neglect, other issues put children at risk for maltreatment, Jones said. These include parental substance abuse, mental health concerns, domestic violence, teen parenthood, low maternal education, parental history of child maltreatment, poverty and unemployment, according to research complied by the Childrens Trust Fund.

Its important to understand all of these risk factors for child maltreatment in order to create sound policy solutions that prevent child abuse and neglect, Jones said.

</quote>
</post>
<post author="Darth Rotor" datetime="2012-03-04T19:07:00" id="p32">
<quote orig_author="Elizabeth I">
Wow, I became an abused child at the age of eight when my mother divorced my alcoholic father. Who knew?

</quote>
You turned out OK. <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/cool.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="jj" datetime="2012-03-04T20:20:00" id="p33">
It is interesting to see how thoroughly people will stretch, duck, and weave in order to fail to see the obvious, clear, and irrevocable implications of a given statement.

It is, however, also very discouraging in terms of the future of the human race.
</post>
<post author="Elizabeth I" datetime="2012-03-04T21:05:00" id="p34">
<quote orig_author="Darth Rotor">
You turned out OK. <img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/cool.gif"/>

</quote>
<img src="http://forums.randi.org/images/smilies/wave2.gif"/> Hi, DR! You're all right too!
</post>
<post author="ponderingturtle" datetime="2012-03-05T10:59:00" id="p35">
<quote orig_author="Puppycow">
According to <a href="http://www.mcguigan.org/Column-Panzer-Grothman.html">this</a>, Grothman opposes abortion even in cases of rape or incest, so his position is that if you are a rape victim you must marry your rapist too, for the sake of the child?

</quote>
Nice to see biblical values making a come back.
</post>
<post author="Craig4" datetime="2012-03-05T11:21:00" id="p36">
Checks the calendar... hmmm... looks like an election year.
</post>
<post author="keale" datetime="2012-03-05T11:32:00" id="p37">
<quote orig_author="ponderingturtle">
Nice to see biblical values making a come back.

</quote>

I know right
</post>
<post author="Moss" datetime="2012-03-05T11:45:00" id="p38">
I think the relevant page might be <a href="http://www.acf.hhs.gov/programs/opre/abuse_neglect/natl_incid/reports/natl_incid/natl_incid_dist_family_char.html"> this, especially section 5.3
</a>
</post>
<post author="jj" datetime="2012-03-05T14:27:00" id="p39">
<quote orig_author="Moss">
I think the relevant page might be <a href="http://www.acf.hhs.gov/programs/opre/abuse_neglect/natl_incid/reports/natl_incid/natl_incid_dist_family_char.html"> this, especially section 5.3
</a>

</quote>
I don't think anyone will be surprised at that link. It is not surprising that when parents have no resources, children may be neglected, is it?

So, the point of this is what, beyond self-fulfilling prophecy.

I suppose, say, a mom with a highschool kid, making minimum wage 20 hours a week, and getting social security from dad's account (both kid and mom), is somehow neglectful she isn't home every night to help with homework, right? Yes or no? How about "cook dinner", yes or no?

Speak up, now, I'm listening.
</post>
<post author="eeyore1954" datetime="2012-03-07T16:31:00" id="p40">
<quote orig_author="jj">
I don't think anyone will be surprised at that link. It is not surprising that when parents have no resources, children may be neglected, is it?

So, the point of this is what, beyond self-fulfilling prophecy.

I suppose, say, a mom with a highschool kid, making minimum wage 20 hours a week, and getting social security from dad's account (both kid and mom), is somehow neglectful she isn't home every night to help with homework, right? Yes or no? How about "cook dinner", yes or no?

Speak up, now, I'm listening.

</quote>
Did you look at the study to see what qualifies as neglect.

Here are the statistics for abuse.

<quote>
As Figure 52 shows, the incidence of Harm Standard physical abuse was significantly lower for children living with two married biological parents compared to children living in all other conditions. An estimated 1.9 per 1,000 children living with two married biological parents suffered Harm Standard physical abuse, compared to 5.9 or more per 1,000 children in other circumstances. In addition, children whose single parent had an unmarried, livein partner were at significantly higher risk of Harm Standard physical abuse (19.5 children per 1,000) compared to children in 4 other arrangements: children whose single parent had no partner in the home (5.9 children per 1,000), children with other married parents (9.8 children per 1,000), children with unmarried parents (8.2 children per 1,000), and children living with no parent (6.8 children per 1,000).

</quote>

I understand that there are many other factors or factors that combine together.
</post>
</doc>
