<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-203-185933-460453">
<headline>
GTKYN: Our Wedding
</headline>
<post author="melko4886" datetime="2012-02-02T16:16:00" id="p1">
Even though I’m a teacher, I hated that my schedule pretty much forced me to get married in the summer if I wanted to take a honeymoon (I wanted our honeymoon to be more than a week, and I didn’t want to stress out about having to go back to work the next day). We decided that we would be fine with taking a postponed honeymoon. Since we got engaged in April, that fall was too short of an engagement for what we wanted, and spring of 2010 was out because my brother was studying in Italy that semester. The following fall was out because I hated the idea of an engagement that was longer than a year. I know some people love it, but it was not for me.

One day, DH suggested January. Hmm. I kind of liked that idea. It was 8 months away at the time, and everything seemed manageable. I was also starting to think that it could be really pretty too. So, we started looking at venues, and we were shocked at how much cheaper everything was! The venue that we ended up going with even gave us another $15 pp off the price just for picking January 2, 2010. This date also made more sense because we had friends that were from OOT that would have to fly in for the holidays, so it was easy for them to attend.

8 months ended up being an awesome length for an engagement, although I probably could have gone even shorter because of certain drama with my mother. We actually didn’t talk for a few days because of the seating chart. She wanted her friends to be closer to the dance floor than my father’s family, because she claimed that her and my father “got shitted on” at another wedding by my Aunt. Whatevs mom, get over it.

On January 2, 2010, we had beautiful weather. It was sunny, and it was lightly misting snow (I seriously can’t think of the drizzling version of snow). The snow was all sparkly in the sun light.

My bridesmaids wore short black dresses, and our colors were black, white and dark purple with a damask print. We took a limo to the church (I’m catholic, and DH is nothing, so we got married in a protestant church in the center of our town). It was a simple, short ceremony, and my grandmother even got to read us our vows because she is a JP. We had 6BM and 6GM, and two flower girls.

We ended up taking pictures in the center of town, which ended up being pretty cool, but then we hurried down to Yale Hospital to visit DH’s grandmother who had surgery about a week before. I’ve never seen her happier than when we walked into her hospital room all decked out.

We had a cocktail hour, followed by an open bar reception with stations. Apparently, the open bar was awesome (gingerbread martinis, and whatever), as was the food (they ended up adding in a bunch more food, which was awesome because the price was already so low for being in January), but we didn’t really enjoy much of it because we were so busy. We even had a mashed potato bar, and an ice cream bar! It went way too fast.

Our first dance was “I wanna grow old with you,” by Adam Sandler, which was perfect because it’s so short. We also had a second dance to Keith Urban’s “ Memories of Us,” which we shared with the other couples.

I keep saying that I wish that one of my friends would throw the exact same wedding, so I can experience it as a guest!

<img src="http://i39.tinypic.com/mrq5h.jpg"/>
<img src="http://i42.tinypic.com/2vj1w9j.jpg"/>
<img src="http://i41.tinypic.com/2a7gdbb.jpg"/>
<img src="http://i44.tinypic.com/15oe6bo.jpg"/>
<img src="http://i41.tinypic.com/34ss58x.jpg"/>
<img src="http://i41.tinypic.com/2z5rwuo.jpg"/>
</post>
<post author="saltypearl" datetime="2012-02-02T16:28:00" id="p2">
awesome, you looked beautiful!
</post>
<post author="madeline10..." datetime="2012-02-02T16:31:00" id="p3">
So beautiful!!!!!
</post>
<post author="spongebobs..." datetime="2012-02-02T16:52:00" id="p4">
That dress was absolutely beautiful on you! I love the silhouette!
</post>
<post author="tara1223" datetime="2012-02-02T16:54:00" id="p5">
gorgeous!!
</post>
<post author="lilliesand..." datetime="2012-02-02T16:59:00" id="p6">
Wow, so pretty! I love winter weddings!
</post>
<post author="Shazzie116" datetime="2012-02-02T17:23:00" id="p7">
Yeah Jan10 Weddings! :)
You know I love everything about your wedding :)
</post>
<post author="ungraceful..." datetime="2012-02-02T19:09:00" id="p8">
I love your dress! So pretty.
</post>
<post author="AGsWife" datetime="2012-02-03T07:19:00" id="p9">
Gorgeous! We are both teachers and got married on Memorial Day weekend. We just postponed our honeymoon til the summer.
</post>
</doc>
