<doc id="bolt-eng-DF-200-192446-3809043">
<headline>
Amanda Knox wins Appeal
</headline>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T20:53:00" id="p1">
thoughts?

I think this is a victory over media hysteria as much as anything else.

PS. - what the ****? the title of this thread has changed, this isn't what I called it.
</post>
<post author="tweety_2479" datetime="2011-10-03T20:53:00" id="p2">
So what are your thoughts on this ??

<a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/blog/2011/oct/03/amanda-knox-appeal-hearing-live?newsfeed=true">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/blog...?newsfeed=true</a>
</post>
<post author="Ano1" datetime="2011-10-03T20:54:00" id="p3">
il bump this thread as you put more then thoughts?

my opinion, i dont know if she did or didnt. so cant say.

that is all.
</post>
<post author="barnetlad" datetime="2011-10-03T20:55:00" id="p4">
Not a great surprise.
</post>
<post author="white_haired_wizard" datetime="2011-10-03T20:55:00" id="p5">
My gut feeling is that she and that Raffaelle fella did kill Meredith Kercher.
</post>
<post author="Lewis :D" datetime="2011-10-03T20:55:00" id="p6">
She won her appeal
</post>
<post author="barnetlad" datetime="2011-10-03T20:56:00" id="p7">
No surprise.
</post>
<post author="neiljeff123" datetime="2011-10-03T20:56:00" id="p8">
Wasn't there DNA that said they were both at the scene?
</post>
<post author="Agent Smirnoff" datetime="2011-10-03T20:57:00" id="p9">
Amanda Knox and Rafaele Solecito have been freed by the Perugian Court of Appeal and cleared of all charges regarding the Murder of Meredith Kercher in 2009.

Discuss.
</post>
<post author="ghanglish" datetime="2011-10-03T20:57:00" id="p10">
Wow that's massive
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T20:58:00" id="p11">
<quote orig_author="neiljeff123">
Wasn't there DNA that said they were both at the scene?

</quote>

that's been discredited and is why they are free.

PS. can't believe this got negs, it's just fact, it was unreliable evidence and so was thrown out.
</post>
<post author="abc:)" datetime="2011-10-03T20:58:00" id="p12">
I honestly don't know if she did or not. All I can say is I hope not really otherwise I feel so sorry for the family.....not that these things can bring people back from the dead anyway <img src="images/smilies/frown.png"/>
</post>
<post author="Ministerdonut" datetime="2011-10-03T20:58:00" id="p13">
Don't know what to think really american TV and some UK newspapers basically poked major holes in the policework however,I always thought she was more involved than she let on,Iam not sure now, she certainly is an odd individual and a pathological liar but that doesn't make her a murderer and mean she should spend life in prison.I certainly wouldn't have sentenced her to death because there were questions over the evidence especially the forensic evidence. The sentence for framing an innocent man was upheld and she was sentened to 3 years and has to pay him compensation, although due to time served she was released.
</post>
<post author="BioFurMatPhyStudent" datetime="2011-10-03T20:58:00" id="p14">
<quote>
8.50pm: Knox and Sollecito are fee after winning the substantive part of their appeal. They are cleared.
</quote>

<img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/facepalm.gif" alt=":facepalm:"/>
</post>
<post author="Consilio Et Animis" datetime="2011-10-03T20:59:00" id="p15">
I don't think she did it, her life has changed but I'm sad for Kercher family.
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T20:59:00" id="p16">
Amanda and Rafelo kept changing their stories, Considering if you are innocent you only have one story, And that's the truth. Changing stories proves you are lying.

I'm willing to put money on them 2 being the killers.

Guilty until proven innocent.
</post>
<post author="fuzzybear" datetime="2011-10-03T20:59:00" id="p17">
not on bbc website <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/>

oh wait it is now
</post>
<post author="H.JJJ" datetime="2011-10-03T21:00:00" id="p18">
<quote orig_author="fuzzybear">
not on bbc website <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/>

</quote>

bbc news live confirms it
</post>
<post author="matt1" datetime="2011-10-03T21:01:00" id="p19">
Just saw this on Sky News, the coverage was very confusing, from their commentary it seemed like she had lost the appeal but then she definitely won.
Not sure what to make of this, I didn't follow the trial closely first time round but it would be interesting to hear opinions on this.
</post>
<post author="rainbow drops" datetime="2011-10-03T21:01:00" id="p20">
I think she's guilty and got off due to poor evidence. Lucky lady.
</post>
<post author="franzk" datetime="2011-10-03T21:01:00" id="p21">
watching her family is hot lol
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T21:02:00" id="p22">
Amanda and Rafelo kept changing their stories, Considering if you are innocent you only have one story, And that's the truth. Changing stories proves you are lying.

I'm willing to put money on them 2 being the killers.

Guilty until proven innocent.
</post>
<post author="eLECTROLOSIS" datetime="2011-10-03T21:02:00" id="p23">
Wow... Not sure what to think...
</post>
<post author="tweety_2479" datetime="2011-10-03T21:02:00" id="p24">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
What planet are you on.

</quote>

what exactly do you mean by this I asking what you thought about her being freed personally im stunned was just asking if everyone thought the same or expected it

why is that so hard for you to understand?
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T21:02:00" id="p25">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
Amanda and Rafelo kept changing their stories, Considering if you are innocent you only have one story, And that's the truth. Changing stories proves you are lying.

I'm willing to put money on them 2 being the killers.

Guilty until proven innocent.

</quote>

I think the part about changing stories was disregarded because they were supposedly given under duress and she apparently didn't have a good grasp of italian at the time either.
</post>
<post author="fuzzybear" datetime="2011-10-03T21:03:00" id="p26">
<quote orig_author="franzk">
watching her family is hot lol

</quote>

why else do you think this whole story has got so much attention in all these years
</post>
<post author="JKGB" datetime="2011-10-03T21:03:00" id="p27">
I feel so sorry for Meredith's family. I think her family are right, the real victim has been forgotten in all of this.
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T21:04:00" id="p28">
<quote orig_author="tweety_2479">
what exactly do you mean by this I asking what you thought about her being freed personally im stunned was just asking if everyone thought the same or expected it

why is that so hard for you to understand?

</quote>

Your original title was Amanda Knox loses appeal.
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T21:04:00" id="p29">
<quote orig_author="SwingOnTheSpiral88">
I think the part about changing stories was disregarded because they were supposedly given under duress and she apparently didn't have a good grasp of italian at the time either.

</quote>

Bull****, They'd have had translators there and then in order to overcome the language barrier.
</post>
<post author="Sharri5" datetime="2011-10-03T21:05:00" id="p30">
The evidence wasn't there. This whole thing was a circus
</post>
<post author="FloydRix" datetime="2011-10-03T21:06:00" id="p31">
I've followed this case very closely since the start and there's never been ANY genuine evidence. Just plenty of circumstantial 'evidence' and some disgracefully poor DNA work.

Fantastic result and the right result.
</post>
<post author="chicagowonderland" datetime="2011-10-03T21:06:00" id="p32">
I'm not going to lie I think she was apart of it somehow.
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T21:06:00" id="p33">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
Bull****, They'd have had translators there and then in order to overcome the language barrier.

</quote>

The point is, they didn't have translators there. Not initially.
</post>
<post author="tweety_2479" datetime="2011-10-03T21:06:00" id="p34">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
Your original title was Amanda Knox loses appeal.

</quote>

this was because the guardian actually first reported that she lost her appeal before they changed it. I think there was some confusion on their behalf.......

so basically you've negged me for no reason <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="franzk" datetime="2011-10-03T21:07:00" id="p35">
what was the apparant reason the girl died in the first place?
</post>
<post author="Butane" datetime="2011-10-03T21:08:00" id="p36">
A big dollar defence team from daddy Knox got them off on a DNA technicality, regardless of the non-DNA evidence like the blackout period of both their cell phones during the murder hours by both Knox and Sollecito. Will no doubt be going to the Supreme Court on appeal by the prosecutors.
</post>
<post author="katy_j87" datetime="2011-10-03T21:09:00" id="p37">
It must be awful for poor Meredith's sister and mother who were sitting there having to watch them cheering and celebrating for Knox in court. So insensitive, as at the end of the day a young girl has been murdered and she seems to have been forgotten in all of this. I suspect Knox is guilty but got off through poor evidence and a brilliant PR team (her family have been rumoured to have spent £1 million on press.) It is sad to think that if you have enough money, you can get away with something as awful as murder.
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T21:10:00" id="p38">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
The point is, they didn't have translators there. Not initially.

</quote>

They'd have had translators when interviewing, It's pretty obvious. You don't interview someone who doesn't speak the same language as you.

I feel sorry for the Kercher's, It's pretty safe to say Knox and her BF did it, If I was them I'd take a contract killing out.

The people on this site who say they didn't do it aren't to be taken seriously.
</post>
<post author="Mr Dangermouse" datetime="2011-10-03T21:10:00" id="p39">
<quote orig_author="Consilio Et Animis">
I don't think she did it, her life has changed but I'm sad for Kercher family.

</quote>

Why? Surely they wouldn't want to see an innocent girl locked away.

And personally I don't trust the Italian system when it comes to Brits and Americans, there's an angry sentiment against those countries in Italy.
</post>
<post author="NOBODY MOVE!" datetime="2011-10-03T21:10:00" id="p40">
shoddy work by italian dna/ forensic people

O.O
</post>
<post author=".eXe" datetime="2011-10-03T21:10:00" id="p41">
Im pretty sure that bitch killed her

Just cause its a girl she got off. Same thing happened in america with the casey anthony case where the wh0re murdered her own daughter.

Hope they both burn in hell
</post>
<post author="white_haired_wizard" datetime="2011-10-03T21:11:00" id="p42">
<quote orig_author="franzk">
what was the apparant reason the girl died in the first place?

</quote>

A couple of years ago I read that it was possibly something to do with sex games that spiralled out of control and it ended up with Meredith Kercher being, well, killed.

It does sound to have been an extremely complicated case, with several people involved in being charged, interviewed, all kinds of alibis etc...

The casualty of all this has been the truth, you just don't know what source to believe tbh.
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T21:12:00" id="p43">
<quote orig_author=".eXe">
Im pretty sure that bitch killed her

Just cause its a girl she got off. Same thing happened in america with the casey anthony case where the wh0re murdered her own daughter.

Hope they both burn in hell

</quote>

the dude got off too. she was convicted once when people thought there was genuine evidence.
</post>
<post author="Aspiringlawstudent" datetime="2011-10-03T21:12:00" id="p44">
Jolly good.
</post>
<post author="chicagowonderland" datetime="2011-10-03T21:13:00" id="p45">
<quote orig_author=".eXe">
Im pretty sure that bitch killed her

Just cause its a girl she got off. Same thing happened in america with the casey anthony case where the wh0re murdered her own daughter.

Hope they both burn in hell

</quote>

I'm still shocked by the outcome of that case there is no way that woman was innocent.
</post>
<post author=".eXe" datetime="2011-10-03T21:13:00" id="p46">
<quote orig_author="SwingOnTheSpiral88">
the dude got off too.

</quote>

yeah they're not gonna convict 1 person and let the other one go, especially since they were both equally involved.

they probably made up some bull**** story. neither had an alibi as to there whereabouts at the time of the murder and yet they got off scot free. its total bs
</post>
<post author="Aspiringlawstudent" datetime="2011-10-03T21:14:00" id="p47">
<quote orig_author=".eXe">
Im pretty sure that bitch killed her

Just cause its a girl she got off. Same thing happened in america with the casey anthony case where the wh0re murdered her own daughter.

Hope they both burn in hell

</quote>

Flat out libel.

I hope you're sued.
</post>
<post author="Bella Occhi" datetime="2011-10-03T21:14:00" id="p48">
Don't know either way - but even if she is innocent, her life is pretty much ruined anyway from now on. Terrible shame if she is actually innocent.
</post>
<post author="KCosmo" datetime="2011-10-03T21:15:00" id="p49">
The decision today was irrelevant. If she won the appeal (which she did) then the perugian court can and will still appeal against it. If she had lost her appeal today, then she could have still appealed to the italian senate. It's not over
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T21:15:00" id="p50">
<quote orig_author="chicagowonderland">
I'm still shocked by the outcome of that case there is no way that woman was innocent.

</quote>

some details of the case are strange, but without evidence they were just trying to convict on a hunch. that should not be happening in 2011, that could happen to any one of us.
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T21:16:00" id="p51">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
They'd have had translators when interviewing, It's pretty obvious. You don't interview someone who doesn't speak the same language as you.

I feel sorry for the Kercher's, It's pretty safe to say Knox and her BF did it, If I was them I'd take a contract killing out.

The people on this site who say they didn't do it aren't to be taken seriously.

</quote>

<img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/>
Well that's a balanced view to be listen to, of course.
</post>
<post author="HumiT" datetime="2011-10-03T21:16:00" id="p52">
Don't know what to think <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/>. Not surprised she's been freed though
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T21:17:00" id="p53">
<quote orig_author=".eXe">
yeah they're not gonna convict 1 person and let the other one go, especially since they were both equally involved.

they probably made up some bull**** story. neither had an alibi as to there whereabouts at the time of the murder and yet they got off scot free. its total bs

</quote>

there were 3 people involved, the third one was convicted. knox and sollecito aren't siamese twins.
</post>
<post author="Consilio Et Animis" datetime="2011-10-03T21:17:00" id="p54">
<quote orig_author="Mr Dangermouse">
Why? Surely they wouldn't want to see an innocent girl locked away.

And personally I don't trust the Italian system when it comes to Brits and Americans, there's an angry sentiment against those countries in Italy.

</quote>

Sad that they haven't found closure.
</post>
<post author="tweety_2479" datetime="2011-10-03T21:18:00" id="p55">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
I didn't neg you but nice of you to assume.
And thanks for the (wrongly) returned rep. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/>

</quote>

lol i didn't neg as well.....run of off reps today...... will do tomorrow though.......
</post>
<post author="sucess" datetime="2011-10-03T21:18:00" id="p56">
i'm happy for her
</post>
<post author="somethingbeautiful" datetime="2011-10-03T21:18:00" id="p57">
I don't understand how they managed to convict her in the first place with such rubbish evidence - that's not to say that I think she is innocent though, rather I think the case against her was pathetic and the DNA evidence was just a complete balls up. In terms of thinking she may be innocent, the fact that there wasn't a jot of her DNA in Kercher's room where she was murdered speaks volumes and the fact that the knife used as evidence against her innocence (that supposedly had her DNA on it which was then called into doubt itself) was a communal piece of kitchenware is just silly. If you've ever lived in halls in uni you'll know that your DNA is probably all over the stuff in the kitchen/bathrooms/communal areas. The other stuff about her own recollection of where she was and the mystery surrounding her mobile phone leads me to think something is fishy though. All in all I think the prosecution messed up big time and I'm still on the fence as to whether or not she was involved.
</post>
<post author="chicagowonderland" datetime="2011-10-03T21:19:00" id="p58">
<quote orig_author="SwingOnTheSpiral88">
some details of the case are strange, but without evidence they were just trying to convict on a hunch. that should not be happening in 2011, that could happen to any one of us.

</quote>

I meant the Casey Anthony case there is no way in hell that woman is innocent.
</post>
<post author="Aphotic Cosmos" datetime="2011-10-03T21:19:00" id="p59">
The only thing that has really struck me about this case is how the American media reported it. "SHE IS AMERICAN THEREFORE NOT GUILTY" is about the summation of the headlines over the last 4 years. Log on to CNN this morning and you may as well have been reading Fox News. Virtually no coverage of the case, no mention of the crime or Meredith Kerchner, just a bunch of Op-eds and commentaries about how she is clearly not guilty.

Fair enough, we're probably guilty of the same thing in some respects like the Gary McKinnon case (although I do sympathise with him) and the Natwest Three a few years ago, but then that was as much about a completely one-sided rendition treaty to the United States as it was about the cases themselves. This story has just been a great excuse for American journalists to slate the Italian judiciary, combined with an opportunity to show American exceptionalism at it's very worst.
</post>
<post author="Samz" datetime="2011-10-03T21:19:00" id="p60">
I honestly don't know if I think she is innocent or guilty, but just reading what evidence has been released to us - I don't personally think it's been proved beyond reasonable doubt. A lot of the evidence seems to be circumstantial.. maybe she was guilty but the police investigation was shocking and she's gotten off because of that, I really don't know.

Also, my law lecturer made a good point about the Knox family $1million campaign today.. he said that if any of his children told him they were innocent of a crime they had been convicted of he would throw everything he had into making sure they were freed - that money would be no object. She is somebodys daughter, of course they are going to campaign for her release.

Personally I think the whole 'foxy knoxy' thing was a bit disgusting, and the tragedy of Merediths death has been forgotten. I hope she has found some peace, and I hope her family can one day find the same.
</post>
<post author="trrr" datetime="2011-10-03T21:19:00" id="p61">
I really wanna know your thoughts on this.
</post>
<post author=".eXe" datetime="2011-10-03T21:20:00" id="p62">
<quote orig_author="Aspiringlawstudent">
Flat out libel.

I hope you're sued.

</quote>

I said I'm pretty sure

That's not libel. It wasn't a factual statement, it was an opinion. Let's see me get sued for stating an opinion.
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T21:20:00" id="p63">
<quote orig_author="tweety_2479">
lol i didn't neg as well.....run of off reps today...... will do tomorrow though.......

</quote>

You did, I can see whose repped me and I've got your name by a nice little red gem.
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T21:21:00" id="p64">
<quote orig_author="chicagowonderland">
I meant the Casey Anthony case there is no way in hell that woman is innocent.

</quote>

ahh right, yeah, that one looks much more suspicious.
</post>
<post author="Panda Bear" datetime="2011-10-03T21:21:00" id="p65">
<quote orig_author="matt1">
Just saw this on Sky News, the coverage was very confusing, from their commentary it seemed like she had lost the appeal but then she definitely won.
Not sure what to make of this, I didn't follow the trial closely first time round but it would be interesting to hear opinions on this.

</quote>

Major translation fail on Sky News' behalf.
</post>
<post author="Jellybean91" datetime="2011-10-03T21:21:00" id="p66">
I'm living in Perugia right now and doing the same thing as Kercher was... I went to watch the trial on thursday and it became clear to me that, although i'm still on the fence about if she did it, they do not have enough evidence to bang her up! I would say, its better to have a guilty person walk free than lock an innocent person up!
</post>
<post author="daphodil" datetime="2011-10-03T21:21:00" id="p67">
So now Meredith's family are just in limbo again, and if they believe she is guilty then it's even worse for them. I don't get how Knox and her boyf can be innocent when 3 people were present, surely they would have stopped it? Can anyone explain to me who the convicted person was and if they have said whether Knox/the other guy were innocent?
</post>
<post author="MossRole234" datetime="2011-10-03T21:21:00" id="p68">
if Amanda Knox and Rafaele Sollecito didn't kill Meredith Kercher, then who the hell did, an invisible man perhaps?
</post>
<post author="Samz" datetime="2011-10-03T21:23:00" id="p69">
<quote orig_author="MossRole234">
if Amanda Knox and Rafaele Sollecito didn't kill Meredith Kercher, then who the hell did, an invisible man perhaps?

</quote>

Rudy Guede has been convicted of her murder. He's appealed twice and his conviction has been upheld both times.
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T21:25:00" id="p70">
<quote orig_author="daphodil">
So now Meredith's family are just in limbo again, and if they believe she is guilty then it's even worse for them. I don't get how Knox and her boyf can be innocent when 3 people were present, surely they would have stopped it? Can anyone explain to me who the convicted person was and if they have said whether Knox/the other guy were innocent?

</quote>

there is stilll one an in jail for this.
</post>
<post author="affinity89" datetime="2011-10-03T21:25:00" id="p71">
Just noticed on Twitter that the <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2044583/Amanda-Knox-verdict-GUILTY-appeal-murder-conviction-rejected.html?ito=feeds-newsxml"> Daily Mail</a> [Fail] have published the wrong article on their website, the article prepared for a guilty verdict/rejection of appeal. This amuses me. As does much of the content of the paper lol. <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>

Spoiler:
<a href="http://t.co/ALqCBHWl">TwitPic of page</a> <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>
</post>
<post author="dothestrand" datetime="2011-10-03T21:26:00" id="p72">
Whether she did it or not, it's sad that this whole thing has been turned into such a circus, and everyone seems to have forgotten that a woman was murdered and her family have to live with that every day.
</post>
<post author="Mr Dangermouse" datetime="2011-10-03T21:26:00" id="p73">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
Amanda and Rafelo kept changing their stories, Considering if you are innocent you only have one story, And that's the truth. Changing stories proves you are lying.

I'm willing to put money on them 2 being the killers.

Guilty until proven innocent.

</quote>

Guilty until proven innocent is ridiculous.
</post>
<post author="MossRole234" datetime="2011-10-03T21:27:00" id="p74">
<quote orig_author="Samz">
Rudy Guede has been convicted of her murder. He's appealed twice and his conviction has been upheld both times.

</quote>

Oh right, maybe should read more into it next time before coming out with strong opinions <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>
</post>
<post author="SpicyStrawberry" datetime="2011-10-03T21:27:00" id="p75">
<quote orig_author="Aspiringlawstudent">
Flat out libel.

I hope you're sued.

</quote>

Oh yeah because people can sue anonymous users of the internet for libel when everyone is saying similar things can't they <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/> In the real world this wouldn't happen.

It wasn't even stated as fact, it's an opinion.
</post>
<post author="Mr Dangermouse" datetime="2011-10-03T21:29:00" id="p76">
<quote orig_author="affinity89">
Just noticed on Twitter that the <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2044583/Amanda-Knox-verdict-GUILTY-appeal-murder-conviction-rejected.html?ito=feeds-newsxml"> Daily Mail</a> [Fail] have published the wrong article on their website, the article prepared for a guilty verdict/rejection of appeal. This amuses me. As does much of the content of the paper lol. <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>

Spoiler:
<img src="http://s1.proxy04.twitpic.com/photos/large/414388465.jpg"/>

</quote>

They just jumped the gun. I was watching live on sky news and it was announced "GUILTY" and flashed on the screen that the appeal was rejected, however the mistake was that, it was first announced on the police slandering case.
</post>
<post author="thunder_chunky" datetime="2011-10-03T21:29:00" id="p77">
Mamma Mia!!!!!

Maybe now the Italians will have to actually do some real police work. God forbid.
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T21:29:00" id="p78">
<quote orig_author="Mr Dangermouse">
Guilty until proven innocent is ridiculous.

</quote>

No, Letting someone free when it's pretty safe to say they did it is ridiculous.
</post>
<post author="Ministerdonut" datetime="2011-10-03T21:29:00" id="p79">
People are forgetting she was found guilty of framing an innocent man and was sentenced to 3 years, of course due to time served she was released.

I still don't understand why she framed him, if she was innocent? I don't know if she murdered Meredith, I have not followed the case and it seems both sides have plenty of argument,even without the forensic stuff,Knox doesn't come off great. I personally think she had some involvement but won't say as it would incriminate her.I think there are probably other incidents where she behaved or did something and this time she slipped up,not saying she killed before just odd behaviour. But my gut feelings should not be enough to lock her up for twenty odd years. I wouldn't want to be locked up for all that time because others thought I was weird and I also happened to be a pathological liar.
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T21:29:00" id="p80">
<quote orig_author="MossRole234">
if Amanda Knox and Rafaele Sollecito didn't kill Meredith Kercher, then who the hell did, an invisible man perhaps?

</quote>

rudy guede is in prison for it.
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T21:30:00" id="p81">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
No, Letting someone free when it's pretty safe to say they did it is ridiculous.

</quote>

but it's not safe to say it at all. there's reason for suspicion but nothing definite.
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T21:31:00" id="p82">
<quote orig_author="SwingOnTheSpiral88">
rudy guede is in prison for it.

</quote>

It's amazing how many people don't know this.
</post>
<post author=".eXe" datetime="2011-10-03T21:33:00" id="p83">
I think she and her boyfriend wanted her dead and hired Rudy to do it.
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T21:33:00" id="p84">
<quote orig_author="SwingOnTheSpiral88">
but it's not safe to say it at all. there's reason for suspicion but nothing definite.

</quote>

It is safe to say, You don't change a story if you are innocent. Period.
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T21:34:00" id="p85">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
It's amazing how many people don't know this.

</quote>

it's not surprising given that the only person who got any media attention was inevitably the woman with the attractive face.
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T21:35:00" id="p86">
<quote orig_author="SwingOnTheSpiral88">
it's not surprising given that the only person who got any media attention was inevitably the woman with the attractive face.

</quote>

Well that's not true, I've seen Rudy Guede's named mentioned and face shown often enough.
</post>
<post author="Mr Dangermouse" datetime="2011-10-03T21:36:00" id="p87">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
No, Letting someone free when it's pretty safe to say they did it is ridiculous.

</quote>

Regardless of my personal feelings, you NEVER lock someone up until it's been exhaustively proven.
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T21:38:00" id="p88">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
Well that's not true, I've seen Rudy Guede's named mentioned and face shown often enough.

</quote>

sollecito and guese have been only a minor footnote at best.

look at the title of my thread. I called this thread "Amanda Knox and Raffaele Sollecito freed." but some moderator person (I assume) has taken it upon themself to change it to "Amanda Knox wins appeal !". She's been the focus here.
</post>
<post author="DirtyPrettyThing" datetime="2011-10-03T21:38:00" id="p89">
Feel bad for Meredith's family, who have suffered a terrible loss.

Amanda Knox is hot - glad she's free finally. Seems as like she was innocent, from what I've read.
</post>
<post author="itsmyname" datetime="2011-10-03T21:38:00" id="p90">
Can someone please some up the main points of this case please? Why people think she's innocent, guilty, someone mentioning her being a pathological liar and the cellphone blackout or something?
</post>
<post author="SpunkyVanDros" datetime="2011-10-03T21:38:00" id="p91">
in the words of The great Chris Rock 'whatever happened to good old fashioned crazy'
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T21:39:00" id="p92">
<quote orig_author="Mr Dangermouse">
Regardless of my personal feelings, you NEVER lock someone up until it's been exhaustively proven.

</quote>

And this is why cases like this happen because of people like you in this world.
</post>
<post author="Origami Bullets" datetime="2011-10-03T21:40:00" id="p93">
<quote orig_author="neiljeff123">
Wasn't there DNA that said they were both at the scene?

</quote>

IIRC they all lived in the same house, so there was every reason for their DNA to be at the scene.
</post>
<post author="issyconnor" datetime="2011-10-03T21:40:00" id="p94">
There's something really creepy about Amanda Knox.
</post>
<post author="katy_j87" datetime="2011-10-03T21:41:00" id="p95">
<quote orig_author="Bella Occhi">
Don't know either way - but even if she is innocent, her life is pretty much ruined anyway from now on.

</quote>

I don't think so. I could see her becoming a celebrity from this - she already has book deals, a possible film and countless TV interviews in the pipeline. The American press are already treating her as some kind of hero.

There is a report called the Massei Report (you can google it) which gives a lot of info that points towards Knox being guilty. Forensic evidence shows that the murder was carried out by more than one person due to the wounds on the girl's body. It was obvious she was restrained and did not fight back in any way, indicating that someone was stabbing her while others were holding her down. This supports the theory that Rudy Guede did not do this alone. He was also let in to the house by someone with a key, and someone staged a break in to cover it up.

There is loads of other stuff on there - such as Knox's phone being turned off for hours, her not having an alibi about where she was that night, a sighting of her buying bleach and cleaning supplies the morning after at 7am...I just can't believe she has won this appeal based on the evidence found from this investigation. Even if the DNA is discounted, some of the above things just make it obvious.
</post>
<post author="DorianGrayism" datetime="2011-10-03T21:41:00" id="p96">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
They'd have had translators when interviewing, It's pretty obvious. You don't interview someone who doesn't speak the same language as you.

I feel sorry for the Kercher's, It's pretty safe to say Knox and her BF did it, If I was them I'd take a contract killing out.

The people on this site who say they didn't do it aren't to be taken seriously.

</quote>

They didn't have translators or a lawyer at the first interview when she made her original "confession".

Hence, her statement was deemed inadmissible.
</post>
<post author="misscharli" datetime="2011-10-03T21:41:00" id="p97">
I dont think she did it but I think she was with Meredith shortly before it happened.
</post>
<post author="Pandora." datetime="2011-10-03T21:41:00" id="p98">
Poor Meredith. I feel genuinely saddened by this case, and I rarely ever do. I hope that her family will get closure one day, and that the truth is uncovered as soon as possible. <img src="images/smilies/frown.png"/>

RIP Meredith.
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T21:42:00" id="p99">
<quote orig_author="DorianGrayism">
They didn't have translators or a lawyer at the first interview when she made her original "confession".

</quote>

The story was changed more than once.
</post>
<post author="hbk4894" datetime="2011-10-03T21:42:00" id="p100">
i think this is on the wrong board, maybe try the Current Affairs board
</post>
<post author="issyconnor" datetime="2011-10-03T21:43:00" id="p101">
And I'm ****ing sick of the tabloids that refer to her as 'Foxy Knoxy'. It's so stupid. But I guess for the tabloids, it was like 'never mind that she was on trial for murdering someone, lets comment on her nice hair and figure'.
</post>
<post author="Ministerdonut" datetime="2011-10-03T21:43:00" id="p102">
<quote orig_author="DirtyPrettyThing">
Feel bad for Meredith's family, who have suffered a terrible loss.

Amanda Knox is hot - glad she's free finally. Seems as like she was innocent, from what I've read.

</quote>

She's not that hot,especially after 4 yrs inside.She's about a 6 at the mo. The only time I have seen her above a 7 was when she was tanned and was holding that machine gun in the photo.

Thing is if you are a hot chick more likely you get away with it, Casey Anthony was another, or pretty much any chick who fuks a teenage boy.Man would do time, many of these women don't.
</post>
<post author="EssexDan86" datetime="2011-10-03T21:43:00" id="p103">
I think they were definitely involved in the murder in some way, even if not the direct killers.

She'll probably write a book about her 'ordeal' now though, and make a fortune...
</post>
<post author="Mr Dangermouse" datetime="2011-10-03T21:43:00" id="p104">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
And this is why cases like this happen because of people like you in this world.

</quote>

Care to elaborate?

This isn't maths. You can't just point the finger at the vulnerable one and make them disprove it.
</post>
<post author="daphodil" datetime="2011-10-03T21:44:00" id="p105">
<quote orig_author="Samz">
Rudy Guede has been convicted of her murder. He's appealed twice and his conviction has been upheld both times.

</quote>

Did he mention anything about Knox and the other guy being involved?
</post>
<post author="Ministerdonut" datetime="2011-10-03T21:45:00" id="p106">
<quote orig_author="EssexDan86">
I think they were definitely involved in the murder in some way, even if not the direct killers.

She'll probably write a book about her 'ordeal' now though, and make a fortune...

</quote>

I will find that totally fuking sickening personally and I don't like her stepfather much either. Bit of a cnut in my opinion.
</post>
<post author="Aequat omnes cinis" datetime="2011-10-03T21:46:00" id="p107">
<quote orig_author="rainbow drops">
I think she's guilty and got off due to poor evidence. Lucky lady.

</quote>

agree
</post>
<post author="ArcadiaHouse" datetime="2011-10-03T21:46:00" id="p108">
She gives me the creeps. I think she's guilty.
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T21:46:00" id="p109">
<quote orig_author="katy_j87">
I don't think so. I could see her becoming a celebrity from this - she already has book deals, a possible film and countless TV interviews in the pipeline. The American press are already treating her as some kind of hero.

There is a report called the Massei Report (you can google it) which gives a lot of info that points towards Knox being guilty. Forensic evidence shows that the murder was carried out by more than one person due to the wounds on the girl's body. It was obvious she was restrained and did not fight back in any way, indicating that someone was stabbing her while others were holding her down. This supports the theory that Rudy Guede did not do this alone. He was also let in to the house by someone with a key, and someone staged a break in to cover it up.

There is loads of other stuff on there - such as Knox's phone being turned off for hours, her not having an alibi about where she was that night, a sighting of her buying bleach and cleaning supplies the morning after at 7am...I just can't believe she has won this appeal based on the evidence found from this investigation. Even if the DNA is discounted, some of the above things just make it obvious.

</quote>

this has gone on for 4 years, it's been dissected to pieces, they've still not gotten rid of any reasonable doubt. They might well be guilty but there just is not enough of a reason to decide they definitely are, so this is the right outcome.
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T21:47:00" id="p110">
<quote orig_author="Mr Dangermouse">
Care to elaborate?

This isn't maths. You can't just point the finger at the vulnerable one and make them disprove it.

</quote>

Leftists mainly. 'Oh you can't do that,' Or ' She's innocent 1111111' The quicker anyone who swings to the left is destroyed or converted the better.

Like I said before

If you are innocent you never ever ever change your story, Why because in your eyes your innocent you haven't done anything. The only time you change your story when dealing with the law is to cover leaking holes that may get exposed.
</post>
<post author="issyconnor" datetime="2011-10-03T21:47:00" id="p111">
It's the disgusting the way the Knox family have absolutely no respect for what happened to Meredith.
</post>
<post author="zazzi" datetime="2011-10-03T21:48:00" id="p112">
<img src="http://newsimg.bbc.co.uk/media/images/45936000/jpg/_45936771_002071907-1.jpg"/>

Computer says NO.
</post>
<post author="SwingOnTheSpiral88" datetime="2011-10-03T21:48:00" id="p113">
<quote orig_author="issyconnor">
It's the disgusting the way the Knox family have absolutely no respect for what happened to Meredith.

</quote>

what makes you say that?
</post>
<post author="Ki_Kudos" datetime="2011-10-03T21:49:00" id="p114">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
It is safe to say, You don't change a story if you are innocent. Period.

</quote>

Not necessarily true. Remeber the Guildford 4? Coercion by Police to make a false statement is possible, and the British authorities are more highly regarded in their methods than their Italian counterparts.

As to whether that is the case with Knox and Sollecito, I do not know.
</post>
<post author="meenu89" datetime="2011-10-03T21:49:00" id="p115">
Guilty. Wouldn't even trust her with a paper round.
</post>
<post author="thunder_chunky" datetime="2011-10-03T21:49:00" id="p116">
<quote orig_author="MossRole234">
if Amanda Knox and Rafaele Sollecito didn't kill Meredith Kercher, then who the hell did, an invisible man perhaps?

</quote>

Prince Phillip?
</post>
<post author="ArcadiaHouse" datetime="2011-10-03T21:49:00" id="p117">
<quote orig_author="Agent Smirnoff">
Amanda Knox and Rafaele Solecito have been freed by the Perugian Court of Appeal and cleared of all charges regarding the Murder of Meredith Kercher in 2009.

Discuss.

</quote>

2007* <img src="images/smilies/wink.png"/>

Also: WHAAAAAAAAT?! <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/eek.gif" alt=":eek:"/>
</post>
<post author=".eXe" datetime="2011-10-03T21:49:00" id="p118">
<quote orig_author="Mr Dangermouse">
Care to elaborate?

This isn't maths. You can't just point the finger at the vulnerable one and make them disprove it.

</quote>

you're right but how do you account for jury's who fail?
like this case
like casey anthony's case
like countless others

the only way these kind of criminals get acquitted is when some technicality gets in the way. Oh the police used too much force, oh the evidence was obtained without warrant, oh the evidence was there, but it was circumstantial (even though the odds of the circumstances actually occurring are miniscule).

This girl and her dumbass boyfriend got lucky. If in fact they were innocent, they wouldn't have done several things they did that actually strengthened their guilt.

They lied
They dont have alibis
They defamed others
They changed their stories multiple times

Does this sound like innocent people to you? The last thing I would do if I was innocent is try to get someone else falsely blamed. That's exactly what this dumb bitch did.

I think the evidence is against them and I am sorry that they are getting off like this. It's a failure of the justice system.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T21:50:00" id="p119">
<quote orig_author="affinity89">
Just noticed on Twitter that the <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2044583/Amanda-Knox-verdict-GUILTY-appeal-murder-conviction-rejected.html?ito=feeds-newsxml"> Daily Mail</a> [Fail] have published the wrong article on their website, the article prepared for a guilty verdict/rejection of appeal. This amuses me. As does much of the content of the paper lol. <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>

Spoiler:
<a href="http://t.co/ALqCBHWl">TwitPic of page</a> <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>

</quote>

How amateurish.
</post>
<post author="DirtyPrettyThing" datetime="2011-10-03T21:50:00" id="p120">
<quote orig_author="Ministerdonut">
She's not that hot,especially after 4 yrs inside.She's about a 6 at the mo. The only time I have seen her above a 7 was when she was tanned and was holding that machine gun in the photo.

Thing is if you are a hot chick more likely you get away with it, Casey Anthony was another, or pretty much any chick who fuks a teenage boy.Man would do time, many of these women don't.

</quote>

TBH that whole issue of a chick banging a young boy is a grey area. Most lads would be well up for that, although I do acknowledge fully that it can lead to issues later in life.

I bet Knox will scrub up well now that she's out of jail. I only wish I could be the first bloke she comes across, bet she'd be ravenous with desire after no men for four years.

Once again I feel sorry for the victims of the case, what I'm discussing here is a trivial aside.
</post>
<post author="rainbow drops" datetime="2011-10-03T21:50:00" id="p121">
Guilty, IMO.
</post>
<post author="Samz" datetime="2011-10-03T21:51:00" id="p122">
<quote orig_author="daphodil">
Did he mention anything about Knox and the other guy being involved?

</quote>

I'm think he's changed his story to suit him, sometimes he's said they weren't there &amp; other times he says they were. It's pretty definate he did it, his DNA was all over the place.. really unsure about why he would keep chopping and changing his mind though! <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/confused.gif" alt=":confused:"/> Playing games I guess.
</post>
<post author="Greeny442" datetime="2011-10-03T21:51:00" id="p123">
Innocent - as that's what the courts have decided.

Of course, the fact that Italy is one of the most corrupt nations and Knox appears to have a cult following in Italy and America that may or may not have swayed the decision should be taken in to account...
</post>
<post author="Ki_Kudos" datetime="2011-10-03T21:52:00" id="p124">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
Leftists mainly. 'Oh you can't do that,' Or ' She's innocent 1111111' The quicker anyone who swings to the left is destroyed or converted the better.

Like I said before

If you are innocent you never ever ever change your story, Why because in your eyes your innocent you haven't done anything. The only time you change your story when dealing with the law is to cover leaking holes that may get exposed.

</quote>

Unbelievably naive.
Imagine someone threatened the life of a member of your family unless you agreed to admit to something you didn't do, would you 'admit' to it?

I know I would.
</post>
<post author="Liam 09" datetime="2011-10-03T21:52:00" id="p125">
Innocent.
</post>
<post author="ninjalamb" datetime="2011-10-03T21:52:00" id="p126">
I am disgusted. Completely and utterly disgusted.

I was dreading today. I knew they would be released.

There is not a doubt in my mind that Knox and Sollecito killed that poor girl, not a single doubt.

Amanda Knox is a pathological liar who constantly declared her innocence yet was entirely incapable of maintaining a logical, consistent story the whole way throughout proceedings. And now she'll be released into a world where she will be regarded as a celebrity.

Sickens me.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T21:52:00" id="p127">
I CANT BLOODY BELIEVE THIS

This girl has got away with so much ****. She is the best actress I have ever seen.
Girl be looking torn up from bottom up. Hell naw she tricked people.

WHY

She is a major liar!
She first tries to blame an innocent man?
She then says Italian police officers slap her and did not feed her?
Her and her fugly boyfriend then have conflicting stories?

I am so angry that I have taken my heels off because hell naww i am gonna be getting all ghetto.
</post>
<post author="Guy Secretan" datetime="2011-10-03T21:52:00" id="p128">
She is hot but I do think she did it there is so much other evidence against her other than forensic. I kind of think the PR machine behind her and the incompetent way they gathered the evidence is what got her off. She will have to be extradited when the prosecution appeal so I think it's unlikely justice will ever be done.
</post>
<post author="DorianGrayism" datetime="2011-10-03T21:53:00" id="p129">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
The story was changed more than once.

</quote>

I am not replying to that point.

You said that they provided a translator. They didn't provide a translator or a lawyer. Hence, that is why her statement was inadmissible in court.
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T21:53:00" id="p130">
<quote orig_author="Ki_Kudos">
Not necessarily true. Remeber the Guildford 4? Coercion by Police to make a false statement is possible, and the British authorities are more highly regarded in their methods than their Italian counterparts.

As to whether that is the case with Knox and Sollecito, I do not know.

</quote>

No, You just don't make a false statement, If you know your innocent you don't change it.

<quote orig_author=".eXe">
you're right but how do you account for jury's who fail?
like this case
like casey anthony's case
like countless others

the only way these kind of criminals get acquitted is when some technicality gets in the way. Oh the police used too much force, oh the evidence was obtained without warrant, oh the evidence was there, but it was circumstantial (even though the odds of the circumstances actually occurring are miniscule).

This girl and her dumbass boyfriend got lucky. If in fact they were innocent, they wouldn't have done several things they did that actually strengthened their guilt.

They lied
They dont have alibis
They defamed others
They changed their stories multiple times

Does this sound like innocent people to you? The last thing I would do if I was innocent is try to get someone else falsely blamed. That's exactly what this dumb bitch did.

I think the evidence is against them and I am sorry that they are getting off like this. It's a failure of the justice system.

</quote>

I would +Rep you for this statement.
</post>
<post author="tillytots" datetime="2011-10-03T21:53:00" id="p131">
she's just been cleared hasn't she?

I'm on the fence,but something isn't right about her.
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T21:53:00" id="p132">
<quote orig_author="DorianGrayism">
I am not replying to that point.

You said that they provided a translator. They didn't provide a translator or a lawyer. Hence, that is why her statement was inadmissible in court.

</quote>

The story changed more than once. Like I said, You don't change your story multiple times.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T21:54:00" id="p133">
I CANT BLOODY BELIEVE THIS

This girl has got away with so much ****. She is the best actress I have ever seen.
Girl be looking torn up from bottom up. Hell naw she tricked people.

WHY

She is a major liar!
She first tries to blame an innocent man?
She then says Italian police officers slap her and did not feed her?
Her and her fugly boyfriend then have conflicting stories?

I am so angry that I have taken my heels off because hell naww i am gonna be getting all ghetto.
</post>
<post author="CombineHarvester" datetime="2011-10-03T21:54:00" id="p134">
I think guilty but the vast majority of Americans have always seemed to think she was innocent so probably the media has something to do with our perception of this (obviously). If there wasn't enough evidence for a conviction then fair enough. Seems dodgy about her lying and changing her story etc. but that's probably not that uncommon anyway.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T21:55:00" id="p135">
sorry double post
My first time <img src="images/smilies/frown.png"/>
</post>
<post author="amtvp" datetime="2011-10-03T21:55:00" id="p136">
Anybody who purports to seriously answer this question within this thread is ridiculous.

How could we possibly decide her guilt, with insufficient access to the evidence?

I haven't got a clue whether she's guilty or not.
</post>
<post author="JCC-MGS" datetime="2011-10-03T21:55:00" id="p137">
Is there any point to this thread really? Nobody has any evidence for or against the idea that she is innocent or guilty, we haven't been privy to the proceedings, it's just going to be pages of people saying she's guilty because she has a 'dishonest face'.

edit: damn you amtvp
</post>
<post author="danny111" datetime="2011-10-03T21:56:00" id="p138">
<quote orig_author="neiljeff123">
Wasn't there DNA that said they were both at the scene?

</quote>

So what? That proves nothing.

It is indeed suspicious but say there are 50 people at a party, someone gets murdered. 49 people have their DNA at the crime scene. Now, it wasn't that many (don't know if any other DNA was found even) but the principle should apply. Doesn't prove they did it. Proved they were there. What happened to innocent until proven guilty?
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T21:58:00" id="p139">
<quote orig_author="danny111">
So what? That proves nothing.

It is indeed suspicious but say there are 50 people at a party, someone gets murdered. 49 people have their DNA at the crime scene. Now, it wasn't that many (don't know if any other DNA was found even) but the principle should apply. Doesn't prove they did it. Proved they were there. What happened to innocent until proven guilty?

</quote>

HEY please understand once a liar always a liar.

When a man cheats then he always a cheater!

If she such an ANGEL then why she CHANGE her STORY!
</post>
<post author="DorianGrayism" datetime="2011-10-03T21:58:00" id="p140">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
The story changed more than once. Like I said, You don't change your story multiple times.

</quote>

I am not sure what is so understand. I am not talking about them changing their story.

You wrote a factually incorrect statement.

They didn't have translator or a lawyer. That is why their evidence was deemed inadmissible by the court.

You don't need to reply to me with an erroneous point if you are factually incorrect.
</post>
<post author="franzk" datetime="2011-10-03T21:58:00" id="p141">
what was the motive to the death/
how does it connect to the sex game they played or whatever it is
</post>
<post author="daphodil" datetime="2011-10-03T21:59:00" id="p142">
Tahe her on Jeremy Kyle and make her do the lie detector. 97% accuracy is the closest we're ever gonna get on this one!
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T21:59:00" id="p143">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
How amateurish.

</quote>

Despite the fact they printed the wrong story to start off with, It's clear the fabricated a lot of stuff in the article such as reactions by each party as well as what happened!
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T22:00:00" id="p144">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
HEY please understand once a liar always a liar.

When a man cheats then he always a cheater!

If she such an ANGEL then why she CHANGE her STORY!

</quote>

Oooh, she changed her story, I guess she must be guilty!!1!
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T22:01:00" id="p145">
<quote orig_author="DorianGrayism">
I am not sure what is so understand. I am not talking about them changing their story.

</quote>

Well I am.

<quote orig_author="DorianGrayism">
You wrote a factually incorrect statement.

They didn't have translator or a lawyer. That is why their evidence was deemed inadmissible by the court.

</quote>

They would have had a translator at interviews be it only 3 interviews or 10, They have had a translator present.

Still doesn't justify a story change though does it now?
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T22:01:00" id="p146">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
Despite the fact they printed the wrong story to start off with, It's clear the fabricated a lot of stuff in the article such as reactions by each party as well as what happened!

</quote>

Lazy journalism.
</post>
<post author="DorianGrayism" datetime="2011-10-03T22:01:00" id="p147">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
HEY please understand once a liar always a liar.

When a man cheats then he always a cheater!

If she such an ANGEL then why she CHANGE her STORY!

</quote>

Maybe she murdered her. Maybe she can't remember. Maybe she remembered something after being interrogated without a lawyer or translator or given any food or water.

Unless you are psychic then you don't know. Hence, why she was released.
</post>
<post author="white_haired_wizard" datetime="2011-10-03T22:02:00" id="p148">
<quote orig_author="DirtyPrettyThing">
TBH that whole issue of a chick banging a young boy is a grey area. Most lads would be well up for that, although I do acknowledge fully that it can lead to issues later in life.

I bet Knox will scrub up well now that she's out of jail. I only wish I could be the first bloke she comes across, bet she'd be ravenous with desire after no men for four years.

Once again I feel sorry for the victims of the case, what I'm discussing here is a trivial aside.

</quote>

I personally wouldn't touch Knox with a barge pole. She certainly hasn't been proven innocent in all of this. She might end up sucking my cock, biting it off before slapping me with my own dismembered 'member' until I lose consciousness. Then the knife would come out to finish me off.

I feel alot of sympathy for the Kercher family. They're the real victims in all of this, as well as the truth in this tragic/complicated case.
</post>
<post author="DorianGrayism" datetime="2011-10-03T22:02:00" id="p149">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
They would have had a translator at interviews be it only 3 interviews or 10, They have had a translator present.

</quote>

They didn't have a translator or a lawyer. Hence, why the evidence was deemed inadmissible by an Italian Court. Just check and read the facts.
</post>
<post author="KingGoonIan" datetime="2011-10-03T22:03:00" id="p150">
I worry that if she had been tried in America then she would've been executed a while ago. Thank god Italy doesn't have the death penalty.

As for people claiming she is guilty, hasn't another person been sentenced to 30 years for the crime after admitting it?
</post>
<post author="TheGrinningSkull" datetime="2011-10-03T22:03:00" id="p151">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
Oooh, she changed her story, I guess she must be guilty!!1!

</quote>

Changing a story is a sign of guilt yes, if I go around changing my story everytime you come to speak to me I'm sure you'd be suspecting me of lying.

I got into uni, I'm still in highschool, I have an apprenticeship. I have a full time career.

Which one is it?
</post>
<post author="Diogenes-" datetime="2011-10-03T22:04:00" id="p152">
Does this mean she is on the market?
</post>
<post author="Billy Pilgrim" datetime="2011-10-03T22:04:00" id="p153">
Never thought she was guilty, the crazy 'sex game' theory is just too unbelievable. Basically a media character assassination.
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T22:05:00" id="p154">
<quote orig_author="DorianGrayism">
They didn't have a translator or a lawyer. Hence, why the evidence was deemed inadmissible by an Italian Court. Just check and read the facts.

</quote>

They would have had a translator at interviews be it only 3 interviews or 10, They have had a translator present.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T22:05:00" id="p155">
<quote orig_author="TheGrinningSkull">
Changing a story is a sign of guilt yes, if I go around changing my story everytime you come to speak to me I'm sure you'd be suspecting me of lying.

I got into uni, I'm still in highschool, I have an apprenticeship. I have a full time career.

Which one is it?

</quote>

Of course it's suspicious, but how does it prove her guilt?
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:07:00" id="p156">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
Oooh, she changed her story, I guess she must be guilty!!1!

</quote>

You don't understand....

Yes she changed her story.... I could understand if she said I woke up on the floor or to then I cant remember exactly really.....

But to firstly frame someone, then secondly have a different story to her bf, then to change it, then to saying police slapped her abt and not fed her.

plz
</post>
<post author="DorianGrayism" datetime="2011-10-03T22:08:00" id="p157">
<quote orig_author="KingGoonIan">
I worry that if she had been tried in America then she would've been executed a while ago. Thank god Italy doesn't have the death penalty.

As for people claiming she is guilty, hasn't another person been sentenced to 30 years for the crime after admitting it?

</quote>

Well, death row takes a very long time especially if there are appeals and etc.

Another person has been sentenced to life for the crime but as far as I know is appealing the decision.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T22:09:00" id="p158">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
You don't understand....

Yes she changed her story.... I could understand if she said I woke up on the floor or to then I cant remember exactly really.....

But to firstly frame someone, then secondly have a different story to her bf, then to change it, then to saying police slapped her abt and not fed her.

plz

</quote>

Please what, how does that prove her guilt?
</post>
<post author="Guy Secretan" datetime="2011-10-03T22:10:00" id="p159">
Does anyone else think that the kercher children have really good genes.
</post>
<post author="DorianGrayism" datetime="2011-10-03T22:10:00" id="p160">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
They..... present.

</quote>

You don't seem to understand. She didn't have a translator present at the first interview hence that is why her statement was deemed inadmissible.

Hence, making your original statement incorrect. I will type it out for you again because you seem to have forgotten

<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
They'd have had translators when interviewing, It's pretty obvious. You don't interview someone who doesn't speak the same language as you.
.

</quote>

This is clearly an incorrect statement since they did not have translators at the original interview.
</post>
<post author="Guy Secretan" datetime="2011-10-03T22:12:00" id="p161">
When that guy said on BBC news that they would give her a charge and the four years she served on prison would cancel it out just to save face was exactly right. Their justice system seems kind of a bit farcical.
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T22:13:00" id="p162">
<quote orig_author="DorianGrayism">
You don't seem to understand. She didn't have a translator present at the first interview hence that is why her statement was deemed inadmissible.

</quote>

She had multiple interviews, In which the statement was constantly changing, Still doesn't justify you point to implying the story wasn't changed.
</post>
<post author="CLARA_" datetime="2011-10-03T22:13:00" id="p163">
what annoys me the most is that all the attention is on Knox, but not the victim Meredith Kercher! she was the one that died a horrid death!!!
</post>
<post author="Svenjamin" datetime="2011-10-03T22:14:00" id="p164">
A story change in itself does not incriminate. Supposition because you think something is slightly off doesn't prove anything. Convictions need to be based upon material evidence, which was lacking in this case. If it's innocent until proven guilty, then it needs to be compelling that she commited the crime.

Whatever the verdict, way too much information on the case was released to the press while it was still ongoing. It's disgusting how open an Italian court is, almost like public entertainment for all the gossip in the media.
</post>
<post author="Lights" datetime="2011-10-03T22:14:00" id="p165">
Not totally convinced on the verdict, there's something about Knox I just don't like, but who knows the real truth. The whole trial has been a total circus focused on "Foxy Knoxy" - even now on the Daily Mail page: "Foxy goes free." The way media like the DM have handled this is disgusting. Totally forgotten about the real victim here. Poor Meredith, I feel so awful for the Kercher family.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:16:00" id="p166">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
Please what, how does that prove her guilt?

</quote>

OKAY

Lets put you in a Scenario

Your dad is knox boss. Right?

She tries to frames your dad?

What is your reaction?...[YOU] She might be right or she is a bit confused.
</post>
<post author="DorianGrayism" datetime="2011-10-03T22:17:00" id="p167">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
She had multiple interviews, In which the statement was constantly changing, Still doesn't justify you point to implying the story wasn't changed.

</quote>

But..... I am not talking about multiple interviews..... I am talking about your statement:

<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
They'd have had translators when interviewing, It's pretty obvious. You don't interview someone who doesn't speak the same language as you.

</quote>

This is clearly incorrect since she never had a translator originally..

Yet you continue to bring up other points about her changing her story which has nothing to do with what I said originally.

I never implied her story wasn't changed since that would be incorrect. In fact, if you look at my previous posts to other users I imply the complete opposite and discuss her changing her story.
</post>
<post author="fourleaf" datetime="2011-10-03T22:17:00" id="p168">
I definitely remember reading that Knox originally confessed to the murder, and then changed her story. You wouldn't say you were guilty and then change your mind.

It's shocking that amid all of the media furore; like the film with the girl from Heroes that came out based on the trial, or Knox releasing a book, that the press seem to have completely detracted from the actual victim in the whole case.

None of this seems to have cleared up who actually did it, and I think Meredith Kercher's family deserve justice &amp; to find out who was guilty for the murder of her.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T22:18:00" id="p169">
<quote orig_author="Guy Secretan">
When that guy said on BBC news that they would give her a charge and the four years she served on prison would cancel it out just to save face was exactly right. Their justice system seems kind of a bit farcical.

</quote>

How is that farcical <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/confused.gif" alt=":confused:"/> She was sentenced to 3 years and served four years, what's that got to do with saving face?
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T22:19:00" id="p170">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
OKAY

Lets put you in a Scenario

Your dad is knox boss. Right?

She tries to frames your dad?

What is your reaction?...[YOU] She might be right or she is a bit confused.

</quote>

What the **** has this got to do with her guilt over the murder?
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T22:20:00" id="p171">
<quote orig_author="fourleaf">
I definitely remember reading that Knox originally confessed to the murder, and then changed her story. You wouldn't say you were guilty and then change your mind.

It's shocking that amid all of the media furore; like the film with the girl from Heroes that came out based on the trial, or Knox releasing a book, that the press seem to have completely detracted from the actual victim in the whole case.

None of this seems to have cleared up who actually did it, and I think Meredith Kercher's family deserve justice &amp;amp; to find out who was guilty for the murder of her.

</quote>

If, as Amanda said, she was subjected to 12 hours questioning with no translator or food and toilet breaks I think you'd find yourself hard-pushed to not want to change your story. I'm not declaring her innocence but just trying to see the "other side".
Also, Rudy Guede has been convincted of murdering Meredith.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:21:00" id="p172">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
What the **** has this got to do with her guilt over the murder?

</quote>

Firstly. I asked you a question?

To answer yours I need your reply to mine. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/confused.gif" alt=":confused:"/>
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T22:21:00" id="p173">
<quote orig_author="DorianGrayism">
But..... I am not talking about multiple interviews..... I am talking about your statement:

</quote>

"They'd have had translators when interviewing"

You do know this is on a general stance. LOL, If I'd have said, They'd have had a translator on first interview, Then ok, Considering that statement gives no specific interview and ranges from all interviews in general, You are in the wrong here not me.

<quote orig_author="DorianGrayism">
Yet you continue to bring up other points about her changing her story which has nothing to do with what I said originally.

</quote>

Y U NO LISTEN.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T22:22:00" id="p174">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
Firstly. I asked you a question?

To answer yours I need your reply to mine. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/confused.gif" alt=":confused:"/>

</quote>

You don't need to know my answer to your ridiculous question to tell me whether her lies prove that she is guilty of murder.
</post>
<post author="humanrights" datetime="2011-10-03T22:22:00" id="p175">
this whole issue highlights the anti white racism of the mainstream media. for years now they ahve been whipping up a frenzy when it was obvious what had happened merideth the mixed race girl of european and india descent was raped and murdered by a racist african who is already serving 16 years.

know and her boyfriend originally got 25 years. so the case must be reopened and the racist rapist murderer must be given a longer sentence.
</post>
<post author="Antonia87" datetime="2011-10-03T22:23:00" id="p176">
I still think she did it - or if she didnt, she knew far more than she was letting on. The whole thing still doesnt add up.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:24:00" id="p177">
I so hope i am still alive to be posting on the TSR when that ACTRESS gets whats coming to her! SHE WILL BE FOUND OUT! Mark my words

I am a international model and I know girls like that!
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:26:00" id="p178">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
You don't need to know my answer to your ridiculous question to tell me whether her lies prove that she is guilty of murder.

</quote>

Well i think that sums you up hunny. Maybe a more simple question is better for you.

Why do people LIE in a court of justice?
</post>
<post author="TobeTheHero" datetime="2011-10-03T22:28:00" id="p179">
****ing scary! knowing a murderer walks out free!
</post>
<post author="DorianGrayism" datetime="2011-10-03T22:29:00" id="p180">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
"They'd have had translators when interviewing"

You do know this is on a general stance. LOL, If I'd have said, They'd have had a translator on first interview, Then ok, Considering that statement gives no specific interview and ranges from all interviews in general, You are in the wrong here not me.

</quote>

There is no need to lie and change your story. <img src="images/smilies/wink.png"/>

Let's look at the original statement that you replied to:

<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
"
The point is, they didn't have translators there. Not initially.

</quote>

Your reply:

<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
They'd have had translators when interviewing,

</quote>

I could also go to your other reply.

<quote orig_author="SwingOnTheSpiral88">
"

I think the part about changing stories was disregarded because they were supposedly given under duress and she apparently didn't have a good grasp of italian at the time either..

</quote>

This is obviously in reference to the initial interview.

Your reply was:

<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
"

Bull****, They'd have had translators there

</quote>

Anyway, this has been fun. <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:31:00" id="p181">
<quote orig_author="doriangrayism">
there is no need to lie and change your story. <img src="images/smilies/wink.png"/>

let's look at the original statement that you replied to:

Your reply:

I could also go to your other reply.

This is obviously in reference to the initial interview.

Your reply was:

Anyway, this has been fun. <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>

</quote>

lollllllllllll post of the thread!
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T22:33:00" id="p182">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
Well i think that sums you up hunny. Maybe a more simple question is better for you.

Why do people LIE in a court of justice?

</quote>

I don't know, you'r the international model who knows girls like that. Maybe you should've offered your services as an expert witness to the prosecution <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/>
</post>
<post author="DorianGrayism" datetime="2011-10-03T22:33:00" id="p183">
<quote orig_author="SwingOnTheSpiral88">
I didn't say that. Some mistake has been made here, those aren't my words.

</quote>

Ahh...thanks for pointing that out to me.
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T22:36:00" id="p184">
<quote orig_author="DorianGrayism">
Let's look at the original statement that you replied to:
Your reply:

</quote>

"They'd have had translators when interviewing,"

Lulz, Still doesn't specify a specific interview, It works on a general stance, Overall majority.

<quote orig_author="DorianGrayism">
I could also go to your other reply.
This is obviously in reference to the initial interview.
Your reply was:

</quote>

"Bull****, They'd have had translators there"

Still doesn't point to a specific interview, LULZ brah!!! better luck next time.

Who said I'm changing a story 0.o clutching straw ends clutching straw ends.
</post>
<post author="TM94" datetime="2011-10-03T22:36:00" id="p185">
Wait who killed her then? Surely she would have been there when the murder took place.
Unbelievable.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:36:00" id="p186">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
I don't know, you'r the international model who knows girls like that. Maybe you should've offered your services as an expert witness to the prosecution <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/>

</quote>

MEOWWWWWWWW lol girlfriend getting her claws out lol <img src="images/smilies/colondollar.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="Goody2Shoes-x" datetime="2011-10-03T22:37:00" id="p187">
I find it sickening. It wasn't about the murder anymore, it had become a media storm. Poor American girl from a nice, well to do family in the brutal Italian courts.

Here's an interesting one - if Raffaele Sollecito had been accused alone - without Knox - would the hype have been so strong? Would there be celebrities, politicans, whole towns baying for his release?

Doubtful.
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T22:38:00" id="p188">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
&amp;quot;They'd have had translators when interviewing,&amp;quot;

Lulz, Still doesn't specify a specific interview, It works on a general stance, Overall majority.

&amp;quot;Bull****, They'd have had translators there&amp;quot;

Still doesn't point to a specific interview, LULZ brah!!! better luck next time.

Who said I'm changing a story 0.o clutching straw ends clutching straw ends.

</quote>

Their point still stands. There wasn't a translator at the original interview when she was supposed to have made the confession so therefore it was disregarded.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T22:38:00" id="p189">
<quote orig_author="TM94">
Wait who killed her then? Surely she would have been there when the murder took place.
Unbelievable.

</quote>

Maybe the guy who was convicted and is currently serving time for her murder...
</post>
<post author="Member737,514" datetime="2011-10-03T22:39:00" id="p190">
Shock, horror, gasp!

To be honest, it's not as though we didn't see it coming...
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T22:39:00" id="p191">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
Their point still stands. There wasn't a translator at the original interview when she was supposed to have made the confession so therefore it was disregarded.

</quote>

It doesn't stand, You don't change a statement if you are innocent.

<img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/>
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T22:40:00" id="p192">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
It doesn't stand, You don't change a statement if you are innocent.

<img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/>

</quote>

I was stating a fact, what happened, what has been made public. It does still stand because her statement was disregarded.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:41:00" id="p193">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
Maybe the guy who was convicted and is currently serving time for her murder...

</quote>

surprised you can answer that <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/eek.gif" alt=":eek:"/>
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T22:42:00" id="p194">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
I was stating a fact, what happened, what has been made public. It does still stand because her statement was disregarded.

</quote>

Y NOBODY IN THREAD LISTEN................

<img src="http://troll.me/images/y-u-no-guy/yu-no-listen-punk-fuuuuuuuu.jpg"/>

Innocent - One statement, All police require.

Guilty - Multiple statements, Different events/stories.

Yes she really is innocent <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/>
</post>
<post author="pocketfulofposy" datetime="2011-10-03T22:42:00" id="p195">
They both got off due to failings by the Italian police, such as errors in collecting the evidence. If that evidence had been collected properly, and without delay, it could not have been queried like it was in the appeal and they wouldn't have got off.

People here in the States are slating the Italian justice system, but given the fact this is a country that two weeks executed a probably innocent man when there was just as much doubt (if not more in his case), I think that's a bit rich!
</post>
<post author="Lamps08" datetime="2011-10-03T22:42:00" id="p196">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
I so hope i am still alive to be posting on the TSR when that ACTRESS gets whats coming to her! SHE WILL BE FOUND OUT! Mark my words

I am a international model and I know girls like that!

</quote>

There is no evidence stupid. Also can I see pics to PROVE ur a model.
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T22:43:00" id="p197">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
Yes she really is innocent <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/>

</quote>

You really are thick as ****. I didn't mention anything about her being innocent. I just stated her original statement was disregarded.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T22:44:00" id="p198">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
surprised you can answer that <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/eek.gif" alt=":eek:"/>

</quote>

God, just shut up. If you really want to be pedantic I asked you a question first and you've failed to answer.
</post>
<post author="fuzzybear" datetime="2011-10-03T22:44:00" id="p199">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
I so hope i am still alive to be posting on the TSR when that ACTRESS gets whats coming to her! SHE WILL BE FOUND OUT! Mark my words

I am a international model and I know girls like that !

</quote>

like what?
</post>
<post author="tweety_2479" datetime="2011-10-03T22:45:00" id="p200">
<quote orig_author="SwingOnTheSpiral88">
thoughts?

I think this is a victory over media hysteria as much as anything else.

PS. - what the ****? the title of this thread has changed, this isn't what I called it.

</quote>

I think we both made a thread about this at the same time because apparantly I'm not the thread starter you are and that was my title to the thread I started!!
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T22:45:00" id="p201">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
You really are thick as ****. I didn't mention anything about her being innocent. I just stated her original statement was disregarded.

</quote>

Lulz the exact response I was goading for:
<img src="http://cdn0.knowyourmeme.com/i/000/106/887/original/backpain-1292835351.jpg?1300412448"/>

Don't like the opinion brah! Don't like that she changed her story multiple times brah!
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:45:00" id="p202">
<quote orig_author="Lamps08">
There is no evidence stupid. Also can I see pics to PROVE ur a model.

</quote>

I said she will be found out... LOL stupid. Evidence does come up in the future.
Plus NO hunny, what you do behind your screen is your business.
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T22:46:00" id="p203">
<quote orig_author="ShadowConspiracy">
Lulz the exact response I was goading for:

Don't like the opinion brah! Don't like that she changed her story multiple times brah!

</quote>

Moron.
Never said I did or didn't like the opinion or anything about her story change. Crawl back ino the hole you came from. Parasite.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:47:00" id="p204">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
God, just shut up. If you really want to be pedantic I asked you a question first and you've failed to answer.

</quote>

which was what? I am sorry if I failed to answer please refresh my memory?
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:48:00" id="p205">
<quote orig_author="fuzzybear">
like what?

</quote>

Girls that will do anything for the spot light.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T22:49:00" id="p206">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
which was what? I am sorry if I failed to answer please refresh my memory?

</quote>

How does her lies prove she was guilty of murder?
</post>
<post author="fuzzybear" datetime="2011-10-03T22:49:00" id="p207">
<quote orig_author="pocketfulofposy">
They both got off due to failings by the Italian police, such as errors in collecting the evidence. If that evidence had been collected properly, and without delay, it could not have been queried like it was in the appeal and they wouldn't have got off.

People here in the States are slating the Italian justice system, but given the fact this is a country that two weeks executed a probably innocent man when there was just as much doubt (if not more in his case, I think that's a bit rich !

</quote>

<img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/congrats.gif" alt=":congrats:"/>
</post>
<post author="RipperRoo" datetime="2011-10-03T22:53:00" id="p208">
Now she will face a tougher trial: Dancing with the Stars...
</post>
<post author="Cicerao" datetime="2011-10-03T22:53:00" id="p209">
<quote orig_author="katy_j87">
It must be awful for poor Meredith's sister and mother who were sitting there having to watch them cheering and celebrating for Knox in court. So insensitive, as at the end of the day a young girl has been murdered and she seems to have been forgotten in all of this. I suspect Knox is guilty but got off through poor evidence and a brilliant PR team (her family have been rumoured to have spent £1 million on press.) It is sad to think that if you have enough money, you can get away with something as awful as murder.

</quote>

Two young people being in jail with little to no evidence they're guilty is not going to bring Meredith back.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:55:00" id="p210">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
How does her lies prove she was guilty of murder?

</quote>

I did not say she was solely guilty of murder, But I have a strong feeling for sure that she was involved but I know for sure she is not innocent

firstly: by her accusing someone innocent.
Secondly: Changing her statements on her whereabouts and other things.
Thirdly: Accusing the Italian police for slapping her and not feeding her.

When someone lies hunny they are hiding something
</post>
<post author="Cicerao" datetime="2011-10-03T22:55:00" id="p211">
<quote orig_author="TM94">
Wait who killed her then? Surely she would have been there when the murder took place.
Unbelievable.

</quote>

So are you always in your student flat all the time?

Rudy Guede killed her. (Just my opinion, of course. But there is actually evidence that places him there. I don't think there's much that implicates the two that have just been freed.)
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T22:56:00" id="p212">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
I did not say she was solely guilty of murder, But I have a strong feeling for sure that she was involved but I know for sure she is not innocent

firstly: by her accusing someone innocent.
Secondly: Changing her statements on her whereabouts and other things.
Thirdly: Accusing the Italian police for slapping her and not feeding her.

When someone lies hunny they are hiding something

</quote>

FFS, stop calling people you don't know hunny. Still haven't answered the question.
</post>
<post author="TheRabbit" datetime="2011-10-03T22:57:00" id="p213">
It doesn't matter what we think - we don't know all the stuff that was put to the jury and with all the stuff in the media if anything there was a lot of pressure on the jury to return a guilty verdict again.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T22:59:00" id="p214">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
FFS, stop calling people you don't know hunny. Still haven't answered the question.

</quote>

Calm down THING...

I did "I did not say she was solely guilty of murder, But I have a strong feeling for sure", "When someone lies hunny they are hiding something"
Her extents to which she lies automatically means she is guilty!
Is that enough for you THING!
</post>
<post author="ShadowConspiracy" datetime="2011-10-03T23:00:00" id="p215">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
Moron.
Never said I did or didn't like the opinion or anything about her story change. Crawl back ino the hole you came from. Parasite.

</quote>

<img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/kym-assets/photos/images/newsfeed/000/174/425/32.jpg?1316156400"/>
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T23:01:00" id="p216">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
Calm down THING...

I did &amp;quot;I did not say she was solely guilty of murder, But I have a strong feeling for sure&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;When someone lies hunny they are hiding something&amp;quot;
Her extents to which she lies automatically means she is guilty!
Is that enough for you THING!

</quote>

So lying about something= automatically guilty of the crime

I ****ing hope to hell that you're never called up for jury service.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T23:02:00" id="p217">
NOW RLW31 ANSWER THIS QUESTION!

Why do people LIE in a court of justice?

ALSO

Lets put you in a Scenario

Your dad is knox boss. Right?

She tries to frames your dad?

What is your reaction?...[YOU] She might be right or she is a bit confused.

P.S IF YOU ARE ASHAMED TO ADMIT YOUR WRONG DOINGS PLZ LEAVE THIS THREAD.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T23:03:00" id="p218">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
So lying about something= automatically guilty of the crime

I ****ing hope to hell that you're never called up for jury service.

</quote>

Yeah and I hope I aint at your trial hunny, because any case you lie your guilty! <img src="images/smilies/biggrin.png"/>
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T23:03:00" id="p219">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
NOW RLW31 ANSWER THIS QUESTION!

Why do people LIE in a court of justice?

ALSO

Lets put you in a Scenario

Your dad is knox boss. Right?

She tries to frames your dad?

What is your reaction?...[YOU] She might be right or she is a bit confused.

P.S IF YOU ARE ASHAMED TO ADMIT YOUR WRONG DOINGS PLZ LEAVE THIS THREAD.

</quote>

I don't know.

I'd be angry. What the **** has this got to do with her acquittal for murder?
</post>
<post author="Lamps08" datetime="2011-10-03T23:04:00" id="p220">
[QUOTE=ANJAL;34318218]I said she will be found out... LOL stupid. Evidence does come up in the future.
Plus NO hunny, what you do behind your screen is your business.

I'm actually an international spy, we may cross paths someday....
</post>
<post author="Dastrea" datetime="2011-10-03T23:04:00" id="p221">
I personally think she is innocent, but I can't remember enough details of the original case to post a full opinion.
</post>
<post author="G50" datetime="2011-10-03T23:04:00" id="p222">
About as innocent as OJ was.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T23:07:00" id="p223">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
I don't know.

I'd be angry. What the **** has this got to do with her acquittal for murder?

</quote>

hmmmm nice answer.
But YOU ARE GUILTY because i know you be like "hell naw she framing my daddy, she did it herself" LAWLLLLLLLL

It just gives me a perspective of what you would be thinking if someone close to you got framed with murder.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T23:08:00" id="p224">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
hmmmm nice answer.
But YOU ARE GUILTY because i know you be like "hell naw she framing my daddy, she did it herself" LAWLLLLLLLL

It just gives me a perspective of what you would be thinking if someone close to you got framed with murder.

</quote>

Guilty of what?
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T23:08:00" id="p225">
[QUOTE=Lamps08;34318585]
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
I said she will be found out... LOL stupid. Evidence does come up in the future.
Plus NO hunny, what you do behind your screen is your business.

I'm actually an international spy, we may cross paths someday....

</quote>

Maybe we will but hunny when people like RLW31 talk ****, it makes me get more lines on my face <img src="images/smilies/frown.png"/>
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T23:09:00" id="p226">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
Guilty of what?

</quote>

ONLY YOU KNOW AND I THE ANSWER TO THAT
<img src="images/smilies/redface.png"/>
</post>
<post author="122025278" datetime="2011-10-03T23:09:00" id="p227">
You have to admit though, Knox is fit...
</post>
<post author="Stray_talk" datetime="2011-10-03T23:10:00" id="p228">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
Guilty of what?

</quote>

I would honestly give up. Your head must be pretty sore from banging it against that mighty brick wall.
</post>
<post author="Lamps08" datetime="2011-10-03T23:10:00" id="p229">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
Calm down THING...

I did "I did not say she was solely guilty of murder, But I have a strong feeling for sure", "When someone lies hunny they are hiding something"
Her extents to which she lies automatically means she is guilty!
Is that enough for you THING!

</quote>

Lol @ THING
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T23:11:00" id="p230">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
I would honestly give up. Your head must be pretty sore from banging it against that mighty brick wall.

</quote>

I like you <img src="images/smilies/biggrin.png"/>
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T23:12:00" id="p231">
<quote orig_author="Stray_talk">
I would honestly give up. Your head must be pretty sore from banging it against that mighty brick wall.

</quote>

No, didn't you know, if I give up I'll be guilty of something, somewhere <img src="images/smilies/colone.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T23:13:00" id="p232">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
No, didn't you know, if I give up I'll be guilty of something, somewhere <img src="images/smilies/colone.gif"/>

</quote>

lol
</post>
<post author="Lamps08" datetime="2011-10-03T23:14:00" id="p233">
[QUOTE=ANJAL;34318661]
<quote orig_author="Lamps08">
Maybe we will but hunny when people like RLW31 talk ****, it makes me get more lines on my face <img src="images/smilies/frown.png"/>

</quote>

Haha thats jokes
</post>
<post author="johndoranglasgow" datetime="2011-10-03T23:15:00" id="p234">
It's not really a huge surprise and the media by no means treated her fairly but I dunno... I just get a bit of a gut feeling whenever I see them and hear some of the things (particularly Knox) says - they seem guilty as hell.
</post>
<post author="j0hn" datetime="2011-10-03T23:17:00" id="p235">
I always believed she was innocent, the DNA evidence even minus the flaws wasn't necessarily strong enough to assert a conviction especially in Amandas case, so when the DNA evidence which seemed to me to be a close shave anyway was discredited, it was only a matter of time. None of Amandas DNA was found in the room, just on a reguarly used kitchen knife which supposedly had Merediths blood on the blade, which turned out not only to be low, but incompatible with the injuries sustained to Merediths body. The entire thing reeked of the Madeline Mcann case tbh when the police tried to use the 'smell of bleach' and Amanda 'shaking incontrollably' in the kitchen bearing similarities to the 'smell of death' in the Mcanns Renault, in other words speculation from police looking for something.

The truth is Amanda Knox got herself into trouble from her innappropriate and bizzare behaviour after the murder that made the police eventually attempt to build a case against her, which or course led to the borderline torture tactics to extort a falsified story that placed her in further suspicion when changed later.
</post>
<post author="green chica" datetime="2011-10-03T23:20:00" id="p236">
No one really knows if she did it or not except for Amanda herself. I don't think anyone on here is in the position to pass judgement either for or against Amanda.
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T23:21:00" id="p237">
<quote orig_author="j0hn">
I always believed she was innocent, the DNA evidence even minus the flaws wasn't necessarily strong enough to assert a conviction especially in Amandas case, so when the DNA evidence which seemed to me to be a close shave anyway was discredited, it was only a matter of time. None of Amandas DNA was found in the room, just on a reguarly used kitchen knife which supposedly had Merediths blood on the blade, which turned out not only to be low, but incompatible with the injuries sustained to Merediths body. The entire thing reeked of the Madeline Mcann case tbh when the police tried to use the 'smell of bleach' and Amanda 'shaking incontrollably' in the kitchen bearing similarities to the 'smell of death' in the Mcanns Renault, in other words speculation from police looking for something.

The truth is Amanda Knox got herself into trouble from her innappropriate and bizzare behaviour after the murder that made the police eventually attempt to build a case against her, which or course led to the borderline torture tactics to extort a falsified story that placed her in further suspicion when changed later.

</quote>

not again..... <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/mad.gif" alt=":mad:"/>
</post>
<post author="Cicerao" datetime="2011-10-03T23:22:00" id="p238">
<quote orig_author="johndoranglasgow">
It's not really a huge surprise and the media by no means treated her fairly but I dunno... I just get a bit of a gut feeling whenever I see them and hear some of the things (particularly Knox) says - they seem guilty as hell.

</quote>

But what of it? I see things like, "She has an evil look in her eye!" But you wouldn't think that if she were a random woman on the street, would you? People are only saying those things because they paraded it around the media as a nice story, the "beautiful she-devil" angle.

I don't personally think she did it, but none of us can know for sure.
</post>
<post author="danny111" datetime="2011-10-03T23:23:00" id="p239">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
HEY please understand once a liar always a liar.

When a man cheats then he always a cheater!

If she such an ANGEL then why she CHANGE her STORY!

</quote>

I hope you never will be a juror in an important case.

And lol at the part in bold. Sexist much?

<quote orig_author="rlw31">
So lying about something= automatically guilty of the crime

I ****ing hope to hell that you're never called up for jury service.

</quote>

My sentiments exactly.
</post>
<post author="dzeh" datetime="2011-10-03T23:27:00" id="p240">
Lol @ Italians

Whole thing was a shambles
</post>
<post author="johndoranglasgow" datetime="2011-10-03T23:29:00" id="p241">
<quote orig_author="Cicerao">
But what of it? I see things like, "She has an evil look in her eye!" But you wouldn't think that if she were a random woman on the street, would you? People are only saying those things because they paraded it around the media as a nice story, the "beautiful she-devil" angle.

I don't personally think she did it, but none of us can know for sure.

</quote>

Well in fairness she has been charged, tried and convicted for slander when she tried to convince the police that a barman was guilty of the murder. Thats a little more tangible than the "evil look in her eye". <img src="images/smilies/smile.png"/>

I'm not some media whore, I try my best to be objective. The fact is that in relation to this case, Knox has been given and served a 3 year sentence; I think its understandable that people remain suspicious of her.
</post>
<post author="bestofyou" datetime="2011-10-03T23:32:00" id="p242">
<quote orig_author="neiljeff123">
Wasn't there DNA that said they were both at the scene?

</quote>

yes, I think there was a bra that had raffelle's DNA on it, but apparently they couldn't use that because it took 46days to be placed in an evidence bag. I don't see how he could have gotten his DNA on it in those 46 days, but there is the possibility it was planted, which is why they couldn't use it. I don't think the police planted anything though, despite what the american media likes to think.
</post>
<post author="j0hn" datetime="2011-10-03T23:34:00" id="p243">
<quote orig_author="ANJAL">
not again..... <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/mad.gif" alt=":mad:"/>

</quote>

The reason the story was changed was because of the unregulated and desperate Italian police force desperate to find answers under international scrutiny. Amanda Knox was questioned none stop for 14 hours with a suggestion of violence also becoming apparent. Even an experienced Ex-FBI agent Steve Moore agrees "I know these type of techniques and believe me if they are used properly you could even get the prosecutor Giuliano Mignini to admit to murder - I'm just surprised it took 14 hours" which is why she changed her story later on after relentless questioning left her fabricating a story that would free her from the persistant bully boy tactics and it's important to remember that there was no solicitor present, which meant the police were under no constraints in their tactics.
</post>
<post author="Guy Secretan" datetime="2011-10-03T23:38:00" id="p244">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
How is that farcical <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/confused.gif" alt=":confused:"/> She was sentenced to 3 years and served four years, what's that got to do with saving face?

</quote>

Because it's quite convenient that it means that she is completely exonerated and doesn't have anymore time to serve. If they had just let her off completely then there would be questions about compensation for four years of her life wasted.
</post>
<post author="HurricaneDominic" datetime="2011-10-03T23:39:00" id="p245">
Too much press interference with this one.
Now it has become so hard to tell whether she was involved or not. There are so many different possibilities!

If I had to give a straight YES or NO answer to whether she is guilty or not, it would be YES.

I think she was most likely at the scene, whether she actually murdered Meredith is another story, but surely if she wasn't there at all this would have been pretty easy to prove?

Anyway, R.I.P. Meredith.
</post>
<post author="Guy Secretan" datetime="2011-10-03T23:39:00" id="p246">
<quote orig_author="green chica">
No one really knows if she did it or not except for Amanda herself. I don't think anyone on here is in the position to pass judgement either for or against Amanda.

</quote>

Rudy Guede also knows.
</post>
<post author="bestofyou" datetime="2011-10-03T23:40:00" id="p247">
<quote orig_author="j0hn">
///

</quote>

yeah sure, but what about the guy? His DNA was found on a bra, and I think had it been bagged straight away that we would have had a different verdit tonight.

Either way, its one of those things that people will alway wander about but never actually know. I just feel sad that a young girl that just wanted to go on a ERASMUS programme ended up dead, never heard about this story 4years ago, so...
</post>
<post author="ANJAL" datetime="2011-10-03T23:41:00" id="p248">
<quote orig_author="danny111">
I hope you never will be a juror in an important case.

And lol at the part in bold. Sexist much?

My sentiments exactly.

</quote>

lol sorry I was going a bit over board LAWLLLLLLLLL
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-03T23:43:00" id="p249">
<quote orig_author="Guy Secretan">
Because it's quite convenient that it means that she is completely exonerated and doesn't have anymore time to serve. If they had just let her off completely then there would be questions about compensation for four years of her life wasted.

</quote>

She successfully appealed against her murder conviction, she made no appeal against her defamation conviction, why would they randomly overturn it <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/confused.gif" alt=":confused:"/>
</post>
<post author="Dekota-XS" datetime="2011-10-03T23:46:00" id="p250">
A good example of how to get away with murder, take the case to the Italian courts where the horny sombrero judge will decide.
</post>
<post author="katy_j87" datetime="2011-10-03T23:54:00" id="p251">
<quote orig_author="Cicerao">
Two young people being in jail with little to no evidence they're guilty is not going to bring Meredith back.

</quote>

I agree that nothing we say will bring her back and that is the sad thing about all this. I just think the evidence that they didn't do it is very questionable and there is something very fishy about all this. I'm not sure the Italian justice system is very reliable from what has been said, it is all very sketchy.

I also don't agree with the press making all of this about Amanda Knox and her 'nightmare' in jail. What about DEAD Meredith Kercher who died in a horrific way? Far more of a nightmare if you ask me.
</post>
<post author="Cicerao" datetime="2011-10-04T00:11:00" id="p252">
<quote orig_author="katy_j87">
I agree that nothing we say will bring her back and that is the sad thing about all this. I just think the evidence that they didn't do it is very questionable and there is something very fishy about all this. I'm not sure the Italian justice system is very reliable from what has been said, it is all very sketchy.

I also don't agree with the press making all of this about Amanda Knox and her 'nightmare' in jail. What about DEAD Meredith Kercher who died in a horrific way? Far more of a nightmare if you ask me.

</quote>

Yes, it's worse to be dead, but you're a student, yes? Imagine if you were convicted of your flatmate's murder, and let's say you're innocent. Would you be all, "Oh my flatmate had it worse, it's fine" or would you, despite acknowledging the terrible death, feel a lot of suffering for losing 4 years of the prime of your life? <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/> There's always going to be worse things going on but that doesn't void the fact that a terrible ordeal is terrible ordeal.
</post>
<post author="Heavenly_Blues" datetime="2011-10-04T00:16:00" id="p253">
<quote orig_author="ArcadiaHouse">
She gives me the creeps. I think she's guilty.

</quote>

Troy Davis gives me the creeps, I bet he's guilty too. <img src="images/smilies/biggrin.png"/>

But naw, in all seriousness, I don't know what to think, her constant story-changing strikes me as suspicious, and she does seem like quite a dodgy person, but we have to go with facts, not instincts in things like this, what bothers me is that this was a horrible crime, and the real victims were Meredith and her family, and for Amanda Knox and her whole bloody family to attempt to play the pity angle in the news (at least it looked like that) is sickening.
</post>
<post author="419" datetime="2011-10-04T00:17:00" id="p254">
It'll be very distasteful if she releases a book as she's expected to. Talk about rubbing salt in to the wound of Kercher's family. If she does, I hope they get all the rights to it ala OJ Simpson.
</post>
<post author="Guy Secretan" datetime="2011-10-04T00:19:00" id="p255">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
She successfully appealed against her murder conviction, she made no appeal against her defamation conviction, why would they randomly overturn it <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/confused.gif" alt=":confused:"/>

</quote>

Because the two are intertwined if she lied about them beating her then obv she did it for a reason. He lying was part of the prosecutions case for murder. Also the defamation was brought about as a defence against charges which are now shown to be false. She knew she wouldn't have to appeal the defamation charge because of time she had already served. Basically it's kind of ridiculous to convict her of lying about the police actions and then letting her get away with murder in my view because the two seem contradictory. The law looks at then as separate events but if she lied and said she was beaten by police and they convict her of that then why did she lie and that affects the murder case aswell.
</post>
<post author="Cicerao" datetime="2011-10-04T00:21:00" id="p256">
<quote orig_author="ArcadiaHouse">
She gives me the creeps. I think she's guilty.

</quote>

Let's hope you never get on a jury if that's your rationale for calling someone guilty. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/lolwut.gif" alt=":lolwut:"/>

I think innocent because there was little to none evidence of them being involved whereas there was lots of DNA evidence of Rudy Guede having committed the murder. So I believe Rudy Guede is the guilty one, but who am I to say.
</post>
<post author="katy_j87" datetime="2011-10-04T00:21:00" id="p257">
<quote orig_author="Cicerao">
Yes, it's worse to be dead, but you're a student, yes? Imagine if you were convicted of your flatmate's murder, and let's say you're innocent. Would you be all, "Oh my flatmate had it worse, it's fine" or would you, despite acknowledging the terrible death, feel a lot of suffering for losing 4 years of the prime of your life? <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/> There's always going to be worse things going on but that doesn't void the fact that a terrible ordeal is terrible ordeal.

</quote>

I see what you're saying but it's difficult for me to think that way as I believe she did play some part in it. I don't think she is completely innocent and I can see that she is going to be given a lot of adoration and positive attention from the press in the future. I just feel for the dead girl's family really, end of. Just my opinion.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-04T00:22:00" id="p258">
<quote orig_author="Guy Secretan">
Because the two are intertwined if she lied about them beating her then obv she did it for a reason. He lying was part of the prosecutions case for murder. Also the defamation was brought about as a defence against charges which are now shown to be false. She knew she wouldn't have to appeal the defamation charge because of time she had already served. Basically it's kind of ridiculous to convict her of lying about the police actions and then letting her get away with murder in my view because the two seem contradictory. The law looks at then as separate events but if she lied and said she was beaten by police and they convict her of that then why did she lie and that affects the murder case aswell.

</quote>

She lied to frame a guy of murder. That's defamation. How does that prove that she committed murder?
</post>
<post author="beepbeeprichie" datetime="2011-10-04T00:27:00" id="p259">
The Kercher family piss me off.
</post>
<post author="419" datetime="2011-10-04T00:31:00" id="p260">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
She lied to frame a guy of murder. That's defamation. How does that prove that she committed murder?

</quote>

It might not prove her to be a muderer but it gives reason to be very suspicious and certainly proves she isn't the angel she's painted as.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-04T00:33:00" id="p261">
<quote orig_author="419">
It might not prove her to be a muderer but it gives reason to be very suspicious and certainly proves she isn't the angel she's painted as.

</quote>

So she's no angel, what's she's said is suspicious, but again how does that prove she's guilty of murder? And how does it make it convenient that she's served time for her defamation charge?
</post>
<post author="UCAS.LOVER" datetime="2011-10-04T00:33:00" id="p262">
So who reckons she is guilty? I have a feeling she was guilty
</post>
<post author="UCAS.LOVER" datetime="2011-10-04T00:34:00" id="p263">
but she is seexy, got to give her that lads!
</post>
<post author="419" datetime="2011-10-04T00:37:00" id="p264">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
So she's no angel, what's she's said is suspicious, but again how does that prove she's guilty of murder? And how does it make it convenient that she's served time for her defamation charge?

</quote>

Ignore.
</post>
<post author="ArcadiaHouse" datetime="2011-10-04T00:39:00" id="p265">
<quote orig_author="Cicerao">
Let's hope you never get on a jury if that's your rationale for calling someone guilty. <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/lolwut.gif" alt=":lolwut:"/>

I think innocent because there was little to none evidence of them being involved whereas there was lots of DNA evidence of Rudy Guede having committed the murder. So I believe Rudy Guede is the guilty one, but who am I to say.

</quote>

Those were two separate sentences. I didn't say "I think she's guilty because she gives me the creeps." <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/>
</post>
<post author="KimKallstrom" datetime="2011-10-04T00:40:00" id="p266">
I read somewhere a few days ago how much Knox's dad spent on all this but forgot how much. It was the GDP of a small country though. He's a rich guy.

Imagine if he wasn't. She'd still be in the smaller for the whole sentence, no doubt.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-04T00:41:00" id="p267">
<quote orig_author="KimKallstrom">
I read somewhere a few days ago how much Knox's dad spent on all this but forgot how much. It was the GDP of a small country though. He's a rich guy.

Imagine if he wasn't. She'd still be in the smaller for the whole sentence, no doubt.

</quote>

What's your point?
</post>
<post author="Guy Secretan" datetime="2011-10-04T00:41:00" id="p268">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
She lied to frame a guy of murder. That's defamation. How does that prove that she committed murder?

</quote>

It doesn't prove it nothing did completely but it formed part of the original body of evidence. Also if I said she killed her I wouldnt get put in prison for three years neither would the people who chanted assassin even after she had been acquitted. For her to accuse him it would imply that she knew something about the murder or she was there. Since she has been acquitted and that is no longer the case legally she could have been just a member of the public saying someone was acting suspiciously or casting aspersions.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-04T00:46:00" id="p269">
<quote orig_author="Guy Secretan">
It doesn't prove it nothing did completely but it formed part of the original body of evidence. Also if I said she killed her I wouldnt get put in prison for three years neither would the people who chanted assassin even after she had been acquitted. For her to accuse him it would imply that she knew something about the murder or she was there. Since she has been acquitted and that is no longer the case legally she could have been just a member of the public saying someone was acting suspiciously or casting aspersions.

</quote>

If you knowingly gave a false statement to the police and it could be proved that you did so knowingly, then yes, you could get a prison sentence for that.

To the bit in bold, yes I guess so.

I still don't see what's convenient about the fact the the defamation charges weren't overturned <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="scriggy" datetime="2011-10-04T00:46:00" id="p270">
Noone on here knows better than the Italian justice system.

She has been found innocent and hence should be treated as such.
</post>
<post author="giordano" datetime="2011-10-04T00:48:00" id="p271">
<quote orig_author="white_haired_wizard">
My gut feeling is that she and that Raffaelle fella did kill Meredith Kercher.

</quote>

Mine too, but I would say that their guilt was not proved beyond reasonable doubt.

When the DNA tests' credibility collapsed, this was the only logical outcome.
</post>
<post author="G50" datetime="2011-10-04T00:49:00" id="p272">
They weren't able to prove that she was guilty. That doesn't mean she's innocent (apart from in a legal sense).

Miscarriages of justice happen both ways round, people. The prosecution will appeal... but she'll have fled to America by then, just like the prosecutors warned.
</post>
<post author="Steevee" datetime="2011-10-04T00:59:00" id="p273">
Guilty in my opinion. Plus those damn yanks got on my nerves, some of them were honestly bemoaning our courts for daring to find a 'sweet, all American girl guilty of such a terrible crime, how could they even think it?' And that is an actual quote from an American on another forum I frequent.

But no, guilty in my opinion, down to all the story changing and the fact that none of her stories actually make that much sense.
</post>
<post author="giordano" datetime="2011-10-04T01:00:00" id="p274">
<quote orig_author="Butane">
A big dollar defence team from daddy Knox got them off on a DNA technicality, regardless of the non-DNA evidence like the blackout period of both their cell phones during the murder hours by both Knox and Sollecito. Will no doubt be going to the Supreme Court on appeal by the prosecutors.

</quote>

In Italy, the Supreme Court (Corte di Cassazione) is not competent to judge again about the substance, but only about procedures

If they find that there was some procedural mistake in this appeals trial, they would quash the sentence and then the appeals trial would have to be repeated.

Not very likely, I would say. In any case, I don't see Amanda returning for a new trial... would have to be in absentia
</post>
<post author="scriggy" datetime="2011-10-04T01:01:00" id="p275">
<quote orig_author="419">
Ignore.

</quote>

I think the point was... maybe she got scared and lied to get him convicted earlier?

If you were innocent and had an opportunity to convict someone you thought was most probably guilty... you'd probably lie to hasten the process.
</post>
<post author="Guy Secretan" datetime="2011-10-04T01:19:00" id="p276">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
If you knowingly gave a false statement to the police and it could be proved that you did so knowingly, then yes, you could get a prison sentence for that.

To the bit in bold, yes I guess so.

I still don't see what's convenient about the fact the the defamation charges weren't overturned <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/>

</quote>

Because I they were they would have to explain why they have been keeping someone in prison for four years for nothing rather than just one year and maybe pay out substantial damages in atrial that has already cost a lot bored of arguing now.
</post>
<post author="Aspiringlawstudent" datetime="2011-10-04T05:52:00" id="p277">
<quote orig_author=".eXe">
I said I'm pretty sure

That's not libel. It wasn't a factual statement, it was an opinion. Let's see me get sued for stating an opinion.

</quote>

You stated it as if it were fact in relation to the Casey Anthony matter.
</post>
<post author="Aspiringlawstudent" datetime="2011-10-04T05:53:00" id="p278">
<quote orig_author="SpicyStrawberry">
Oh yeah because people can sue anonymous users of the internet for libel when everyone is saying similar things can't they <img src="http://static.tsrfiles.co.uk/images/smilies/rolleyes.gif" alt=":rolleyes:"/> In the real world this wouldn't happen.

It wasn't even stated as fact, it's an opinion.

</quote>

"Im pretty sure that bitch killed her

Just cause its a girl she got off. Same thing happened in america with the casey anthony case where the wh0re murdered her own daughter.

Hope they both burn in hell "

Where's the opinion in that? It's stated as a fact.

Either way, there is no defence of fair comment when the comment is motivated by malice - calling people bitches and whores and saying you hope they burn in hell generally sounds malicious to me.
</post>
<post author="Mr Dangermouse" datetime="2011-10-04T07:48:00" id="p279">
The Casey Anthony case was different in every way. That was one of these cases where everyone knows she did it, there just wasn't enough evidence. Knox is different, with Italians forging evidence to convict an American girl, which when you consider it is really unsurprising. My gut is the whole thing was a drunken mistake and Guede is the lone killer.
</post>
<post author="giordano" datetime="2011-10-04T08:01:00" id="p280">
<quote orig_author="Mr Dangermouse">
Italians forging evidence to convict an American girl

</quote>

why should they do that ?

be the way, they also convicted an Italian boy
</post>
<post author="Ministerdonut" datetime="2011-10-04T08:44:00" id="p281">
It is justice jim but not as we know it. The yanks have OJ'd the ruling, pretty obvious that. I tell you what I think, I think she is a psycho loopy loop and probably has a history of odd behaviours from childhood, she did some fuked up things beforehand but this time she slipped up. Iam not saying she actually did the killing, do I think she was involved? yes, do I think she might have got a guy or several guys to do her dirty work for her because she was a manipulative b1tch? yes.She may not have even been in the room at the time,doesn't mean she wasn't involved. I firmly believe she was involved.

I actually think her attractiveness hurt her case,this is why I think lack of natural light and a prison diet made her seem more vunerable and helped her appeal,She didn't seem like this predatory vampiric slut that the prosecutor painted her as this time. No high jinks in the court room or flirting with the media this time..But a nice innocent american girl out of her depth. I think what got her out was she was american,some interference perhaps, and step daddy is rich,has connections and not an idiot,and worked with the media.

Knox is sorted for life now, step daddy will get all his money back and more thanks to media deals. Anyone heard of a film called midnight express? There will be a film similar to that out, and her family will make millions. That is not counting all the US media interviews. And you lot should like fox news this time, as that was the only US media network who thought she did it. I don't hear much mention of the fact the appeal upheld her conviction for framing an innocent man.

Merediths family must be devastated,thing is for her family it wasn't just about revenge but about justice and closure,thinking those that wronged their daughter in such away have been punished severely. As a supporter of capital punishment Iam not in favour of it in this case,because I said earlier I have enough doubts that knox did the actual killing,but do I think prison was the best place for her for another couple of decades? yes.
</post>
<post author="Ministerdonut" datetime="2011-10-04T09:18:00" id="p282">
Well I wouldn't want to be female,be pretty and be her flat mate to be quite honest. I certainly wouldn't want my sister sharing with her. I think she had involvement but what level of involvement Iam not certain about as evidence is all over the place and I don't think those there that night are going to come clean.Wouldn't surprise me if the Black man sitting in prison for 16 yrs hasn't been slipped a tidy sum to keep his mouth shut and he won't serve the full sixteen. She could have been involved in a conspiracy without actually doing the killing. In my opinion she was the type of female who gets men to do her bidding for her.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-04T09:25:00" id="p283">
<quote orig_author="Guy Secretan">
Because I they were they would have to explain why they have been keeping someone in prison for four years for nothing rather than just one year and maybe pay out substantial damages in atrial that has already cost a lot bored of arguing now.

</quote>

The first sentence doesn't make sense. Her appeal for the murder charge concluded after having spent 4 years in prison, her conviction for that was quashed. She was convicted to 3 years for her defamation charge, having already served that time, she's been released. I don't know why you think that's farcical <img src="images/smilies/s-smilie.gif"/>
</post>
<post author="ElNormo91" datetime="2011-10-04T11:45:00" id="p284">
<quote orig_author="j0hn">
The truth is Amanda Knox got herself into trouble from her innappropriate and bizzare behaviour after the murder that made the police eventually attempt to build a case against her, which or course led to the borderline torture tactics to extort a falsified story that placed her in further suspicion when changed later.

</quote>

I would have thought that it was down to the emotion she illustrated. Even though the cartwheeling at the police station seemed very surreal, the initial framing of a barman and then the slandering of the Polizia Di Stato was done out of a rather confused and dazed plea for innocence after being at the wrong place at the wrong time. She was, and still will be of good character, no matter what the media (Italian or not) thinks of her, or whether or not the whole thing was trying to pull a Casey Anthony or OJ.

Knox's prosecutor has been accused for abusing his position after it had been revealed that he mishandled past cases, such as the "Mostro di Firenze" and the case about the death of a Freemason back in 1985, and ordered the unauthorised bugging of telecommunications during the Mostro case (Source: <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2011/oct/03/giuliano-mignini-knox-prosecutor-conspiracy">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2011...tor-conspiracy</a> ). I'm definitely not surprised that his corruption led to the fabrication of a prosecution that led to a miscarriage of justice being placed upon a rather aspiring American who has done completely nothing wrong. And those who think that she still should have been prosecuted should think again.
</post>
<post author="Cicerao" datetime="2011-10-04T13:56:00" id="p285">
<quote orig_author="ElNormo91">
Even though the cartwheeling at the police station seemed very surreal

</quote>

Apparently she was actually doing various yoga moves such as the windmill, and that got mistranslated/misinterpreted to be a cartwheel.
</post>
<post author="G50" datetime="2011-10-04T14:30:00" id="p286">
Why yes... I often start fancy yoga moves while I'm being held at the police station under suspicion of murder.
</post>
<post author="rlw31" datetime="2011-10-04T14:35:00" id="p287">
<quote orig_author="G50">
Why yes... I often start fancy yoga moves while I'm being held at the police station under suspicion of murder.

</quote>

So what?
</post>
<post author="eggnchips" datetime="2011-10-04T14:37:00" id="p288">
She's is stunning though isnt she, obviously guilty and a complete nutter, but incredibly attractive none the less. Her eyes are terrifying so cold and vacant, I could just imagine her holding a knife to my through as we made love. Hope she does a lads mag/playboy shoot would be amazing
</post>
<post author="PAPAdawg" datetime="2011-10-04T14:41:00" id="p289">
let's face it, none of you are qualified to have any opinion on this really. the italian courts have spent years going over the evidence of this case, and they have 10 times the information we have, and even then they aren't sure really who killed meredith. i'm sick of gossipy old mail readers saying ''oh, just look at 'er, you can see it in 'er eyes, she's guilty as sin''. the truth is that none of us can possibly no

And this is why we have a legal system. This legal system may have initally convicted her, but the reason appeals processes are compulsory in these trials is because all good legal systems such as the italian one accept their fallability and the possibility of mistakes. this is why every murder convict in italy will have 100s of thousand spent on their appeal. in this case, the sppeal ahs cleared amanda, this means the people who have been exposed to the evidence to the greatest extent of anyone on the planet, more than some gossipy old ''no smoke without fire'' skeptic or any journalist, have decided her guilty conviction was not strong enough to stand. that is not a decision taken lightly.

so basically, deal with it. she may indeed have done it, we will never know, but to the best of our knowledge as people who have to take things at face value have to accept that she has been found innocent. that means we need to get off her back, regardless of how many theories the papers bring up.

interestingly, i've read before a paper on psychology that explains that in a lot of cases of death row/lifer being released from prison after years in america due to new dna testing, almost always the familys of the victim will actually refuse to belive the dna evidence, and continue to puish for the person to be locked up again, and scupper police efforts to find the real killer. basically, when we believe someone is guilty, we ingrain that view and it is very hard for us to ever change your mind. when people refuse to acknowledge the hours of analysis that went into the judge and jury deciding the conviction of know was untenable, they are undergoing the same flawed thought process. every time you see her face, your brain says guilty andf it will always do so no matter how many times she is found not guilty, she's a bad 'un to you

and it scares me how easy it would be to have the whole world hate you for something you may not have done. people are like a mob sometimes
</post>
<post author="G50" datetime="2011-10-04T14:47:00" id="p290">
lol, oh those thorough Italian courts! Nothing could get through them!

<quote>
The Italian appeals process offers more guarantees to defendants than any other legal system in the world, whereby only the weakest evidence is treated, not the whole case. Knox's team only had to attack the DNA evidence against her to undermine the whole edifice of the original trial. Italy has one of lowest prison populations in the world because of its lenient appeals process.
</quote>

<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-15157384">http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-15157384</a>
</post>
<post author="Agent Smirnoff" datetime="2011-10-04T14:56:00" id="p291">
It was when I learned the astounding fact that the police
had found traces of Amanda Knox's DNA on Amanda
Knox's own kitchen knife that it all became clear
</post>
<post author="Greeny442" datetime="2011-10-04T18:14:00" id="p292">
<quote orig_author="eggnchips">
She's is stunning though isnt she, obviously guilty and a complete nutter, but incredibly attractive none the less. Her eyes are terrifying so cold and vacant, I could just imagine her holding a knife to my through as we made love. Hope she does a lads mag/playboy shoot would be amazing

</quote>

Her and Casey Anthony - you wouldn't survive the night, but at least you'd have a good time.
</post>
<post author="SpicyStrawberry" datetime="2011-10-04T20:05:00" id="p293">
<quote orig_author="Aspiringlawstudent">
"Im pretty sure that bitch killed her

Just cause its a girl she got off. Same thing happened in america with the casey anthony case where the wh0re murdered her own daughter.

Hope they both burn in hell "

Where's the opinion in that? It's stated as a fact.

Either way, there is no defence of fair comment when the comment is motivated by malice - calling people bitches and whores and saying you hope they burn in hell generally sounds malicious to me.

</quote>

It's an opinion that Knox is a bitch/whore. It's an opinion that she got off because she's a girl.
</post>
<post author="Aspiringlawstudent" datetime="2011-10-04T20:35:00" id="p294">
<quote orig_author="SpicyStrawberry">
It's an opinion that Knox is a bitch/whore. It's an opinion that she got off because she's a girl.

</quote>

It does not matter if that is opinion because it is malicious. There is no defence of fair comment when the comment is a malicious one. Stating someone is a bitch and a whore is clearly overtly malicious, as is stating you hope they "burn in hell".

You've also ignored the libel of Casey Anthony.
</post>
<post author="SpicyStrawberry" datetime="2011-10-04T20:52:00" id="p295">
<quote orig_author="Aspiringlawstudent">
It does not matter if that is opinion because it is malicious. There is no defence of fair comment when the comment is a malicious one. Stating someone is a bitch and a whore is clearly overtly malicious, as is stating you hope they "burn in hell".

You've also ignored the libel of Casey Anthony.

</quote>

I don't know that case, but people hurl insults at each other every day, they don't take each other to court over it. What I'm trying to say is, in reality, nothing would come of one malicious comment (unless it was racist or homophobic or similar). If it was tirades of abuse then it would be taken much more seriously.
</post>
<post author=".eXe" datetime="2011-10-04T21:03:00" id="p296">
<quote orig_author="Aspiringlawstudent">
It does not matter if that is opinion because it is malicious. There is no defence of fair comment when the comment is a malicious one. Stating someone is a bitch and a whore is clearly overtly malicious, as is stating you hope they "burn in hell".

You've also ignored the libel of Casey Anthony.

</quote>

I made those comments and I would still make them again. They weer insults not threats. Also, calling someone a whore does not make them one. If you call me an idiot, that's your opinion of me and the last thing I can do is sue you for making an insulting remark towards me.

Defamatory comments is when you take something that isn't true, and make it true and then publicize it to the world.

What I did was publicly insult her.Its like you calling me an idiot in the middle of the street.

Not libel. Not defamatory.
</post>
<post author="Aspiringlawstudent" datetime="2011-10-04T21:19:00" id="p297">
<quote orig_author=".eXe">
I made those comments and I would still make them again. They weer insults not threats. Also, calling someone a whore does not make them one. If you call me an idiot, that's your opinion of me and the last thing I can do is sue you for making an insulting remark towards me.

Defamatory comments is when you take something that isn't true, and make it true and then publicize it to the world.

What I did was publicly insult her.Its like you calling me an idiot in the middle of the street.

Not libel. Not defamatory.

</quote>

You have stated "Same thing happened in america with the casey anthony case where the wh0re murdered her own daughter."

You state that Casey Anthony is a whore and a murderer.

You do not state it as an opinion.

It also would not matter if it was an opinion or not, as it is malicious (you admit it is an insult).

If a comment is malicious, there is no defence of fair comment (the "opinion" line you seem to be talking about).

You have published these comments to the world (note however that saying even once to anyone aside from the person you're talking about can be defamation. You don't need to say it in a book, newspaper, tv or even online to defame someone.)

As you've published these comments in a permanent format, ie online in text, they are libel.

You have libelled Casey Anthony.

It's black and white.
</post>
<post author="Aspiringlawstudent" datetime="2011-10-04T21:23:00" id="p298">
<quote orig_author="SpicyStrawberry">
I don't know that case, but people hurl insults at each other every day, they don't take each other to court over it. What I'm trying to say is, in reality, nothing would come of one malicious comment (unless it was racist or homophobic or similar). If it was tirades of abuse then it would be taken much more seriously.

</quote>

You're very much entitled to "hurl insults" at the person you want to insult (you can't defame someone to their face - only to a third party).

However, you cannot state "X murdered their child and is a whore" when there is no proof of that.

That is defamatory.

An innocent woman being called a child killer is disgusting.
</post>
<post author="issyconnor" datetime="2011-10-04T21:24:00" id="p299">
What's I'm wondering is that if Knox did do it (I personally think she did, but off due to inconclusive evidence) why? Why would you choose to allow your housemate to be sexually abused and murdered so brutally? That's what I find disturbing about this case.
</post>
<post author="Aspiringlawstudent" datetime="2011-10-04T21:25:00" id="p300">
<quote orig_author="issyconnor">
What's I'm wondering is that if Knox did do it (I personally think she did, but off due to inconclusive evidence) why? Why would you choose to allow your housemate to be sexually abused and murdered so brutally? That's what I find disturbing about this case.

</quote>

I'm confused; you're saying "if Knox did do it" and "why would you allow it to happen"; the two aren't the same.

Which do you think happened?

That Knox killed Kercher, or Knox knowingly allowed Kercher to be murdered by a third party (who?).
</post>
<post author="Rebellious-Steve" datetime="2011-10-04T21:26:00" id="p301">
I have no opinion.
</post>
<post author="S119234" datetime="2011-10-04T21:30:00" id="p302">
She's been let off on a technicality, doesn't mean she's innocent though, which she isn't. She knows what happened in that apartment on that evening and all the evidence points to her being there.
</post>
<post author="SpicyStrawberry" datetime="2011-10-04T21:31:00" id="p303">
<quote orig_author="Aspiringlawstudent">
You're very much entitled to "hurl insults" at the person you want to insult (you can't defame someone to their face - only to a third party).

However, you cannot state "X murdered their child and is a whore" when there is no proof of that.

That is defamatory.

An innocent woman being called a child killer is disgusting.

</quote>

Personally I think Knox had an involvement with her death, she might not have actually killed the woman but if she helped she's just as guilty. You can just tell she's happy to be free rather than glad she's been "proven" to be innocent. It's all about her and not the innocent victim which is sad. The media don't help either with talks of book deals and films. Making money out of someone's murder is what I find disgusting, especially when Ms Kercher's family barely afforded to attend the trial.
</post>
<post author="Aspiringlawstudent" datetime="2011-10-04T21:32:00" id="p304">
<quote orig_author="S119234">
She's been let off on a technicality, doesn't mean she's innocent though, which she isn't. She knows what happened in that apartment on that evening and all the evidence points to her being there.

</quote>

The technicality being "oh, the evidence is actually completely ruined"?

You can't convict people with shoddy evidence.
</post>
<post author="Aspiringlawstudent" datetime="2011-10-04T21:34:00" id="p305">
<quote orig_author="SpicyStrawberry">
Personally I think Knox had an involvement with her death, she might not have actually killed the woman but if she helped she's just as guilty. You can just tell she's happy to be free rather than glad she's been "proven" to be innocent. It's all about her and not the innocent victim which is sad. The media don't help either with talks of book deals and films. Making money out of someone's murder is what I find disgusting.

</quote>

If you'd been in prison for four years for something you say you didn't do and the evidence is not reliable, wouldn't you be happy to be free?

Being free and being innocent are the same.

You are innocent until proven guilty.

She has not been proven guilty.

The evidence doesn't show that beyond reasonable doubt.

Therefore, she is innocent.
</post>
<post author="SpicyStrawberry" datetime="2011-10-04T21:47:00" id="p306">
<quote orig_author="Aspiringlawstudent">
If you'd been in prison for four years for something you say you didn't do and the evidence is not reliable, wouldn't you be happy to be free?

Being free and being innocent are the same.

You are innocent until proven guilty.

She has not been proven guilty.

The evidence doesn't show that beyond reasonable doubt.

Therefore, she is innocent.

</quote>

Lol, there's no need to put it like I'm stupid. I'm well aware of the law, and she got let off on a technicality because of the poor performance of the Italian police. I refuse to believe she is innocent.

Guilty people get let off all the time, it's about time you realised that just because you've not been sent down you could have still done wrong.
</post>
<post author="Antonia87" datetime="2011-10-04T21:56:00" id="p307">
I dont trust this woman at all, I'd bet my house she was involved (innocent people dont change their stories multiple times, or pretend they saw someone else do it). She's a liar and she's hiding something...

But I really, really wish the bloody papers would stop calling her "Foxy Knoxy". It was on every front page today. Its so juvenile and inappropriate.
</post>
<post author="122025278" datetime="2011-10-04T23:14:00" id="p308">
<quote orig_author="Antonia87">
I dont trust this woman at all, I'd bet my house she was involved (innocent people dont change their stories multiple times, or pretend they saw someone else do it). She's a liar and she's hiding something...

But I really, really wish the bloody papers would stop calling her "Foxy Knoxy". It was on every front page today. Its so juvenile and inappropriate.

</quote>

You don't find Knoxy Foxy?
</post>
<post author="KimKallstrom" datetime="2011-10-05T19:47:00" id="p309">
<quote orig_author="rlw31">
What's your point?

</quote>

It's a bit depressing.
</post>
<post author="s04582" datetime="2011-10-05T19:58:00" id="p310">
I just hope she doenst make a fortune from the death of poor meredith. That would be disgusting.
</post>
<post author="giordano" datetime="2011-10-05T23:02:00" id="p311">
<quote orig_author="PAPAdawg">
let's face it, none of you are qualified to have any opinion on this really. the italian courts have spent years going over the evidence of this case, and they have 10 times the information we have, and even then they aren't sure really who killed meredith. i'm sick of gossipy old mail readers saying ''oh, just look at 'er, you can see it in 'er eyes, she's guilty as sin''. the truth is that none of us can possibly no

And this is why we have a legal system. This legal system may have initally convicted her, but the reason appeals processes are compulsory in these trials is because all good legal systems such as the italian one accept their fallability and the possibility of mistakes. this is why every murder convict in italy will have 100s of thousand spent on their appeal. in this case, the sppeal ahs cleared amanda, this means the people who have been exposed to the evidence to the greatest extent of anyone on the planet, more than some gossipy old ''no smoke without fire'' skeptic or any journalist, have decided her guilty conviction was not strong enough to stand. that is not a decision taken lightly.

so basically, deal with it. she may indeed have done it, we will never know, but to the best of our knowledge as people who have to take things at face value have to accept that she has been found innocent. that means we need to get off her back, regardless of how many theories the papers bring up.

interestingly, i've read before a paper on psychology that explains that in a lot of cases of death row/lifer being released from prison after years in america due to new dna testing, almost always the familys of the victim will actually refuse to belive the dna evidence, and continue to puish for the person to be locked up again, and scupper police efforts to find the real killer. basically, when we believe someone is guilty, we ingrain that view and it is very hard for us to ever change your mind. when people refuse to acknowledge the hours of analysis that went into the judge and jury deciding the conviction of know was untenable, they are undergoing the same flawed thought process. every time you see her face, your brain says guilty andf it will always do so no matter how many times she is found not guilty, she's a bad 'un to you

and it scares me how easy it would be to have the whole world hate you for something you may not have done. people are like a mob sometimes

</quote>

this is all very precisely observed, and amazingly true
</post>
<post author="419" datetime="2011-10-05T23:57:00" id="p312">
<quote orig_author="s04582">
I just hope she doenst make a fortune from the death of poor meredith. That would be disgusting.

</quote>

She will. The world is a ****ed up place where the villian are massively loved. Especially one that is 'foxy' with rich parents. Its truely sad!
</post>
<post author="419" datetime="2011-10-05T23:59:00" id="p313">
<quote orig_author="Aspiringlawstudent">
If you'd been in prison for four years for something you say you didn't do and the evidence is not reliable, wouldn't you be happy to be free?

Being free and being innocent are the same.

You are innocent until proven guilty.

She has not been proven guilty.

The evidence doesn't show that beyond reasonable doubt.

Therefore, she is innocent.

</quote>

Why the need to constantly change her story and blame the murder on another man.

She might be innocent of the actual killing but she knew the **** that went down that night and wasn't somewhere else- sorry not buying that story.
</post>
<post author="TheEssence" datetime="2011-10-06T00:02:00" id="p314">
I'd rather fight and keep a guilty man innocent than not do a thing and watch an innocent man suffer
</post>
</doc>
